<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2206" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">29</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">22</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">06</biblScope><date value="18920601" TEIform="date">June 1892</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">121-144</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="22" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="06" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
JUNE.
THE
MANIFESTO.
Published by the United Societies.
VOL. XXII.
"For what is a man profited, if he shall gain the whole world, and
lose his own soul ? or what shall a man give in exchange for
his soul."Matt. XVI., 26.
Canterbury, N. H.
1892.

<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
The Kentucky Revival, No. 18,
Which the Real or Ideal,
Evolution,           ....
Faith Dual,        ....
Letter,Elder A. Perkins,
Something New,
Editorial,            ....
Inquiry,       -       ....
Scripture Text,
In MemoryS. A. Weatherford,
In Memoriam,
Notes About Home,
Not for an Orange,
Deaths,           -        -         -      Books & Papers,
Page.
Vi\
124
127
128
139
130
132
133
134
135
136
143
- 144
WROO    i
i/9l    10
OO A MONTH can be
i made working for us.
Persons preferred who can furnish a horse
and give their whole time to the business.
Spare moments may be profitably employed
also. A few vacancies in towns and cities.
B. F. JOHNSON & CO., 26th. and Main St.,
Richmond, Va.
Scientific American
Agency for
       CAVEATS,
i-   TRADE MARKS,
DESION PATENTS
____         COPYRIGHTS, etc.
For information and free Handbook write to
MUNN & CO.. 361 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.
Oldest bureau for securing patents In America.
Every patent taken out by us is brought before
the public by a notice given free of charge ic tne
Largest circulation of any scientific paper to the
world. Splendidly illustrated. No intelligent
man should be without it., Wefclj\JS3.00 a
yoar; $1.50 six months. Address MUNN & CO.,
publishers, 3d Broadway, New Y. ori.
 WOELE^ COLUMBIAN EXAGENTS WANTED nkf \fo
MAKE PEOLI            vDOU
1  Ujrri/ working for WOELlTS COL- - - - - - - - - 
A nttlV POSITION ILLUSTRATED; authentic organ of the World's Fair. Most beautiful, interesting and popular publication issued. Sells
at sight. Send 15 c. in stamps for full particulars and sample copy containing COLOEED LITHOGBAPEIC VIEWS of EXPOSITION BUILDINGS. J. B.
Campbell, Pres., 218 LaSalle St., Chicago, 111.
Hall's Journal op Health. May. Con.
A word with our Readers; Talks with D.
Mandeville; Rescued by his horse; How is
it Done; Sunstroke; Alcohol and Insanity;
Whole Wheat Bread; School Girl's Luncheon; Meat Eaters; The Sabbath; The Tobacco Habit, etc., etc. Office 340 West 59th St.,
New York.
THE  ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetie
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley,
901 Olive St.,  St. Louis, Mo
LIFEOFCH.SPURGEON,
By the noted Author, Patter, Journalist
and Platform Orator,
RUSSELL H. CONWELL.
5OO Pages,       I    75c. OUTFIT FOR 30c.
ELEGANTLY  ILLUSTRATED.   Greatest Chance you
OUTFIT   $1.5O.      I ever had to Make Monej.
EVERY CHRISTIAN FAMILY WANTS HIS LIFE.
It is full of intensest interest from beginning
to close.   It is a mine of valuable information, and filled with the purest thought, keenest
wit, richest experience and truest philosophy.
It WILL PAY YOU to WORK for US.
Remember we allow our agents to sire to
erery one wh buys this book, which retails
for only 81.5O, a free six months' subscription to "Thk Christian," which was
Mr* Spurgeon's Favorite Paper,
he having had it for years, and hayiDg said of it t
" 'THE CHRISTIAN' Is the Best Paper that comes to me."
It requires a salesman to sell some hooks;
this one anybody can sell, because the people
want it, and the premium we give (The
Christian) makes the work still easier.
The people are anxious to have the book,
and wait with the money to pay for it.
WILL YOU TAKE IT TO THEM?
Sample Book, prepaid, and " The Christiak "
Six months, for only $1.6O.
lyBest Terms        I |gp-Act  Quick!
To Our Agents.     |   No Time to J.ose!
The first to send 30c. (postage) for Outfit, gets
the territory. Address JOHN K. HASTINGS,
Mngr. of "THE CHRISTIAN," 47 COFNHILL, Boston, Mast.
(Preierv* thii, it may not appear again.   Mtntion this paptr.y
JOHN   F.   STRATTON   &   SON'8
CELEBRATED
Importrofnd WholeleDealeriln all kindtof
JflUSiCAL   .MERCHANDISE,
Violins, Guitars, Baniot, Mandolines, Accordeons,
Harmonicas, 4c, all kinds of Strings, etc.etc.
43 * 45 Walker St.,                     SEW IOBK.
IF you wish to  advertise   anything anj
where at any time, write td GEO. I
ROWELL & CO., No. 10 Spruce St., N. Y.
Vol. XXII.
JUNE, 1892.
No. 6.--><pb n="121" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kentucky revival. no. 18" TEIform="index"/> THE KENTUCKY REVIVAL.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M'Nemar, Richard" TEIform="persName"/> By Richard M'Nemar:</byline><p TEIform="p"> of Union Village, Ohio. Ptihlixhed in Albany, N. Y., in IMS. No. 18. Explanations.
                            Continued. The work of God never did go on in spite, but in love and kindness to all men,
                            even the Calvinists not excepted. But while the Christians upon the slightest evidence of
                            the Shakers being liars, can fall to shouting and praising their God, or at the sight of
                            them, stop every medium of information with loud cries for deliverance, a work of some kind
                            will no doubt go on in spite of every thing that claims any relation to the coming of
                            Christ. How long God may trouble these mighty waters, and what degree of power may operate
                            round about in that preparatory work, has never been predicted. Truth has its foundation in
                            the nature of God. Like the Eternal himself, it is one, and is as necessary to the
                            preservation of the soul, as food to the body, or heat and moisture to the plant. And yet,
                            alas ! that best and only preservative of the noble mind, is unnaturally despised and
                            rejected of men. The Savior of sinners, who calls himself the truth, was made flash and
                            dwelt among us, but how few, comparatively beheld his glory. The men of the world knew him
                            not, therefore they did to him what they listed. But though he was put to death in the
                            flesh, yet he was quickened by the spirit, and now livelh forevermore. The world seeth him
                            not but Christians see him, for he is in them, and will be with them; and because he lives
                            they shall live also. He is the same in his word that he was m human flesh; and in every
                            form his treatment has been the same. How often even among us, has he been crucified afresh,
                            and put to an open shame; pronounced powerless, dead, and buried among the rubbish of human
                            tradition. But amidst all this infamy, the blessed truth has been preserved, that not a bone
                            of him is broken. And has not a great stone, the confession of faith, been rolled off him ?
                            Has he not risen indeed ? and has not the earth quaked at his resurrection? Surely the word
                            of God <pb n="122" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> could not be bound ; it was impossible that he should be holden
                            of death. He is risen indeed, and we are witnesses of his resurrection, and do testify that
                            this is he whom God has appointed to be the judge of both the quick and the dead. We have
                            already showai in our viewT of the gospel, that it is by the eternal word that we are to be
                            new created ; the inquiry now before us is, how are we to be governed? Must we be kept by
                            the same power through faith unto salvation; abide in the light as he is in the light; have
                            fellowship with the Father and with his Son Jesus Christ, and grow up in him in all things
                            who is the head? or must the dispensation be changed, the Creator withdraw and hide himself,
                            and leave the subjects of his grace to certain delegated powers, ordained to scatter and
                            divide ; to be shut up in particular apartments, and prepared for heaven by certain and
                            definite forms? It will be granted that he who creates has a right to govern. Upon this
                            principle God is acknowledged to be the governor of the world. It will also be granted, that
                            he who has wTisdom and powrer to create, has also to govern; and that the same power which
                            brings any system into being, is necessary for its preservation. We learn that God created
                            all things by Jesus Christ, and made him the head over all things to his body, that is, the
                            Church. His eternal power and Godhead is the nail upon which the glory of his house is
                            suspended. We have known Christ after the flesh, and acted as vicegerants in his oom and by
                            his supposed authority, but now liencei'orlii know we him no more in such a puiut of light.
                            He is the everlasting Father, the prince of peace. Through the veil of the flesh, God had
                            entrance into the world, that God who was the same from the beginning : He promised to be
                            with those that love him unto the end of the world. Jesus promised to send the comforter,
                            that is, the Holy Spirit, to abide with his people forever. If this spirit of truth, which
                            works by love and purifies the heart, can govern an individual, why not the whole body?
                            Would it be an introduction to anarchy, should all the human family come under the influence
                            and government of this one spirit? And can we suppose that any external rules could be more
                            productive of order and harmony? For example, if the principle of love be sufficient to
                            regulate the conduct of one man towards his wife, why may it not influence two? and if two,
                            why not a thousand? But if the principle of love be wanting, can any external form of
                            government and discipline make him a good husband? Men have been generally fond of mending
                            what they supposed God had left imperfect, filling up and supplying what they judged
                            deficient, and making plain what divine wisdom had left in the dark. Thus have they wandered
                            from the plain, simple rule of God's word, and taken the reins of government into their own
                            hands. They have changed or amended, added or diminished, as times and circumstances made
                            necessary till at length the church has become every thing, or anything, but what it should
                            be. Should we attempt to impose any <pb n="123" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> form of government upon the
                            church, we should justly be abandoned by every child of gospel liberty. This is not left for
                            us, nor any set of men in the world to do. The author of the Scriptures has not left us to
                            supply anything either in doctrine, discipline or government. The precepts and examples of
                            Christ and his Apostles are sufficient, and left on record for this very purpose. The
                            government of the church, like the gospel itself, is exceedingly plain and simple. If we
                            advert to the New Testament, we shall plainly see what is the nature of the Christian
                            church, who are its members, the mode of constitution, its union, communion, government and
                            discipline. The nature of the Christian church. The church in Scripture is denominated the
                            kingdom of heaven, or the kingdom of God. This church is spiritual. "My kingdom is not of
                            this world." Jno. xviii., 36. "They are not of the world even as I am not of the world."
                            Jno. xvii., 16. It is invisible. The natural eye cannot see it, for "except a man be born
                            again he cannot see the kingdom of God." Jno. iii., 3. Therefore the world knoweth us not,
                            because it knew him not." 1 Jno. iii., 1. The kingdom of God cometh not with observation;
                            neither shall they say lo here, or lo there; for behold, the kingdom of God is within you."
                            Luke xvii., 20. Hence we see the reason why Christ spoke so often to those who were without
                            this kingdom in parables ; for they being in a state of unbelief, could not understand. "To
                            you it is given to know the mystery of the kingdom of God, but to them that are without, all
                            things are done in parables; that seeing they may see and not understand." Mark iv., 11.
                            While men reject the testimony of Christ respecting plain facts which they can understand,
                            they reject himself and therefore remain in darkness, incapable of receiving divine light
                            into their souls. Thus when Christ told Nicodemus, ye must be born again, he replied with
                            astonishment, how can these things be ? Jesus answered and said unto him : ' 'Art thou a
                            master in Israel, and knoweth not these things? Verily, verily, I say unto thee, we speak
                            that we do know, and testify that we have seen and ye receive not our witness. If I have
                            told you earthly things, and ye believe not, how shall ye believe, if I tell you of heavenly
                            things?" Jno. iii. "The natural man receiveth not the things of the spirit of God, for they
                            are foolishness unto him : neither can he know them because they are spiritually discerned."
                            1 Cor. ii., 14. But he that is spiritual, judgeth [or discerneth] all things ; yet he
                            himself is judged [or discerned] of no man. Men in this state are not only incapable of
                            receiving the things of the spirit, but also incapable of receiving the spirit himself.
                            "Whom the world cannot receive, because it seeth him not, neither knoweth him; but ye know
                            him for he dwelleth with you, and shall be in you." Jno. xiv., 17. It is not surprising then
                            if Christians are unseen and unknown in the world, if they be mistaken for fools and madmen,
                            for hypocrites and enthusiasts. It cannot be otherwise, for <pb n="124" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> these
                            things are hid from the wise and prudent, and revealed unto babes. The members of the
                            church. From what has been said you will easily see who are members of this church: They are
                            believers and only believers, for no other can be a member. It is indeed freely offered to
                            all, to every creature under heaven, no person or character is excluded, who does not
                            through unbelief exclude himself. "Go ye into all the world and preach the gospel to every
                            creature." Mark xvi., 15. Since the days of John, the kingdom of heaven is preached and
                            every man [that is, every believer] presseth into it. Luke xvi., 16. But there were many who
                            could not enter in because of unbelief ; for the word preached did not profit them not being
                            mixed with faith in them that heard it. It is impossible for men to come to Christ who do
                            not believe on him; nor can they seek to enter into the kingdom, who do not believe there is
                            a kingdom. While Christ remained visible on the earth, his body was the temple of God; for
                            "In him dwelt all the fulness of the Godhead, bodily," that is corporeally. And though many
                            hailed him, "good master," yet none were considered as real members, but those who believed
                            his doctrine and felt his sacred influence in forming their hearts anew. (to be
                        continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If we follow the light of God we shall be found..." TEIform="index"/>
                            If we follow the light of God we shall be found...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">If we follow tlie light of God we shall be found in the path where that light shines where
                            peace and safety are found. Having found the true light, it is not creditable to be found
                            prospecting in by-ways of sin and selfish pleasure.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S., B. H." TEIform="persName"/>B. H. S.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Which, the real, the idealistic or materialistic?" TEIform="index"/> WHICH, the REAL, the
                            IDEALISTIC or MATERIALISTIC?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/> Hamilton DeGraw.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Depending largely upon the comparative development both intellectual and spiritual of the
                            mind that is trying to solve the problem of what is life. To the understanding of a large
                            majority of mankind, what their physical senses take cognizance of is the real, ignoring or
                            not knowing that back of all physical manifestations or materializations there is a "great
                            first cause." Omnipotent, Omnipresent, unchangeable ! While material forms are evanescent
                            and constantly breaking up, disorganizing and reorganizing, not destroyed but assuming new
                            forms, the idealistic or spiritual motive power that is making these changes in the material
                            world is unchangeable. To the architect that has evolved in his mind the form of an object
                            to be materialized in wood, stone, iron or what not, which is the real ? when perfected and
                            fully evolved in his own interior consciousness, fire and flood may destroy and pulverize
                            the outer manifestation yet the ideal remains intact, perfect in the mind's eye, ready again
                            to be brought out in tangible form. The farther removed from the inertia that characterizes
                            the lowest forms of inorganic matter the more potent and powerful they become ; so subtle
                            that they cannot be viewed with our material vision and developing a power by which grosser
                            forms of matter are moved irresistibly. The electrical forces that man has harnessed and
                            made to do him service <pb n="125" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> are the most subtle and powerful of any
                            elements that he has been able to grasp and retain. But who can say that it is the ultimate?
                            may not forces be unfolded that in point of energy and power far transcend any as yet known
                            ? Like the sunlight through a prism the red rays are the crudest and ascending to the violet
                            which is the most refined, and clairvoyant minds say they can see other colors that are too
                            refined for our material vision to view. "Beware when the great God lets loose a thinker on
                            this planet." What does he do? thinl?s. Whoever saw a thought only as it has been
                            materialized ? All the acts of men in the outward form are but materialized thought. The
                            mighty universe itself is but an evolved thought of the Infinite mind. The materialist
                            insists upon the Infinity of matter, we upon the Infinity of mind which created matter, and
                            as there cannot be two infinites, hence as a logical conclusion matter is finite, a created
                            substance evolved from mind. The world is prone to laugh at the so-called dreamers or
                            visionary minds who, living largely in the ideal are more in the future than the present.
                            But as the wheels of time roll on, these become the piactical workers, moving constantly
                            ahead, planning and making the way easier for oncoming generations. We have constantly
                            before us an indisputable array of facts proving the reality of mind and the secondary
                            position that matter the offspring of mind takes in the universe. The series of undisputed
                            victories of the mind of man over the forces of nature, in mastering the elements that have
                            long evaded his grasp and compelling them to do him service, and the field is constantly
                            widening in which to give scope to the latent but awakening powers that in time will give
                            him complete control over every thing below him is conclusive proof of the spirit's
                            supremacy. Still further proof lies in the fiict that the soul is dissatisfied with its
                            present environments and is placing its ideal always ahead of its reality, and in struggling
                            to attain to its ideal is constantly placing it still further ahead and so on in infinite
                            progression. As parallel lines never meet, so the material never reaches the spiritual but
                            is always in a position of dependence to it, moving as a secondary, subject to the primary
                            or first cause If such mighty results can be brought out of thought, that mankind are told
                            to beware when a thinker is let loose to project his thoughts upon the race, who can measure
                            the concentrated power developed when the whole race are thinkers and their united thought
                            is used for the higher culture of the world. The alacrity with which progressive movements
                            will take place cannot be comprehended at present. Awakening from the slumber of ages
                            mankind are virtually renewing their youth, casting off the swaddling clothes of spiritual
                            infancy and assuming the proper dignity of developed men and women. Does this come from
                            merely physical culture? by no means. Though it is important to have a healthy body as the
                            medium for the <pb n="126" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> Blind to act through, yet if the materialistic is the
                            real, then the ox is equal to the man. Why do we feel the necessity of having an ideal in
                            life, a something that is above the common condition of mortality? A holy of holies, a
                            shrine at which the soul can worship and do homage to its ideal ? Why do we embody this
                            ideal in many instances in human form, some soul at whose feet we feel a pleasure in sitting
                            and enjoying a holy communion away from and far above the material environments that are
                            around us, and feel in the presence of such souls that holy "peace that passeth all
                            understanding, and which the world can neither give nor take away." Why? because material
                            conditions however perfect they may be fail to satisfy the spiritual perceptions, and when
                            we see the embodiment of that ideal our souls instinctively know it, we need no herald to
                            proclaim the truth. Why? because the love awakened in the soul by the contemplation of the
                            perfect wishes to share unselfishly that which it possesses. With this view of life there is
                            awakened in the soul powers not dreamed of by the materialistic earth-bound, who like the
                            man with the mud rake was constantly looking downward, his sense attracted to that which is
                            beneath him instead of that which is above. The fact that a few controlling minds can sway
                            the mass of mankind and move them as mere automatons, subject to their mental power is one
                            more testimony given to substantiate the foregoing facts, How soon the soul when deprived of
                            the outward instinctively retires to the inner temple and draws from that hidden fountain
                            vitalizing forces that in times of material prosperity were buried beneath the engrossing
                            thoughts of worldly gain. Greater enjoyment is felt in the anticipation of some pleasure
                            than in its material actualization. The struggle to gain a compt tence in worldly things is
                            to the majority more invigorating and inspiring than its use after acquired. The former
                            acting upon the mental forces, and the latter appealing to the bodily senses. While it is
                            important for the cultivation of the intellectual and spiritual nature that outward
                            conditions should be harmoniously adjusted the power of mind over materiality lies in the
                            fact that it is able to compel many times an adjustment of outward conditions when to the
                            materialistic view it seems impossible, as the rising from a bed of sickness when a great
                            emergency demands vigorous action: the soul asserts its supremacy and compels from the body
                            the homage due from the inferior to the superior. When to the soul has been opened these
                            heavenly portals revealing to its understanding the fact that its real life is not in the
                            material but spiritual realm, possibilities of growth are opened that to the materialistic
                            mind are hid like precious treasures under large accumulations of earth. In the realm of
                            invention back of all visible signs is the realm of pure thought. Why does the inventor
                            strive and agonize and labor for what? not to build the material form but to bring out the
                            ideal, to perfect the mental conception, to evolve from chaos the idea. Then the rest is
                            comparatively <pb n="127" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> easy. Finite can never grasp the Infinite, and secondary
                            can never assume the place of the primary cause. Down in the interior ocean reigns a
                            perpetual calm, so in the inner soul, the real, the pure idealistic is never disturbed by
                            the exterior conflict that at times rages in the outer temple of life, because the nearer we
                            approach the fountain of real life the more harmonious the adjustment. To live in the world
                            of causes does not imply a neglect of the duties of life in the one of effects : for, "to be
                            faithful with the unrighteous mammon" prepares the soul to enjoy the true riches. Jesus
                            prayed that his disciples might be saved from the world, not taken out. Lifted above the
                            material where bondage to the physical senses holds the soul, into one where perfect freedom
                            is attained. When this condition becomes the conscious inheritance of life it works a
                            purifying process in all the faculties eliminating the crudities from our being that prevent
                            us from enjoying the "communion of saints," intensifying our loves and making us more like
                            the real, the ideal. Sonyea, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Evolution" TEIform="index"/> EVOLUTION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/> Martha J. Anderson.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Oh, bright and fair is this world of ours! If we dwell on the sunny side of earth We shall
                            see that the thorns are crowned with flowers, That plants through the darkness come to
                            birth. The snow-white lily, with heart of gold, Comes forth from the ooze of the shallow
                            river And speaks as its petals pure unfold Of the wondrous work of the Great LifeGiver. All
                            things struggle from low conditions, The germ of the beautiful dormant lies, Till nature
                            reaches a glad fruition, Through painful process of sacrifice. The potent rays of the sun,
                            magnetic, Work with a destined end and aim, Till the diamond gleams with a light prophetic,
                            Which shows God's laws to perfection tend. Out from chaos and revolution, Up through the
                            elemental wars, Comes life's glorious evolution, All things thrilling from sands to stars.
                            And through the throbbing pulse of nature Sentient beings a kinship feel, Union with every
                            living creature Sets on the soul of man its seal. From innermost heart of the microcosm, To
                            outermost bound of the rolling sphere, Rock, plant and insect from protoplasm Progressed,
                            through higher types appear. When we behold the divine relation Wrought through creation's
                            wondrous plan, We know that the steps of each g .'adation Are the connecting links to man.
                            Crowning glory of things terrestrial, Two-fold being of earth and skies, Spark of the
                            Infinite Soul Celestial, Heir of unfading paradise. Buried in matter for high tuition,
                            Wrought by earnest and ceaseless strife, Growing brighter through time's attrition, Reaching
                            Nirvana, the goal of life. Blest inheritance! through the portal Of earth-existence we come
                            to thee, To drink ambrosia of life immortal In blissful realms of eternity. Mount Lebanon,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Labor-saving proposition..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Labor-saving proposition...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Labor-saving proposition."Well, I shall forgive you this time, Johnny,; and it's
                                    very pretty of you to write a letter to say you're sorry." "Yes, ma; don't tear it
                                    up, please." "Why, Johnny?" "Because it will do for next time."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian nation" TEIform="index"/>Christian Nation.</bibl></cit></p><pb n="128" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith dual" TEIform="index"/> FAITH DUAL.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/> Alonzo G. Hollister.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "Faith is a gift of God," and "without faith it is impossible to please Gol." "True faith,"
                            said Father James Whittaker, "is a saving grace. True faith is to believe a thing to be what
                            it really is. If I believe a thing to be what it is not, I am deeeived." "Faith cometh by
                            hearing, and hearing by the word of God," spoken'by his messengers. The first and greatest
                            visible messenger of the Divine Spirit, said "No man can come to the Father but by me."
                            Again, "No man can come to me except the Father who ,hath sent me, draw him." It is written
                            in the Prophets, "And they shall all be taught of God. Every man therefore, that hath heard
                            and learned of the Father, cometh unto me. He that is of God, heareth God's words." As "no
                            man knoweth the things of a man save the spirit of a man which is in him, so the things of
                            God knoweth no man, but the Spirit of God." Faith then, is primarily a gift of the Spirit of
                            God, enlightening the conscience, ministered by his angels or messengers. "For he shall send
                            his angels with the great sound of a trumpet, to gather his elect." And secondly, a trust or
                            confidence in the visible messengers or bearers of light, whose works must be in and of the
                            light and their fruits must correspond, else they are proved to be false teachers"thieves
                            and robbers," who steal the sacred fire and light of "heaven to give life to an image of the
                            Beast" in fallen human nature. These two degrees correspond to the first and second
                            commandments of the Law, viz. "Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, with all
                            thy soul and with all thy mind." And "Thou shalt love thy neighbor as thyself; which is like
                            unto the first." "On these two," said Jesus, "hang all the Law and the Prophets ; and there
                            is none other greater than these." Therefore, upon the reception of these two phases or
                            degrees of faith and obedience to it, depends the soul's new birth, and all subsequent
                            growth and progress in the new and eternal creation of God. True faith then, is predicated
                            upon a revelation of thre Spirit of God (or Christ) in the conscience, and an order of
                            Teachers standing in the light? of that revelation, and hence includes a trust or confidence
                            in the teachers or messengers of light. For without a teacher there can be no disciples and
                            no school; and the pupil must confide in his teacher, else how can he be taught ? (No soul
                            has a knowledge of the way of abiding happiness naturally in them, nor can any acquire it
                            without assistance, except the head of a dispensation.) Therefore Jesus says "wThosoever
                            receiveth a little child in my name, receiveth me, and whosoever receiveth me, receiveth Him
                            that sent me." He that receiveth the kingdom of heaven as a little child, can receive it of
                            a child, if such be the duly accredited teacher; of which fruits must be the test. What if
                            the teacher ignorantly or wilfully mingles false doctrine with the true, as in the case of
                            those duly <pb n="129" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> appointed, who have fallen like stars, from heaven to
                            earth? Jesus says, "If any man will do his will, he shall know of the doctrine, whether it
                            be of God, or whether I speak of myself." Why and how? Because the internal and external
                            witness will agree, and experience will confirm their testimony. He that doeth not God's
                            will, i. e. disregards the inward monitor, his internal ear is closed by that spirit which
                            "is not of God" (not by constraint, as of some superior power, but because he chooses it,)
                            and therefore he "heareth not God's words," and of course in that state, cannot know God,
                            imagine as he may. Again, "The pure in heart shall see God." Not personally, for "no man can
                            see God' and live;" (a carnal life.) But by an interior view and knowledge of the character
                            of God, (which is God's likeness in the mind,) he will be able to "discern between him that
                            serveth God and him that serveth Him not;" also to discriminate between the true and false
                            in doctrine, and the real and specious in practice. Because he loves to obey the
                            commandments of God, which bring death to the carnal will, and destruction to that nature
                            which separates man from his fellows. Such as "keep the commandments of God and have the
                            testimony of Jesus Christ," united and traveling together in the Order of the kingdom of
                            heaven (now revealed among men,) constitute the visible sanctuary and church of Christ in
                            this dispensation. These have no need of human learning and research, nor for the wisdom of
                            this world, (which "is foolishness with God,") to give them knowledge of the way of
                            salvationfor the indwelling "spirit of Truth" speaks and works through them ; and is their
                            life, which they feel as a substance, daily increasing in their souls. As this is the
                            beginning of that kingdom to be "set up by the God of heaven," which the Spirit declared by
                            the prophet should "never have an end nor be given to another people;" therefore though
                            individuals may err and fall from this holy Order, the Order will remain intact; and there
                            will always be enough of that faithful number united, to fulfill the prophecy; vindicate
                            present and past revelations of the Divine Spirit"convince the world of sin committed ; of
                            righteousness attainable ; and of judgment to be executed," and advance the kingdom of the
                            God of heaven to its final completion. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lydia Dole, Beloved Sister:--Your letter of the 17th inst..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Lydia Dole, Beloved Sister:--Your letter of the 17th inst...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Enfield, January 1892 " TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H., Jan. 1892.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Lydia Dole, Beloved Sister : Your letter of the 17th inst. was duly received. To be so
                            kindly remembered is very comforting. I thank you for the fruits of your pen and the love of
                            your soul; and as is your prayer for the blessing and prosperity of Enfield, so is my
                            interest in Sonyea and prayers for continued blessing. Nay, kind Sister, I had not heard of
                            the demise of my well-remembered and long-loved brother Emmory. In early manhood he sought
                            righteousness and honored Zion. Many long years and through many scenes of trial and
                            heaviness of heart he toiled for her interest and the salvation of <pb n="130" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/>
                            his own soul. I can but weep as I write, in memory of his brave and noble struggles to
                            preserve the honor of the gospel, protect the church of his adoption and maintain the divine
                            Order revealed to his understanding. The measure of his days was full and his life, as I
                            trust, was rounded out with a reward that gave him a satisfactory triumph. My heart blesses
                            him. In the course of nature I must soon follow him. I am but about three months his junior
                            in age, he being born July 1807, and I the October following. It is a great satisfaction,
                            that as people age, grow in years, mentally their faculties are preserved, in their
                            spiritual interests they do not wane, and in dropping the mortal it be in honor. When my
                            usefulness is no more here, then I pray that I may be gathered to my fathers and my mothers,
                            and in no sense or degree would I be left to dishonor my profession or the Christian name.
                            It seems Sonyea has had her afflictions from La Grippe, the mortal foe to human weal. We too
                            have been visited and suffered from his heavy hand. None, however, are or have been
                            dangerously ill. You kindly invite me to visit Sonyea I thank you, assuring you it would
                            give me great pleasure. Three times it has been my privilege to share your kind hospitality
                            and enjoy the soul ministrations of your people. This is to me valuable, a favor granted
                            only to a very few of our people. As much as it would please me again to be with you it is
                            not likely such a privilege will ever be mine. In this life I may never see you again and
                            personally enjoy communion or interchange of thought, unless you come to New Hampshire which
                            I really wish you would. This wrould give you rest, thus lengthening your days and giving to
                            Sonyea the blessing of your more extended usefulness. Our winter has been remarkably mild ;
                            but few cold days and very little snow. Sleighing only for a few days. Our love for
                            Groveland is not abated. It grows with our years. Please accept it and extend to all our
                            dear friends. Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/> Abraham Perkins.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Something new" TEIform="index"/> SOMETHING NEW.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, Jessie" TEIform="persName"/> Jessie Evans.</byline><p TEIform="p"> A desire for something new seems to possess the minds of all classes in this day of unrest
                            and dissatisfaction, an undefined longing for something from a new source, an outline of
                            character of a new design and pattern. The old course of dishonesty and deceit, entailing
                            misery, has been pursued by millions to its hollow, bitter end. Even those conscientiously
                            seeking a better or religious life, have become so embarrassed by forms and creeds1,
                            teaching implicit trust in Jesus, who died on Calvary, that the exhortation to "work out our
                            own salvation," has been lost sight of by the masses, while the soul cry still goes out,
                            "Where shall we find, the new and lasting good?" "Not here," cries Wealth, "shrouds have no
                            pockets ; I am simply a condition of Time." "Not here," answers Fame, "what's in a name?"
                            "Not here!" is the response from the votaries of Pleasure, "all is old, old and
                            dissatisfactory." <pb n="131" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> Thus have we the past experiences of time,
                            strength, health, wealth, pleasure, all, spent "chasing a shadow." Still we urge, Where may
                            we look for the "Something New?" Listen !"Behold, I make all things new." "New things do I
                            declare; I will bring the blind by a way that they knew not." "I will make crooked paths
                            straight." The Savior of men alone answers our question satisfactorily. What can be newer
                            than a life "hid with Christ in God?" Things of earth "perish with their using;" and its
                            pleasures and fruits are but the joys of a moment. With our dual existence, the something
                            new must embrace both Time and Eternity to be perfect in its attraction. Our Elder Brother
                            presented a beautiful picture when he said, as in Luke, xx :They that are accounted worthy
                            to obtain that world and the resurrection from the dead * * are equal unto the angels in
                            heaven and are the children of God, being the children of the resurrection. Equal unto the
                            angels! Is this an old story? The testimony of the Christ opened the way for a separation
                            from the oldness of sin and self, which had been lived previous to his advent and the
                            prospect of new conditions and new rewards was held before "Whosoever will." The laws which
                            governed the old life referred to, have been so thoroughly impressed upon the characters of
                            the past generations, that these have become a second nature, until now, one writer
                            declares, taht "Doing nothing is doing ill;" as yet we are so wedded to old ideas and the
                            soulless worship of tradition. From these phases of oldness, we yearn for something new. A
                            change from old to new necessitates a change of law, and we must consult the new conditions.
                            Will not the following quotations be embodied in the "New Covenant" promised:"Unless a man
                            forsake all that he hath, yea and his own life also, he eannot be my disciple." "Thou shalt
                            love the Lord thy God with all thy might, mind and strength, and thy neighbor as thyself."
                            "Not every one that saith unto me, Lord, Lord, shall enter into the Kingdom of Heaven, bat
                            he that doeth the will of my Father which is in Heaven." The Apostle James wrote of the
                            tongue "which no man can tame." In the new order of Christian discipline, the same tongue
                            that could not be. governed under the old law, is heard proclaiming the word of God, to the
                            entire exclusion of less worthy themes. It is thus within our power to become new beings,
                            equal to the angels of God. Dear young Christian workers, will we not have the "Something
                            new?" It is within our reach and attainment. Will we not enter a new field of labor which
                            will afford soul happiness, through Time and Eternity? It is before us. There are prayers to
                            be offered for the needy, words of encouragement to the halting, principles of deep and
                            lasting truth to be upheld in daily association. No phase of selfishness can retard the
                            upward progress of the genuine Christian worker. The burning coal from the altar of eternal!
                            truth, leads to a full and honest confession of all sin, which so lights the pathway of the
                            sincere-hearted, that he is made able thereby to discern between the ' 'precious and the
                            vile," between him that feareth God and him that feareth Him not, and will render him a
                            swift witness against all who work iniquity in this new order of discipleship. Who will
                            enter at this strait gate? The reward is a "hundred-fold" of blessing and the chastening of
                            persecution in this life and in the world to come life everlasting. Who will enter? The
                            reward will be "Something new." Let us strive for its possession. East Canterbury, N. H.</p><pb n="132" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> THE MANIFESTO. 1S93. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious views of
                            the Okdek and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All communications should be
                            addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. .75 .40 One copy per year,
                            postage paid, " " six months, " " Send for sample copy, free. Entered at the Post Office at
                            East Canterbury, N. H., as second-class matter.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial.</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Moving on seems to be the watchword of the day..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Moving on seems to be the watchword of the day...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Moving on seems to be the watchword of the day, and those who fail to comply with this
                                inexorable law of God toward man must inevitably be left in the rear, or be lost sight
                                of entirely. From the earliest history of man may be traced the footprints of a
                                progressive march, and whether in civilization, in morality or in the higher gifts of
                                spirituality ; the race as a whole has moved onward to a better state. In some instances
                                a phenomenal advance has obtained in a nation, while morality and even spirituality have
                                blessed the mind of man to a remarkable degree. Should these fail at any time to
                                maintain their places, there is great danger of a retrograde movement and a consequent
                                loss of position. Moving on, however, has nothing to do with the common construction
                                that is placed on the term. The advance movement may be made very slowly or it may be at
                                a rapid pace. It may even be in a circuitous form which at times may give the impression
                                of falling back or even standing still, and yet, on the whole the march is onward and
                                upward. When we read of the changeableness of man, and of the tortuous path in which he
                                has walked, even from his first introduction into that beautiful garden of Eden, we
                                claim that it is a living miracle to find a class of men and women, in these last days,
                                who will sacrifice their own comfort and work early and late to ameliorate the
                                conditions of those in poverty or in sickness, as thousands are doing at the present
                                time, and then beyond this are those who have separated themselves from the customs and
                                practices of the world, agreeably to the teachings of the Christ, and are working for
                                the peace and prosperity of each other as children of one Heavenly Father and Mother. It
                                may be no special credit to us who have accepted the cross of Christ and have determined
                                in our own minds to crucify the world with all its affections and lusts, and to pray
                                with Jesus, "Thy kingdom come, <pb n="133" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> Thy will be done in earth as in
                                heaven." If the light of a better life has found entrance into the soul; it is the gift
                                of God and he will in proper time demand his own with usury. Jesus in his evangel of
                                peace is accepted as the inspired medium of God and he said he came not to do his own
                                will, but the will of God who sent him. This should represent our mission, as it did
                                that of Jesus% As servants of God, his word should become our law. With this as our
                                guide we cannot stand still nor become lukewarm in the cause of practical righteousness.
                                Through the force of our common language we illustrate the life of the Christian as a
                                soldier of the cross, as one contending with a powerful enemy whom we wish to conquer,
                                and then destroy. Paul in his ecstacy thought of the great care that was exercised by
                                those who went upon the battle-field. They were so careful in the preparation, that he
                                would have the Christians equally as particular while contending for their spiritual
                                interests. "Put on the whole armor of God," said he. Allow no part to be defective. If
                                they had been so careful in preparing to fight against their earthly enemies, they
                                should be no less careful in preparing to fight against those of a spiritual order. Have
                                with you, said he, a breast-plate of righteousness, a girdle of truth, a shield of
                                faith, a helmet of salvation and by all means, a sword of the spirit. Your feet should
                                walk in the gospel of peace, and as you go, pray, and as you work, pray, believing that
                                the victory will be obtained. *</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inquiry. no. 4" TEIform="index"/> INQUIRY. No. 4.</head><p TEIform="p"> What is the difierence between the Unitarians and the Shakers ? The same may be said in
                            reference to this question as was said concerning the Quakers, (See No 3. in Apr. 1892,)
                            with these exceptions; the doctrine of non-resistance and the Trintarian mystery. The
                            Unitarians, like their evangelical brethren, teach their disciples to fight, and during a
                            war, to kill both their friends and enemies, although in violation of the sixth commandment,
                            and even pray to their war God to give them victory over brethren belonging to their own
                            church.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scripture text" TEIform="index"/> SCRIPTURE TEXT.</head><p TEIform="p"> Explain John, iii., 13. "No man hath ascended up to heaven but he that came down from
                            heaven, even the Son of man which is in heaven." And reconcile it with 2 Kings, ii., 11. '
                            'And it came to pass as they still went on and talked, that behold, there appeared a chariot
                            of fire and horses of fire and parted them asunder and Elijah went up by a whirlwind into
                            heaven." Jesus in his earlier remarks had said, "If any one be not born from above he cannot
                            see the Kingdom of God." God was to be his Father, and <pb n="134" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> God's Kingdom
                            his home. Jesus was anxious to have his disciples understand about the coming of this
                            Kingdom, and to bear in mind that it was to be above the earth, where they could, in safety,
                            lay up their treasures. Mis prayer was that God's will might be done on earth as in Heaven.
                            Some entertained the erroneous idea that this heaven was above the earth in the firmament in
                            which the sun, moon and stars are placed. They had reached that degree in speculative
                            theology that they had located their personal God and his heavenly Kingdom in the fixed
                            stars, while others were quite positive that it must be in the sun. Jesus would disabuse
                            their minds of this false notion, and remarked that no man hath ascended up to any such
                            heaven. Many had supposed that Enoch was carried bodily, up from the earth, and became an
                            inhabitant of that heavenly sphere. "For God took him," and that Elijah went up into the
                            same heaven, in a whirlwind. But neither Enoch nor Elijah had occasion for any such special
                            demonstration. To walk with God, is to walk in the light and in the truth. It is the
                            spiritual relation which Jesus taught should exist between himself and his disciples. It was
                            the heavenly relation which he said would not come by observation, but that it was already
                            in the hearts of his people. Heaven is happiness, a state of atone-ment with God, and no
                            whirlwind nor chariot of fire can ever transport the soul to this blissful abode. The
                            calling of Elijah and Elisha rendered them highly susceptible to spiritual influences and
                            the chariot and horses of fire, and the falling of the mantle wTere from the illumination of
                            the mind of the seer, rather than real. The mantle that fell upon Elisha was the baptism
                            into a deeper prophetic work upon which he undoubtedly entered with renewed zeal after the
                            death of his teacher. The laws of God in the government of the affairs of this world, are
                            still remaining, no doubt, "very good" as they were in the beginning. At that time it was
                            declared of the mortality of man,"Dust thou art and unto dust thou shalt return." That a
                            deviation has been made in one or two instances as manifestations of wonder for man, is
                            quite questionable. The words of the preacher convey a very correct idea of this subject.
                            "Then shall the dust return to the earth as it was : and the spirit shall return unto God
                            who gave it."</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memory of our sister Sarah A. Weatherford" TEIform="index"/> In Memory of our Sister
                            SARAH A. WEATHERFORD.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Settles, Mary C." TEIform="persName"/> Mary C. Settles.</byline><p TEIform="p"> When Death comes to those who are far advanced in years, and have "borne the burden and heat
                            of the day," we feel it is a blessed release for their weary feet, and although we may be
                            crossed to part with our aged ones, yet it is what we may expect;but when Azriel, claims for
                            his own, the one in the prime of life, and with ruthless hands, bears her away, from our
                            midst, we are constrained to weep and mourn that one so useful should be taken from us, one
                            with whom our youthful days were spent. Joy and sorrow alike shared with each other, and how
                            swiftly time has borne us on through varied scenes of toil and care. <pb n="135" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/>
                            Dear Sister we would not call thee ack for we know thy pure spirit now rejoices with those
                            who have preceded thee to the Summer Land but we shall hope to meet again, and be parted no
                            more. May we who remain, [join "So live, that when thy summons comes to The innumerable
                            caravan that moves [take To that mysterious realm, where each shall His chamber in the
                            silent hails of death, Thou go not like the quarry slave at night, Scourged to his dungeon,
                            but sustained and soothed By an unfaltering trust, approach thy grave Like one who wraps the
                            drapery of his couch About him, and lies down to pleasant dreams." Pleasant Hill, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eads, Harvey L." TEIform="index"/> IN MEMORIAM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/> Oliver C. Hampton.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Elder Harvey L. Eabs died on the 13th. of Feb. at 6 o'clock a. m. of la grippe, being 84
                            years 10 months and five days of age. About six weeks ago he was attacked with the grip and
                            gradually grew weaker till he calmly and painlessly passed away on the morning of the 13th.
                            Elder Harvey Lauderdale Eads was born near South Union on the 28th. of April, A. D., 1807.
                            He has' always lived among the Believers called Shakers. Quite early in life he wTas called
                            to share in the heavy burdens and responsibilities of the Church at South Union, standing as
                            associate minister with Elder Benjamin S. Young, one of the three original missionaries from
                            the eastern Church to the western country in 1805, and who located finally and permanently
                            at South Union, Logan county, Ky. Our dear Elder was called to this position with Elder
                            Benjamin when about 20 years of age. From that period to within 3 or 4 years of his decease
                            he continued almost uninterruptedly to occupy some important lot of care in the Church.
                            About the year 1844 he was removed to the Church at Union Village in Warren county and State
                            of Ohio. There for 19 years he faithfully filled the office of Leading Elder, mostly in the
                            novitiate or gathering order. Perhaps no western man has ever occupied that weighty and
                            important position with the same amount of success and general acceptation as our well
                            beloved Elder Harvey. At Union Village he waa universally loved, esteemed and highly
                            appreciated for his versatility of talents and his many social and Christian qualities of
                            character. He was an enthusiastic Shaker, always ready to defend the faith and doctrine of
                            our system as a true incontrovertible Pentecostal church modeled after the pattern of that
                            which was based upon the Evangel of Jesus, eighteen hundred years ago. About the year 1862
                            he was once more called to the ministerial offie at his ancient home at South Union, Ky.,
                            and left for that Society in July of 1862. This office he continued to fill with scrupulous
                            integrity until the infirmities of old age unfitted him f#r its arduous duties. Though by no
                            means a classical scholar, linguist or titled professor, yet his reading and research were
                            so extensive and in so many divers directions that he was held in high esteem among literary
                            magnates far and near and enjoyed the confidence and friendship of many of this class during
                            all of his latter daysHe was charitable and forgiving almost to a fault, and so confiding,
                            forbearing and long-suffering that his life was often embittered by the mean and perfidious,
                            whom he persisted in thinking as good and noble as himself. Elder Harvey in his old age
                            wrote a book entitled "Shaker Theology," which is creditable to his genius and true to his
                            principles, and is one of the missionary publications of our Society, several hundred copies
                            of which book have already been sent out. The four cardinal points of our religious
                            faith,celibacy, community of goods, confession of all known sin, non-resistancewere most
                            conscientiously and practically adhered to by our beloved Elder through all the joy and
                            sorrow, prosperity and adversity of his long and useful life. He was always instant in
                            season or out of season in the benevolent work of gathering souls into the Church and
                            offering <pb n="136" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> them the bread of life. He was truly one who "cast his bread
                            upon the waters that it might be found after many days." Indeed we are comforted in the
                            assurance that if there ever was a man to whom the words of the rapt seer of old will justly
                            apply it is our good Elder Harvey: "The wise shall shine as the brightness of the firmament
                            and they that turn many to righteousness as the stars forever and ever." Union Village,
                            Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/> NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/> Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Average of Weather at Mount Lebanon. April. Thermometer. Bain. Snow. 1891. 28.7!? 2.%in.
                                23 in. 1892. 43.9 .%in. 1. in. C. R. "Fokkn'oon and afternoon and night. Forenoon And
                                afternoon and night. Forenoon and what! The empty song repeats itself. No more? Yea,
                                that is life. Make this forenoon sublime, This afternoon a psalm, this night a prayer,
                                And Time is conquered and thy crown is won." And such is life. When we say "Life is what
                                we make it," we means not the singular editorial we but it is strictly plural.
                                Especially is this true in Community, where our close relation makes of each member, a
                                responsible factor for the good of the whole. Each one is different originally, yet this
                                very difference, when under the strict discipline of self-denial, makes life a grand
                                harmony. Such are our possibilities, and this ideal should be our aim. In this we find
                                no monotony, for life is one grand aspiration for the greatest of all conquests, the
                                ruling of the spirit. With this object in view it matters not whether sunshine or storm
                                is our portion. The storm gives us fortitude, and in the clear sunshine, we can enjoy
                                the fruits of our toil. We have no need to say "Spring has come," for it comes every
                                year. By the "Home Notes" we see that our experiences are identical. A late spring in
                                one locality east of the Alleghanies, is the same throughout. Yet a difference is
                                noticeable in the use people make of their advantages or disadvantages. A report of the
                                success of the different Societies, tends to stimulate the otherwise indifferent, and
                                creates a laudable emulation. In no kind of business is promptness and perseverance more
                                richly rewarded than in agriculture; and by the diligence of our toiling Elder Calvin,
                                we expect even our late spring will not deprive us of the usual ample maintenance of our
                                vegetable garden. Father Time against whom even absolute necessity cannot prevail, has
                                so enfeebled our worthy Elder Daniel Boler, that he resigns his position at the head of
                                Community. Long and bravely has he stood at the helm, and his sturdy faithfulness to his
                                trust, wins for him the epithet, "Well done, good and faithful servant." He retires to
                                the quiet of the Infirmary where we know he will receive the kindest care and attention,
                                from those who occupy in that department. Our old saw-mill erected in 1835, becoming
                                unfit for use. is now being taken down and though we delight in having the useless and
                                unsightly removed, still with the usual clinging to old landmarks, we regret to see it
                                go, since all through our early life, the opening of its door was as sure a harbinger of
                                spring as were the blue-birds and robins, and the music of its saw seemed to hasten the
                                departure of winter. We had our first thunder-storm of the season during the night of
                                May 3rd. lasting four hours, and going entirely around us, showing that we were in the
                                storm center. A. D. Center Family. May 11, 1892. Everything seems to be progressing,
                                very nicely at present, although the season is rather late. Our potatoes are all planted
                                and the Brethren are preparing the ground for corn. We have a small <pb n="137" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> portion of the garden sown to early vegetables. We expect to cut a meal of asparagus
                                tomorrow. The trees are not leaved out as yet although a few cherry trees have begun to
                                blossom. The summer term of school has opened with manifest interest on the part of the
                                pupils. Last Sabbath we were notified of the resignation of our good Father, Elder
                                Daniel Boler from his position as first Minister. Elder Joseph succeeds him and also
                                retains his own position. May he always have the good-will and assistance of the
                                Brethren and Sisters in his numerous burdens is the sincere prayer of the writer. North
                                K'ainily. May, 1892. We had a very dry April, and it was thought we should have a very
                                early spring: but it has proved a very late one. Peas sown three weeks ago are just
                                above ground. Our gardens are not yet all planted. Farm work is a little ahead of usual.
                                Sisters have had the houses about all turned inside out, and put back again, according
                                to gospel order just as far as we could attain to it. We realize that the gospel is not
                                as yet manifest in its perfection. We are longing and working for a renewed baptism of
                                gospel life, fire and light. Habits and customs we have been in for many years become
                                almost second nature, and often without thinking we assert that they are all right; and
                                anything coming against them is apt to be taken for error and fought against with a
                                great deal of zeal. This I think is especially true in the realm of thought. It needs a
                                good deal of divine wisdom to discern the truth, and more simplicity to acknowledge it
                                when it is presented. Nothing but a genuine love for the truth will enable any one to
                                accept and obey it. Who can possibly have this love, but those whose lives are made
                                straight by being squared in accordance with the Golden Rule. In kindest love, D. O.
                                South. ITamily. May, 1892. Dear Editoe;We feel it a duty as well as a privilege to
                                occasionally drop you a few lines. The beautiful month of May that we always hail with
                                joy is ushered in, and the aspect of the universe round about us, prompts us to come
                                forth to action, and enjoy a newness of life. The earthly elements are doing their duty
                                so beautifully, that we feel to cheer, comfort and bless the true and faithful. We
                                endeavor to do right continually regardless of the deceitful works of the enemy. We have
                                been busy lately, filling orders for Boston people who know the comfort found in the
                                Shaker Chairs. They were first manufactured by the Shakers and are the same in all parts
                                of our country. Necessity demands chairs for comfort, for the poor body, and the
                                testimony of the gospel for the poor sonl, as long as the earth is peopled with
                                civilized men and women who want righteousness to rule the gospel must be preached. Of
                                late I have looked through three new books and each one alluded to the Shakers, they are
                                never forgotten. They were good books. Our worthy friend O. W. Holmes wrote one "Over
                                the Teacups." The others were "There is no Death," and "flow she became a Spiritualist."
                                I found a great deal of useful information in the last book one side of the spiritual
                                part. House-cleaning is being done. By keeping cleanly the year round, we find much
                                lighter work in the spring but must then make a general move. Our Dear Eldress Ann
                                called at our home lately and we were all pleased to have her tarry over night with us.
                                Hope she will come again. More blessed is her life than that of the Empress Eugenie and
                                more glorious her reward. None of us on the sick list just now. S. A. C.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canaan, New York" TEIform="index"/> Canaan, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Apr. 1892. Beloved Elder Henry;It gives us great pleasure to read the "Home Notes" <pb n="138" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> ia the Manifesto and so we thought we would add our mite also. A
                                little practical common sense is much more interacting and instructive than dry
                                theology. The former contains the essence of true religion and whenever brought into
                                activity, has always benefited humanity; while the latter has caused bitter strife and
                                angry contests and consequently great suffering. / We are a little band few in number
                                and young in years, enjoying a beautiful home In the lovely land of Canaan. We think and
                                study, and are trying to learn and comprehend truth in its simplicity and reduce it to
                                practice. We are trying to solve the problem of getting a living minus hirelings, as the
                                hired element is antagonistic to pure Christianity. It savors too much of the master and
                                slave principle to be tolerated by a religious Community, and we hope that in the march
                                of progress mechanics will be developed and educated in our institution that we may be
                                entirely relieved of this great evil, which like a canker worm is sapping the life out
                                of the best fruit of our Order. Our three good Brethren and six boys have labored
                                indefatigably the past winter. They have procured a good supply of ice, chopped down
                                trees, hauled the logs home, sawed, split and piled wrood for home consumption, and made
                                brooms, besides attending to all other duties peculiar to farming without any hired
                                help. The Sisters also heartily co-operate, all are determined to maintain the
                                principle, though it cramps our acquisitiveness and even deprives us of some of this
                                world's goods which we now deem indispensable; the oss of which however might redound to
                                our advantage in the ultimate. The sacrifice would seem trifling when compared with the
                                great spiritual benefits consequently derived, resulting from a lively growth and
                                development of a Community reared on the divine base of justice mercy and love. Forming
                                a paradise, a home whose attractions would be so strong, whose internal influence so
                                potent, as to be clearly seen and felt by truth- loving souls. School for both boys and
                                girls has been ably taught by one of our Sisters the proof of which is seen in the
                                improvement of the pupils. E. O.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/> Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> t Soiitli Family. May, 1892. Apkil has been a cold, dry, windy month. Oats all sown,
                                potatoes nearly all planted. Grass and winter grain, backward; we may say vegetation has
                                been at a stand-still. We had a severe frost on the 24th. It is too early yet to say
                                what the prospect for fruit will be. Elder Calvin Reed of Mount Lebanon, made us a
                                flying visit. Our beloved Ministry returned to the Mount the 4th. inst. Spring thus far
                                is backward, still we have enough to do at present to obey the counsel of Mother Ann, to
                                repair our fences, plant and sow, that we may reap a harvest to sustain the natural
                                body. This is "hands to work," but her counsel did not stop here, for she added, "Hearts
                                to God." How about the spiritual fences? Are they kept in repair, by obeying the orders
                                of God, which are a wall of protection to all who keep them? Is the spiritual soil
                                prepared by an honest confession and true repentance, to receive and grow the seeds of
                                love and good-will, combined with all the Christian graces, that help to make us what
                                our profession calls for, true followers of Christ and Mother? Let us not lose heart and
                                courage to perform our part, nor let selfishness, personal ease or lukewarmne ss be our
                                sin. Let us begin anew, and bring forth the spiritual plow, and if need be, follow with
                                the sub-soil plow, till we mellow up the cold, selfish indifference, underlying the
                                surface, so that God's light and sunshine can penetrate and warm this dormant soil, and
                                cause the good seeds, not tares to grow in our hearts. Having prepared the spiritual
                                ground, will not a continual cultivation bring about that much-needed condition,a
                                revival such as the Apostles experienced at the day of pentecost. We cannot expect an
                                increase of numbers until this condition <pb n="139" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> is obtained. Let us work
                                and pray in fait!i, trusting in Him, who has never yet forsaken those who sincerely
                                trusted Him in the past, neither will He in the present. Let us not be foolish virgins,
                                expecting God to come to us in our selfish, worldly ideas and ways. We must go to Him in
                                childlike simplicity and obedience.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p"> May, 1892. A feeling of thankfulness pervades the Society that Elder George has regained
                                a measure of health. To be deprived of his visible presence would "leave an aching
                                void." We kindly thank him for getting better. It is said that "trifles make up the sum
                                of earthly things," and this is true. The day is made up of small things, all linked
                                together. Let us think of that. The little things of every-day life have a bearing on
                                the endless life beyond. So it is clear that they are worth thinking of and looking
                                after, to see if they are good or evil. They must be one or the other, for nothing that
                                forms part of our lives is or can be neutral. Let us look well to the little things.
                                "Little leaks make great losses, little savings make great gains." Good judgment and the
                                capacity for taking pains in little things fits one for success in poultry growing. What
                                an infinitude of details there are! And how much depends on these little things. In
                                providing succulent vegetable food for hens, cabbage is the best. A winter's supply is
                                essential to their health. "Bowker's Animal Meal" for hens is the most economical of all
                                the meat preparations. Dried sweet corn is the best food for sitting hens, also give
                                them a good s*upply of milk. 3530 spaces of cream were sold in April. D. Okcutt. May,
                                1892. The beauties of the May month are once more realized. They are most charming to
                                behold and inspiring in their effects. We may have our chosen themes of meditation, and
                                every possible advantage for the constant acquisition of valuable information, but never
                                reach the highest ideal of fruition, and aspiration, until every desire conforms to the
                                standard of true Gospel liberty and charity. Everything at the present time bears the
                                impress of Divine beauty, and is radiant with loveliness, which causes ambition to take
                                the place of depression, joy lights the countenance, and hope is kindled in the eye, in
                                the blissful prospect be.'ore us. And has not God been pleased to institute the finer
                                senses as the medium through which the spirit communicates with the external wTorld
                                during seasons o: discipline and development. We are hard at work tilling the soil. Ten
                                acres of potatoes planted with the Aspinwall planter a good thing; four acres per day
                                can be planted with it. We are preparing for sowing sugar beets, and hope to plant nine
                                acres of corn this week. Our crops this year will be thirty acres of rye, thirty acres
                                of corn and fodder corn, fifteen acres of oats ten acres of potatoes, two and one half
                                acres of sugar beets, besides the mowing. All this having to be done with Breed's
                                weeder. Shortness of water is experienced owing to the long drouth, we had but one good
                                rain in about two months. Cherry and pear trees are in full bloom, we hope the cold
                                winds may not injure them. M. W.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ayer, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/> Ayer Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> May, 1892. There is nothing in which mankind make so many mistakes as in estimating the
                                happiness of others. We often envy those who are objects of pity, and waste our
                                commiseration on those who are in reality worthy to be envied. The hovel is not
                                necessarily the abode of misery, nor the palace of pleasure. The beggar may be happier
                                than the king and the slave than his master. He who is at the top of the ladder is in
                                perpetual fear of falling, while if at the foot he only thinks of rising. These are some
                                of my musings, while holding sweet <pb n="140" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> converse with the immortals;
                                and while in prayer for more strength, physically, as well as spiritually, to give for
                                the upbuilding of my beautiful Zion home, and echo says, beautiful Zion home! How has it
                                been made beautiful except by the consecrated labor of willing hands and hearts? And
                                still there are those who are faithfully working in the same cause. We are an active
                                people and the love of action sometimes diverts the mind from the true love of home
                                life, but the effort to make home pleasant is a common duty, that rests upon every
                                member of the family. The pleasure, the friends, the interest of one should receive the
                                polite attention of all. To treat the subject or employment that interests another
                                member of the family as if it was not worth the consideration of intelligent people is
                                to say the least, not very polite. The outside of the house is not always the true Index
                                of the comfort that is within, nor can all the gifts of fortune atone for what nature
                                has denied. The sweetness of good manners has its source too deep to be learned by
                                practice, or rote. It must be innate for it is the visible sign of an inward, spiritual
                                grace. A cheerful and contented mind is the best gift which Providence can bestow upon
                                man. If we have a pleasant home we must make the sacrifices that are necessary to make,
                                the pleasant home. First the unruly tongue must have a bridle that will keep it from
                                uttering slanderous remarks. We must put forth the helping hand to those who are too
                                weak to bear the burdens of life, and so cast the sunshine of blessing upon every one
                                whereever we go. The first of May finds us with the work for spring almost finished. The
                                pleasant weather has hastened the work along so that we are in advance of last season.
                                A. D. B.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/> East Canterbury, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p"> May, 1892. "The beautiful month of May, when the fields and forests smile with gladness
                                all clad in new robes of beauty." So says the anthem that was made and sung some forty
                                years anterior to the present date. Central Xew Hampshire now enjoys all the beauty and
                                loveliness of the above song. The fields especially are clad in new robes that are
                                beautifully green and the farmers eyes must sparkle at the thought of well filled barns
                                in the anticipated midsummer harvest. The many varieties of trees are pleasantly
                                awakening from their protracted slumbers and making glad the hearts of old and young.
                                Health follows in the beauty of all this new life, as with a whole soul we remember the
                                great goodness of our Heavenly Father. The Willows whose home is on the shore of the
                                pond or by the side of the stream, were the first to awaken and welcome the return of
                                spring. On the development of their pretty yellow catkins, tens of thousands of little,
                                honey-gatherers are in the air to harvest the treasures of pollen. The red maples
                                decorated in beautiful, scarlet plumes are among the ornamental flowering trees of our
                                northern climate. The white birches are now sending forth their new formed leaves, and
                                the clusters of trees in the distance look like a light green band suspended in the air.
                                The leaves on the maple trees are just beginning to expand, while the apples, pears, and
                                cherries are still closely hid away in their buds. In a very few days and before these
                                lines will reach the reader, a wonderful change will have taken place. With this new
                                development of life from God, we share in the universal good that comes to all mankind,
                                and may also rejoice in that marvelous promise which was given to our fathers, many
                                thousands of years in the past. "While the earth remaineth, seed-time and harvest, and
                                cold and heat, and summer and winter, and day and night shall not cease." With this
                                precious promise the farmers and gardeners may make all due preparations for ploughing
                                and planting. <pb n="141" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> Our family of feathered songsters have slightly
                                increased and now include the robins, bluebirds, sparrows and martins. We shall
                                anticipate a visit from a few more families before the month closes. The crows,
                                blue-jays, chickadees and English sparrows have been with us all winter. June is said to
                                be the most beautiful month of the year in New Hampshire. It is full of nature's
                                northern beauty and cannot otherwise than make the heart to rejoice. * Weather Record,
                                for April 1892. Highest Temp, during the mo. 65. Lowest " " " " 20. Mean " " " " 43.1
                                Total rainfall " " " .82 in. Number of days rain " " :3 N. A. Biuggs.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/> Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p"> May, 1892. As I take my pen for writing I ask myself the question. What shall I
                                write'for the beautiful month of June? At this date the wind is blowing and the weather
                                is cold for the time of year. By the sound of old JEolus one would think we were about
                                to have a January snow-storm. Sr. E. B. says, that Mascoma Lake loosened its icy fetters
                                April 11th. Sabbathday Lake was a few days later. April 16tli showed its rippling,
                                sparkling waters to full advantage. Arbor day was observed by the school in this place,
                                not in setting out many trees but in trimming and taking care of those already started
                                and by the gathering of many bunches of beautiful May-flowers which are now adorning
                                tables and mantles, filling the rooms with their lovely fragrance. The ground is ready
                                for planting. There are ten acres of grain sown and five of potatoes planted. Corn will
                                have to wait for warmer weather. 254,000 ft. of logs have been sawed at our mill this
                                spring of which 104,000 belong to us and the remainder^ to the neighbors. As Baldwins
                                are the best apples we have for market we have grafted between five and six hundred wild
                                trees with that variety. The Sisters have set out 1}4 doz. fruit trees and 1,000
                                strawberry plants. Before these notes reach the Manifest:), we shall transport 50 tons
                                of pressed hay to the Portland market. A. S. C.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p"> May, 1S92. Dear Editoij:"Notes about Home" have come to be quite an institution in our
                                monthly, occupying nearly half the space, counting out that used for reviewing the
                                Revival of 1808., and if the same amount was to be covered with selections from other
                                papers, it is far better appropriated. The Editorial is always excellent, the legitimate
                                fruit of a life devoted to the best interests of our respective homes, but it often
                                occurs to the mind of any thoughtful reader we presume, that the principles which do or
                                should govern these homes, are too seldom discoursed upon: insomuch that the casual
                                reader abroad would too often fail to find the question answered even in part. What do
                                these people believe? A church without a formal creed is n &gt; cause of alarm, in these
                                days of the crumbling of all creeds but where societies are constantly being organized,
                                however short-lived, taking parts of our belief as a foundation, certainly, one which
                                has existed for one hundren years, upon principles, firm, in that they are unselfish, as
                                the everlasting hills, should often place said principles before the reader, in language
                                not mis-leading. The "Confession of sin," so often conconfounded with the belief and
                                practice of the Roman Catholic church, where male priests alone minister; however
                                erroneous this idea may seem to us, it invariably manifests itself in conversing with
                                strangers. We are doing as all good Christians aim to, at this season, when nature decks
                                herself in fresh attire, some interior painting is in progress; the fashion of our
                                foremothers, of turning every thing upside down, is greatly improved upon: but we <pb n="142" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> have yet to learn that repose, at times, is not indulgence, and
                                that body or mind, "forever busy" is sure to find vengeance. Blessed are they who find
                                the happy medium, and learn wisdom before too late, ! may not be among the proverbs of
                                Solomon, but it is just as necessary that the | earthly existence may be rounded out to
                                its full capacity for doing good and working righteousness. I We send a loving welcome
                                in advance, j to the dear friends whom we are expect- | ing to entertain as guests the
                                coming season, also to any who may be kind enough \ to surprise us with a visit. E. B.
                            j</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/> West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> May, 1892. Deab Editob;The wise man tells us in the good book, that "to everything there
                                is a season and a time to every purpose under the Heavens." We find that the rapidly
                                revolving wheels of time have again brought round the season for collecting "Home Notes"
                                and if we do not make haste we shall be as far in the rear as the present spring season.
                                "Smiling May seems not to come this way," tkough we find her name registered on the
                                calendar. April appears to hold dominion yet, and through smiles and tears is slowly
                                covering the earth with verdure. Have to-day for the first time, turned a portion of our
                                stock to pasture. A few events have transpired since our last writing. On the 24th ult.
                                Sunday, P. M. a company of tramps while strolling over our fields, either accidentally
                                or purposely set fire to the dead grass which rapidly spread, burning over some ten
                                acres but was happily arrested before it reached the woods or did serious damage. A few
                                days prior to this, Br. Thomas Farish of the East family, owing to the breaking of the
                                harness, was thrown from a carriage and badly injured, but is fast recovering.
                                Notwithstanding this an$ other afflictions the enterprising members constituting that
                                family are not disheartened, but are alive and active. Are remodelling their dwelling
                                house somewhat, by dispensing with the old windows in a portion of the house and
                                replacing them with large plate glass windows adding bathrooms and other modern
                                improvements. House-cleaning painting and some small repairing is in progress and dirt
                                ought to feel that it is a nuisance. Our dear Sister Maria Donne took her departure from
                                earth very suddenly and unexpectedly. We miss her from the circle in which she has moved
                                for nearly half a century, but we would not recall her to earth for she has suffered
                                much physically, and is no doubt happy in the change and now rejoicing in her freedom
                                from the pains of mortality. J. L. S.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sonyea, New York" TEIform="index"/>Sonyea, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> May, 1892. "March may blow and April try, But May will tell who'll live or die." Sunny
                                May lias showered the parched earth to a fulness; six days of continuous rain has caused
                                all living vegetation to "bud and blossom" as the rose. Peach, pear and cherry trees are
                                laden with their perfumed fruits, a forerunner of "the great and glorious harvest" in
                                which all men delight; if drought and frost do not blight them. 154 rods of barbed wire
                                were built the past week in connection with much more farm work. The sowing of spring
                                grain was finished some days since, and the sowers are watching the upspringing of their
                                labor with interest. Housecleaning scenes are among the principal plays of the day. As
                                the curtains go up, a clearer and brighter view of external things is presented to the
                                vision, and all out door life appears beautifully beautiful. The Sonyea depot, owned by
                                the Erie Co., was burned on the morning of the 26th. ult. As it was but a port of
                                shelter for waiting pilgrims no loss of property was sustained; fortunately the wind was
                                light, had it been otherwise, the large ware-house standing in the rear would also have
                                been destroyed. We are thankful for its preservation. G. D. G.</p><pb n="143" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/> Alfred, Me.</head><p TEIform="p"> May, 1892. Beloved Elder Henky:The days pass so swiftly that I can hardly keep pace with
                                them. It seems but a few days ago I was writing "Notes" for May Manifesto and it is now
                                time for June "Notes." There does not seem to be much of interest to write about. All
                                are busy wTith no time for idleness. if we remember our Mother's injunction, "Hands to
                                work and hearts to God," I believe a blessing will come to us, and we shall realize
                                fully that God is good, and his mercy endureth forever. Warm spring weather has not
                                reached us yet, even yesterday a few snowflakes fell, followed by a cold rain. Potatoes
                                and peas are all that the weather permits of planting as yet. Spring term of school
                                commenced the 10th. inst. Housecleaning almost finished, and the Sisters are very glad.
                                We read in the good book that it is first pure and then peaceable, and if our hearts are
                                as clean and pure as our dwellings, surely we ought to live in peace, love and union,
                                with never a word to mar our happiness. This cleansing work must and will go on, and
                                every soul that is willing to endure the cleansing, will come off victorious in the end,
                                and be numbered with the hundred forty and four thousand. Let us keep in the way, for we
                                know that "God's work will stand, It cannot, will not fail; "Pis founded on eternal
                                truth, Enduring as the heavens are; It cannot, will not fail. F. C.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Not for an orange" TEIform="index"/> NOT FOR AN ORANGE.</head><p TEIform="p"> A pleasant memory of my dear friend and gospel Sister, Ehoda Offord, who took charge of me
                            when a child, Lucy S. Bowbks. Some varied years of my humble life Have gone to the distant
                            past, But my mind some recollection holds That through future years will last. Yea last when
                            the misty veil is drawn, And time is to me no more, When I meet dear friendsthank God they
                            On the river's other shore. [live, The thoughts that circle so lovingly, Are of scenes when
                            just nine years Had marked the length of my life on earth, 'Mid its joys, its pains and
                            fears. I was held in charge by a gentle soul Who sought my utmost good, Who knew the springs
                            of ray little heart, And my mind well understood. She said to me one Sabbath time, "If you
                            will be kind and true, Quite perfect prove the whole week long, A gift I will give to you."
                            A child I was, but I labored not With the stimulant thought of praise, Nor with hope of a
                            pleasant recompense That might crown the seven good days. I cherished the thought of
                            affection, pure, That I knew to my soul would flow; That union too that would gather me And
                            help me Godward to grow. I labored on with a constant care, Discreetly and true each day,
                            [beam, And found at the time of the sun's last I had won it in every way. She called me
                            aside to a closet room, And gave me with gentle hand An Orange, as large and sweet and round
                            As grows in the sunniest land. I cannot tellso I will not try How my heart leaped up for
                            joy; A true delight and a holy peace I had gained without alloy. I can see it now, oh it
                            truly seemed Like a golden ball of love, I think I couldn't have prized it more Had it come
                            from the world above. She said in her kind and winsome way, "Not for an orange my dear, Not
                            for an orange was all your strife, But for love's own sake and cheer." I might have returned
                            the treasure given And felt my toil well repaid; Not for the symbol, but riches unseen I
                            sought for, lived for and prayed. She knew it, and that was half of the gain My courage grew
                            buoyant and strong; I loved her, she felt it; she loved me I felt it, How glad was my
                            triumphant song. And I think of it now, how well it would be Should we give the good we
                            possess From out of our spiritual caskets each day, Symbolized in deeds that will bless. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p><pb n="144" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scarlet letter" TEIform="index"/>The Scarlet Letter
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A GREAT STORY. "The Scarlet Letter." Nathaniel Hawthorne's most celebrated story, and
                                one of the most famous in American literature. up to a few weeks ago cost, in cheapest
                                cloth binding, 81.00, or in paper, 50 cents. We have just received a very neat and
                                thoroughly well made cloth bound edition from John B. Alden, Publisher, New York, which
                                he sells for 20 cents, plus 5 cents for postage, if by instil: the same in paper covers
                                he sells for 10 cents, postpaid. His Catalogue of choice books, over 100 pages, which he
                                sends to any one for 2-cents postage, is a literary curiosity, which every book-buyer
                                ought to have, of corn's". His publications are not sol 1 by booksellers, but only
                                direct. Address, .John B. Alden, Publisher, 57 Rose St., New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>The
                                Ladies' Home Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> There is an
                                interesting group of bright girls at the New England Conservatory of Music, in Boston,
                                who represent the quality of push characteristic of the American girl. There are some
                                thirty-five of these girls, and they are being musically and vocally educated by The
                                Ladies' Home Journal of Philadelphia. Some time ago this magazine offered, as a
                                stimulant to girls to get subscriptions for it, free education at the Conservatory. The
                                American girl is quick to see a chance, and one by one these thirty-five girls have come
                                from all parts of the country to Boston. They receive the very best the Conservatory
                                affords, the most desirable rooms in the building are theirs, and they have all their
                                wants carefully looked after by a wealthy periodical. Perhaps in no other country on the
                                face of the globe could such a thing be possible. These girls, too, the reporter was
                                told, belong to nice families, but they preferred to earn their own musical education
                                rather than depend on the family purse. Of course, the particular girls are unknown to
                                the scholars at large, and to all intents and purposes they are paying their own way.
                                And they certainly are. It is said that the magazine is also educating a number of other
                                girls at Wellesley, Smith and Vassar Colleges. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                In Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">In Phrenological Journal and Science of
                                Health for May a gentleman who has distinguished English journalism gives stiriking
                                testimony for the usefulness of Phrenology. It is Mr. Wm. T. Stead, whose portrait
                                stands in the opening page. Some views of Persia from the sketch book of a lady traveler
                                follow. The function of Acquisitiveness is variously illustrated, and a writer
                                vigorously attacks the notion that appears to prevail in society that there are men and
                                women stand on a different moral footing. Some spicy reading occupies the department of
                                Practical Phrenology, and D. P. Butler, of Boston, the "Health Lift" man, is the
                                phrenological example of the number. Mrs. Hull points out the use and manner of coercion
                                in training young children, and little Queen Wilhelmina of Holland is portrayed in
                                significant style by the editor. How to Care for the Sick, The First Schools on
                                Manhattan Island and the late Senior Admiral of the British Navy, sir Provo Wallis, who
                                died recently over a hundred years of age, are notable parts of the month's record. The
                                editorial matter is suggestive and varied, as usual. Published at 15c. a number, or
                                $1.50 a year. This number is dated from the new office, and letters should be addressed
                                Fowler &amp; Wells Co., 25 East Twenty-first St. New York.IT PAYS TO READ THE
                                PAPERS, especially your county paper, for often through this medium business chances and
                                opportunities are presented that might otherwise entirely escape your attention. For
                                instance, B. F. Johnson &amp; Co., Richmond, Va., have an advertisement in this
                                paper that will prove of especial interest and value to a large number of people
                                hereabouts. Write to them for further particulars.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peep into a mountain-walled treasury of the Gods" TEIform="index"/>
                                A PEEP INTO A MOUNTAIN-WALLED TREASURY of the Gods
                            </head><p TEIform="p">UTAH. "A PEEP INTO A MOUNTAIN-WALLED TREASURY of the Gods," is the title of a beautifully
                                illustrated book forwarded to us by Cassius C. Smith of Denver, Col. In his illustrative
                                notes referring to this wonderful country the Editor writes."Earth has no other land
                                like ours. Among all the nationalists and realms of the Globe, Columbia the Gem of the
                                ocean is peerless, unrivalled and unrivable. The grandest empires of the old world, of
                                ancient or of modern times, sink into petty provinces beside its vast dimensions." This
                                very interesting, instructive and beautiful work will be sent to any address upon
                                receipt of 25 cts by J. H. Bennett, Gen'l Passg'r agent, Rio Grand Western Railway, Salt
                                Lake City.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Doane, Laura Maria" TEIform="index"/>Laura Maria Doane
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Laura Maria Doane, at West Pittsfield, Mass., Apr. 25, 1892. Age 58 yrs. 5 mo. and 10
                                days. Sister Maria has been a member of the Society for fifty-one years. I. E. L. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Weatherford, Sarah A." TEIform="index"/>Sarah
                                A. Weatherford
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Sarah
                                A. Weatherford, at Pleasant Hill, Ky., May 9, 1892., in the fifty-third year of her age.
                                Our beloved Sister was gathered into the Society at the age of eight years. Was called
                                from earth in the prime of usefulness, and will be greatly missed by her associates and
                                friends. Yet it is well if, in our affliction we can say, "Thy will, O Lord, not mine be
                                done." J. W. S. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wayne, Ada M." TEIform="index"/>Ada M. Wayne
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Ada M. Wayne, at Mount Lebanon, N. Y. May 13, 1892. Age 22 yrs. Five
                                years among Believers. Earth's trials o'er, the victory's won; Her spirit doth rejoice
                                With her loved friends of Lebanon, The people of her choice. Sophia Wayne.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE WORLD'S FAIR.
The 250,000 readers of this interesting and
unique publication will be pleasantly surprised with the April issue, decidedly the
handsomest so far published. The frontispiece is an especially fine full page engraving
of the Hon. Thomas M. Waller, of Ct., First
Vice-President of the National Commission.
There are also full page engravings of the
U. S. Government Building, the Transportation Building, and the Fisheries Building, as
they will appear when finished.
One of the prominent features is a beautiful
colored lithographic view of the prominent
Exposition Buildings as they will appear
when finished. There will be found several illustrations showing the buildings in course of
erection, an exquisite panoramic view of the
buildings and grounds as they appear at present, a photograph of Chicago as it appeared
in 1833, a beautiful photograph of the members of the National Congress as they viewed
the Exposition grounds February 22d, together with photographs of the Congressional
Committee on the World's Fair.
This number is rich in biographies of prominent men connected with the Fair, besides
leading articles such as "The President's Endorsement of the Exposition." "The Lesson
of the Exposition," and "Hellenic Art," also
special reviews of all the details and work
done to date, giving the amounts of money
paid out, dimensions and costs of the different
buildings. It contains extracts from the oration of Gen. Woodford, delivered before the
National Congressmen when they were in Chicago, that are well worthy of careful perusal.
There is an article stating till the appropriations of the different States and foreign
countries to date, besides many more interesting articles which are invaluable for their
information and instruction in World's Failmatters. Altogether this number is not only
well worthy of reading, but is invaluable to
all those who expect to visit the World's Fair
in 1893, or to any one who wishes to have an
authentic record of the World's Columbian
Exposition. Price 25 cents per copy. Early
in the fall this publication "will he issued semimonthly, down to the beginning of the Fair.
During the Fair it will appear weekly.    Annual subscription  price $4.00 which will entitle subscribers to at least eighteen copies.
Published by           JAS. B. CAMPBELL,
218 La Salle St., Chicago. 111..   V. s. A.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
E.C. Morris &, Co,
64 Sudbury St., Boston, Mass
FIRE AMD BURGLAR-PROOF SAFES.
Bank Safes, Bank Vaults, Bank Vault
Doors, and Deposit Work of all kinds.
The Best Safe in the World.   150,000 in use.
Always preserve their contents
150 sold in Lynn, Mass., since that great fire
where 50 of our safes were subject to intense
heat, preserving their contents.
Champion Record also in the Great Chitago Fire in 1871, in the Great Boston Fire in
1872, and in all the great fires since. Send
for circulars.         Agents Wanted.
f HE O
tr TOD CADKOT GET THKH O TCOB
VOCAL DEALF.nS, WE WILL HOT 60313
WAV  or SUPPLYING TOO WITB TH
STRATTON
RUSSIAN GUT
VIOLIN STRINGS.
Deafen ami) (or Catalogue u-PHc Lbt
JOHN F STRATTON & SON,
 OSOUttLB UUM A
Musical Merchandise.
^tt tVtlkarSu.       HEW VO&k.
Sfratton
BAND  INSTRUMENTS,
Mreand BaS Drums, Fifes,   Piccolos, Clarionet*, Cytib
baistnd an other instruments psrtaimng to
Brass Bands and Drum Corps.
JOB* B*. BTRATTON & SON,
43 & 45 WalUr Stuet. NW YORK.
DO YOU KEEP BEES
If so, send your name and address for a
Free Sample of the AMERICAN BEE
JOURNAL Weekly32 pagesOne
Dollar a year.
Thomas G. Newman & Son,
PUBLISHERS
CHICAGO, ILL.
LIBERAL and MUSICAL.
"Shaker Music" is the title of a Look
of 250 pages, beautifully printed and neat>
ly bound. It was published by the Believers of Mount Lebanon, N. Y.
We will send the Manifesto during the
year 1892 and a copy of the Music Book,
to any address for $1.25 postage paid. If
desirable the Book and paper may be sent
to different persons.
Address,
The Manifesto,
East Canterbury. N. H.
Every-Day Biography.
Containing a collection of nearly 1400
brief Biographies, arranged for Every Day
in the Year, as a Reference for the Teacher,
Student, Cliautauquan, and Home Circles.
By Amelia J. Calver. A large handsome
vol., nearly 400 pages, handsomely bound;
price, $1.50.
"Every-Day Biography," is an outgrowth
of the increasing popularity of observing the
birthdays of noted people.
Nearly 1500 names are here found, representing sovereigns, rulers, statesmen, founders of colleges, institutions, etc., besides
pioneers in every art, science, and profession.
To Chautauquans it will prove invaluable,
since every week will bring some name to
mind prominent in that universal study.
This work will be found a valuable addition to any library or collection of books.
Agents wanted to introduce thig, and take
orders for it. Sent by mail, postpaid, on receipt of price, $1.50.    Address,
FOWLER & WELL'S 00., 775 BE0ADWAT, New York.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cream of tartar baking Powder. Highest of all in leavening strength.Zatett
Untied States Government Food Heporl.
Royal Baking Powder Co., 106 Wall St., N. Y.
SPECIAL
FROM
West Pittsfield, Mass.
F. A. Owen;
Pkes. Am. Correspondence
College :Dear Sir :Some of your
students at this place having called my
attention to the course of instruction
provided by the AMERICAN CORRESPONDENCE COLLEGE, I
can say, from a personal examination
of the same, that I consider the information and benefit it imparts to be of
very great educational value to teachers and students as well as to any one
who wishes to increase or revive his
fund of practical knowledge.
Yours truly,
Louis Basting,  Pastor of Church at W. Pittsfield, Mass.
& METHOD COURSE" given by
mail. A course of 10 weeks costs but
$2.50. (40 per cent discount to teachers.) A 82 page catalogue of all our
courses on receipt of stamp. Our mail
course in SHORT HAND is the best
and cheapest. Send stamps for full
particulars.
AMEEIOAN
COLLEGE.
SOUTH DAffSVILLE, U. Y.
JOHN F. STRATTOK & SON,
48 & 45 Walker St.            K. EW YORK.
Importers of all kinds o*
MUSICAL   MERCHANDISE,
Violins,  Guitars,   Banjos,
Accordeons, Harmonicas, &c.
All kinds of STRINGS, etc., etc.
CASH   PRIZE.     Particulars   free.
)j. B. Caldwell, 104 Franklin St.,
Chicago.
BIOGRAPHICAL   SKETCH
DANIEL FRASER
Of the  SHAKER    COMMUNITY,
of
MOT7NT    IiEJB^.n'Oir,    TV.
By Catherine   Allen.
o
Price, 10.
SKETCHES
OF
SHAKERS & SHAKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the
United Society of Believers in
Christ's Second Appearing.
By Gr. B. Avery.
Price, 15 cts.
SHAKER'S   ANSWER
To THE OFT KEPEATED QUESTION,
"What   will   become   of  the
World, if all become Shakers?"
Price, 10 cts.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>