<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2201" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">29</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">22</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18920101" TEIform="date">January 1892</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="22" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                        <pb id="p1"/>
                                        <p>JANUARY. THE MANIFESTO, Published by the United Societies, VOL. XXII. "For what is a man profited, if he shall gain
                        the whole world, and lose his own soul? or what shall a man give in exchange for his soul."—Matt. XVI., 26.
                        Canterbury, N. H., 1892. <pb id="p2"/> THE MANIFESTO. CONTENTS. Page. Kentucky Revival, 1 Our Roll Call, 5 Seven
                        Baptisms, " Lette - H. Hollister, 8 Love, -10 Letter - L. Wentworth, The New Year, 11 Future of Religious Thought, "
                        Editorial, - ... 12 In Memory of, 13 Notes about Hoine, 14 Too Late,..... 20 Diary of N. B. Moore, " Letter - R.
                        Jackson, 22 Music - The "Landing," , 23 Books and Papers, 24 Deaths, </p>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    <pb id="p3"/>
                    <div2 type="none">
                        <p>THE MANIFESTO. Published by the United Societies. VOL. XXII. "For what is a man profited, if he shall gain the
                            whole world, and lose his own soul? or what shall a man give in exchange for his soul."—Matt. XVI., 26. East
                            Canterbury, N. H. 1892.</p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="1" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kentucky revival, no. 13" TEIform="index"/>THE KENTUCKY REVIVAL</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="M'Nemar, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>Richard M'Nemar OF Union Village, Ohio. Published
                            in Albany, N. Y., in 1808.</byline><p TEIform="p">No. 13. A Letter written to Richard M'Nemar. My Dear Bkothek Richard :—I never longed to see
                            any person so much. If I was not confined in this clay tabernacle I should be with you in
                            less than an hour. The floods of earth and hell are let loose against us, and me in
                            particular. I am seriously threatened with imprisonment, and stripes I expect to receive for
                            the testimony of Jesus. Kentucky is turning upside down. The truth pervades in spite of man.
                            Cumberland is sharing the same fate. The young preachers, some of them, will preach Jesus
                            without the covering put on him by the fathers. The scribes, the disputers of this world are
                            gnashing upon us. Brother Matthew Houston has clean escaped the pollutions of this world,
                            and he and his people are going on to perfect holiness in the fear of God. A few more will
                            soon follow. Come over and help us, is the cry made to us from every part. Brother Purviance
                            is gone to Carolina to preach the gospel, by the request of some there. In a few weeks I
                            start to fulfill a long daily string of appointments to Cumberland; by request I go. I have
                            appointed two communions among many Christians on the heads of Little and Big Barrens.
                            Brother Dooley is among the Cherokees again. His last rout there was successful; some poor
                            Indians received the gospel. He was solicited to return. He is truly an Apostle of the
                            Gentiles. Some few are getting religion among us. What shall I say ? I know not: my heart
                            grieves within me. Certain men from afar whom you know, inject ter- ror and doubt into many;
                            and now religion begins to lament in the dust among us. Some, as I suppose, will cast away
                            the ordinances of Baptism, and the Lord's Supper, but not many as yet. Most dear Brother,
                            inform me what you think of these men among us and you, from a distant region. Thank God he
                            gave me his word. Letters show the substance and faith eats it. We all want to meet with you
                            shortly ; but by reason of my absence <pb n="2" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. to Cumberland,
                            Brother Purviance to North Carolina, Brother Houston in Madison, we cannot meet on
                            TurtleCreek, nor sooner than third Sabbath in June, and that in Kentucky. Brothers Marshal
                            and Houston parted from us yesterday. We administered the Lord's" Supper at Caneridge the
                            day before; many communicants; much exercise. I am pushed for time to write to you. We have
                            five students of the Bible, all but one know the languages, full of faith and of the Holy
                            Ghost, just ready to preach. They all fled from the Presbyterians, to their grief, pain and
                            hurt. Brother Stockwell exceeds expectation, and is beloved and useful. Our Apology is yet
                            living and working, and tearing down Babylon in Virginia. It was reprinted there to the
                            great injury of Presbyteriaiiism. It is also reprinted in Georgia. We are just publishing a
                            short tract on Atonement, I will send you one. This truth has unhinged the brazen gates
                            already. I am hurried. Pray for me. Farewell. B. W. STONE. Great prospects were presented
                            according to the above letter, on the part of the revival; the truth pervading and turning
                            the whole country upside down. The Macedonian cry sounding from every part. The Apology and
                            tract on Atonement, tearing down Babylon, or unhinging her brazen gates. Some, full of the
                            Holy Spirit, just ready to preach, and one among them all who had escaped the polhitions of
                            the world, and was going on to perfect holiness. But all this appeared unspeakably short of
                            the glad tidings brought by the Brethren fr om New Lebanon, provided that what they
                            testified concerning the church was true. It was well enough for those .who were in Babylon
                            to cry for help, and for such as were appointed to the work, to tear her down and unhinge
                            the brazen gates ; but something bej'ond this must be taken into the account. We have news
                            of a Zion, and what if her foundations are already laid. May it be that God has sent down
                            the New Jerusalem for the refuge of souls, before he began to tear down the old buildings ?
                            The Lebanon Brethren paid their first visit to Matthew Houston. Perhaps he has believed and
                            taken up his cross. How else can he have escaped the pollutions of the world? They have also
                            been with Br. Stone, and opened the testimony there in part: perhaps he has taken hold of
                            it, and means to make a final push for the kingdom through stripes and imprisonment. Or have
                            these students of the Bible learned to appropriate Scripture phrases to false and inferior
                            objects. Br. Stone and others may have received the name, Holy Spirit out of the Bible, but
                            the thing must certainly dwell in the church. Admitting that they are blazing full of the
                            spirit, burning and shining lights, this goes no further than John the Baptist, it is far
                            short of the kingdom of God. Those Brethren from the East tell us that their people have got
                            the kingdom, that they have attained it, by taking up the cross, and doing the works of
                            Christ, and overcoming sin by faithful and diligent combat, that they are of God and do not
                            commit 2 <pb n="3" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. sin; but walk even as Christ walked, and are
                            righteous even as he is righteous. He that committeth sin, whatever his profession or gifts
                            may be, he is yet of the devil. These things inject terror and doubt into many. John was
                            full of the Holy Spirit, and for his testimony concerning Jesus, he was actually cast into
                            prison, full of terror and doubt, whether this was he that should come or whether he should
                            look for some other. In fine, I could see nothing in the past work as a foundation to build
                            upon. And what these strange Brethren testified, appeared plain Scriptural truth, and
                            presented a way entirely safe for those who were able to receive it, and whether they were
                            the people or not, who had actually attained this salvation, it was very evident they were
                            far before us in light and understanding concerning the way; and it was no doubt the will of
                            God, that those who desired to be saved should walk in it. Thus in the midst of reasonings,
                            doubtful disputations, and close examinations, the testimony was in- vestigated at
                            Turtle-Creek publicly and from house to house until it obtained the full credit of a number
                            who had been leading characters in the revival. Malcham Worley was the first who embraced
                            it, opened his mind and took up his cross. With this I confess I was at first staggered,
                            from a deeprooted prejudice that I had imbibed against some of his peculiar sentiments ; but
                            finally concluded that if Malcham had been more wild in his former exercises than the rest,
                            he certainly needed salvation the more; besides it appeared that his conflicts with the man
                            of sin, the son of perdition as he expressed it must shortly have terminated his existence
                            upon earth,* had not his expected deliverer come out of Zion to turn away ungodliness from
                            Jacob. But I wTas not a little surprised, that these strange Brethren should come directly
                            there, and he receive them with such, cordiality, when I was well assured that no previous
                            acquaintance had existed between them. This, with many other singular circumstances that
                            occurred, restrained me from attempting to judge the nvysterious work of God's spirit, but
                            rather labor to get a deeper and more practical acquaintance with it. Soon after Malcham set
                            out in the narrowway, he was followed by a number, so that within three or four weeks from
                            the first opening of the testimony, it, had pervaded ten or twelve families. And from that
                            period continued grad- ually to increase, and at Turtle-Creek * It was necessary that a work
                            which promised redemption from sin, should include a perfect revelation of the whole root
                            and foundation of it. And as tn:e subject of this revelation, God made choice of Malcham
                            Worley; who, notwithstanding he was a man of unspotted character, of an independent fortune,
                            and a liberal education; yet neither his learning, his estate, nor his good name, could have
                            saved him from total distraction, and the wildest convulsions of despair, when he came to
                            behold in the open light of divine revelation, the whole depth of human depravity. Nothing
                            but the miraculous power of God, could have supported him through such a scene, and kept him
                            alive in the cheerful hope of deliverance, amidst the violent conflicts of an inbred nature,
                            and the outward rage of blind and superstitious professors. 3 <pb n="4" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. the number of families which now stand in the faith of Christ's Second
                            Appearance, may be stated between thirty and forty. I shall now consider the entrance and
                            progress of the testimony more particularly, as it respects the individual who receives it.
                            The first point of faith in relation to the testimony, is to believe that he who bears if is
                            a true messenger and witness of Christ, in whom the spirit of truth continually abides ; and
                            that whatever instruction, reproof or counsel is ministered by such, it comes from Christ,
                            who speaketh in him. Therefore all who are taught in this manner are strictly and properly
                            taught of God, and in obeying what they are taught they yield obedience to Christ. Upon this
                            ground the believer has to make a final settlement with an old systematic idea, that the
                            spirit of God speaketh invariably in the Scriptures. Upon an impartial examination he finds
                            that all the contradictory spirits among the professors of Christianity, speak in the
                            Scriptures, even the devil himself; so that the Scriptures are as liable to be spoken by an
                            evil spirit as the good. It then remains to follow that spirit which goes contrary to sin,
                            and manifests its purity by its fruit, according to the Scriptures, and the inward test of
                            conscience. This is the spirit of Christ, and it sets them immediately to work to do the
                            righteous will of God. And first of all to confess before God what they have done contrary
                            to his will and the light of their own conscience. In this work, the honest Believer might
                            as well try td cover or conceal the most chafing mote in his eye, as try to hide or conceal
                            any thing which he has committed, contrary to the pure doctrine of the Scriptures, and the
                            example of Jesus Christ, of which he stands convicted by the witness of the spirit in his
                            own conscience. Here he has to combat the spirits of wicked men, who pretend to speak in the
                            Scriptures, and say that it is idolatry to confess sin in the presence of man, and that God
                            is to be found anywhere, in the fields, on the hills or un- der the green trees, and there
                            we ought to make our confession in secret. By following the spirit of truth, he overcomes
                            this wild pagan error, and discovers, that according to the Scriptures, God never accepted a
                            confession of sin, which was not either made to those whom he had set in order in the
                            church, or at least with the face toward that temple which was typical of his last
                            habitation, man. But the greatest evidence the true Believer receives of this being the
                            order and institution of heaven, is the divine light which he receives m consequence. Light
                            by which sin appears more than ever hateful, and by which he is inspired with a growing zeal
                            to roll out of his heart and practice the last remains of it; and by which he discovers with
                            increasing brightness the succeeding footsteps of true gospel obedience. To the' sense of
                            those who iu the faith of Christ, have cleared their con- science from the deep-rooted
                            stains of sin, and received his spirit as their ruling principle of life, sin is so
                            exceeding sinful, so hateful and pernicious that I am bold to say they cannot commit it. He
                            that is begotten with the divine nature of the Son of God, 4 <pb n="5" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. keepeth himself in the element and works of that nature ; so that he can no more
                            commit sin than a fish can fly through the air, or an eagle dive to the bottom of the sea.
                            But that abiding fervor and power of spirit which overcomes every motion of evil, belongs
                            not to the entrance of the testimony, but a degree of progress in it. This degree all must
                            attain who come into it, or fall off as withered branches for there remains no more room for
                            either imputing their sins to Christ, or to a deceitful heart, or anything else by which
                            they can be excused; but the soul that sinneth must bear its own iniquity, and burn under it
                            without any mitigation or covering. (to be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our roll call" TEIform="index"/>OUR ROLL CALL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wayne, Sophia" TEIform="persName"/>Sophia Wayne</byline><p TEIform="p">Let us finish the work, we have nobly begun, Let vis cling to our faith, till the victory is
                            won, O Christian Believers, our work is not done, We must gather more into the fold. Lead
                            forth in the march, raise our voices in song, Remember the order to which we belong, Let us
                            show the light path to the one in the wrong, And gather more souls in the fold. Against
                            caste and monopoly our conscience must fight, For in heart and hand labor we know we are
                            right, Our leaders are trusty, they walk in the light, And will gather more into the fold.
                            We own all our dwellings, we are not oppressed, We labor with pleasure, and so earn our
                            rest, From the north and the south, from the east and the west, We are gathering them into
                            the fold. Ballston Spa, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Seven baptisms: a visionary dream" TEIform="index"/>SEVEN BAPTISMS. A Visionary Dream</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catherine" TEIform="persName"/>Catherine Allen</byline><p TEIform="p">I was standing with a company of young Brethren and Sisters by the entrance of a magnificent
                            white temple. Near us were Elders who beckoned \is to follow them. They called in sweet and
                            pleading tones:—"Come to the Baptism ! Come and fear not; 'tis the love of God that calls
                            you." We ascended the steps. At our approach the door of the vestibule swung open by some
                            invisible power. Entering, we found basins in which water was upspringing, fountain-like.
                            Here, as little children we were taught how to wash our hands. While doing this, we heard
                            uttered as from a voice in the air:—"Yea wash thy hands in innocency before thou canst
                            handle the Word of Life, or compass the altars of the Lord." This done, other doors were
                            opened where we found a flowing stream, and there, were shown that before we could enter
                            further into the sanctuary, we must wash our feet from the dust of earthliness, which had
                            clung to us while treading unhallowed ways. Other doors were then opened to a more spacious
                            apartment, where we indistinctly saw many things of which we knew not the meaning, and also
                            heard deep and earnest tones, but 5 <pb n="6" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> the manifesto. could not understand
                            what was beingspoken. Perceiving our confusion, the Elders said :—"Having eyes ye see not
                            the glory of the Lord, and ears ye hear not the power of his word ; for ye have lent your
                            eyes to behold the vanity and foolishness of this world, and ye have given your ears to
                            hear, and your lips to speak of those things which savor not of the truth, nor of life
                            everlasting. These must be cleansed from all ungodliness." Then there came upon our faces a
                            beautiful shining spray which seemed to penetrate to our memories, and bring forth as living
                            objects, those things conceived by sight or hoaring, that had taken shape in the mind. This
                            form of baptism was not accomplished in a moment, and it re- quired true courage to endure
                            its continuance, because of the mortification it brought, as one object after another came
                            to our view. The Elders who stood by us with sustaining strength, rejoiced with us to see
                            them borne away by the flowing tide. We pledged ourselves to turn forever away from all
                            forms of worldliness; to handle no unclean thing ; to walk only in paths of purity;—to
                            behold not, speak nor hear, of any thing shapen in iniquity ;—henceforth to serve God with
                            our whole being. We were then shown that to serve God acceptably, the gift of hand-labor
                            must be sanctified by another form of baptism. Moving forward a few paces there descended
                            bright and powerful jets of water upon our shoulders. We were told that in the shoulders
                            were united the muscles principally used in labor;—there must rest the yoke of Christ, if
                            now we would bear the burden of the Lord ; and this baptism was to cleanse us from all
                            ambitious strivings, and self-centered motives, that had hitherto neld more or less sway in
                            prompting us to action. Leading us still on, our Elders said ; —"Now ye may enter the House
                            of Prayer." Curtains being drawn aside disclosed an altar, beneath which issued a stream
                            that divided and coursed in semi-circular form, thus completing a circle around the
                            apartment. To approach the altar we must walk upon our knees through this stream. We were
                            instructed that this was to purify our devotions ;—that even in them had been mingled
                            worldly elements ;—selfish desires and errors of thought, with unmeaning forms which we had
                            received from those not illumined from the higher, resurrection spheres. As we advanced, the
                            waters deepened and flowed with increasing power and we heard a voice saying ;—"Arise !
                            plant your feet upon the rock, bend beneath the tide, wash, and wash again till your whole
                            being is cleansed and your garments are sinless and spotless." Here our Elders stood with
                            us, and in their firm and loving grasp, held us till the work was done, (as we thought,) for
                            wre supposed wre were then fully cleansed. Ascending we formed in circle around the altar,
                            and spontaneously united in a song of rejoicing and praise, for the peace, liberty and sweet
                            refreshing we had found. Again we heard the voice calling us to another baptism. We were
                            told that all our washings thus far had been comparatively outward, and only reached
                            effects. As yet we knew not of that deeper baptism of "fire and the 6 <pb n="7" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE MANIFESTO. Hoi}7 Spirit," which alone could pen- etrate with sanctifying power our inner
                            life, whence spring all the motives and impulses that prompt to action. TutU this weie
                            received, we would be liable to repeat the errors of the past, and could not be born into
                            the Kingdom of God. All knelt, and as we silently breathed forth soul-petitions, the heavens
                            seemed to open. Above our circle, we beheld one of glorified spirits, robed in gleaming
                            vestments. We could not see their countenances, so bright was the aureola surrounding them,
                            and still stronger the central light above them, whence descended upon us a radiant shower.
                            It was neither fire nor water, but as kindled drops ;—a penetrating fluid which left
                            unconsumed only the pure and the true. While receiving this baptism, from the inner spheres
                            there burst upon us a rapturous song of melody, and we felt as if transported above earth;
                            its brightest glories seemed only as dust. Every earthly desire had perished, and the holy
                            purpose of living only for the truth, now fully possessed our being. We had received seven
                            successive baptisms. First, of hands. Second, of feet. Third, of the vision, hearing and
                            utterance. Fourth, of the shoulders, (manual labor.) Fifth, of the knees, (spiritual
                            devotions.) Sixth, the full water baptism and cleansing of garments. Seventh, one of "fire
                            and the Holy Spirit," purifying the inner life. The feelings realized, and the strong
                            impressions retained, are of that deep spiritual nature which words can but feebly convey.
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fredonia, New York" TEIform="index"/>Fredonia, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Brother Alonzo ;—I have shown the things you sent, to a few members of our church, hoping
                                to draw from Uiem a hopeful forecast as to their reception. Such opinions as they have
                                expressed to me, are given not with the fervor of souls hungering for truth but rather
                                with the mind of the Greek, ready to hear or to tell of any new thing. Yet who can
                                foresee how truth works ? It is not so much our business to observe how we succeed, as
                                it is to proclaim the truth always ; first to persuade, and then to provoke others to
                                receive it. Only so that we detract not from the truth, we may dress it in such language
                                and parables as will attract the attention of our fellowmen. Plain, sincere and concise
                                expression carries the day, on the platform or in the pulpit. Christianity, or the
                                Shaker interpretation of it, may be presented as the only complete life insurance, in
                                which souls realize immediate results upon immediate death to the carnal life. It is the
                                last and only discovery of rapid transit from the place of business, of turmoil, dirt
                                and weariness, to the home of rest, cleanliness and kinship, where strange feel- ings
                                are not permitted to live. Shaker Christianity is not only the school of study, but it
                                is the highest and best equipped University on this round globe. Not in mathematics,
                                engineering or disputatious theology which this world makes so much of, but in the
                                athletic training of a soul to restored health, and in all knowledge 7 <pb n="8" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. pertaining to ourself and duties to God and our
                                fellow-beings, it lacks nothing in equipment. Shaker thought is the telephonic and
                                telegraphic means through which our Heavenly Father is quickening and enlightening the
                                benumbed senses of seeing and hearing in his children. The systemizing of geology or
                                chemistry or of knowledge in any other department of natural science, will not com- pare
                                in utility and importance with the system of order displayed in a Christian Shaker life.
                                It has no need of a prohibition party. Each soul is aided by every other soul to
                                prohibit itself from all hurtful ways. Is it the eye that is past saving? It is plucked
                                out by its possessor. Is the hand gangrened past recover}1 ? It is cut off by his
                                consent. Is licentiousness his bane? He binds it to the daily cross till life is
                                extinct. We rejoice that we are in the light of this Holy City which John saw coming
                                down to us. Your brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Henry" TEIform="persName"/>Henry Hollister</byline></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="This is the judgement age...." TEIform="index"/>This is the judgement age....
                            </head><p TEIform="p">This is the Judgment age. Considerate people, those within and those without the
                                churches, listen, to weigh, and to apply the tests of reason. None can remain the same
                                that they were before, after hearing the truth of the spiritual life rationally
                                presented. Through the word uttered by the messengers of Truth, faith has entered
                                consciously or unconsciously and cannot be dislodged if any are so unwise as to wish it.
                                The beginning of faith is like the least of all seeds, and in every heart open to the
                                Source of all life and light, it will find nourishment and grow till ripe for the
                                harvester ; Therefore let us continue to sow in faith and courage, knowing that the
                                harvest will be sure in its season. "How canst thou claim the harvest, If thou hast not
                                sown the seed, Or think the blessing will be thine, In thy hour of need?"</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Alonzo" TEIform="persName"/>Alonzo</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Systematic arrangement" TEIform="index"/>SYSTEMATIC ARRANGEMENT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>Oliver C. Hampton</byline><p TEIform="p">"Behold all ye that kindle afire, that compass yourselves about with sparks. walk in the
                            light of your fire and in the sparks that ye have kindled, this shall ye have of my hand; Ye
                            shall all lie down in sorrow." Isa. /., 11. "And without all contradiction, the less is
                            blessed of the better." Heb. vii, 7. Many have tried the among Believers, of "kindling a
                            fire and compassing themselves about with sparks." Not being satisfied with the bright
                            purifying flame of the Altar they start a separate illumination composed of a strange fire.
                            A systematic arrangement of spiritual fire and illumination is ;is necessary in the Church
                            as in any department of its general system. Wisdom is extremely profitable to direct in this
                            matter. Some honest individual thinks he has a special revelation, a new and important
                            illumination. He is soon compassed about with the sparks that he has kindled. And then what?
                            His fire and light are so dazzling he loses sight entirely of the great and vivifying Altar
                            fire of the Church. He thinks his few sparks have quite ex8 experiment <pb n="9" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE MANIFESTO. 9 tinguished that, and should be substituted in its place. When this point is
                            reached he is about ready to ulie down in sorrow." And he is dead sure to do this unless
                            reclaimed from his state of separateness from the altar fire and light of the Church. I have
                            been privileged to enjoy a membership in the Church for a great many years (sixty-nine) and
                            have witnessed the "lying down in sorrow" of many from this cause. Our Church which we call,
                            and which is, a second appearing of Christ's Pentecostal arrangement on the earth, has never
                            ceased to be illuminated and warmed by the sacred altar fires of cleansing and perfect
                            purification of all its inmates who calmly submitted to their renovating and cleansing
                            influence. Those who are, or have been, called to conduct these sacred illuminations have
                            never suffered them to go out day or night, for over one hundred years. Those to whose care
                            these sacred fires have been entrusted, have uniformly been chosen in accordance with a
                            great and sublime law, which has flashed through the universe ever since its evolution from
                            the mind of God. "Without all contradiction the less (experienced) are blessed of the better
                            (or more experienced.)" This sublime law of the universe involves a systematic arrangement
                            and organization of the Church of Almighty mag- nitude and importance, inasmuch as it has so
                            far saved from guilt and sorrow every sincere spirit wrho has submitted him or herself to
                            its elevating and salutary discipline. To this statement there is absolutely no exception.
                            If any one doubts thereof he can know of its sublime certitude and efficacy by doing the
                            works therein involved. The whole process of divine service consists in being saviors to one
                            another in the different duties, orders, situations, places from highest to lowest, (if
                            there be any highest or lowest, though there be less and greater according to experiences.)
                            We who know by long experience and trial the blessedness of the gospel of Jesus and Mother
                            Ann, feel almost like going forth and compelling others to come in and share with us the
                            manifold blessings of such a life. You will not need to kindle little rush-light fires and
                            compass yourselves about with sparks only to lie down in sorrow at last. It is so good to
                            enjoy the Eternal Now and not have to live on sickly hopes of the future. To know that
                            present at-one-ment writh God insures an eternity of present bliss and invulnerable peace
                            and contentment forevermore. O ye who have not so far found the peace Christ promised, give
                            us a call and see if we cannot put you in possession of the same. You need not stay if you
                            do not like it, but we cannot help believing many of you would like it who are disgusted
                            with the sins and shams and sorrows of the rudimental plane. Union Village, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If life had no crosses and trials..." TEIform="index"/>If life had no crosses and trials...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">If life had no crosses and trials, we would be but weak and vacillating in character. We grow
                            better, braver and stronger by the polishing process of abrasion. Difficulties help to
                            develop and mould in greater perfection the qualities of mind and soul.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><pb n="10" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love" TEIform="index"/>LOVE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/>Lucy S. Bowers</byline><p TEIform="p"> Love born of God! what power is more divine ? Transcendent excellence! oh what compares With
                            this great sovereign good? What soul declares A holier power? it will all hearts refine;
                            Unlimited, no boundaries confine. Possessing all, the light of truth it wears, Unceasingly,
                            surpassing gifts it bears, In it all true and sacred things combine. Pure love is ¦watchful,
                            tho' it slumbers), does not sleep, Fatigued, but not exhausted, long endures. Who sows to
                            love, the fruit of love will reap, And treasures which its blessedness insures. Expand O
                            heart, its power transforming feel, God's love in thee will God alone reveal. Mt. Lebanon,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, December 4, 1891" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Dec. 4, 1891</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Hexry :—The summer is past and the harvest ended. Now, if our souls are not
                            saved whom can we blame? Surely, not our heavenly Father, who has so abundantly provided for
                            all our needs, both spiritual and temporal; neither can we say, we lack the teaching, for
                            even the dying year echoes the sound of kind words, instructive lessons and earnest
                            solicitations which oft have been given by the teachers in our Zion home. Among these is our
                            venerable father, Elder Albert Battles, having a countenance aglow with love, extend- ing
                            the hand of Charity to the erring, and never, never tiring of giving counsel to those who
                            need spiritual instruction. May the good Lord lend him to us for years to come, is the
                            sincere prayer of each and all of his little flock. Now let us make a good use of the
                            lessons we have learned. Strive to retire within our own souls and find the Christ there.
                            Look to the Father, in faith, for whatever wre may want Simply believing that Jesus died on
                            the cross to appease God's wrath, never did and never can save any one from present sin or
                            sickness, and this doctrine was not what Jesus taught. There must be something more soul-
                            searching than this ; a living touch ; an inspiring of our souls from the Divine Source of
                            all good. We are to have faith in the Christ, believe that the Christ dwells within the soul
                            that has been thoroughly cleansed by the gospel fire ; has power to save and to make whole ;
                            aye, more, that it has made us whole, already. Did not the Teacher say, ''Whatsoever ye
                            desire when ye pray, believe that ye receive and ye have it already?" This matter of
                            trusting the Christ within to do all things for us, is not that which comes to any of us
                            spontaneously ; it conies by persistent effort on our part. No habit bursts fullgrown into
                            our lives, but every one comes from a succession of little acts. Now my dear young friends,
                            let us enter the New Year with a firm resolve to make an effort for a greater baptism, a
                            pentecostal baptism of the Holy Spirit and fire. This will destroy every element that
                            hinders the Christ from entering the soul and filling us with his divine Spirit. All will
                            please accept a New Year's greeting and true gospel love from Your Sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wentworth, Lois" TEIform="persName"/>Lois Wentworth</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Active in duty and prudent in all things..." TEIform="index"/>Active in duty and prudent in all things...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Active in duty and prudent in all things becomes a member of community life.</p></div2><pb n="11" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New year" TEIform="index"/>THE NEW YEAR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, Amelia J." TEIform="persName"/>Amelia J. Calver</byline><p TEIform="p">Since earliest childhood the opening of the New Year has seemed a sacred time. It was with
                            almost bated breath that we thought of the departure of the Old Year, and the incoming of."
                            the New; and with our little notebooks in hand in which to mark our merits and demerits, we
                            stepped with awe over the threshold into a new and enlarged chamber, which many earnest
                            resolutions had converted into an elysium of perfection. And it is even so to-day. These
                            childhood impressions have strengthened with age and we dread to step from the Old Year
                            until we nre prepared to tread with a firm and free step upon the weedless path of the New.
                            But Experience has taught us many lessons during life, the sternest of which is "Only the
                            present moment has actual being;" and if we impress upon each as it passes a well-learned
                            lesson of self-denial, time is well spent; and we can feel at the close of the year a
                            consciousness of spiritual strength. Together we all now stand waiting for the golden gates
                            of the New Year to open which reveals to us an unmarred future. We all have the same
                            privilege to right all our past wrongs, cancel all debts, and with white robes take up the
                            sacred duties of the New Year, remembering that this grand New Year is made up of 366 new
                            days, each of which should be begun with a clear understanding that there is no victory
                            without a conflict. A sad ending has that year, the balance sheet of which shows more losses
                            than gains; but even then we have a hopeful New Year before us; but sad, sad indeed must
                            that life be whose closing year finds no victory over sin nor self; where remorse steals the
                            peace of mind, and selfishness the friendship of life; for we "pass this way but once" and
                            there is no returning track over the paths of time ; eternity alone, offers the only hope of
                            salvation. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><byline TEIform="byline">(Contributed by <persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>Hamilton DeGraw.)</byline><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Future of religious thought" TEIform="index"/>THE FUTURE OF RELIGIOUS THOUGHT</head><p TEIform="p">In a new magazine of considerable promise issued from Boston and called The Arena, the Eev.
                            J. Minot Savage concludes an unusually able and brilliant paper on "The Agencies that are
                            Working a Kevolution in Theology," witli the following words:—"Such, then, are some of the
                            causes of the great theological changes the world is passing through. What is to be the
                            outcome? Is religion dying? No more than it means death for the life within to burst the
                            chrysalis, to take to itself wings and be at home in God's upper sunshine and air. No more
                            than it means death for childhood to put away childish things and enter man's estate. A
                            grander faith in God, a larger trust in man, a higher type of religious thought and life, a
                            nobler outlook for the future—these are some of the things it means. It is not faith, but
                            the lack of it, that is displayed by those who dare not fearlessly face the search for truth
                            and take the consequences of investigation. The real infidelity to-day is to be found with
                            those who stand with back to the sunrise, and see no reality except in the shadows of the
                            night that is passing away. God is in the power that is wheeling the earth into a new day;
                            and that day is one of such promise as the weary old world has never seen."</p></div2><pb n="12" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manifesto. January, 1893. Office of Publication" TEIform="index"/>THE MANIFESTO. JANUARY,
                            1893. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION</head><p TEIform="p">The Manifesto is published by the "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month,
                            and is the only work issued regularly by the Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and
                            simple statement of the religious views of the Oedee and to inculcate the spirit of
                            righteousness. All communications should be addressed to Henky C. Blinn, East Canterbury,
                            Mer. Co., N. H. TERMS. One copy per year, postage paid, " " six months, " " Send for sample
                            copy, free. .75 .40 Entered at the Post Office at East Canterbury, N. H., as second-class
                            matter.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Glad new year" TEIform="index"/>THE GLAD NEW YEAR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">With this initial number we are pleasantly introduced to the opening of a new volume of
                                the Manifesto. Since the beginning of the last year to which we now bid a long and lov-
                                ing adieu, the days, weeks and months have flitted away as on the swift wings of the
                                wind, and brought us safely to the place of new thoughts, new resolves and new
                                aspirations. With these beautiful treasures we are making some choice, welcome gifts for
                                all our many dear friends, through hope for unbounded peace and prosperity to dwell in
                                their hearts and homes, during the incoming auspicious year. Abundant blessings have
                                been with us during the past twelve months which have far more than compensated for all
                                the time and care that has been expended in obtaining them. God's protective Providence
                                has signally held us, unharmed, through all the many perils that may have transpired.
                                All have reason to give thanks and rejoice, while they open their souls to accept a
                                deeper and holier inspiration and a more resolute determination to walk in Wisdom's ways
                                of pleasantness, and in her paths of peace, The Manifesto accepts a liberal share in all
                                these good and choice gifts, and while returning thanks that abounds so fully in the
                                heart, for all who have, even in the least degree, either by writing or speaking,
                                contributed to the success of our little paper, would kindly solicit a continued
                                remembrance for the present and the many days yet to come. It is the living word that is
                                to accomplish the good and saving result. Without this word of God and the inspiring
                                influence which accompanies it on its mission among men, there would be but little
                                chance to circulate our voice of truth and gospel experience beyond the borders of our
                                own home. The acceptance and the disburse<pb n="13" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 13 merit
                                of this gospel testimony is, agreeably to our Christian faith, quite necessary for the
                                salvation of the soul. It is God's great gift of knowledge to those who are the children
                                of the spiritual resurrection, and without knowledge, or for the want of this special
                                truth through God's love, the people may perish. Above all other classes, a Christian
                                Community should be zealously active in presenting that light which God has vouchsafed
                                to their charge, before those who may have been less fortunate. It is not through an}7
                                special merit on our part that we have become heirs to these heavenly treasures, in
                                preference to others, but God's free gift of love through the kindness of his accepted
                                sons and daughters has reached us, and to-day we inherit the multiplied blessings which
                                others have earned through faithfulness to the cross of Christ. To consume these
                                treasures without making every effort possible for the accumulation of more, and insure
                                the temporal and spiritual prosperity of our gospel home, would make of us, in very
                                deed, a class of unprofitable servants in the Lord's vinevard. OUT &amp; IN, "La
                                Grippe" entered the Printing Office, and hence the enforced di'lny of the January
                                number.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memory of Eldress Katie Ferguson" TEIform="index"/>IN MEMORY OF ELDRESS KATIE FERGUSON</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Beaver, Orrin" TEIform="persName"/>Orrin Beaver</byline><p TEIform="p">Oub souls are filled with sorrow, as we chronicle the very sudden departure of our
                            well-beloved Eldress from the shores of mortality, to don the shining robes of purity and
                            holiness in the beautiful home of the angels, on the evergreen shore. During an acquaintance
                            of nearly thirty years with our deceased Sister, I had learned to love her as a true,
                            devoted mother in Israel, for such she ever proved to be to me, as well as to all her
                            surrounding Brethren and Sisters. True to her highest convictions of Christian duty and
                            right, she labored hard at all times with every faculty of soul and body she possessed, to
                            sustain the glorious cause of gospel principle and virtue, as exemplified in the life of a
                            true Believer. Kind, loving and affectionate to all of God's creatures with whom she came in
                            daily contact, even the poor dumb animals seemed to realize this in a great degree, while in
                            her presence. In all my long acquaintance with her no one, whether friend or foe, who came
                            to her in want or suffering of any kind, was sent away uncared fsr, if she had it in her
                            power to assist them in any degree. Honest and square in all her dealings with others, I
                            have had many not of our order say to me they had rather trade with Eldress Katie than
                            almost any one they ever dealt with, as they always found her fair and honorable in all her
                            dealings even to the last penny. Possessed of the noblest patience and forbearance, even
                            under most trying circumstances, I have often seen her when assailed by harsh and bitter
                            words spoken perhaps in the heat of passion, stand calm and firm as a rock till the angry
                            storm passed by; then she would effect a reconciliation if possible and if she proved to be
                            at fault in the matter, was ever ready to acknowledge it when convinced of the fact. She
                            often remarked that she had not an unkind feeling toward the least <pb n="14" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> 14
                            THE MANIFESTO. child of the infinite Father, but loved and wished them all well. What more,
                            clear Brethren and Sisters can any of us do than this? I feel that in this respect our
                            Sister has set us a beautiful model, which we cannot imitate too closely. One little
                            circumstance that occurred just before she left the form, I will here relate. About two days
                            before the decease of Brother James Langridge, on Sunday morning I think, she came into the
                            room where James and I were and asked how he was, and on my replying that he seemed to be
                            slowly sinking, she said she had a singular vision just before she awoke and thought he
                            could not last long. She thought she met Br. George Price in spirit-life and he showed her
                            his residence there, also another mansion, the most beautiful one she ever saw in her life,
                            full of the most gorgeous colors and on his asking her how she liked them, she replied, "Oh
                            they are so lovely, just the ones you know I always admired in earthlife ;'' then she awoke
                            and informed a Sister that she thought Br. James would not last long, as she thought she had
                            seen his future residence in the higher life. Alas, how little did any of us imagine that it
                            was her own future glorious home and not his; her inner spirit had caught a faint glimmer of
                            it, ere it took its final transition from scenes of time, to dwell with loved ones in the
                            fields Elysian; but all this was wisely hidden from her sight. And now in conclusion dear
                            Sister, we commend thee to God and loving guardian angels, knowing thou hast gone to inherit
                            a glorious harvest reward of "Well done good and faithful servant," trusting you will not
                            forget us poor pilgrims on the shores of time, but extend thy spirit strength and blessing,
                            to sustain us amid the fierce trials and temptations that beset us here below. Watervliet,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The thought that lives and burns..." TEIform="index"/>The thought that lives and burns...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The thought that lives and burns, is drawn from the blazing forge of truth and shaped on the
                            anvil of experience.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. November. Thermometer. Bain. Snow. 1890. 36.36 15-16
                                in. 12 in. 1891. 35.98 3 in. 1 in. Geo. M. W. Dec. 1891. Since so many are responding to
                                the earnest invitation to send Home Notes, interesting brevity becomes us all: so I add
                                my rose-leaf to the brimming glass knowing as of old, that it will not overflow. Since
                                last writing our weathers here have changed; more clouds out and fewer in. Gentle and
                                dashing rains have added to our water supply and still more would be beneficial. In our
                                home, blessings have followed sacrifice, for our dear Eldress Ann is restored again to
                                as good health as her advanced age will permit, and she is still among us, a ministering
                                angel of love, blessing and peace. Sister Fannie Tyson, who removed from the North
                                Family into the Church Family during the recent changes, is another of our home
                                blessings, an exemplification of the beautiful fruits of the spirit; while our dear
                                Eldress Dorothy, successor to Eldress Augusta, and our loved companion from early
                                childhood, is a treasure. We have also many more in our home whose light is quietly yet
                                steadily shining out over the sometimes troubled waters of life whose aid has guided us
                                over many reefs and breakers, and with such strength have we not the hope to say A Happy
                                New Year to all.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., A. J." TEIform="persName"/>A. J. C.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South family" TEIform="index"/>South Family</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1891. Deae Editok;—Not long since, the writer was privileged to call on our dear
                                mother, Eldress Ann. While conversing with her, and noticing how quick were her
                                perceptions, how bright her eyes and how alert her ears, at her advanced age <pb n="15" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. If) and feeble bodily state; Tea, while drinking in her
                                motherly words and beholding her Christ-like spirit, I thought,—Surely I am sometimes
                                too silent in giving honor where honor is due. We love, deeply, our sainted mother, as
                                has often been expressed. I think all who have known her as a Teacher in our gospel
                                order have known her to love and bless her as a mother in Israel. While thinking of her
                                blessed existence, of her beautiful character and her almost supernatural disposition, I
                                was prompted to send you the little poem entitled, "Too Late." (See page 20.) I trust it
                                will not be too late as others may find truth in it. I do not know the author, though
                                for a long time I have prized the lesson it conveys. We see by the papers that ISfew
                                York is making a move now in the right direction; if they can have plenty of water to
                                drink to help on the work, we shall look for a better state of things in the future; the
                                best thing we have heard lately is the Union move among the Ministers. God be praised!</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., S. A." TEIform="persName"/>S. A. C.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North family" TEIform="index"/>North Family</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1891. "O "my kind, loving friends In the gospel so dear; Let us greet one another
                                With a Happy New Year." Yea, and I wish every body could have a happy new year: but
                                alas! they will not. Why? because of selfishness and sin. Even though crops in some
                                places have failed and the people by the million, as in Russia, are crying for bread, if
                                it were not for greed, and the wrong system of things that prevails in the external
                                order, those people would not cry long; one dispatch across the ocean would be enough to
                                fire the hearts of those who had plenty and start the vessels laden with food to the
                                hungry ones, if nations would all as brothers greet and each seek the good of all; but
                                we have not got there yet; hence all will not have a happy new year. We had a very
                                pleasant gathering at the Church Family on Thanksgiving day. All the young people, and
                                somo older ones of the Church and Center families, recited, read and sang, very much to
                                our entertainment. Sister Amelia Calver was the leader, and deserves great credit for
                                the training of those young people, and the pupils showed a good deal of ability. It was
                                held in the meeting room of the brick house, which was very appropriately decorated;
                                nuts, candy and lemonade were served in profusion which made a feast to both the inner
                                and outer senses. I thought what a profitable season we could have if every Society
                                should turn their attention in that direction, in a centennial celebration. Are now
                                engaged threshing. We find the use of the binder quite an advantage in threshing, the
                                bundles being all of the same size, and no straw knots. The threshing machine can be fed
                                very uniformly. Have had some very nice rains, and hope for more. Beautiful weather just
                                now. Happy greetings to all. In kindest love, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="O., D." TEIform="persName"/>D. O.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>WestPittsfieldd, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1891. Deak Editor :—As the present year is nearing its close, perhaps it will not be
                                amiss to recall some of its incidents. Our broad, fertile country has been wonderfully
                                productive in the past season; the cereal crop has been large, and the various kinds of
                                fruits have generally been plentiful. We have, like those in other localities been
                                threatened with a water famine; but the long wished for rain finally appeared, and our
                                fears have somewhat abated, but more rain is needed. Weather is remarkably line for this
                                season of the year. Have had only one light snow fall and that quickly disappeared. The
                                Old World seems to have met with a reverse in regard to food supplies, what may have
                                been the cause of the failure is to us unknown. Some attribute it to their forms of
                                government, but whatever may have been the cause, it is pleasant to contemplate that our
                                country is blest with a surplus and can assist in providing sustenance for the starving
                                millions of Europe. <pb n="16" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> If) THE MANIFESTO. Rightly estimated it has
                                with us been a year of prosperity and benefits. Sickness has prevailed to some extent in
                                our communit ', and a few are still in an enfeebled condition. An occasional mishap has
                                also occurred. A few days since, as Br. Oliver was driving in the city of Pittsfield two
                                teams that were left standing untied became frightened and ran. One of them ran against
                                the carriage in which Oliver was seated damaging the vehicle considerably, and causing
                                him to be thrown over the dash-board upon the ground. He however with remarkable
                                presence of mind retained his hold on the reins and escaped serious injury. Maj the
                                coming New Year be a happy one to all our Dear Friends.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S., J. L." TEIform="persName"/>J. L. S.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1891. A Happy New Tear.—The happiest year of our lives. Let us welcome it with the
                                brave purpose to be more true and virtuous, asking God's blessing on our efforts. May
                                every one of its three hundred and sixty-five days bring to us some joy of service, some
                                added blessing of gratitude from a fellow pilgrim guided heavenward by us. The service
                                we render may seem to us to be small, but if the purpose be in our souls, there will
                                come the blessing. So many souls need Christian help all over this broad land. Let us
                                give of our gospel, strength, joy, affection and peace. Ah! this soul-wealth is just
                                what we can give. We can spend it freely and not impoverish ourselves. May our hearts be
                                full of symjiathy and our hands full of help. And as the new year offers us a time for
                                growing better, let us see to it that our Christian kindness is in- exhaustible, and
                                that we are liberal in using it. 2469 spaces of cream were sold in Nov. A large crop of
                                corn and of good quality. Several buildings are improved by new shingling. The most
                                important feature of poultrygrowing is the financial basis. We do not claim that there
                                are millions in it for a single individual, but it is certain that properly managed,
                                poultry raising is a paying business. To all, who faithfully attend to the needs of
                                their hens, their efforts are crowned with success. A variety of food is necessary to
                                secure eggs. No one ration will furnish all the needed elements. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, D." TEIform="persName"/>D. Orcutt</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ayer, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Ayer, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1891. Deae Editor ;—It has been said, that a hero is one who in an emergency would
                                do that which would be a shame for him not to do. Doing duty at any cost, is heroism. In
                                judging of the acts of our friends let us accord to them the meed of true heroism, if
                                faithful in duty. "Hands at work and heart to God," was the testimony of Mother Ann.
                                This shows the necessity of gaining a gift for manual labor. "Conviction, were it never
                                so excellent, is worthless until it converts itself into conduct."—Carlyle. Let each one
                                improve the talent with which God has blest us. One faithfully improved is more
                                acceptable than five neglected. In the days of Israel, all were not hewers of wood and
                                drawers of water, each had a place to fill to make God's temple complete. Home duties
                                are being done as fast as possible, and we are making preparation for winter.
                                Thanksgiving afternoon was spent in adjusting the premises about home.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., A. D." TEIform="persName"/>A. D. B.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1891. As the year draws near its end, without doubt the "Happy New Tears" will be
                                exchanged thicker and faster than the snow-flakes come down, if all are enjoying the
                                serene, sunny weather we are having in our locality; so we will be satisfied with
                                wishing one big Happy New Year for 1892, for all our brothers and sisters, at home and
                                abroad, knowing just as well as we are permitted to know anything, <pb n="17" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/>
                                THE MANIFESTO. 17 that some of the days will be hallowed with the sunshine of joy, and
                                some shadowed by sorrow; yet, if it all brings a discipline on the unregenerate
                                disposition, and carries us one step nearer the kingdom of heaven (within) what matter
                                is it? We like the "Notes from the Diary of Eldress Nancy Moore," and hope she was a
                                model in this line, so they may be long continued, for two reasons: First, that we may
                                learn how our foremothers disposed of their precious time, and second, that those now
                                forming habits may acquire this one, of keeping a daily record; system, even in small
                                things, gives tone to character. If a diary cannot be procured, make one. "Where there
                                is a will there is always a way." We know of those who made diaries more than one year,
                                of brown paper, and they served a good purpose. If nothing worthy of note occurs through
                                the day, then pencil a good thought or resolution, or quotation from some good author,
                                and it will help to keep the "soul on top" as one little one said in Sunday School. At
                                least this is our experience, and it may be others have similar needs. What are we here
                                for if not to aid each other in the little ways that daily opportunities afford; but few
                                are born for great conquests; the mass must work in the lowly walks of life, and these
                                are what keep the ship moving. A few weeks since we were standing in the door-way of one
                                of the mammoth stores in Boston, waiting for a chance to run the gauntlet and take a
                                horse car, when an elderly lady who was watching the surging crowd of humanity pass,
                                said to us, "Do see them rush on, and God knows the motive of every heart there." She
                                wras evidently a conscientious, thoughtful woman. We jot down this thought, as a
                                profitable one for reflection the coming year. The spirit of God recognizes the motive
                                that actuates each word and deed; no trouble about the outward issues, if the heart is
                                pure and kind. We have not written much about home affairs this time, for we are all
                                doing just the same as we were before, perhaps we should have said, a little better.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., E." TEIform="persName"/>E. B.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury, N. H</head><p TEIform="p">Weather Record, for Nov. 1891.' Highest Temp, during the mo. 44 . Lowest " " " " 5. Mean
                                " " " " 43.2 Total Precipitation Snowfall " " 1.16 in. " 1 in.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Briggs, N. A." TEIform="persName"/>N. A. Briggs.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Alfred, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1891. It is the 13th. of December and no sign of winter yet. This year we can truly
                                sing, '¦December is as pleasant as May." The Brethren say there is no frost in the grass
                                ground. The drouth, which has been a long one, has not ended yet. The water in the
                                springs and wells is unusually low. Harvesting being over we can say no more of the
                                goodness of God in that line, but we will never cease to feel thankful for our many
                                spiritual blessings. It is easy to count up our temporal blessings as shown in our
                                store-houses. But what do our spiritual store-houses contain? Is it not well, at the
                                close of the year, to examine them, and see what the year has done for us? Our Elders
                                often remind us that life is made up of such periods, and unless at the close of the
                                year we can see that we are nearer that angelic condition to which we are aspiring, than
                                when it commenced, it is a lost year to us, and can never be recalled. It shows that we
                                failed to sow the good seed in spring-time, but instead have been cultivating the tares
                                which so readily spring up in the unguarded heart. How sad! how very sad at the close of
                                life to find we have "nothing but leaves" to show for the time given us. On taking the
                                census of our little Society we are pleased to find that we can count as many in the
                                Society as when the <pb n="18" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> 18 THE MANIFESTO. year came in,
                                notwithstanding some changes and the loss of one who has gone to her spirit home. How I
                                wish our houses could be filled with faithful souls, striving to become clean by a daily
                                washing in the blood or life of the Lamb. We would count such a harvest as much more to
                                be thankful for than any mere temporal harvest. Health of Society generally good.
                                Beloved Ministry now with us, comforting the afflicted, blessing the strong and
                                strengthening the weak. "God bless our faithful Leaders who keep alive the altar fires
                                in Zion, the sharp and quickening testimonies of eternal truth," were expressions of our
                                aged father, Hiram Tarbox, in our meeting last evening. Every earnest, honest soul will
                                strive to bless Zion's Leaders. To all our gospel kindred far and near, we extend the
                                kindly greeting, A prosperous New Year. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., F." TEIform="persName"/>F. C.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1891. The pages of the New Year lie before us, every one of which is clean and
                                white. Let the record that will be engraved upon each as we turn them from day to day be
                                as clean and as white. There does not seem to be much that is new going on here now. The
                                Sisters have lately been filling orders of their work for parties in Chicago, Buffalo
                                and Washington D. C. We have also been sending Shaker Apple Sauce to the markets of
                                Lewiston and Portland. Thus far the month of Dec. has in our state been very fine, much
                                warmer than Nov. No snow on the ground and but very little rain. It has been interesting
                                to us to read the notes in the Manifesto describing the weather in different localities.
                                We anticipate ¦ the coming week, the pleasure of having our good Brother James Pinder of
                                Alfred with us. The communion of worthy and tried souls always brings an increase of
                                gospel love. Our dear Sister Mary Ella Douglas has returned from Alfred and is spending
                                the winter months with us for the renewal of her health, which blessing we very much
                                desire in her behalf. We close by wishing all our dear friends a Happy New Year.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., A. S." TEIform="persName"/>A. S. C.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sonyea, New York" TEIform="index"/>Sonyea, N. Y..</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1891. 'Tis time to remember Our notes for December, The last of the year ninety-one.
                                The moments we're noting Away they are floating They scarcely arrive ere they're gone.
                                ''Tis losing anil grasping, Our time so unlasting, The time no mortal can stay; Time's
                                onward flowing, Forever 'tis going, 'Tis here, then away, far away. Fakm work,
                                generally, seems to be advancing as effectually as is consistent with time and
                                circumstances. We meet in the various conditions of life the class who believe in
                                letting their moderation be known to all men, such a type of beings dot this planet from
                                pole to pole. The wells drilled during the past montli are not finished. Well No. 1
                                contains sixty feet of water with an odor of gas every thing but agreeable. Well No. 2,
                                records seventy-five feet of water with gas in abundance, (Groveland must be noted for
                                its natural gas.) Mr. Dixon is in favor of shooting the wells with dynamite cartridg-
                                es, arguing that this method will produce a greater and better flow of water. The wells
                                will not in any case be flowing ones, as Mr. Cook was so sure they would be. It would be
                                well for him to visit his flowing well. Plowing and soil preparing for another year's
                                crops continues. Work of some kind must ever be the motto of the laboring community. One
                                hundred and twenty-five acres are now in readiness for the growing of future fruit, a
                                few more days will find a larger territory of newly turned soil. The summer days of
                                December are just delightful, work indoors and out can be conducted with no concern for
                                cold contracting, the tax on fuel and raiment is much lightened since the wonderful
                                moderation in our winter weather. Perhaps the seasons are becoming mixed, a little of
                                all in each.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="G., G. D." TEIform="persName"/>G. D. G.</byline></div3><pb n="19" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dayton, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>Dayton, Ohio</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1891. Ais" interesting Thanksgiving Service was held at Watervliet, Ohio, on Thurs-
                                day forenoon Nov. 26, which consisted of responsive readings from appropriate portions
                                of Scripture, interspersed with singing of familiar hymns, together with reci- tations,
                                singing, and physical exercises by the children under the personal supervis- ion of
                                their teacher. After congregational singing of the piece, "I know that God is Love," the
                                following recitations were given. "My Pledge." ( Singing, By the Scholars, j "When rum
                                shall cease to reign." Congregational Singing, "I will rise and go to my Father's
                                house." "Jedediah and his vote." By a little girl. { Singing, By the children. ( "Jesus
                                bids us shine." "Watch your lips and ears." "Cuckoo Song." By three girls. j Recitation,
                                By a little boy. I "What shall we do with the Saloon." Exhibition of Physical Exercises.
                                \ Singing, By the Children. ( "The Lord's Prayer. After feeling and appropriate remarks
                                by Elder Stephen Ball and Eldress Hester Frost, the Families separated to their
                                respective homes, all doubtless feeling to exclaim. "O give thanks unto the Lord for he
                                is good, for his mercy endureth forever." '</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M., M. S." TEIform="persName"/>M. S. M.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant Hill, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hill, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1891. The swift flying hours remind us of the passage of time, and now that
                                Thanksgiving has passed, we will soon celebrate Christmas. We had our society meeting at
                                9.30 A. M. which was well attended. After singing a hymn, our Elder, in a brief dis-
                                course, touched upon the day, as it was a National one, and also that we should give
                                thanks every day, and especially at this time; others of the Brethren and Sisters
                                responded to the thanksgiving sentiment, and a good feeling of harmony seemed to pervade
                                throughout. We have indeed been blest in "our basket and store-house," also with good
                                health, and reasonable prosperity; we have good Brethren and Sisters, and should, each
                                one, pray that the same blessing that we are enjoying, may be accorded us in the future,
                                and that we may be able to make each other's path brighter, and their burdens lighter.
                                May we ever be able to say with the poet,— "Teach me to feel another's woe, To hide the
                                faults I see, That mercy, I, to others show That mercy show to me." Our Brethren have
                                secured a fine crop of corn, also an extra crop of Irish potatoes, with plenty of wheat
                                and other cereals. The West Family are actively engaged in the manufacture of "staveless
                                wooden ware," and it is thought it will be a source of revenue. We trust they may find
                                it a successful enterprise, as what is profitable in one part of Zion, should be the
                                interest of all. This will promote union and that is what we desire. Our Sunday School,
                                has about forty-five members, and we trust the seed sown in that part of the vineyard,
                                may spring up and yield a hundred-fold. We keep trying and leave the rest with our
                                Father, and look to the future for results. As the "Yule-tide" approaches we feel glad
                                and rejoice that our lives have been spared, whilst many have been called into eterni-
                                ty. We think too of the angels that sang,—"Peace on earth, Good-will to man." Our hearts
                                overflow with gratitude, that we in our peaceful homes, may worship at the shrine of the
                                meek and lowly Jesus, and follow his example. Let us remember those for whom the
                                Christmas holidays bring no joy, no happiness, and let us at this time bless one another
                                and keep "the prize of the high calling of Jesus Christ" before us. Wishing the
                                Manifesto, and its readers a "Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year," and our prayers for
                                its success as a missionary, we bid you adieu.</p></div3></div2><pb n="20" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Too late" TEIform="index"/>TOO LATE
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline">[Contributed by <persName reg="Collins, S. A." TEIform="persName"/>S. A. Collins.]</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">What silence we keep year after year. With those who are most near to
                                    us ami dear; We live beside each other day by day, And speak of myriad things but
                                    seldom say The full sweet words which lie Justin our reach Beneath the common-place
                                    of common .speech. Then out of sight and out of reach they go, These close familiar
                                    friends who loved us so, And sitting in the shadow they have left Alone with
                                    loneliness, and sure oereft, We think with vain regret of some fond word That once
                                    we might have said and they have heard. For weak and poor, the love that we
                                    expressed Now seems beside the vast, sweetunexpressed And slight, the deeds we did,
                                    to those undone, And small the service spent, to treasures won, And undeserved the
                                    praise for work and deed, That should have overflowed the simple need. This is the
                                    cruel cross of life, to be Full visioned, only -when the ministry Of death has been
                                    fulfilled and in the place Of some dear presence is but empty space; What
                                    recollected services can then Give consolation for the "might have been."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eldress Nancy E. Moore, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>Eldress Nancy E. Moore. No. 2</head><p TEIform="p">South Union, Ky., 1863. My Dear Young Brethren and Sisters ;—It would be well for us to
                            examine, carefully, the foundation upon which we stand. Let us with willing hearts make the
                            sacrifice that those dear friends have made who have gone on before us. Let us be interested
                            in putting our hands at work and our hearts to God, that we may obtain a gospel treasure for
                            our own . souls and be able to provide something for the generations that may come after us.
                            Is there not too much of an inclination to consume all we can make and then draw upon that
                            which has been obtained by our older Brethren and Sisters. Let us not spend too much,
                            precious time in talking over their faults, but rather do the work in our hearts for the
                            justification of our own souls. We shall certainly be rewarded for all we may do for the
                            upbuilding of the habitations of our Zion home. Let us examine ourselves and keep busy in
                            doing good. Do not let a high sense creep in to make us selfish in the management of our
                            beautiful home. We had better subdue this spirit by an honest confession. Instead of finding
                            fault with others, we will imitate their good examples, and be a comfort to the aged in
                            their declining years. We will learn while we have the full power of mind and body to govern
                            our feelings and do better as we advance in years. We should watch that nature in ourselves
                            and subdue a fretful, peevish disposition, by laying the axe at the root of the tree. In
                            this way we may be a comfort and strength to all around us. Then my dear young friends, let
                            us sow thai which we may joyfully reap, with peace and justification, and as- sure our aged
                            friends that they will leave their inheritance to true and worthy heirs, who will be able to
                            appreciate its worth, and after adding thereto, hand it. down to others, as our ancestors
                            have to us. In the spirit of love, Nancy E. Moore. MY THANKFULNESS. I was greatly favored in
                            my childhood, and I wish to manifest my appreciation of the blessings that fell to my lot.
                            The dear friends with whom I lived spared no pains, day or night, to teach me of God's love
                            and care. I am thankful to my natural and to my <pb n="21" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 21
                            spiritual parents. To all my older Bretlnen and Sisters who have given me words of
                            encouragement in my hours of trial. I am now fifty-eight years of age, and am thankful that
                            in childhood I was endowed with a heart that was willing to receive instruction, and that
                            had confidence in my instructors. I am particularly thankful to my guardians that I was
                            early impressed to know that God and his holy angels knew all my thoughts, words and
                            actions. That I could hide nothing from his all-seeing eye, and that the time must come when
                            I should be called upon to render a strict account of all my doings. I do not wish to boast
                            of my goodness, but the spirit of an eye servant or of a hypocrite has always been
                            detestable to me, and as I look back over my life, I am thankful that it has been no worse.
                            I know full well that through carelessness and ignorance I have made many mistakes, but on
                            seeing what I had done, my conscience brought me to an honest confession. I was early taught
                            by my dear friends that I must not wantonly cruelize any living thing. To be prudent and not
                            let any thing be wasted or lost through my carelessness or neglect. That I must not deceive
                            nor take what was not my own. That I must not be a mischief-maker and carry stories from one
                            person to another, nor let hatred, envy or malice ever find room in my heart. That I must do
                            unto others as I would have them do unto me in like circumstances. I was taught that there
                            were three things which were sure to meet every one, Death, Judgment and Eternity. I
                            received the impression that no external goodness would profit me, and I wished to be known
                            as I write, that I might give an account of the deeds done in the body. Now, as I have given
                            heed to these good impressions, I have enjoyed true peace and heavenly comfort, through my
                            whole life. (to be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Philadelphia, 1891" TEIform="index"/>Philadelphia, 1891</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Eldkess Marion:—We feel thankful for this opportunity to answer your kind letter. We
                            feel doubly thankful to realize and sense the ever-progressing and increasing power, from
                            that everflowing fountain, that quenches the thirst, and feeds the famishing soul, in this
                            life of trials and tribulations. It enables us from true thankful hearts to say, Father and
                            Mother, we are thankful for these "blessings, and for the power of feeling, seeing and
                            testing, that we be not deceived by those in the body or out; and thus made able to draw
                            from that never failing fountain that keeps our souls aglow in love and duty and spiritual
                            light; that guides Mother's children in this life, and points to the marvelous increase and
                            progressive power which unfolds beauties for time and eternity. Dear Sister, knowing as we
                            do your great interest with us in striving to spread our precious Gospel, whether we live to
                            reap the fruit of our labors in this life it matters not to us, we ever feel the love and
                            blessing of the dear fathers and mothers of our precious Zion Home. We have been over the
                            river to a place called Pensaukin to fix the time for holding meetings and the lady said,
                            The people are anxious to hear the gospel. She also called in her minister to converse with
                            us, and he was deeply impressed with the truth, and drank in every word. He said, "Some
                            fourteen years ago while passing through Mt. Lebanon one Sabbath, we stopped to <pb n="22" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> 22 THE MANIFESTO. rest our horses awhile, and we saw the meeting of the
                            Shakers, but not one Shaker even turned his head to look at us, but all seemed so earnest,
                            that we thought they must be the people of God. We heard some of the words spoken, and felt
                            the power of the spirit at the time, and have loved them ever since." It was Elder Frederic
                            who was speaking, and when we gave him his name he was delighted. Brother William explained
                            to him what he heard. He seemed surprised beyond measure and said he would attend our
                            meeting to hear more about the "Inner Court." A friend said to us last Sabbath, "You have a
                            living, present power that we do not have and I must come to you for it." May we not see
                            clearly that God has a spiritual people on the earth. The way of the true cross-bearer is
                            the road to salvation from sin, and in no other way. Our frequent communications to each
                            other of the things given to us, helps the strong and strengthens the weak and adds fuel to
                            the flame of love in the hearts of Brethren and Sisters, in our Zion Home, to those who care
                            not for the things of the world, but for the constant unfolding of the gospel of Christ that
                            is willing to be led withersoever He wills. We can write only a little at a time, but are
                            thankful for that. If we are hindered, O praise the Lord, our love goes in advance. We know
                            that you are here in spirit for we feel, sense and see you. We held our meeting and had a
                            glorious time. People are anxious to hear the gospel. We will tell you more in our next. We
                            send you our kindest love. Tour Sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Jackson, Rebecca" TEIform="persName"/>Rebecca Jackson</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hail the new year" TEIform="index"/>Hail the new year</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Harding, Florina" TEIform="persName"/>Florina Harding</byline><p TEIform="p">O king ye bells! ye merry bells, Thy harmony we love full well; We know the joy thy music
                            tells, And welcomes in the glad New Year. O ring ye bells of love and cheer, Let roll thy
                            echoes far and near; O welcome, welcome, welcome here The grand, the bright and glad New
                            Year. O chime ye bells, O chime again,— Until we learn thy joyous strain; Let peace on
                            earth, and union reign Throughout the happy, coming year. We'll strive the seed of good to
                            sow,— The way of life, the erring show; Thus friendship's links will stronger grow,
                            Throughout the glad and bright New Year. The errors that have dimmed the past, We'll from
                            our vision ever cast, And with a courage that Will last, We'll toil throughout the coming
                            year. ^Redemption's hill though steep to climb, We'll strive to reach while here in time;
                            And step by step those heights sublime, We'll gain some bright, some happy year. As tender
                            buds in spring expand, Well nurtured by a Father's hand; So will our souls in grace expand,
                            And grow throughout the happy year. Then ring ye merry, merry bells, Thy harmony we love
                            full well; Still louder let thy music swell, And welcome in the bright, New Year. West
                            Pittsfield, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><byline TEIform="byline">[Contributed by <persName reg="Shepard, Harriet" TEIform="persName"/>Harriet Shepard.]</byline><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gentle guide" TEIform="index"/>A GENTLE GUIDE
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> A heart by Jesus gentle made and meek, Has power to rule his
                                    people few and weak, Won all the world by true love's gentle might, By words said
                                    tenderly, and deeds of light; A gentle voice makes obedience sweet. . A happy
                                    captive, all his actions prove The power there is in gentleness and love. . . "Love
                                    one another," try the gentle way; Think not rough words and savage blows pre'Tis not
                                    the waterspout, the raging hail, [vail The thunder's bellow, nor the lightning's
                                    sheen 'Tis the soft shower that makes the valley green, When thou art tempted
                                    roughly to respond To him who hates thee, choose some phrases fond, And breathe them
                                    out in accents kind and low So shalt thou find a friend in him who was your foe.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Heavenly gifts descend like showers" TEIform="index"/>Heavenly gifts descend like showers
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Heavenly gifts descend like showers.</p></div2><pb n="23" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Landing" TEIform="index"/>THE "LANDING."</head><p TEIform="p">"Ye are my friends, if ye do whatsoever I command you."—John, xv., 14. Canterbury, N. H.
                            Andante. I shall meet the brave souls at the "Landing," When shore unto shore shall respond;
                            Where kindred and guardians are joyful, To widen the spiritual bond. I shall meet them as
                            friends of the Saviour, Who vict'ry in earth-life have found; Where he triumphed they also
                            had conquest— Together they reign, and are crowned.</p></div2><pb n="24" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books &amp; Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of hygeio-therapy" TEIform="index"/>
                                Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                Hall's Journal of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy. Dec. Contents. Treatment of the Sick; Chronicles of Ruth;
                                Dress Reform; Anti-Vaccination; Physical Culture, etc., etc. Dr. T. V. Gifford &amp;
                                Co., Kokomo, Ind. In the December Phrenological we find Sir Edwin Arnold on the first
                                page. A very well written article on Ideality and Imitation comes from a careful
                                thinker. How the old Chaldeans buried themselves is illustrated freely and suggests an
                                improvement on the common practice among us moderns. Baron Hirsch, the millionaire
                                philanthropist, is sketched very appropriately when so much is heard of Jew persecution.
                                The editor evidently thinks it is time that Jerusalem was reoccupied by the sons of
                                Israel. A very full and interesting report of the late Banquet of the Phrenological
                                Institute Alumni occupies a dozen or more pages. This will be appreciated highly by the
                                regular reader. As it includes addresses by the Rev. Dr. Deems, Dr. H. C. Houghton, Mr.
                                G. G. Rockwood and several others. The services that were rendered to phrenological
                                science by the late Andrew Boardman, well known as a jurist in New York are detailed
                                entertainingly. Dr. Boardman was a man who should not be forgotten soon. The departments
                                of Health and Child Culture are rilled with good things, and so also are Editorial,
                                Correspondents and Book Sections. The clqsing number of the year, is uncommonly large
                                and packed with such interesting substance that every subscriber will doubtless thipk or
                                say more emphatically than ever "Must have the Phrenological for another year." It is
                                published at a price placing it within the reach of all, only $1.50 a year or 15 cents a
                                number. Now is the time to subscribe. Address the publishers, Fowler and Wells, 777
                                Broadway, New York. DICKENS'S DAUGHTER. The Great Novelist's Favorite "Mamie" to write
                                of Her Father, Pretty "Mamie" Dickens was already considered by those who knew Charles
                                Dickens best to be his favorite daughter. To none of his children, perhaps, was Dickens
                                more affectionately attached, and the "Pet daughter" saw much of her father under all
                                circumstances. When even the dogs were chased out of the novelist's study, Mamie was
                                allowed to stay. The daughter is now a full-grown woman, living quietly just outside of
                                London. For the first time since her father's death, Miss Dickens has been persuaded to
                                write of him whom she knew so well. During 1802 there will be published in The Ladies'
                                Home Journal, of Philadelphia, a series of articles by Miss Dickens under the attractive
                                title of "My Father as I Recall Him." Fortunately for the thou- sands who will read what
                                she writes in this series, Miss Dickens has a retentive memory, and she made copious
                                notes during her father's lifetime. She will tell in this series everything she
                                remembers of her father; how he educated his children; his family life and his personal
                                habits; how he wrote his famous books; his love of flowers and animals; how Christmas
                                was spent in the Dickens household; how the novelist played with his children; the
                                famous people who came to the Dickens home, and his last years and closing days. No
                                articles ever published have in them so much promise of telling the world things which
                                it has never known of Dickens, and Miss Dickens's story of her father's life will be
                                eagerly looked for in thousands of homes where the name of Dickens is like a household
                                word. Hall's Journal of Health. Dec. Contents; Habits of Eating; The waste of the
                                Household; Oatmeal as a Food; Overstrung Nerves; Food for Dyspeptics; Celery; The
                                Medicinal value of Onions; An Insect worth Millions; A Hint on Economy; Cleaning Windows
                                and Paint; Contagious Diseases; Care of Clothing, etc.,. etc. Office 34 WTest 59th St.
                                New York.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Burgess, Harriet" TEIform="index"/>Harriet Burgess
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Burgess, Harriet" TEIform="persName">Harriet Burgess</persName>, at Second Family, West
                                Pittsfield, Mass. Nov. 21, 1891. Age 80 yrs. 2 mo. and 6 days. Sister Harriet came into
                                the Society when fourteen years of age. In the soft twilight of morning Her freed spirit
                                passed away To behold the glorious dawning Of a bright, eternal day. J. L. S.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hart, Harriet P." TEIform="index"/>Harriet P. Hart
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Hart, Harriet P." TEIform="persName">Harriet P. Hart</persName>, at Harvard, Mass. Nov. 24,
                                1891. Age 57 yrs. 10 mo. and 27 days. Sister Harriet was called our artist Sister, and
                                has lived in the Community for three years. She was an educated nurse and since being
                                with us has given her life to the interests of our religious home. L. E. G.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Advertisements" TEIform="index"/>[Advertisements]</head><p TEIform="p">[Advertisements deleted.]</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>