<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm1701" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">17</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18870101" TEIform="date">January 1887</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="17" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                    <pb n="t.p." id="p1"/>
                     <p>JANUARY. THE MANIFESTO. Published by the United Societies, " Every plant which my heavenly Father hath not planted
                        shall be rooted up."—Matt. XV, 13. SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H. 1887. </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="none">
                        <p>CONTENTS. The Gospel Testimony, Christianity, Sure Promise. .... Letter from Eldress II. B. " " D. Fraser.
                            Hindering, From Home, Peace, T'-ibute of Love to Sister Mary Kelley, Sabbath, Question by Eldress A. D. Letter
                            from Ernest Pick, Notes.—The Xew Year, Cure of Dyspepsia, The Hour and the Year, Education, Christian Resolve,
                            Speak no Evil of the Absent, Music :—Keep Away, The Parson's Text, Letter, Daniel Orcutt, Agnus Dei,
                            Washington's Code of Manners, Beautiful Words, Books and Papers, This Life is what we make it. " Little Hinges,"
                            Deaths, ....1 3 7 8 10 11 12 13 15 16 17 18 19 20 22 24</p>
                    </div2>
                    --><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Advertisements" TEIform="index"/>[Advertisements]</head><p TEIform="p">[Advertisements deleted.]</p></div2><pb n="1" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the Elders, William Lee and James Whittaker, no. 10" TEIform="index"/>The Gospel Testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the Elders, William Lee and James Whittaker.
                            No. 10</head><byline TEIform="byline">Published expressly for the several Communities of Believers in IS 16. Re-written
                                by<persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>Henry C. Blinn</byline><p TEIform="p">Mother Ann and the Elders visit Petersham, Mass. In December, 1781, Mother Ann and the Elders
                            made a journey to Petersham, which is forty miles west from Harvard. It was along and
                            wearisome journey and quite late in the evening when they reached the residence of Thomas
                            Hammond. The whole family were anxiously watching in expectation of their arrival. "It is
                            good to watch,'' said Mother, " and you should always watch and always pray. " The next day
                            being the Sabbath a large company of people came to attend the meeting. Elder James
                            Whittaker preached the gospel of Jesus Christ from these words : " Cleanse your hands ye
                            sinners, and purify your hearts ye double minded : be afflicted and mourn and weep." James
                            iv., 8, 9. He urged the necessity of confessing, forsaking and repenting of all sin. '•What
                            is cleansing the hands," said he, ''but the confession of sin? and what is purifying the
                            heart, but forsaking them? And what is being afflicted and mourning and weeping but
                            repenting of sin?" His discourse continued nearly two hours. This was the first visit that
                            the Believers had made to the town of Petersham, and the people, generally, manifested a
                            desire to see and hear for themselves. As all conducted with civility they were allowed the
                            full liberty of the meeting. At the Monday evening service a large number of well-ordered,
                            civil people attended, and also a company of lewd fellows who styled themselves the. '•Black
                            Guard Committee." Elder James gave notice that all who had come with an honest desire to
                            obtain information, might walk into an adjoining room. Quite a number accepted the
                            invitation and gave due respect to the occasion. The above n^med Committee, however,
                            remained in the rear, as they had come, evidently, for no good purpose. Elder James opened
                            the Bible and read a selection, and then began to speak. At this same lime the Committee
                            began to crowd into the room and were gradually moving toward the place where Mother Ann and
                            some of the Sisters were seated. As the at<pb n="2" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. tention of the
                            assembly was so closely directed to the preacher, this movement of the mob had not attracted
                            much notice. Instantly the cry was heard, "knock out the lights." In a moment the lights
                            were extinguished except the one used by Elder James. The mob immediate- ly forced a passage
                            from the door to that part of the room occupied by the Sisters. Three ruffianly characters,
                            having their faces painted black, rushed forward and seized Mother Ann, and attempted to
                            drag her from the room. In this attempt, however, they were foiled by the sudden appearance
                            upon the scene of several able sisters, who succeeded in driving these white and black
                            savages from the house. After a few closing words from Elder James, the meeting was
                            dismissed and the people passed quietly and peacefully from the place. The mob had left the
                            premises, and all danger, apparently, was at an end. Some entertained fears that tha mob
                            would return. The Believers that lived in the neighborhood also returned to their homes,
                            leaving only a small company to remain in the house. As the family wTere retiring to rest,
                            the house was again assaulted by some thirty persons belonging to the "Black Guard
                            Committee." The doors were burst open and suddenly the house, was filled with the uproar of
                            this cruel and wicked horde. David Hammond was knocked down and cruelly beaten. His wife,
                            Mary, was subjected to the same inhuman treatment. Elder James was so abu- sively beaten,
                            that for a time, he w^as not expected to live. Several other persons suffered more or less
                            abuse. As their object was to seize Mother Ann, they began a search through the premises.
                            Not being able to obtain lamps and candles for this purpose, the mob caught burning sticks
                            from the fire to be used as torches, and hurried through the house. They broke into the
                            private chamber where Mother Ann had retired, and seizing her by force, inhumanly dragged
                            her from the house. With as little care as they Avould exercise over a beast, they threw her
                            into a sleigh and drove away from the place. The conduct of this company of men, in acts of
                            inhumanity and of indecency were too disgraceful to comment upon. In this situation, in
                            December, a night cold and stormy, Mother Ann was obliged to ride a distance of three miles
                            to Peckham's tavern. Elder William Lee and David Hammond folloAved the company, but were
                            severely beaten witli blows from their whips. The Brethren remonstrated with Peckham, who
                            had hired these brutal men, against the ungodliness and cruelty of their behavior. Being
                            ashamed of their conduct and fearful of the consequences, for a violation of the law, the
                            men now promised to release Mother Ann upon condition that David Hammond would sign an
                            obligation not to pi'osecute them for what they had done. On account of the safety of Mother
                            Ann he reluctantly yielded to their demands, and left them to answer at the bar of divine
                            Justice for a crime, for which they were unwilling to appear before an earthly tribunal.
                            Mother Ann was accordingly released and in company with the Brethren, taken back to the
                            residence of David Hammond, by the same men that carried her away. On her arrival at the
                            house she sang for joy at the thought of 2 <pb n="3" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. her
                            restoration. The "Black Guard" had now white faces, and were ashamed of their conduct, and
                            confessed that Mother Ann had been shamefully abused. They admitted that they were sorry for
                            the deeds done and desired her forgiveness. Mother Ann replied, "I can freely forgive you,
                            and I pray God to forgive you." After their departure, Mother Ann related the wicked abuse
                            to which she was subjected by these merciless men. "I thought," said she, "that they would
                            take my life, as they dragged me from the house and threw me into the sleigh. But I was
                            kindly treated at the house where they carried me. The woman in charge offered me some drink
                            and a place in a comfortable room. One of the men that carried me away gave me a kerchief to
                            throw over my head, and another loaned me a garment to wear home." The forgiving spirit in
                            Mother Ann was ready to acknowledge any kindness even if found in her worst enemies. Elder
                            James who had been so severely beaten, had partially recovered, and in referring to the act,
                            said he could pray for them and kneeling, said, "Father, forgive them, tor they know not
                            what they do." Some of this abusive company who were supposed to be very respectable members
                            of a respectable Christian society, were found to be the instigators and leaders of this
                            cruel mob. Sanders the deacon of a Presbyterian church, and Peckham, the sheriff of the
                            county, with John llawksy were the persecutors of Mother Ann. The people of Petersham seemed
                            to be very much enraged. There Avas nothing too bad for professor or profane to say or do
                            against the Believers in general and especially against Mother Ann in particular. The priest
                            in his pulpit was as active in his accusations and as slanderous in his speech as were those
                            Avho made no profession of religion. The general cry Avas, "Witchcraft and delusion. "</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christianity, 'the end of the world,' and how it is so" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIANITY, "The
                            End of the World, " and how it is so.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">A very" wide-spread, and almost universal effort prevails among Christian professors,
                            so-called, to harmonize the Christian with the worldly life ! The practical consequence is,
                            the corruption^' and, in a large majority of instances, the utter spoliation,
                            characteristically considered, of the Christianity of its professors, who thus, mere
                            nominally, profess it I yhe disciples asked Jesus, "What shall be the sign of thy coming,"
                            (the second coming of the Christ spirit and dispensation) "and of the end of the world."
                            What is to be understood by the " end of the world" here spoken of? Jesus thus explains,
                            "The harvest is the end of the Avorld; and the reapers are the angels." In the parable of
                            the tares, Jesus declared, " the field is the Avorld. As the tares are gathered and burned
                            in the fire, so shall it be in the end of the world. The Son of Man shall send forth his
                            angels, and shall gather out of his kingdom all things that offend, and them Avhich do in-
                            iquity." Thus Jesus made the end of the Avorld synonymous and synchronous with the
                            purification of his kingdom 3 <pb n="4" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. with the judgment work ;
                            and he said, "The Father judgeth no man, but hath committed all judgment unto the son." Jno.
                            v., 22. And again, "For judgment I am come into this world" Thus Jesus demonstrated that the
                            "end of the world" is to be made by the labors of each individual Christian, in himself: for
                            the true Christian is one who lives as Jesus set forth the work of his disciples. "If any
                            man would be my disciple let him deny himself, take up his daily cross and follow me." Yet,
                            speaking of his personal will and work, aside from his baptismal commission, Jesus said, "I
                            can of mine own self, do nothing." " As I hear I judge, and my judgment is just, because I
                            seek not mine own will, but the will of the Father which hath sent me." Jno. v., 30. "He
                            that rejecteth me and receivetli not my words, hath one that judgeth him— the
                            Word"—testimony "that I have spoken, the same shall judge him at the last day." Jno. xii.,
                            48. Here Je,sus forestalled the theological idea of Godship ia his person, abstractly
                            considered, and placed the vice-gerency in his agency, yet only as clothed with his heavenly
                            Father's spirit, and the revelation of God through him. Here we have an example of the end
                            of the world in Jesus, to all intents and purposes, taking all his selfish life. Jesus still
                            further shows upon whom and how the end of the world is to come, thus, "Verily I say unto
                            you there is no man that has left house, or brethren, or sisters, or father, or mother, or
                            wife, or children, or lands, for my sake and the gospel's, but he shall receive an hundred
                            fold, now, in this time, houses, and brethren, and sisters, find mothers, and children, and
                            lands, with persecutions, and in the wrorld to come, eternal life." Mark xxix., 30. Thus,
                            the leaving of these selfish treasures, was bringing the end of the world to all these
                            self-denying followers, and here we have a plain declaration that the end of the world was
                            synonymous and synchronous with Christ's second coming, but not the end of time with earth's
                            inhabitants, nor yet of the earth's existence, speculative religionists to the contrary,
                            notwithstanding; for the hundred fold treasures above promised were to be enjoyed "in this
                            time" by those in this world, who had brought " the end of the world on their own lives."
                            Thus again is demonstrated that "the end of the world" is synonymous and synchronous with
                            the harvest, and the "harvest" is the work of judgment, and thirf is, the gathering out the
                            tares—men's sins—the violation of God's laws, from the field—the world— in all who should be
                            harvested into Christ's kingdom. In other words, bringing the end of the world upon all true
                            and genuine Christians. This brings us to the question,—What is the world which should be
                            brought to an end? The apostle John answers this question thus,—" For all that is in the
                            world, the lusts of the flesh, and the lust of the eyes, and the pride of life, is not of
                            the Father, but is of the world ; and the world passeth away,"—cometh to an end. 1 Jno. ii.,
                            16, 17. "My kingdom is not of this world, else would my servants fight" said Jesus ; thus,
                            war is of the world and must cease, with all who come to the end of the world—all true
                            Christians. But, what a spectacle we now behold, the fact of so-called Christian nations,
                            sending forth millions of so-called 4 <pb n="5" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. Christians to kill
                            each other ; and the nations vieing with each other in inventive skill to produce the most
                            deadly weapons of warfare. " But what most showed the vanky of life, Was to behold the
                            nations all on fire, In cruel broils engaged, and deadly strife, Most Christian (?) Kings
                            inflamed by black [desire! With honorable (?) ruffians in their hire, Cause war to rage, and
                            blood around to pour. Of this sad work, when each begins to tire, They set them down just
                            where they were [before, Till, for new scenes of woe, peace shall their [force restore.
                            "—Thompson. bhakespere illustrates, ironically, the inconsistency of carnal warfare
                            practiced by persons calling themselves Christians, thus,—"The Priest War- rior." " It
                            better showed with you, When, that your flock, assembled by the bell, Encircled you, to
                            hear, with reverence, Your exposition on the Holy Text, Than now, to see you here,- an iron
                            man, Cheering a rout of rebels with your drum, Turning the Word to Sword, and Life to
                            [Death. " Burke truly said, "War suspends the rules of moral obligation ; and what is long
                            suspended, is in danger of being totally abrogated. " Much more does war exterminate the
                            Christian principle of love ; and Jesus said, "By this shall all men know that ye are my
                            disciples, if ye love one another. " War sets at naught even the Mosaic Law, "Thou shalt
                            love thy neighbor as thyself." Even Luther, in his day, declared that " the principles of
                            Christianity forbade acts of violence, and desired that neither party in a war, should be
                            called Christians." Napoleon recognized the importance of a depraved character, for a good
                            soldier. He allowed no Chaplain in his army, and was accustomed to say, "the worse the man,
                            the better the soldier ; and if the soldiers are not corrupt, they should be made so." But,
                            nations calling themselves Christians, the followers of "the Prince of Peace" raise and
                            equip hundreds of thousands of men for war; and the blood of untold millions slain in
                            battle, and by the horrible tortures of the inquisition, or by persecution's wand through
                            persons calling themselves Christians, crieth unto God from the ground, and standeth in the
                            high courts of Heaven, as witness against a spurious Christianity. Professed Believers in
                            Christian precepts, can read in their Testaments with awe and veneration. "Whence come wars
                            and fightings among you ? Come they not hence, even of your lusts that war in your members.
                            " " Ye adulterers and adulteresses," (of Christianity) " know ye not that the friendship of
                            the world is enmity with God; whoever, therefore, would be a friend of the world, is the
                            enemy of God," Yea, Christian professors can quietly read these Christian precepts, but heed
                            them not, and be justly the subjects of censure by the Christian testimony of the same
                            Apostle, thus. "But be ye doers of the word, and not hearers only, de- ceiving your own
                            selves; for, if any man be a hearer of the word and not a doer, he is like unto a man
                            beholding his natural face in a glass ; for he beholdeth himself, and goeth his way, and
                            straightway forgetteth what manner of man he was. " But, alas, alas ! The Christian
                            admonition in this epistle of the genuine Christian, the Apostle James is called by a great
                            professional reformer of socalled Christian society "An Epistle of 5 <pb n="6" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. Straw!'' But, with the tongue of an angel from heaven, this blessed Apostle of
                            Christ, in this epistle, sIioavs that true Christianity is the end of the world to every
                            true follower of Christ, verifying the testimony of Jesus Christ to his true followers, "Ye
                            are not of the world, for I have chosen you out of the world, therefore the world hateth
                            you." Think of it, friends of progress, between 4 and 500,000,000, of people calling
                            themselves Christians—followers of the Prince of Peace—but holding regular standing armies
                            for war, amounting to 3,908,925 soldiers, with numbers on a war footing amounting to 18,
                            414,525 men, at a cost of $746,448, 600 annually ! Add to all this for Avar, to destroy
                            men's lives, and yet more spent in dissipation in the use of beers, liquors, tobacco
                            &amp;c, than would be requisite for food, clothing, shelter, and needful protection,
                            were all so-called Christians really such, in truth. When Ave survey the status of the so-
                            called Christian world as a mass, in its present state of demoralization, degradation,
                            selfishness, corruption, lust, confusion and strife, instead of that peace Avhich is the
                            genuine fruit of Christianity, after nearly two thousand years of the Christian profession,
                            it would seem to tire out the patience of the saints, in Avaiting for the kingdom of God on
                            earth. What would be thought of a, physician, Avho, having the benefit of two thousand years
                            of the experience of physicians, Avas not able to save one single life and make it whole? Or
                            of a chemist avIio had the benefits of the experimental knowledge of two thousand years of
                            scientific research, but was not yet able to make a simple analysis so as to clearly
                            distinguish substances of elements as opposite as the elements of ihe world, and those of a
                            Christian character? And yet, professors of the chemistry of Christianity, elements that,
                            duly applied, will purify the character from every kind of dross, go on, ostensibly trying
                            to live the Christian life, but pursuing the course of the world, and mixing with their
                            religious professions, all the elements of the A'anity, folly, selfishness, and Avickedness
                            of the Avorld ! No Avonder the name "Christian" is a by-Avord of reproach among many of the
                            heathen, Avhose homes have been spoliated, Avhose lands have been seized, Avhose families
                            have been ruined and characters corrupted by so-called Chris- tians ! No Avonder that a
                            so-called Christian Priesthood, teaching Avith the Bible in one hand, and a sword in the
                            other, a purchased indulgence to sin in the pocket, with a liquor or prostitution license on
                            the lips, should be scouted as the butt of contempt by the loAver classes ; so that to
                            express extreme disgust of a vile character, the phrase, "Viler than a priest" should be
                            coined and used in England. With all of the professed reverence of many Christian professors
                            for the Bible, the single epistle of the Apostle James, puts to shame almost the Avhole
                            so-called Christian Avorld, and anchors her sails under the ban of condemnation. While the
                            life of our exemplar Jesus—the King of the Heavenly Order—the true Christian church, is a
                            clear demonstration of the "end of the world" and his declaration seals the same
                            demonstration as truth. "The Prince of this Avorld cometh, and findeth nothing in me. " Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is a fraud to conceal a fraud" TEIform="index"/>It is a fraud to conceal a fraud
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is a fraud to conceal a fraud.</p></div2><pb n="7" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sure promise" TEIform="index"/>SURE PROMISE</head><p TEIform="p">My soul immortal cannot live On gross material things, And all the wealth this Avorld can
                            give, No lasting'comfort brings; Then let me labor for that meat Which ever will endure ;
                            That food which saints and angels eat, That hidden manna pure. O Father give me daily bread,
                            And wine that's ever new ; No famine then I need to dread, Or what my foes can do. While
                            anxious cares of earthly toys, So many millions wound, My spirit feasts on inward joys And
                            pities those around. The earth is promised to the meek, Eternal life beside, If heaven's
                            kingdom they would seek, Their Father will provide, lie feeds the ravens when they cry,— lie
                            clothes the smiling mead, And will he not my wants supply AVith every thing I need. O then
                            let nothing rob my soul, Nor any doubts prevail; For while eternal ages roll, His goodness
                            shall not fail. 'I need but little here below, Have little time to learn ; Then O that world
                            to which I go, Shall be my great concern. Pleasant Hill, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York, August 1886" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, Albany Co., N. Y. Aug. 1886</head><p TEIform="p">My Dear Sistkii L.— Your beautiful letter came duly to hand, for which accept many thanks. I
                            count it a great privilege, that I have enjoyed, to see so many dear gospel relations, and
                            feel their devotion to this all important, soul elevating work. Not only are they working
                            out their own salvation, but are holding out the beacon lijrht to others. This is a most
                            commendable feature of the travel of the sisterhood, in our Zion home. Having found the
                            pearl of priceless value, and obtained it by a full surrender, and giving up of all that
                            belongs to a selfish nature, we are thus enabled to work for humanity, and secure for
                            ourselves that blessed benediction, " well done, good and faithful servant." While so many
                            may admire our order of life, and the fruits of the holy spirit, but few are willing to
                            unite in the song of redemption, still, we have our duty to perform, in sowing the good
                            seed. Let us sow beside all waters, sowearly, sow late and sow in all fields, even if the
                            pleasures of the world should choke the good seed. Some germ may remain, and spring up and
                            bear fruit, after the harvest of thistles and weeds, have somewhat passed away. Some persons
                            may be so spiritually blind that they are not able to see how much better it is to give the
                            first ripe fruits of their souls to God, and devote the strength of their days to his
                            service, but such rather wait till self is served and no sacrifice make in their offering to
                            God. Let us remember our covenant, and keep it unbroken, and not present to the Lord a
                            broken covenant, an offering He cannot accept. My covenant of fall consecration shall be
                            made strong with every faithful soul, throughout our many beautiful homes. For the many
                            tokens of love and respect, bestowed upon the order, of which your humble servant, largely
                            shared, we extend our heart felt thanks. All of those good gifts are placed on the altar, as
                            an offering to the Lord. In our prayers we ask that all may have their days of usefulness
                            and 7 <pb n="8" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. strength, lengthened, and that the sun of
                            righteousness may shine brightly upon them through their pilgrimage here lelow. Your Sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bullard, Harriet" TEIform="persName"/>Harriet Bullard</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Prof. Richard T. Ely, Respected Friend ;¦—Your work, *' The Labor Movement" came duly. I have
                            the pleasure to thank you for the book, and to acknowledge our indebtedness for your many
                            labors of love. Your work associates you with the noblest spirits of these eventful times.
                            The violence of the first French Revolution was an outburst against repression. To prevent
                            destructive outbursts of the forces of the stupendous movement, or rather revolution now in
                            progress, is the object of your labors. Hence, witli gladness we hail the publication of
                            "The Labor Movement." To acknowledge the wrongs that do exist, and say they ought to be
                            righted, Is to assure to a certain extent, that the procedure of the revolution will be
                            peaceful. Again, the existence of our institutions giving practicability m a quiet way, to
                            socialistic speculations has also a peaceful influence. It is interesting to notice the
                            facts, that socialistic ideas were interwoven with the Jewish economy every seventh year,
                            the products of the vineyards, the olive yards, and of the fields, became common property.
                            And that the first manifestations of Christiau life were socialistic. The British House of
                            Peers, is a repressive institution. A certain amount of blind stupidity on their part would
                            endanger the public peace. In these States, to maintain peace, and give perpetuity to their
                            institutions, an early practical recognition "That all men are not only .equal before God,
                            before each other, and before the Law, but that all men and women shall have equal access to
                            all the elements of subsistence." This, with some financial limitations, would go a great
                            way towards solving all of our badly snarled social problems. The weakness of this Republic
                            lies in the fact, that she has not yet reached to the opening of said access—she has not yet
                            reached to giving practicability to her "Declaration of Independence." Hence she has social
                            troubles, as have other unfinished forms of political life. All men and women having said
                            access, class distinctions would disappear, and also the systems of education supporting
                            such distinctions. Under the present forms of education, we have educated men in, and out of
                            Penitentiaries, who are villians of size. The largest, at large, absorbing Legislatures,
                            ruling over men, and assuming to call themselves society. Modern education is based on the
                            expansion of the intellect, and character is not even incidental. Such being the case, would
                            it not be well, to accept the suggestion, " That Primary schools, Universities, and kindred
                            institutions, take a change of base—That the formation of character, and not the cramming of
                            the intellect, shall be the prime endeavor. Man being dual in his emotional forces, as
                            either prevail, so is the man, so is the woman, animal or divine. The intellect, is but the
                            servant of these forces. Hence it is a mistake to neglect the emotional impulses, they being
                            the 8 <pb n="9" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 9 chief factors in the formation of char- acter.
                            This state of things characterized the heathen of old, as it does to-day most prominently.
                            The civilizations of old became putrid, and passed away iD decomposition in the height of
                            intellectual unfoldmetvts. One of the remains of Roman civilization, is the beggared bandit
                            populace of Italy. To seek to improve, or to revise the present system of education, would
                            show a lack of comprehension. To upset the whole fabric, remove its foundations, abrogate
                            its procedure, and nullify effects ; is what is wanted. The origin of our educational system
                            is from that of heathen Greece and Rome. The people of these states, when most enlightened,
                            were the most debauched. The unrestrained gratification of animal desires, was the
                            fulfillment of Pagan ideals. Their hygiene, was without law. Their morals, conventional
                            heathenism. In both particulars, the Christian of to-day, is a transcript, only more
                            ignoble. If society expects educational institutions to turn out just, kindly, and
                            serviceable men and women ; it must furnish a suitable foundation. The elements of
                            subsistence must be open to all. All kinds of legalized robberies must cease, and financial
                            iniquities be done away with. They have created a most insidious form of human vassalage. "
                            That which is the most real, is the unseen. " Ourb is a world of effects— of unfoldments.
                            The unseen, is the world of causes, of conception, of organization, of design. Unless there
                            are forces, powers, sufficiently strong and intelligent to intro- duce and maintain higher
                            civilizations than now is, our efforts will be failures, and our aspirations after higher
                            forms of social life will be unavailing. Suppose we construct history by, and with the
                            events of the past three hundred and sixty years. The rapid suc- cession of important
                            events, spiritual and material; the order of their introduction, and results, during that
                            time, are truly marvelous. First, we have the Reformation, or rather " the Great Protest."
                            Then we have the Puritan. In due time, the Quaker ; and by and by, the Shaker. Well, what
                            has the Puritan done? He earned his title—He lived a purer life than those around him, and
                            firmly withstood cruel repression. Took possession of a new world and filled it with almost
                            magical devices to facilitate production, and lessen toil. He has opened widely all the
                            avenues of thought; and has secured to all, freedom to worship God in unison with their
                            highest ideals. And also, freedom to bring forth forms of social life, whether from
                            spiritual impressions or from philosophic thought. To his home the op- pressed of all
                            nations wend their weary steps. From the moors and bogs, from the Rhine and the Volga, they
                            come. The spirit of the Puritan from ocean to ocean, presides over his vast domain, and
                            gives a oneness to his mixed multitudes. The influence of his spirit is world-wide, to
                            liberalize governments, and to elevate the lowly. What has the Quaker done ? He would not
                            take off his hat to noble, prince, or king. That was the "First Declara- tion—All men are
                            equal before God. " He was the first to free the slave. The first to move in '' the
                            Temperance cause." He was the first in modern times to practice Non-resistance—To raise the
                            standard of "Peace on earth, good will <pb n="10" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 10 THE MANIFESTO. to all. " He
                            was the first to exclude from his sphere of social life want and crime. He was a divine
                            force among men, to prepare the way for the advent of the divine man and woman—the Shaker.
                            The supernatural gifts of the early Friends, were remarkable. Some of their predictions were
                            as striking, and as completely fulfilled as any on record. He is crowned with peaceful
                            victories. The Shaker, what has he done ? The form of social life he maintains is.a complete
                            and ample fulfillment of the "•Lord's Prayer;" he maintains, that there is a state of
                            probation beyond the grave. That the "spirits in prison'' can be preached to—can be helped
                            and released. That to be clothed with the spirit of Christ, is the, and the only
                            Resurrection. He holds, that there is no material hell; that the love of God shed abroad in
                            the sinner's heart, is all the hell that can be endured. He has done away with want, crime,
                            panics, and labor troubles. His is the Millennial day. His home is open to all who will
                            accept it on millennial terms. Can he do more ? His ideas operate as do the leaves of the
                            "Tree of Life"—for the healing of the nations. The Shaker, the Quaker, the Puritan. The apex
                            of this triangular base,— Shakerism, penetrates the heavens. A beacon light to humanity.
                            Clothed with the sun, sublunary attractions under her feet. She is crowned with the stars of
                            heaven—the Christian virtues. Her mode of ascension, and procedure, is, " He or she, who
                            would be great, let them be servants." To the surging millions she waves her hand, the lan-
                            guage of her silence is, "Peace be still. Violence, gains no victories. " Please accept from
                            us many good wishes, and allow us to pray that your life to yourself, and to humanity, may
                            be full of blessings. Respectfully your friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, D." TEIform="persName"/>D. Fraser</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hindering" TEIform="index"/>HINDERING</head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by N. G. Danforth.] "Lest we should hinder the gospel of Christ." 1 Cor. vi., 12. Many an active willing helper
                            in the church is too often an unconscious hinderer of the gospel. Let us try to find out how
                            we may have hindered, that we may do so no more. A vexation arises, and our expressions of
                            impatience hinder others from taking it patiently. Disappointment, ailments or even weather
                            depresses us ; and our look or tone of depression hinders others from maintaining a cheerful
                            and thankful spirit. We drop a discouraged remark and another's hope and zeal is
                            wet-blanketed. "Whatman is there that is fearful and faint hearted ? Let him go and return
                            to his house, lest his brethren's heart faint as well as his heart." We say an unkind thing,
                            and another is hindered in learning the holy lesson of charity that thiuketh no evil. We say
                            a provoking thing, and our sister or brother is hindered in that day's effort to be meek. ''
                            Make straight paths for your feet, lest that wThich is lame be turned out of the way." We do
                            not heed the thoughtful look on some household face just after prayer or public worship, and
                            our needless chat about earthly things. We make a critical remark about a preacher or
                            writer, and it is brought back by the enemy in swift temptation, at the very moment when a,
                            word in season was about to find en<pb n="11" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 11 trance. "Them
                            that were entering in, ye hindered. " Oh, terrible condemnation. "Let not those that seek
                            Thee be confounded for my sake. " How sadly too, we may hinder without word or act! For
                            wrong-feeling is more infectious than wrong-doing; especially the various phases of
                            ill-temper, gloominess, touchiness, discontent, irritability,—do we not know how catching
                            these are? If the Lord asked us,— Wherefore discourage ye the heart of the children of
                            Israel in this way, should we not be utterly without excuse ? What if He asked each hindered
                            one, ''Who did hinder you?" are our consciences sure our names would not escape mention ?
                            May we never be the helpers of the great hinderer ! When "Satan hindered" St. Paul, he
                            probably found human agents. Let us ask that the Lord Jesus would so perfectly tune our
                            spirits to the key-note of his exceeding great love, that all our unconscious influence may
                            breathe only of that, and help all with whom we come in contact to obey the gospel of our
                            Lord Jesus Christ. And let us consider one another, to provoke unto love and to good works.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Havergal, Frances Ridley" TEIform="persName"/>Frances Ridley Havergal</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="From home" TEIform="index"/>FROM HOME</head><p TEIform="p">How we see the parting distance, When we've traveled from our home ; Cannot wing it or
                            dissolve it, Steps alone make the return. Thus it is in Christian travel, When we've gone
                            from truth and light, A returning by repenting, Are the only steps to right. Canterbury, N.
                            H. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rule the appetite and temper the tongue" TEIform="index"/>
                            Rule the appetite and temper the tongue
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Rule the appetite and temper the tongue</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peace" TEIform="index"/>PEACE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, Chauncy" TEIform="persName"/>CHAUNCY DIBBLE</byline><p TEIform="p">There is no germ in the human mind more precious than a clear conscience. To feel that each
                            day our work for eternity is being done. God the Father and Mother of all intelligences
                            created them for happiness in a life of innocence not in sensational enjoyments which only
                            demoralize the mind, but in the fruits of the spirit of harmony and love. Every lesson in
                            the experience of humanity proves that virtue alone brings happiness. When shall we hail
                            this universal harmony ? Will man ever learn that love begets love? Shall wars ever cease,
                            and will men yet be brothers? Shall human life always be valued as mere straws? Shall one
                            man continue to lead thousands to be butchered and men to be put up as marks to be shot at?
                            Shall the happiness of their families at home be of no account in the reckoning of men of
                            military fame? O, will the world not move on to a better state. Is not arbitration
                            preferable to war and slaughter even though a great sacrifice of national pride be the
                            consequence ? Surely, pecuniary interests are never benefited. A congress of nations might
                            settle disputes with far less expense than war could possibly do and avoid the human
                            butchery, save the widows and orphans, do away with the inconsistency of forcing men from
                            their employment on the authority of Government to maintain war, a relic of barbarism,
                            national highway robbery. Overlooking the cost the sacrifice of life the widows and orphans,
                            the maimed and the tramps, look at the destruction of morals by the vicious tend- encies of
                            war and camp life. The blunt<pb n="12" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 12 THE MANIFESTO. ing of every virtuous
                            feeling of humanity, the contradiction of all the principles of Christianity, the ignoring
                            of all physiological laws of health or happiness, the utter disregard of the feeling of
                            brotherhood inasmuch as national gods are supreme, all pray to their respective gods in the
                            name of Christ to destroy the other. Military despotism is a power above powers from whose
                            crushing car none can escape. To whose authority all gods must bow and human life and
                            happiness be sacrificed. If these utterances were untrue we might all feel comforted, but
                            who can deny them in view of the misery that has stalked the earth from its earliest
                            history. War is but the outward expression of the selfishness that reigns and riots within
                            the heart. War would never be if men were pure within. Wheu men purify their lives then will
                            wars cease. Watervliet, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute of love to sister Mary A. Kelley" TEIform="index"/>Tribute of Love to Sister Mary A.
                            Kelley</head><byline TEIform="byline">Contributed by <persName reg="Pickard, Lena E." TEIform="persName"/>Lena E. Pickard, one of her pupils</byline><p TEIform="p">Dearest Sister thou hast left us Life's short span is at an end; All too soon, death has
                            bereft us, Of a sister and a friend. Entering quietly among us, With a solemn, silent tread,
                            And hath taken from our number, One now counted with the dead. Pause ! we cry, 0 angel
                            reaper, Stay thy hand, and heed our cry, Do not thus bereave our household, Hear, and heed,
                            and pass us by. But the Master's need is greater, One more sheaf, the garner fills ; And the
                            form of our dear sister, Lieth silent, cold, and still. And we bow, a stricken household, As
                            we gather here to-day; To do honor, to our sister, Ere we lay her form away. We have known
                            thee, but to love thee, Though we've known thee, long and well And no one can fill the
                            places, That in life thou filled so well. When we saw your step grow feeble, Saw the
                            strength of life depart; Saw thy form grow weak and weaker, Then we knew that we must part.
                            Knew that soon from out our circle, We should miss thy sailing face ; Knew that soon, we'd
                            find another. In thy old accustomed place. And we pray, 0 dearest sister, If we've caused
                            thee pain and grief; By an unkind word or action, In thy journey here so brief; That thou
                            wilt forgive our weakness, And though oft we caused thee pain, Know the fount, of love
                            undying, In our hearts, was still the same. We have brought a wreath of flowers, And we lay
                            them at thy shrine ; They will never fade or wither, But brighter grow, with lapse of time.
                            'Tis a wreath of pure affection, Amaranthine flowers are seen, Closely twined, and neatly
                            blended, While mem'ry, keeps them ever green. Love, the lily white and fragrant,
                            Friendship's green and living vine, True affection's sweetest l-oses, From the garland we
                            entwine. And in gratitude we bring it As an offering that will live ; When our earthly form
                            shall slumber, In the cold and silent grave. Fare thee well, though we consign Thy mortal
                            form unto the sod; Yet we know thy spirit's living, In the blissful realms of God. And the
                            parting is but transient, Thou hast only gone before; To the home of blessed promise, On the
                            bright eternal shore. Farewell, dearest friend, and sister; May thy spirit rest in peace,
                            Thou art free from earthly suffering, Pain and sorrow now shall cease. Fare thee well, we
                            gently breathe it, <pb n="13" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 18 Angels wait to bear thee o'er
                            To'thy home in brighter regions, On that blest immortal shore. Harvard, Mass.</p><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kelley, Mary A." TEIform="index"/>Mary A. Kelley
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Demise occurred Oct. 7, 1886. Age 31.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbath of the lord" TEIform="index"/>SABBATH of the LORD</head><p TEIform="p">''The American Government has no constitutional right to legislate upon theology—to recognize
                            any Sabbath Day in a National Exposition. Under God, our protection as a people depends upon
                            the government being kept in its integrity, unsectarian, a home for all nations, kindreds
                            and tongues. This dispensation of Christ's second appearing, is the kingdom of Heaven, for
                            which Jesus set people praying. It is the Sabbath that remaineth for the people of God,
                            wherein the daily bread of its subjects, was to be as sure as was the manna in the
                            wilderness. All could gather it, and he who will work can eat in this Sabbath of the Lord.
                            The Jewish Sabbath fed the poor cne day in seven ; one month in seven ; one year in seven ;
                            and in the Jubilees gave them the land; but the pentecosta" church gave the poor the land
                            from the beginning, the same as the Shakers do now, in perpetual possession, thus swallowing
                            up all types as short time Sabbaths in a Jubilee of Jubilees, the true Sabbath of the
                            Lord."—Selected by J. 8. P.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reply to question by Antoinette Doolittle" TEIform="index"/>Question by Antoinette Doolittle</head><byline TEIform="byline">REPLY BY <persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p">What is the divinest thought that can en ter the finite mind concerning the Infinite Is it
                            Love, Goodness, or Purity ? If they al belong to the same fountain, which, sepa rately
                            considered, forms the head,—whenc the highest flow. In other words, when the darkened night
                            passes away and the mornng of a new day, breaks upon the siumberr, which of those attributes
                            gild the highest eak on the mountain's summit? Purity is the divinest thought that an enter
                            the finite mind concerning the nfinite. It is the fountain-head of ife's immortal stream,
                            the source of every attribute, and spring of every &gt;lessing. In purity are love and
                            goodless perfect. It is the very essence of Divinity that permeates and infuses the lighest
                            spheres, the unclouded light of eternity's perpetual day. " God is light, in him is no
                            darkness at aU." The purer we become the nearer we approach Deity ; for, "Blessed are the
                            pure in heart, they shall see God. " Most precious of the promises given by the Christ
                            inspired teacher, whose life example, as well as precept was virgin purity. Impurity
                            broodeth in darkness, and in secret. God is not there ; and the mind that harbors unchaste
                            thoughts, or the heart that cherishes unhallowed desires, shrinks from the light, with a
                            sense of shame and disgrace. " Know ye not that ye are the temple of God ? if any man defile
                            this temple him will God destroy ; " by a withdrawal of His spirit; it is a law inevitable.
                            "The soul that sinneth it shall die." The written and unwritten revelation of God's eternal
                            truth declare the certainty of this. What stultifies the sensibilities, be- clouds the
                            intellect, sears the conscience, drains the vital forces, turns love to hatred and disgust,
                            and creates on earth a hell? The carnal mind unreined by moral law. Lasciviousness is the
                            destructive cancer that is eating out the very heart of society, it nips the flower in the
                            bud, <pb n="14" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 14 ThrJ MANIFESTO. and blights the blossom of youthful life. Its
                            dens of infamy are the plague spots of every civilized community, where virtue is swallowed
                            up and demons of vice are generated. The slimy serpent crawls over every threshold
                            victimizing the fair, the beautiful, and would be lovely by the secret charm of its
                            magnetic, but debasing power. What hearth-stone boasts of purity's unsullied shrine? Whoso
                            still worships there, yet knows of love, of home and heaven ; these words holy and sacred in
                            their significance are all embraced iu purity. What means the cry we hear all over the land,
                            the social evil—domestic unhappiness, ungoverned households, family brawls, infanticide,
                            matrimonial dissolution, and an army of neglected vagrant children ? The earth reels drunk
                            with crime of every name and nature, all springing from the hydra headed monster lust.
                            "Whence comes wars and fightings among you? come they not hence, even of your lusts that war
                            in your members?" The greatest of all sins is the sin of transmission, through which
                            depraved influences are stamped upon the embryotic brain ; the consequence is that
                            generations walk the earth and mingle in society, in whom the inclination and impulse is
                            stronger to do evil than good. What mighty lever shall lift such up, from conditions they
                            did not create, into the sunshine of a purer and better life ? True love is the offspring of
                            purity, and only under its benign control can be expected prop- erly developed human beings.
                            Few seem to realize this all important truth. The praises of virtue were sung by the bards
                            of olden time. Seers declared the glory of the ransomed. " These are they who have come up
                            out of great tribulation, who have washed their robes white in the blood (life) of the
                            Lamb." Prophets, Sages, Philosophers, and holy men and women of all ages, inspired by the
                            Christ ideal, conquered the impulses of passion, and took upon themselves a perpetual vow of
                            celibacy. Ancieat temples, cloistered their vestal virgins and beautiful priestesses ; far
                            out of sight of worldly eyes, reserved for holy purposes, they were the divinely inspired
                            oracles, the only fit vessels through which the word and will of God could be revealed to
                            man. The baptized Jesus, inculcated purity foremost in his system of ethics. The teachings
                            of his apostles whether to Jew or Gentile hold forth this heavenly principle or attribute as
                            the goal of spiritual attainment, recognizing the fact, that because of low conditions, few
                            would be able in this life, to bear the cross and practice the self-denial necessary to
                            reach the perfect state. In every heart, no matter what the education, or yet the ignorance,
                            there lingers a hope of probation, and though long and dark may be the night of error and
                            sin, there will at some future period in the soul's history, be kindled a desire for
                            something better and purer than the unsatisfactory fruits of a sen- sual life. Then will
                            come an awakening—self-judgment—God's light will unveil the soul—the dawning of a new day
                            will break upon the inner vision, and the first thought that shall fill the mind will be
                            purity, it is the presence of God, his light and love—it gilds the mountain tops of His
                            eternal goodness and in its fullness alone will the soul ever find peace and rest or realize
                            the blessing of an unending existence. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="15" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="San Francisco, California, June 1886" TEIform="index"/>San Francisco, Cal. June, 1886</head><p TEIform="p">Louis Basting, Dear Friend ;— I have received both your letter and pamphlets, for which I am
                            much indebted to you. In the meantime my mind has been highly enlightened in what is called
                            spiritualism. I had finished reading R. I). Owen's " Foot falls" just the day before your
                            pamphlet (Sketches of Shakers and Shakerism, by Giles B. Avery) came, wherein, to my great
                            satisfaction I found it cited. I found this doctrine, considered by itself, easily
                            understood. As to the phenome-1 na, I am not very anxious to witness or experience them ;
                            they were just the impediments that prevented a correct understanding of true spiritualism.
                            "A Shaker's answer," in the pamphlet, had the effect of balm to a sick heart, and I felt
                            myself elevated above all earthly wants and suffering. I, too, claim to be called for a
                            spiritual life. Like St. Augustine, I must thank God to have saved and withdrawn my soul out
                            of the abyss of scholasticism. From the day that I was able to reason for myself I stood
                            alone against all the wisdom of common life, as given by teachers, friends, and even
                            parents, whose best intentions I could not doubt. All warnings and admonitions could not
                            suppress my longing for a higher life. After having blown down the whole artificial fabric I
                            had built during my young life, (just for my parents' sake) abandoning all prospects and
                            hopes already attained, I undertook to look for the realization of my craving in another
                            world. And indeed I have found the "new world." Here, in low and humble situations, I viewed
                            the highest regions. Like Moses I was allowed to view the promised land. Shall I be chosen
                            among the few ? I like to compare my life with the following incident that happened the
                            other day. On the road to Golden Gate Park, near the Odd Fellow's cemetery, there is amid
                            the waves of sand-hills one hill towering above them all. On the top a simple wooden cross
                            like an admonishing finger points towards heaven and a higher life to the thousands passing
                            by in search of never satisfying' pleasures and vanities. Last Sunday I took a walk out to
                            breathe a purer air, and coming near this hill the sudden impulse to climb up to that cross
                            was soon followed by the deed. In rash resolution of youth I took just the side before me,
                            which was the steepest one. The sides are sandy, giving no firm support to the foot, which
                            slides back the half of every step. After a few steps I always took a rest and respired,
                            then aspired again. Now I was up half way the other half steeper still and my force growing
                            weaker. I climbed with hands and feet; about thirty feet more and I shall have reached the
                            summit where the upper part of the cross is now visible. But I hardly could go on and nearly
                            fainted, for I was exhausted after this violent exercise, not being ac- customed to it. But
                            with the last effort I reached the summit, clinging to the cross. You have a wide prospect ;
                            there the city of living men, here the city of death. And I said to myself: All I do, speak
                            or think, shall be as if I were on the top of a hill, visible to all, and I'll never be
                            ashamed of any deed, wTord or thought. Believe me willing to be aspiring with all my heart
                            and soul. Yours truly</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pick, Ernest" TEIform="persName"/>Ernest Pick</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The first step to greatness is to be honest" TEIform="index"/>
                            The first step to greatness is to be honest
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The first step to greatness is to be honest-</p></div2><pb n="16" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>THE MANIFESTO. JANUARY, 1887</head><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Office of Publication" TEIform="index"/>Office of publication</head><p TEIform="p">The Manifesto is published at Shaker Village, Mer. Co. N. H. All articles for publication
                                should be addressed to Henry C. T3unn, and all letters on financial business to A. Y.
                                Cochran. .70 .40 One copy per year, postage paid. " " six months, " Send for specimen
                                copy, free.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes: the new year" TEIform="index"/>NOTES, THE NEW YEAR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The dawn of a welcome new year. It comes as a most beautiful gift from the Divine Hands.
                                May it be to all our dear friends, a new, A happy New Year ! and no less in its
                                development an inspirational new year, that it may represent to us more fully the growth
                                of (he new heavens and the new earth wherein shall dwell righteousness and peace.
                                Abundant blessings have been proffered to us, and as we bid farewell to the friendly old
                                year, we will rei-nember that on every hand we have seen and shared the kind guardian
                                care of our Heavenly Father and Mother,—God. Seed time and harvest have been to us in
                                all the plenitude of the promise, giving the renewed assurance that a wise protective
                                spirit still watches over the interests of the whole earth. If the heavy hand of
                                adversity has unfortunately fallen upon us, for a moment, we may still rejoice that
                                while we were wounded, we were not destroyed, " persecuted, but not forsaken, " and
                                though deprived of some few of our earthly comforts, we still retain our precious,
                                gospel homes. A new year would be incomplete without new thoughts and a new inspiration.
                                We need these to clothe the mind and bring forth a more consecrated life for God and for
                                humanity. New resolutions that shall embody additional zeal and interest for the
                                promotion of righteousness in the earth, and the determined effort we make, that this
                                may be accomplished, will be proof of our devotion to the cause. Our extended privilege
                                will, evidently, afford us ample opportunity for the manifestation of our anxious care
                                in the dissemination of the truth as we have learned it of the Divine Teacher, and also
                                for the promulgation of the spirit of God as it has been received into our hearts. If we
                                can do but little toward the mitigation of the ills of humanity, and for the education
                                of the mind that it may be better able to accept of higher religious truths, that little
                                will be our great consolation, and our crown of eternal life. While some may be
                                justified to tistand still and see the salvation of God," we are assured that in order
                                to live and prosper in the service of the Lord Jesus we must walk as|hetwalked, live as
                                he lived, and crucify in our own souls the element of the world, with all its affections
                                and lusts. With the apostles become teachers of this essential, Christian discipline.
                                "God forbid that I should glory, save in the cross of our Lord Jesus Christ, by whom the
                                world is crucified unto me and I unto the world. " Of one thing we are fully persuaded :
                                that the manifestations which accompany this spirit will bring the sure evidence 16
                                TERMS. January, <pb n="17" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 17 of a happy and prosperous new
                                year, and culminate in a bounteous and satisfactory reward. The Manifesto enters upon
                                the work of a new year. With the present number it begins the seventeenth volume. In
                                this we have the assurance that its past record has been carefully guarded and that its
                                mission has beeu good news to many readers, and we are now led to believe that the pages
                                for the incoming year will be no less satisfactory. "Those who have tasted of the good
                                word of God and of the powers of the world to come," will undoubtedly have a desire to
                                place their living testimony before the readers of the Manifesto, and in this way be
                                able to give to God and to humanity some of the treasures which have beeu so bountifully
                                conferred upon them. Our honest testimony, although simple, may have in it goodly
                                treasures from a heavenly kingdom,—the pi'otective gifts of God. If we can so live as to
                                merit the blessing of divine protection, and in return accept the pleasure of assisting
                                others, this most assuredly, will form the happiness that is to be found in this
                            life.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True way to cure dyspepsia" TEIform="index"/>THE TRUE WAY TO CURE DYSPEPSIA</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A lady who has suffered from dyspepsia almost all her entire life, considers
                                        the fol- lowing suggestions to be the most in accord with her own experience of
                                        anything as a method of cure. Hurried eating of meals, followed immediately by
                                        some employment that occupies the whole attention, and also takes up all, or
                                        nearly all, of the physical energies, is sure to result in dyspepsia in one form
                                        or another. Sometimes it shows itself in excessive irritability, a sure
                                        indication that the nerve force has been exhausted; the double draft, in order
                                        to digest the food and carry on the business, has been more than nature could
                                        stand without being thrown out of balance. In another case, the person is
                                        exceedingly dull as soon as he has a few minutes of leisure. The mind seems a
                                        dead blank, and can only move in its accustomed channels, and then when
                                        compelled. This, also, is an indication of nervous exhaustion. Others will have
                                        decided pains in the stomach, or a sense of weight, as if a heavy burden was
                                        inside. Others, again, will be able to find nothing that will agree with them;
                                        everything that is put inside the stomach is made the subject of a violent
                                        protest on the part of that organ, and the person suffers untold agonies in
                                        consequence. Others suffer from constant hunger. They may eat all they can and
                                        feel hungry still. If they feel satisfied for a little time, the least unusual
                                        exertion brings on the hungry feeling, ard they can do no more until something
                                        is eaten. It is almost needless to say that this condition is not hunger, but
                                        inflammation of the stomach. Scarcely any two persons are affected exactly m the
                                        same way, the disordered condition manifesting itself according to temperament
                                        and occupation, employments that call for mental work, and those whose scene of
                                        action lies indoors, affecting persons more seriously than those carried on in
                                        the open air, and those which are merely mechanical, and do not engage the mind.
                                        All, or nearly all, of these difficulties of digestion might have never been
                                        known by the sufferers had they left their business behind them and rested a
                                        short time after eating, instead of rushing off to work immediately after
                                        hastily swallowing their food. Xature does not do two things at a time and do
                                        both well, as a rule. We all know hat when a force is divided, it is weakened.
                                        If the meal were eaten slowly, without preoccupation of the mind, and the
                                        stomach allowed at the least half-an-hour's chance to get its work well
                                        undertaken before the nervous force is turned in another direction, those
                                        suffering from dyspepsia would be few. <pb n="18" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 18 THE MANIFESTO. A
                                        physician once said: "It does not matter what we eat as how we eat it. " While
                                        this is only partly true, it certainly is true that for dyspeptics the most
                                        healthful iood hurriedly eaten, and immediately followed by work which engages
                                        the entire available physical and mental forces, is much worse than a meal of
                                        poor tood eaten leisurely, and followed by an interval of rest. To those whose
                                        lives are devoted to physical labor, it is less injurious to work immediately
                                        after eating, provided the labor is not unusually severe and straining.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/> The Herald of Health.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">[Beloved Elder II:—I copied these beautiful thoughts from the Chkistian Union some years ago,
                            and I find them worthy of so much consideration at each New Year's dawn that I thought they
                            might be acceptable to you. Amelia.}</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hour and the year" TEIform="index"/>THE HOUR AND THE YEAR</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Over the gateway of the New Year every one writes some new and inspiring
                                    resolution. Life may have been small and mean in the past, the days may have been
                                    full of selfishness, indifference or languor, but the days to come shall shine with
                                    the beauty of unselfish affection, and be full of the fruits of honest work! It
                                    seems so easy to shape the future while it is the future. It stretches before the
                                    thought in its indeftniteness like a mountain lake at night, fading out into mist,
                                    and yet reflecting in its mysterious depths, the very splendor of the heavens. As we
                                    stand on the shore of the future, and feel rather than see, the infinite
                                    possibilities which shine in it, we forget that those glories are only the
                                    reflections of our own noble purpose, and that there is no beauty and light there,
                                    unless it be caught from ourselves. The future is not a harvest-field into which we
                                    can wander at will and reap the golden grain; it is an unsown field, to be plowed
                                    and sown and watched and worked upon, with hourly fidelity, and daily toil, if its
                                    furrows are hidden by the waving grain. There is nothing there, but the soil upon
                                    which to worK; every thing else the worker must furnish. Opportunities will crowd
                                    the days, but will pass empty-handed unless we recognize and hold them; suns will
                                    shine, rains fall, dews lie sweet and fresh under the morning sky, but the end of
                                    the year will find us as empty and poor,*as the begin- ning, unless we yoke all
                                    these elements of success, and drive them with a firm and steady purpose. Men and
                                    women who succeed, greatly understand that the future is a matter of detail, and
                                    that he who conquers it, makes his conquest, foot by foot. No glowing resolution
                                    solemnly made on the first day of the year, consecrates and redeems the time, but
                                    the steady discharge of the least and smallest duty, in the largest and most
                                    aspiring spirit from sunrise to sunset, the whole year through. An hour at a time,
                                    is all the busiest man gets, for tiie grandest work, and to understand, that the
                                    hour in hand is the best that will ever come, in which to make one's soul visible
                                    and potential in action, is to have mastered the secret of success. There is no form
                                    of imagination so fruitful as that which is able to mass the hours together, and
                                    give their true proportions, in spite of their poor and mean appearance. To know the
                                    value of the present hour, is to know the value of the whole future. The shining
                                    stretch of that sea, is as vast as the largest reach of thought can make it, but it
                                    pours itself into the individual life, by a channel so small, that men forget the
                                    volume back of the hourly flow, and are always waiting for the incoming tide, which
                                    shall float the great purposes that now lie stranded and hopeless, Condense and
                                    compare your resolution, omit it from your diary, and write it on your hour. Be
                                    jealous of your moments, lavish your life, and thought, and heart, on the things of
                                    each day, and when the months have made their solemn circle, your resolution will be
                                    written across them so broadly, that the world will read it without your
                                    interpretation.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian nion" TEIform="index"/>Christian Union</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Live for to-day..." TEIform="index"/>Live for to-day...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Live for to-day, If you would live aright, The past is gone, The future not in sight.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer prevails against temptation" TEIform="index"/>Prayer prevails against temptation
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Prayer prevails against temptation.</p></div2><pb n="19" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Education" TEIform="index"/>EDUCATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Aitken, Robert" TEIform="persName"/>ROBERT AITKEN</byline><p TEIform="p">This being an important subject, and more than once discussed in the Manifesto, perhaps a
                            little more about it may not be amiss. As commonly understood to educate is to impart
                            knowledge from the possessor to one ignorant of that knowledge. The possessor of knowledge
                            is active to instruct when he finds one willing to receive. Here comes in the question,
                            whether education is bounded by human knowledge. We who talk of being taught the way of God,
                            and the way out of all sin, cannot rest there ; because we experience a deeper teaching by
                            revelation, which has been obtained by submission and not by any objective study. If then
                            all is to come under the head of Education, the one is objective and the other subjective
                            education. Hence the question, Is this the whole? As before stated Man can educate only
                            objectively and subjectively. But it is a self-evident truth, that the latter is limited to
                            teaching the conditions required to obtain what the gospel of salvation from sin can give.
                            It is also selfevident that the gospel is the poioer of God unto salvation, which we receive
                            after we have been taught the needful conditions, and have submitted ourselves to them.
                            Hence man's agency in the educational as relating to the gospel is to teach the needful
                            conditions. God's agency, after we have submitted to the required conditions, is to create
                            in us a New Being or a new creature. These are the only terms on which we can be benefited
                            by all that education can give us for the proper development cither of our physi- cal,
                            intellectual, and spiritual or Godlove natures; because man is a free agent and God can do
                            nothing for him except as he submits to his terms. This gives those of small abilities or
                            knowledge the same hope for redemption as those of greater abilities or attainments ; for
                            God is just. In order to cast off all ground for selfexaltation it seems necessary to
                            remember that Paul may plant and Apollos may water but God alone can give the increase. The
                            foundation of all human misery is that man will not submit himself to receive the spiritual
                            or love nature which can alone bring the light and life or intellectual and physical natures
                            into proper order. It is superficial to look at the unfoldment of man's outward faculties as
                            being of first importance in the gospel which, while it will inevitably develop the whole
                            man, yet primarily is designed to unfold the inner or spiritual powers on the basis of a
                            gradual death to the carnal worldly life. Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian resolve" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN RESOLVE</head><p TEIform="p">I'll trust my enemies with God xVs well as all my friends, Well knowing He who holds the rod,
                            Hath justice in his hands. I'll not retaliate, or pay A wrong, with wrong of mine; But
                            carefully will go my way, And will improve my time.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Speak not evil of the absent..." TEIform="index"/>SPEAK NOT EVIL OF THE ABSENT
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"SPEAK NOT EVIL OF THE ABSENT." It is said that Socrates, (a so-called heathen
                            philosopher,) had this motto inscribed in letters of gold over the door of his studio. Would
                            to kind heaven it could be written with a pen of diamond in the heart, memory and will of
                            every professing Christian. Obedience is better than many oblations.</p></div2><pb n="20" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keep away" TEIform="index"/>KEEP AWAY</head><byline TEIform="byline">South Union, KY.<persName reg="Ashford, E. L." TEIform="persName"/>Mrs. E. L. Ashford, Nashville, Tenn.</byline><p TEIform="p">1. Keep a way, keep a way, let my spirit have rest, All ye vanish 8. Keep a way, keep a way,
                            let my spirit go free, That no heaven ing fol lies which tend to mo lest, And to hinder my
                            progress in ly gifts be with-holden from me, And that I may keep pace with the Heaven's
                            highway, From my soul, from my soul, keep away. 2. Keep away, light of the day, From my
                            soul, from my soul, keep away. 4. Let me live keep a way, all ye idols of time, That are only a hindrance with my Brethren and Sisters in love, And with them in sweet un ion <pb n="21" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> and clog to the mind, That would be of no use, but would lead me aand
                            meekness improve By rejecting all evilly night and by stray, From my body and pout,
                            keep away. day, Where all bondage and death keep a way, 5. O my soul keep a wake, and be
                            ready to flee, And to hide from the evil which you may fore see; And to be in your duty,
                            this word you'll obey, And from all that is wrong, keep away, keep away, keep away, keep
                            away</p></div2><pb n="22" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Parson's text" TEIform="index"/>THE PARSON'S TEXT
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Brown, M. Alice" TEIform="persName"/>M. ALICE BROWN
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A pabsox once, the story goes, Maligned by
                                    friends as well as foes ; 3?or tales made up, surmisings dark, And cruel slanders,
                                    made the mark ; Bethought himself a blow to deal, Which etery guilty soul should
                                    feel. Without a word of his intent, He to his Sabbath duties went,— "My text you'll
                                    find within the book Of Exodus, if you will look, The chapter twenty-three, the
                                    clause And verse are first, but here I pause,— As it is broad and comprehends, The
                                    highest nights, the farthest ends, To which I wisli your thoughts to soar, No words
                                    of mine could add aught more ; To every one within my fold, This text I give to
                                    Iceej) and hold; An application in it lies, But 'twill be plain to all the wise,
                                    'Tis sermon, rule of life as well, It's worth if heeded who can tell! I now proceed
                                    to close my theme. Your own reflections best I deem." Then home they sped, with
                                    wonder stirred At this new preaching they had heard; Each one in heated haste to
                                    see, What such a wondrous text could be, But what was their chagrin to read, Though
                                    terse and trite, most fit indeed, These words, more keen than long retort,"Thou
                                    shalt not raise a false report."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="American rural home" TEIform="index"/>The American Rural Home.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Connecticut, 1886" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Conn. 1886</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Children :—Another year has joined the past. How swiftly and how silently the fleeting
                            moments fly ! Begin the New Year right. Take another step toward the heavenly goal. " Good
                            to begin well, better to end well." The reward of "\vell-doing is^a priceless treasure. ' Be
                            virtuous, that is more than wealth Do right, that's morefthan place; Then in the spirit
                            there is health,. And gladness in the face. " Virtue is strength. Never stop for little
                            troubles or give up for great ones. It is unmanly to " look back. " God will give you
                            strength and power, trust Him and labor, hour by hour. Keep good vows so firmly that
                            temptation shall be powerless for evil. Good vows and good efforts will win. Faith and good
                            works will save your souls, though raging billows round you roll. Review the past and profit
                            by its lessons. Profit by the mistakes of others and shun their penalties. " Make your
                            record clean. " A sure way to win " a righteous name" is to deserve it. Examine your lives,
                            weigh your motives, watch your conduct. Fill this hour with worthy work and you will be
                            ready for the hours that follow. Carefully guard your innocence. Grow in purity day by day,
                            keep in mind to watch and pray. Purity is a rare jewel. Would you enjoy a conscience clear,
                            and blessings that endure? Be pure. A clear conscience is an eternal inheritance. Your
                            Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agnus dei" TEIform="index"/>AGNUS DEI
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline">[The following lines are contributed by <persName reg="Justice, William" TEIform="persName"/>William
                            Justice, </byline><p TEIform="p">aged 84 years, who is patiently awaiting the call of the Lord.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Great God, thy name be blessed, Thy goodness be adored; My soul has
                                    been distressed, But thou hast peace restored. A thankful heart I feel, In peace my
                                    mind is stayed : Balsamic ointments heal The wounds by sorrow made. Though elements
                                    contend, And winds and waters rage: I've an unshaken friend Who doth my grief
                                    assuage. Though outward storms arise— Emblems of those within— Oa Christ my soul
                                    relies, <pb n="23" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 23 The sacrifice for sin. Though inward
                                    storms prevail, Afflicting to endure, I've help that cannot fail In Him who's ever
                                    sure, Though outward war and strife, Prevail from sea to sea, I've peace in inward
                                    life, And that sufflceth me. Though clamor rear its head And stalk from shore to
                                    shore, My food is angels' bread— What can I covet more? Though ill reports abound,
                                    Suspicion and surmise, I find, and oft have found, In death true comfort lies ; That
                                    death I mean whereby Self-love and will are slain, For these the more they die, The
                                    more the Lamb doth reign. And well assured I am, True peace is only known Where he,
                                    the harmless Lamb, Has made the heart his throne. Then may the tempest rage, And
                                    cannon roar in vain, The Uock of every age, The Lamb, the Lamb dotli reign. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Washington's code of manners" TEIform="index"/>WASHINGTON'S CODE OF MANNERS</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Eveki" action in company, ought to be with respect to those present. Be no
                                    flatterer, neither play with any one who delights not to be played with. Read no
                                    papers, letters, or books in company. Come not near the papers or books of others,
                                    to read them. Look not over another when he is writing. Let your countenance be
                                    cheerful, but, in serious matters, be grave. Show not yourself glad at another's
                                    misfortunes. Let your discourses on matters of business be short. It is good manners
                                    to let others, especially if your peers, speak first. Strive not with your
                                    superiors, but be modest. When a man does all he can, do not blame him, though he
                                    does not well succeed. Take admonitions thankfully. Be not hasty to believe flying
                                    reports to the injury of another. In your dress be modest, and consult your
                                    condition. Play not the peacock, looking vainly at yourself. It is better to be
                                    alone, than in bad company. Let your conversation be without malice, or envy. Urge
                                    not your friend to disclose a secret. Break not a jest where none take pleasure in
                                    mirth. Speak not injurious words, either in jest or earnest. Gaze not on the
                                    blemishes of others. When another speaks, be attentive. Be not apt to relate news.
                                    Be not curious to know the affairs of others. Speak not evil of the ah sent I When
                                    you speak of God, let it be with reverence. Labor to keep alive that spark of
                                    heavenly fire called conscience.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beautiful words" TEIform="index"/>BEAUTIFUL WORDS
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Cast thy bread, vpon the waters; for thou shah l it after many
                                    day-s."—Eccl. xi., 1. Mid the losses and the gains, Mid the pleasures and the pains
                                    ; 'Mid the hopings and the fears. And the restlessness of years, We repeat this
                                    passage o'er— We believe it more and more— Bread upon the waters cast Shall be
                                    gathered at the last. Gold and silver, like the sands, Will keep slipping through
                                    our hands ; Jewels, gleaming like a spark, Will be hidden in the dark; Sun and moon
                                    and stars will pale, But these words will never fail— Bread upon the waters cast
                                    Shall be gathered at the last. Soon like dust to you and me, Will our earthly
                                    treasure be ; But the loving word and deed To a soul in bitterest need, They will
                                    Hot forgotten be, They will live eternally— Bread upon the waters cast Shall be
                                    gathered at the last. Fast the moments slip away, Soon our mortal powers decay ; Low
                                    and lower sinks the sun, What we do must soon be done; Then what rapture, if we hear
                                    Thousand voices ringing clear— Bread upon the waters cast Shall be gathered at the
                                    last.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="24" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health. December. Contents, lied Cloud; Chief of
                                the Dakotas; A Chapter on Anthropometry; Familiar talks with our young Readers;
                                Decadence of Orthodoxy; A beautiful Father; Selkirk's Colony; A great Day; Reciprocal
                                Influence of Mind and Body; The Philosophy of Religion; Home Culture vs. Home Work; Hair
                                and Character; Fruit in Florida, etc., etc. Fowler &amp; Wells Co. 753 Broadway, 2s.
                                Y. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>Herald of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Herald of Health. December. Contents. Sources of Dampness in Houses; Hygienic
                                treatment of Bright's Disease; Home Education; Sore Throat; Sleep a Medicine; Causes of
                                Disagreeable Dreams; How I cured my Cold Feet; How long to Sleep; The Teeth of Xegroes;
                                Studies in Hygiene for women, etc. etc. M. L. Ilolbrook, M. D. 13 Laight St.N. Y..</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/> Hall's Journal of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">
                                Hall's Journal of Health. Nov. Contents. Dreams; Prof. Joseph R. Buchanan; Magnetic and
                                Electric Forces; Signs of the Times; Twenty years in a Trance, etc., etc. Oflice 206
                                Broadway, N. Y.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="This life is what we make it" TEIform="index"/>THIS LIFE IS WHAT WE MAKE IT
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">. Let's oftener talk of noble deeds, And rarer of the
                                    bad ones, And sing about our happy days, And none about the sad ones. We were not
                                    made to fret and sigh, And when grief sleeps to wake it; Bright happiness is
                                    standing by— This life is what we make it. Let's find the sunny side of men, Or be
                                    believers in it; A light there is in every soul That takes the pains to win it. Oh !
                                    there's a slumbering good in all. And we perchance may wake it. Our hand contains
                                    the magic wand— This life is what we make it. Then here's to those whose loving
                                    hearts Shed light and joy about them ! Thanks be to them for countless gems We ne'er
                                    had known without them. Oh ! this should be a happy world To all who may partake it;
                                    The fault's our own if it is not— This life is what we make it.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Truth" TEIform="index"/>Truth.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Little hinges" TEIform="index"/>LITTLE HINGES
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Clyde, Kate" TEIform="persName"/>BY KATE CLYDE
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> "Mighty doors on little hinges Oft with ease and
                                    smoothness swing. So it is from merest trifles Often great events will spring.
                                    Little, thoughtless words and actions Hold a pow'r none can foretell; They are but
                                    the tiny seedlets From which later growths will swell. Oft some little word we utter
                                    With unheeding, careless lips; Oft perform some trifling action That as swift from
                                    mem'ry slips, Till some after act, resulting Prom the strong but secret pow'r Hidden
                                    in that deed forgotten, Comes to view some future hour. If that word were one of
                                    kindness, If we did a loving deed— Ah, we know from Christian sources Only good
                                    results proceed! Just when some poor heart was sinking 'Neath a load of grief and
                                    care, May be that kind word or action Ileav'nly whispers seemed to bear. If that
                                    word were cruelly spoken, If that deed were mean and bad, Surely their results could
                                    only Serve to make the angels sad. Oh, by life's most trifling actions, If they are
                                    but kind and true— By each soft word gently spoken— How much good we each can do !</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thomas, Eliza" TEIform="index"/>Eliza Thomas
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Thomas, Eliza" TEIform="persName">Eliza Thomas</persName>, at Union Village, 0. Nov. 25,
                                188(). Age 70 yrs. 10 mo. and 12 days-</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whittaker, John" TEIform="index"/>John Whittaker
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Whittaker, John" TEIform="persName">John Whittaker</persName>, at Enfield, N. H. Nov.. 30,
                                1886. Age 71 yrs.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Price, Ann" TEIform="index"/>Ann Price
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Price, Ann" TEIform="persName">Ann Price</persName>, at Union Village, Ohio. Dec. 8th.
                                188.6. Age 71 yrs. and 6 mo.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gilman, Ransom" TEIform="index"/>Ransom Gilman
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Gilman, Ransom" TEIform="persName">Ransom Gilman</persName>, at South Family, Mt. Lebanon,
                                N. Y. Dec. 8th. 1886. Age G7 yrs. 4 mo. and 1!) days. His death was very peaceful,
                                though sudden. W. A.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Advertisements" TEIform="index"/>[Advertisements]</head><p TEIform="p">[Advertisements deleted.]</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>