<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2607" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">26</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><date value="18960701" TEIform="date">July 1896</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">105-120</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="26" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1">
                    <!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
1896.
A CONCISE HISTOEY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
with large type  and on excellent paper.
It contains  130 pages and has
ILLUSTRATIONS
of the Shakers and their
The work gives quite an extended account* of the Several SOCIETIES, their
organization and general management.
Price,  50 cts.
Address   H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF THE
 CHURCH,
OB
"United   Society    of   Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price 50 cts.
A Visit to the
of EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
BY
LLOYD H. CHANDLER.  U. S. N
Liberally Illustrated with half tone
pictures of persons and places.
The Village of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the lovliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price, 15 cts.
AUTHORIZED RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   0OMMUNITY.
The religious'basis of the Order must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individ
ual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence j
of his upright standing before the woi'ld.
Price, 10 cts.
JULY,
MILLENNIAL
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
The illustrated "Lee of Virginia" series is
continued in the May number ofJFRANK LESLIE'S Popular Monthly with a paper by
Henry Tyrell, relating to General Lee's part
in the momentous events of the years 1859
1862. These events include the John Brown
raid at Harper's Ferry, the secession of the
Southern States and outbreak of the Civil
War, General Lee's resignation from the
United States Army, and appointment to the
command of the Confedeiate forces of Virginia, his campaign in the West, 
the establishment of Jefferson Davis at Richmond as President of the Confederacy, the first battle of
Bull Run, and General McClellan's invasion of
Virginia by way of the Peninsula and advance
upon Richmond. Akin to this subject is a
charming sketch written by Mrs. Jefferson
Davis, descriptive of life in the "White House
of the Confederacy" during the war. Mrs.
Roger A. Pryor adds an interesting chapter
and an exquisite portrait to her "Ancestry of
General Lee." Other notable features of the
number are the illustrated articles upon:
"Cuban Noncombatants," by Frederick A.
Ober; "The Prince of Wales on American
Prairies," by Mrs. J. Leduc; "Sons and Daughters of Feudal Sires," by Mme. Barbara Mac
Gahan; and "Vagabond Wanderings in Guatemala," by Thomas R. Dawley, Jr.
Humanity for June has for Frontispiece,
St. King who contributes an excellent article
on the interests of the people of the United
States. The Unity of Law, By W. Benj. Putnam.
A Criticism by Bolton Hall and the same
answered by W. Benj Putnam.
The Bible by R. G. Ingersoll. As it is, by
Cyrus W. Coolridge. That Terrible Mortgage,
illustrated Protection? illustrated etc, etc.
Published by the Humanity Pub. Co., Kansas,
Mo.
The enormous circulation of such a magazine as The Ladies' Home Journal can, in a
sense, be understood when it is said that during the last six months of 1895 there were
printed, sold and circulated over four million
copies(in exact figures 4,058,891.) Figures
such as these give one some idea of the influence which may be exerted by e^en a single
one of the modern magazines.
The Pulpit for May accepts as its leading
article a "Memorial Day Oration" by Major
Wm. McKinley of Ohio.
Then follows a sermon on the resurrection.
"But with what Body?" by Rev. Horatio Hodson.   Episcopal.
"A Sermon to Young Men" by Rev. Richard
Hooker, Protestant Episcopal.
"The Glorious work of the Y. M. C. A." by
Kev. Theodore L. Cuyler.
"What God thinks of Man," by Rev. R. Lutherland, Presbyterian. "Gratitude for Past
Blessings," by Rev Eustice King, Baptist.
Pub. by G. Holzapf el, Fredericksburg, Pa.
The Phrenological Journal and Science
of Health, for June has returned to its former management, and to its former size. Its
first article is the "Centenary of Horace Mann"
by Nelson Sizer. Mr, Mann speaking of himself, says, "I have always been exempt from
what may be called common vices. I never
swore, indeed, profanity was always most
disgusting and repulsive to me, and I never
used the vile weed in any form. I formed the
resolution to be the slave to no habit."
A New Discovery in Photography, by H. S.
Drayton, with illustration of Prof. Roentgen,
and also of William Crooker.
Hypnotic Experiment as proof of Phrenology, by G. Stirling Wines.
"Attitude and Expression," with illustrations is "for the purpose of convincing the
reader,who has not given much thought to the
matter, that a given attitude will be productive of impressions on others that may be favoiable or unfavorable."
"Order, its uses and abuses," by Nelson Sizer.
"Baron DeHirsch," with portrait. "The
Clayton Family" by Nelson Sizer, with illustrations.
Science of Health, etc., etc. Fowler &
Wells Co.   27 East 21st St. New York.
The Journal of Hygejo-Therapy, for May
has a Chapter on the Science of Life, by T. V.
Gifford, M. D. The subject of Hygiene in Relation to Food is fully discussed, and should
be carefully studied.
The Science of Phrenology by Ella Young
M. D. is one of a series of papers, read before
a class at the Invalid's Home. Water as a
Drink, by J. G. Stair, M. D. He says that the
ideal water is that which is distilled. This
is in fact the only pure water. Other valuable articles may also be found in this same
number. Published by Dr. T. V. Gifford & Co.
Kokomo, Ind.
A Study of the. Pentateuch, by Rufus P.
Stebbins, D. D.
The very word Pentateuch conveys a magic
influence and we at once become interested
in that portion of the Bible which has awakened so much curiosity among the readers of
Biblical History. These five books of Moses
have been assailed on one side by the religious higher criticism and on the other by those
who believe fully in the "Mistakes of Moses,"
till hardly enough is left for a Sunday sermon.
The Preface to this little work has been
written by the Publisher H. L. Hastings, and
his thorough knowledge of the Bible, carries
with it the assurance that we are receiving
the best of evidence. He writes as follows
"The candid reader is thus advised as to what
he will find within the pages of this book. He
can read it for himself and thus verify the--><pb n="105" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Autobiography of Chas. D. Hampton of Union Village, Ohio, no. 6" TEIform="index"/>AUTOBIOGRAPHY OF CHAS. D. HAMPTON OF UNION VILLAGE, O. NO. 6.</head><p TEIform="p">T^HE Washingtons, Jeffersons, Adams and Hancocks, and all those wor_L thy and
                            honorable men drank deeply from the fountain of this inspiration, and were influenced by the
                            same army of spirits until they were enabled to do the will of God by establishing the first
                            chapter of the rights of man, and liberty of conscience followed as an unavoidable result.
                            These important principles being settled on a firm basis, opened the way for minds of a
                            peculiar bent to pursue the quiet tenor of their way unmolested by the tyranny of
                            government, and had nothing to fear but the ignorance and avarice of their cotemporaries.
                            Every important invention from a pinhead to the magnetic telegraph owes its origin to the
                            kind assistance and patient labors of an invisible spiritual agency, to whose constant care
                            and active exertions all these grand improvements and invaluable additions to human
                            prosperity and happiness are indebted as much as to the human agency used by them in
                            introducing the blessings enumerated to our immediate use. This lower world being but the
                            world of effects, and all causation having its origin in the Spirit world, as a world of
                            causes, those immense improvements and many salutary changes in the moral and civil world
                            are but patterns which are stamped on the minds of men, and then reproduced in material
                            forms as representations of the beauty, perfection and usefulness of the substantial
                            creations of that beautiful and splendid world of which this comparatively dark, mundane
                            sphere is but an obscure shadow. JULY, <pb n="106" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 106 THE MANIFESTO.
                            To the natural man the Spirit world is a world of shadows, and the natural world, or
                            material world round about him appears to be substantial. The truth is, the spiritual world
                            is alone substantial and the natural world sustains a relation to it somewhat like the
                            shadow of a tree to the tree itself. The tree is material and the shadow a mere imponderable
                            representation. It is known that the natural body is the shadow only of the spiritual man
                            and that his spirit is the real substantial man. The body of itself is dead only as the
                            living substantial spirit animates it, and gives it life and action. This is understood by
                            the fact that when he puts off his mortal body, his spirit lays it away or leaves it as wre
                            put away a worn out garment. Just so the whole Spirit world in relation to the natural, the
                            one is material and perishable, the other substantial and durable, and when the man leaves
                            the body, he leaves nothing but the body. Every spiritual faculty and sense with which his
                            natural only corresponded, are taken with him and serve his purpose in his new and more
                            perfect home. For instance his natural eye is now dim and sightless, the organ through which
                            his spiritual eye conveyed true knowledge to his mind, and the substantial spiritual eye now
                            looks out again in its proper order on a beautiful spirit, and substantial world where again
                            he finds a charming view of mountains, rivers, forests and fields with hill and dale, and
                            all the delight derived from an enlivening, stimulating prospect of which in this world he
                            had seen the outlines in a lively shadow. He finds now that his whole life had been spent in
                            a world of shadows and that he has just reached a world of pleasing realites. His former
                            friends are before him, clothed in the habiliments of spiritual life, the veritable and
                            substantial entities identified,the very essence of the parents he obeyed, the Brethren and
                            Sisters with whom he lived in his childhood and youth and the friends whose company he had
                            enjoyed in his more mature manhood. Such are the views which my mind entertains of a future
                            existence, and such are the views which first drew my attention to the Society of Believers.
                            The spiritualism that is abroad in the world is doing much good. It is destroying the
                            influence of a mercenary and aspiring priesthood, but the mediums often suffer and are often
                            deceived by evil and designing spirits. And of the value of the communications both the
                            mediums and their attendants are equally ignorant for want of experience, not having learned
                            to discriminate between truth and error, between reliable and unreliable statements. (The
                            end.)</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Providence ordains storms..." TEIform="index"/>Providence ordains storms... </head><p TEIform="p">Providence ordain^ storfns, disasters, hostilities, suffering; and the great
                            question whether we shall live to any purpose or not, whether we shall grow strong in mind
                            and heart, or be weak and pitiable, depends on our use of these adverse circumstances.
                            Outward evils are designed to school our passions and rouse our faculties and virtues into
                            intense activity.</p></div2><pb n="107" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Angels of the new dispensation" TEIform="index"/> ANGELS OF THE NEW
                            DISPENSATION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mace, Aurelia G." TEIform="persName"/>By Aurelia G. Mace.</byline><p TEIform="p">(Read in our meeting for Soul Communion.) BEHOLD we come !Wafted upon the zephyrs
                            from the Elysian fields we come unto you. Glory and brightness are in our wake and the
                            beautiful rivers of heavenly love are rolling onward, deluging the land from shore to shore.
                            Home of the favored and the blest! Home of the pure and the true! We came unto you first,we
                            came unto you in the early dawn, when the birds sang of this New Hope from the tree tops of
                            your lovely groves; the Hope that is now being established as a reality by the scientific
                            researches of the day. Search your records, for laid away in your archives are thousands of
                            messages, words of prophecy, of love and of comfort, which we brought unto you, before we
                            went abroad to do our work with the nations of the earth. We will come unto you again. In
                            God's good time we will come. Hush! Breathe not a thought of doubt while undergoing the
                            throes of this mighty change. Not one jot nor one tittle of all that we have said unto you
                            shall fail. Your banner shall be raised on high;higher than ever before shall be thy
                            standard, and thy victory shall be acknowledged by the nations of the earth. Children of the
                            New Hope, look well to the path in which your feet are found to be walking, for on the plain
                            of nature is the home of discord and strife. We can never walk with you there. But in the
                            bower of purity and spiritual lifeyou will find us. Here we will walk with you and talk with
                            you and sing unto you the beautiful songs of the Redeemed among men. Listen and you shall
                            hear our voices. Come near unto us, and we will draw near unto you. We will feed you from
                            our ambrosial stores and clothe you in fine linen, clean and white. Come unto us all ye that
                            labor and are heavy laden and we will give you rest. Amen and amen. Sabbathday Lake, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pray without ceasing" TEIform="index"/>PRAY WITHOUT CEASING,</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Estabrook, Fidella" TEIform="persName"/>By Fidella Estabrook.</byline><p TEIform="p">Pray with a spirit firm and true, Pray with a resolute will; Pray for a hope, a
                            love divine That will your being thrill. Pray for a heart made lree from sin, Pray for a
                            spirit pure; <pb n="108" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 108 THE MANIFESTO. Pray for the strength and
                            aid of God That ever will endure. Pray to thy God in the hours of need ; Pray on through sun
                            or rain ; Pray to Him for a hope secure And you that hope will gain. Pray when fierce doubts
                            do you assail, And darkened seems your day; He will an answer give to you In his own better
                            way. 4'Ask, and ye shall receive" of Him, "Knock," and the gates are ajar ; "Seek, and ye
                            shall find him" then, If true and sincere you are. God is a refuge and strength to us; A
                            guide and a shield for all; He ever has a listening ear To hear his children call. To Him in
                            prayer we render thanks, And they ascend above To echo through the golden streets The story
                            of his love. Hancock, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ ideal in shakerism, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>THE CHRIST IDEAL IN
                            SHAKERISM. No. 2.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tyner, Paul" TEIform="persName"/>By Paul Tyner.</byline><p TEIform="p">AS yet, Ann Lee's fame is confined to the records and traditions of a small and
                            obscure sect. She does not live in history; her life and her deeds have not found place in
                            song or story. No glowing canvas pictures the splendid drama of her labors for humanity; the
                            histrionic stage has not yet given or received lustre from the reflection of her heroism;
                            she is not among those to whom an admiring world pays tribute in enduring marble and bronze.
                            Time will come when Ann Lee's name will be placed on the roll of liberty's champions,
                            foremost among the lovers and leaders of men,with Luther and Bruno, Savanarola and Knox,
                            Cromwell and Hampden, Washington and <pb n="109" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 109
                            Jefferson. Dazzlingly dramatic and romantic as was the brief career of the Maid of Orleans,
                            it is only nowfive hundred years after she saved France and was burned at the stakethat her
                            glory is finding fitting recognition in art and literature. So Ann Lee is in very good
                            company and can afford to bide her time. Meantime, her fame is secure in the hearts of
                            generations of followers, who lovingly give her the title of "Mother," and her monuments
                            ma}7 be found in nearly a score of thriving communities of robust-souled, pure-minded,
                            clean-handed, earnest, diligent, loving men and women, who having lost the life of worldly
                            strife and illusion, have found a higher life in the strength and peace of ''Mother's
                            Gospel." Nearly eighteen hundred years had passed since Jesus preached the Gospel of Love on
                            the shores of Galilee, and the whole civilized world claimed his name and professed to
                            follow his teaching, when this illiterate Manchester factory girl commenced her mission. It
                            began with a personal experience, not uncommon then (we may hope it is at least less common
                            now,) an experience the pathos and tragedy, horror and shame, of which perhaps only a woman
                            can entirely understand. While still very young she was married against her will to a man
                            much older than herself, a blacksmith like her father, and, like her father, or any other
                            average good man of that time, incapable of understanding that reluctance on the part of a
                            good wife to be at all times "subject to the desiiv of her husband" could be anything but a
                            foolish fancy,or worseunrea.-onable, undutiful, and unbiblical rebellion against the lot to
                            which it had pleased God to appoint her. In this view, it must be remembered, they were
                            sustained by Church and State, although the law restrained the husband from reducing his
                            wife to due discipline and submission with any stick larger around than his thumb! To be
                            outraged with impunity, to submit body and soul to the pleasure and passion of her husband,
                            was the wife's accepted condition, against which she might not even allow the protest of her
                            woman's nature to find voice, without incurring the shame and ignominy of being regarded as
                            undutiful and "flying in the face of Providence." The tragedy of Ann Lee's loveless marriage
                            is briefly, but all too eloquently, told in the simple record that "she bore four children,
                            all of whom died in infancy." Thousands of women, millions of women, had suffered in the
                            same way before Ann Lee, and millions since have suffered like torture and agony and shame.
                            This grim and ghastly subjugation and slaughter of the mother sex, and so of the race, is
                            still going on among us in every country of Christendom, and is hardly less flagrant and
                            frequent among the rich and favored than among the poor and unfortunate. Ann Lee was the
                            first woman who overcame the awful social pressure upon women to suffer and endure in
                            silence, resigning themselves to propagating a race conceived in lust and slavery. Resolved
                            to rise against this infamy, not for herself alone, but for all her sisters and her brothers
                            as well, her soul <pb n="110" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 110 THE MANIFESTO. sought the salvation
                            of the world. Out of the crucible of suffering and out of the tires of struggle, her great
                            soul rose purified and resplendent, as pure gold out of the'ore that is crushed by the
                            refiner and tried in the furnace. She wasted no time in weeping over her own hard lot; her
                            personal pain and sorrow were not allowed to absorb and consume her. We are told that in her
                            twenty-third year (probably soon after the death of that fourth child,) she came under the
                            influence of a little society of people called the "Slinking Quakers," a spiritual band
                            founded in England early in the eighteenth century by a few scattered French exiles, known
                            in England as the "French Prophets" and in France as the Camisards. The burden of their
                            message and teaching was : "Repent! Coufess your sins and amend your lives, for the Kingdom
                            of Heaven is at hand!" Serious and thoughtful, even in her childhood, and always subject to
                            deep religious impressions, often taking the form of heavenly visions, she early realized
                            that her sins were the sins of the worldthe world's sins hersand this conviction caused her
                            such travail and tribulation of soul that she sp &gt;ut many sleepless nights in
                            laboring with her mind and crying to God to open some way of salvation. As she herself has
                            related : "Many times when I was about my work, I felt my soul overwhelmed with sorrow. I
                            used to work as long as I could keep it concealed and then would go out of sight, lest any
                            one should pity me with that pity which was not of God. In my travail and tribulation my
                            sufferings were so great that my flesh consumed upon my bones, bloody sweat pressed through
                            the pores of my skin, and I became as helpless as an infant. And when I was brought through
                            and born into the spiritual kingdom, I was like an infant just born into the natural world.
                            They see colors and objects, but they know not what they see. It was so with me; but before
                            I was twenty-four hours old I saw, and knew what I saw." ("Ann Lee: A Biography," page 135.)
                            Crying earnestly and incessantly to God to show her the cause of man's loss, and to open to
                            her understanding the way to his redemption, "Mother Ann" was thus wrought upon for a space
                            of nine years. During this time, however, she had intervals of release, in which her bodily
                            strength and vigor were marvelously renewed and her soul filled with divine visions and
                            revelations. She became a leader in the little society, greatly enlightening the minds of
                            its members and strengthening their faith by her testimony. Thus was she prepared for the
                            great revelation on which was based Shakerism and that Christ Ideal that was to redeem the
                            world. In the year 1770, while Ann Lee was imprisoned in Manchester on account of her
                            preaching of repentance and righteousness, she believed that Jesus came to her, as He had
                            come to the disciples after his Resurrection, to Paul on the road to Damascus, to Swedenborg
                            when his spiritual vision was opened concurrently with his attainment of "a new manner of
                            breathing." Jesus the undying Man, came to Ann Lee, as He has come and will hereaf- <pb n="111" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. Ill ter come to every man or woman whose
                            consciousness is prepared to receive, assimilate and transmit even the smallest further
                            comprehension of that grand mystery by which the Oneness of Father and Son, of God and Man,
                            was made manifest in the flesh, and every enemy, even Death, that last and most terrible,
                            was vanquished. Jesus, who had never been very far away from her and who,flesh of our flesh
                            and bone of our bone, One with the Father only through His Oneness with us,has never been
                            really absent from any of us, however much our eyes may be blinded to His presence, this
                            same Jesus visited Mother Ann in prison. He conveyed to her mind with clearness and
                            conviction that measure of Divine Truth embodied in the Christ Ideal which her
                            consciousness,developed as it had been by sin, suffering and aspiration,was enabled to grasp
                            and pass on to her follows. She was permitted to see in clear and open vision, she tells us,
                            the root and foundation of human depravity, "the very act of transgression committed by Adam
                            and Eve in the Garden of Eden,"which we may, in the light of later development, take to mean
                            that her mind was opened to the fact that all the ills that flesh is heir to, all the vices
                            and crimes that afflict humanity, disease and death itself, may be traced to selfishness,
                            and mostly to that form of selfishness called lust; to the man's subjection to his will and
                            pleasure, by brute force and not by love, of the woman on whose perfect purity, through
                            perfect freedom, the very life of the race depends. Ann saw and understood this plainly,
                            since it was through this subjection that her own womanhood had been despoiled and
                            defiled,and, seeing this, it is not to be wondered at surely that she saw nothing more. To
                            her literal mind, what more there was to be shownthe more known to Shelley and Godwin, and
                            Mary Wolstonecraftwould have been incomprehensible and confusing. It was as essential to the
                            success of her great mission to humanity that she should not see all, as that she should see
                            and feel what she did with all her heart and all her mind and all her soul. To her this was
                            the basis of the existing social system; it was what her husband called love, what her
                            father and her mother and brothers and sisters upheld, what the law allowed and the Church
                            sanctioned. She had never known any other sort of lovenever known real love ! Ann Lee went
                            forth from prison filled with the godlike resolution to give her life, at any and all costs,
                            to the one glorious cause of man's redemption. Thenceforth she lived only to bring sinners
                            to a realization of their sins and to lead them through the gate of repentance into the
                            regenerated life of the purified and the free. The intrepid Joan of Arc went forth at the
                            head of her defeated and discouraged countrymen to meet the victorious and confident armies
                            of the invaders ; but she had at her back the king and the people of her native land and
                            their recognition that God was with her. Picture to yourselves the magnificent courage, the
                            unfaltering faith, the sublime heroism of this one poor <pb n="112" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/>
                            112 THE MANIFESTO. English woman, as she went forth to battle for the freedom of the race
                            against an institution guarded and upheld by the banded forces of the civilized world.
                            Truly, she had to contend, not merely with the armies of a foreign enemy, but with the far
                            more formidable foes of her own household. Ignorance and prejudice, law and custom, property
                            rights and vested interests, the passions of the mob, the scorn and oppression of the
                            powerful. Aye more, she was called to do battle with the principalities and powers of
                            darkness. But she had seen the Master, had received her mission, knew God was on her side,
                            and was not afraid. In preaching the gospel of purity, she thereafter delivered her
                            testimony against lustful indulgence as the source of all human corruption and misery with a
                            mighty spiritual power. The little flock of Shaking Quakers who now called her to their
                            leadership and lovingly hailed her as "Mother Ann," were strangely stirred in their
                            meetings, singing, dancing, shaking and shouting, speaking with strange tongues and
                            prophesying. All the gifts of the spirit known in the Pentecostal Church were manifested by
                            them and were continued increasingly until the full establishment of the church in America,
                            as indeed, they continue among her followers to this day. During the next four years she
                            preached in England, and with her followers was repeatedly mobbed and imprisoned. Once she
                            was put on trial before an Ecclesiastical Court charged with blasphemy, and threatened with
                            branding on the cheeks and boring of the tongue, if she did not justify her claims to
                            spiritual gifts. The learned divines who constituted her judges testified that she spoke
                            with strange eloquence for four hours of the wonderful works of God, strengthening her
                            arguments with quotations from the Hebrew and the Greek scriptures, from Latin, French,
                            Italian and Spanish authors, and discoursing fluently in every ancient and modern tongue
                            known to them, and in many they did not know. She was acquitted by the Court; but this
                            verdict only enraged the waiting mob, who cried out for her death. Taking Mother Ann with
                            three of her followers to a field outside the town, they bound their limbs, and pelted them
                            with stones. To their consternation, not one of the stones they cast hit the mark, and in
                            the confusion that followed their design was abandoned. While the people were throwing
                            stones, Mother Ann's soul was filled with love and she felt herself surrounded by the
                            presence of God. "I knew they could not kill me," she said, "for my work was not done !" (To
                            be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The greatest men..." TEIform="index"/>The greatest men... </head><p TEIform="p">The greatest men are the most believing; to believe only what we can understand,
                            or what meets our present views, is infatuated foolishness; for no man starts in life with
                            full views; while the higher he mounts, the wider is the horizon.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dawson, G." TEIform="persName"/>G. Dawson.</byline></div2><pb n="113" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Remarks of mother Lucy Wright, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>REMARKS OF MOTHER LUCY
                            WRIGHT, NO. 2.</head><p TEIform="p">HOW" much easier it is to live in a cheerful, joyous spirit which is refreshing
                            to both soul and body, than to let a heavy, moody feeling prevail. It is so easy and so
                            clever to be good, that we will be good, but it is so repulsive to be bad, that we will not
                            be bad." Then in the tenderness of a Mother, she dismissed us, saying, she should not
                            dismiss us from being good. If all realized their faith and privilege, it would be easy to
                            feel thankful; but there is so much darkness, it is difficult to penetrate it. There is a
                            pleasant way to be thankful, that is, to be humble. If a soul really feels humble, and
                            realizes the tender mercy of God, he will be thankful. A great deal of darkness comes from
                            an unreconciled mind. Some persons feel that they are above the simple ways of being and
                            doing good. The gospel is meek and simple, and none are too old or too young to serve God.
                            Brethren and Sisters, we wish you to keep in remembrance, that the gospel is ever new, it
                            will not grow old neither will it fade away. All who are faithful to take up their crosses
                            against the undisciplined rulings of the mind will feel, increasing satisfaction in the
                            newness of their lives. To attain this, we must maintain the union of the Spirit, in the
                            bond of peace. There must be union in the Spirit, Brethren with Brethren, Sisters with
                            Sisters and Brethren and Sisters together. Short of this, the gospel is not fulfilled in its
                            requirements. Those advanced in years need the gospel of our Savior as much as those of
                            younger years and the young as much as the aged. When we feel unhappy and unsatisfied in our
                            desires we should examine our hearts, to know if our minds are subject to the spirit of God
                            in all things. Mother Lucy felt great anxiety that Believers realize the great privilege
                            which is theirs, to live a life of holiness unto God, and the merciful way in which they
                            rest compared with the people of God, in past ages. She often exhorted us to maintain our
                            faith with integrity for, said she, you are under binding obligations to keep unbroken your
                            covenant with God and with each other. It is your duty to set a godly example before those
                            of less experience in ways of virtue. How do we expect to reach Heaven, or to gain our
                            salvation? There is so much to take up the mind and lead it astray, that it seems almost
                            impossible to find God on the earth. We plunge into the business of life, and our whole
                            being becomes so engrossed in temporal things and the cares of this world that we can hardly
                            find time to think of our souls. The time however will come, when we must give an account of
                            our stewardship. May we all so improve our day that we may do it with joy and not with
                            grief. Mother Lucy exhorted us to a greater degree of thankfulness. We certainly have great
                            cause to be thankful above all creatures, and are accountable to God for these blessings we
                            enjoy. If we are unthankful for our daily <pb n="114" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 114 THE
                            MANIFESTO. and abundant blessings, we are not followers of Christ. The spiritual and
                            temporal blessings which we enjoy are the gifts of Heaven to us, we can not call one of them
                            our own and we are not certain of them from day to day. Those things which the earth brings
                            forth are of the earth, and will yet return to its own. We can not make one plant grow
                            though we sow with great care ; it is God who giveth the increase. It is our duty to humble
                            ourselves in the sight of God, that our judgment may be taken away. Let the soul seek God's
                            mercy in humiliation before it is too late, and while we may be heard; if we are not humble
                            and cry to God in our need, we may yet cry and not be heard. If we trust to our great
                            privilege and experience, we trust in something which will fail us. Remember a haughty
                            spirit goeth before a fall. I hope we shall not be unthankful in the midst of plenty, with a
                            fullness of spiritual and temporal blessings on every hand. Many precious promises are given
                            to the faithful. Some, being darkened, think that the gospel is not sufficient to save them.
                            The gospel is not at faul', it is sufficient to save every soul that will obey it. If we
                            obtain the precious blessings that are promised to the willing and obedient, we must gain
                            them. We make our heaven. All who are true will realize the blessing of God. God forbid that
                            we glory, save in the cross of Christ. We must be what we profess to be, and profess to be
                            what we really are. Do not glory in a profession for it will not save you. We shall appear
                            just what we are when we enter eternity. Mother Lucy seemed to feel great anxiety for the
                            children. She would often speak of the great responsibility their guardians were under to
                            care for their daily welfare, their protection; the example before them, the language used
                            to them; all this should be the burden of those who care for them. She would speak
                            particularly to the children and youth, saying, "You are young ; your youth is the best and
                            easiest time for you to learn to serve God. I wish you could realize this. I pray for you
                            often for I feel the burden of your salvation, and desire you to live a life of uprightness.
                            Those who are called by the good Spirit in their youth should often return thanks to God
                            that they are thus noticed of their heavenly Father. If you do not want to do wrong, then
                            you will do right, for the master we love, we serve. The gospel requires no more than is
                            just, and you must part with all that is contrary to its requirements. I do believe that
                            every one who can sense it will be thankful that they have found the blessing of God that
                            will separate them from all evil and make them acceptable before God. Love begets love. I
                            have that love for poor, lost souls that I would suffer in their stead, if this were
                            possible. If we love the gospel we shall obey it, and if we truly love God we shall serve
                            Him. (To be continued.)</p></div2><pb n="115" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. JULY, 1896. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by
                            the "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religijus views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all
                            communications to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. TERMS. One copy one year,
                            postage paid. .50</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. May. Thermometer. Bain. 1895. 57.35 3 in.
                                1896. 61.71 2.25 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 86 above 0 Lowest " " " " 38 " ' Number
                                of rainy days " " 6 " clear " " " 11 " " cloudy" " " 14 C. G. Reed. North Family. June,
                                1896. I ask the pleasure of a visit with dear Brethren and Sisters to whom my mind goes
                                out in loving interest. In the growing west, the sunny south, and the rugged east, there
                                have been homes reared by consecrated toil; may these be sustained and kept inviolate,
                                by those who hold the sacred inheritance. Puiity of life, honesty integrity, and non
                                indebtedness in business relations with the world, these are the strongholds of
                                Christian Communism. Without close adherence to these, there comes loss and failure.
                                Under good Br. Levi's supervision and thoroughness the farm is regaining its fertility.
                                Rye and oats, of which many acres are planted, are looking splendid. Brother Ezra and
                                the boys keep the gardens in good condition. The stock are well kept and the young fowls
                                are growing finely, but one chick lost out of a hundred hatched. We fear a meagre supply
                                of small fruit this season; no sweet cherries or plums, but few pears and quinces, apple
                                trees blossomed full, and fruit has set nicely. Our blackberry patch looks as though a
                                fall of snow had settled upon it. On the afternoon of the 3rd inst. there was a school
                                picnic in the orchard by the school house, to which all were invited. Sr. Grace Brown,
                                the teacher, arranged an interesting program. The young people played games, and at six
                                p. m. refreshments were served. The time passed pleasantly until seven o'clock, when the
                                company dispersed. Martha /. Anderson. Center Family. June 11, 1898. We repeat the same
                                old story of very dry weather. In this section we consider the drought for the past two
                                months to be unparalleled for the season of the year still the crops are looking finely,
                                taken as a whole. Cherries, pears and plums will be almost a total failure; where we
                                have had a hundred bushels there will not be five. The strawberries are coming in
                                nicely. Since our last Home Notes we have taken in a young man on probation and we hope
                                he will do well. Ministry returned to their Central Home two weeks ago yesterday. Health
                                of our people pretty fair. Timothy D. Ray son.</p></div3><pb n="116" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. June, 1896. The month of roses has arrived and is refreshed by
                                beautiful showers, the last day of May giving us the most abundant rain that we have had
                                since the advent of warm weather. The warble of the birds is music that to one whose
                                interior life is rightly attuned gives tones that are free from discordant vibrations
                                and cause us to feel that they are the earthly counterpart of the music of the spheres.
                                As we write we hear the cheerful notes of a pair of Orioles that have nested in a tree
                                near our window and of our summer birds they can be classed with the most useful as they
                                are great destroyers of injurious worms and insects. We may have placed our
                                anticipations higher than at present can be realized, but when we read of those
                                heretical burnings we could not help asking, can it be possible that the closing years
                                of the nineteenth century is to witness the revival of that monster of theological
                                bigotry and it has again showed its form! The destruction of life and property that has
                                latelj been caused by those devastating storms that have swept over different sections
                                of our country, causes our feelings to go out in sympathy for the afflicted, and
                                thankfulness that we have been protected. Hamilton DeOraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1896. Not in the recollection of the oldest members of our Society has
                                there been such a confluence of unwelcome life, as was manifest in the unfolding foliage
                                of our fruit trees and shrubbery this spring. Woven among the leaves and blossoms was
                                the vail webbing of the insect commonly called the apple-worm. Appearances indicated
                                they had come to stay, but some of us thought otherwise. Accordingly, with poles, tar
                                and kerosene oil, fourteen Sisters and four Brethren invaded their chosen homes making
                                sad havoc, not only of their nests, but of themselves also. How they regarded our
                                intrusion will never be known: possibly they look upon us in the same light that the
                                poor Armenians do the cruel Turks. We were able to combine much pleasure with our
                                disagreeable business, that of partaking of our dinner and supper at the sugar-camp,
                                where two hundred and forty-two gallons of syrup was made the past season. The loftiness
                                of our position which gave us an excellent opportunity to view the picturesque landscape
                                about us, which, inspires the mind with a love for the Infinite goodness of our Maker
                                and when incorporated into the characters of human beings, broadens and strengthens the
                                intellectual faculties, and transmutes all low instincts into spiritual forces that
                                deify life, and cause the soul to worship only at the shrine of its ideal Spirit of
                                truth and holiness. George H. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1896. The beautiful month of June has rolled around with its warm days
                                and bright sunshine. May was cold, with very little rain and the hay crop will no doubt
                                be light as the grass, at this writing, is indeed very thin and short. Many of the
                                farmers in our vicinity are planting large fields of fodder corn to feed their stock on
                                another winter. Some of the Brethren have recently completed sawing about sixty M.
                                shingles, while others were engaged on the farm and garden. Sisters have about 1000 ft.
                                of sweet peas now under cultivation. On the 5th inst. the Brethren and Sisters of this
                                place visited the "waste places of Zion" and made them beautiful by picking up and
                                taking care of the debris and at noon we had a fine picnic dinner, served under the
                                shady trees at the North end of our brick dwelling. This had been <pb n="117" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MA NIFtiS TO. 117 planned as a Decoration day celebration, but
                                the rain prevented, thus the postponement. We are anticipating a pleasant visit with
                                good Father Abraham Perkins and our beloved Editor of The Manifesto Elder Henry C.
                                Blinn. Ada S. G'ummings.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear -----;--The Believers in that state..." TEIform="index"/>Dear
                            -----;--The Believers in that state...</head><p TEIform="p">[Elder Louis Basting who has been on a visit to Florida writes,-Ed.]Dear- - - -
                            -;The Believers in that state are pleasantly situated by the shores of the lake, and the
                            location is very healthful. The house of course, is in an unfinished state but quite
                            comfortable. It serves its purpose as a temporary habitation quite well. The permanent
                            dwelling is to be erected upon a ridge about two miles or more from here. This ridge is
                            covered with a heavy growth of trees and underwood. The work of clearing it has been started
                            and is quite heavy work. The soil is rich and the new railroad is to come within one mile of
                            the place. It is really astonishing to observe the amount of work these lew Brethren have
                            accomplished in one year's time. None of them have been sick at any time, and they are
                            living very well. Their table is profusely supplied, chiefly with productions of their own.
                            Something is growing ready for use the year round. They had everything to learn;the nature
                            of the different soils and the best season to plant the different fruits and vegetables. It
                            seems to me that Florida is a land well suited to people of moderate expectations and who
                            are willing to work and earn their support. The land is cheap and the taxes very low. In
                            Hancock about 1500 are annually paid for taxes, here they are less than $20. And then there
                            is a glorious climate whose value can not be estimated by dollars. Fish can be had in
                            abundance out of the lake. Calla lilies are blooming now, April 16th, out of doors. The lake
                            water is quite pure and good to drink. The well water has a slight sulphurous taste, like a
                            medicinal spring. I like it, while many people prefer rain water. Dairying can be made a
                            source of profit here, but the chief source of income will be from fruits and vegetables.
                            The finest hotels are located in Florida, where the Sisters would probably find a market for
                            their fancy goods. There is talk of having a wind mill to pump water from the lake for
                            irrigation. I have helped the Brethren some about gardening and grubbing, and feel decidedly
                            better than when I left home. Of course there are some unpleasant things to be met with here
                            as well as anywhere else. There are alligators and snakes and mosquitoes, and the half wild
                            pigs may bring some fleas. But these can all be controlled. The Shaker domain extends over
                            twelve square miles of land, not including the lakes. So the residents, present and
                            prospective, have pleuty of room. Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Basting, Louis" TEIform="persName"/>Louis Basting.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Few days from home" TEIform="index"/>A FEW DAYS FROM HOME.</head><p TEIform="p">June 25, 1896. Elder Abraham Perkins and the writer left home on the 10th inst
                            and taking the cars at Lakeport, a distance of fourteen miles from Shaker Village, found
                            ourselves before the close of the day in the old city of Rochester, N. H. The Wrisley Hotel
                            was accepted as our home during our sojourn, and the attention and care afforded us was very
                            pleasant. From this j)lace we take the cars to Alfred, and were very kindly met at the
                            station by Elder Henry G. Green. From this station to the Shaker Village was a pleasant ride
                            of two miles, but for a short distance was fearfully near the Railroad. The home of the
                            Alfred Believers is on the western hill-side, and the view of the surroundings can but make
                            all hearts glad, as does most of the scenery of our New England states. The highway passes
                            through the village from south to north <pb n="118" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 118 TRE
                            MANIFESTO. and the larger part of the buildings are on the west side of the road. All the
                            buildings situated near the highway are painted white and trimmed with green blinds. Those
                            more distant are of a darker shade. The farm at this place is hard to till on account cf the
                            liberal supply of granite boulders that have been strewn broadcast throughout this section.
                            A nice herd of stock is kept at this place and most of the milk is sent to the station every
                            morning. A silo of more than 100 tons is one of the progressive features of the New England
                            farmer, and we were interested to hear the Br. Herdsman say that it was highly appreciated.
                            Very handsome cattle with white faces are the most common, and one farmer who was driving a
                            pair of steers through the village, invited the Brethren to come out and see his beauties.
                            At the dairy we saw a large separator and a barrel churn. The machinery was operated by a
                            gasoline engine the whole management of which is under the charge of the Sisters. A visit to
                            the school-house was very pleasant and Eldress Fannie very kindly gave us every attention.
                            The pupils are amply supplied with every convenience for an education and all encouragement
                            given to promote their progress. The blackboards were large glass plates, held to the walls
                            by suitable frames. The great variety of fancy work manufactured at this place makes a
                            beautiful exhibition, and many trips to the White Mountains and to the Hotels at the ocean
                            resorts are required to make the desirable changes, that convert these treasures into gold
                            and silver. A ride around the Massabesic Lake, with Elder Henry afforded us a rare
                            opportunity of seeing more of the beautiful landscape. A drive to the village of Alfred also
                            afforded us the privilege of visiting the new Court House. We were met very pleasantly by
                            several of the officers present and many pages would be required to illustrate the beautiful
                            rooms through which we were escorted by the very polite and affable janitor. After a visit
                            of three days with our beloved gospel friends, through whom we shared many blessings and
                            every attention of gospel care, we were taken in a carriage by Elder Henry, a distance of 18
                            miles to Old Orchard. Here we make a tarry of one day. On the 18th we reach the station at
                            New Gloucester, a distance of six miles from the Shaker Village. Elder William Dumont is at
                            the station with a carriage, and we are soon on the road to his beautiful home,on the
                            hill-side, at the foot of which on the east is that lovely sheet of water that bears the
                            name of Sabbathday Lake. The farm at Gloucester is easy of cultivation and makes ample
                            returns for all the labor bestowed upon it. The family garden is on the hill- side west of
                            the Village in which may be found a liberal variety of food plants, and all under good
                            cultivation. At the north end of this same enclosure, the Sisters have about 1000 ft. of
                            sweet peas, and also a large \ ariety of other flowers. The larger part of these flowers are
                            arranged into pretty bouquets and sold at the Hotel at Poland Springs, which is some three
                            miles north of the Shaker Village. The Believers at this place have a beautiful brick
                            dwelling which is very handsomely finished and furnished from attic to cellar. A tank
                            holding some 500 gall, is in the attic and amply supplies the whole house. A steam engine of
                            six horse power carries the machinery that is used in the laundry and essentially reduces
                            the burden of washing. A visit to the barn shows readily, the attention that is given to the
                            stock and the care and kindness that holds rule over the dumb animals. Every Shaker Village
                            should be a "Band of Mercy" and all the creatures should be treated with great kindness. An
                            hour spent at the school-house was a season of much interest and the recita- <pb n="119" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 119 tions and singing by the pupils afforded much
                            satisfaction. On the highest point of land near the Village, the Brethren have anticipated
                            the finding of a better supply of water for domestic purposes. Machinery for drilling a six
                            inch hole is in operation and they have already readied a depth of 30 or more feet, but as
                            yet no water has been found. We visit the glass house and see some beautiful plants. The
                            building of the frame, furnace and chimney are wholly the work of the Brethren. It is about
                            60 ft. long and 15 ft. wide. A visit to Poland Springs with Elder William gave us the
                            pleasure of seeing that wonderful health resort which accommodates not less than 500 guests.
                            The water at this place is said to bepure and this with the beautiful surroundings is quite
                            enough to inspire health in those who are privileged to reside in this mountain home. The
                            Main State Building which was erected in Chicago at a cost of $18,000 has been safely
                            removed to Poland, and again rebuilt, and now contains a beautiful Library, a room for
                            mounted botanical specimens that are to be gathered within a distance of three miles from
                            Poland Springs. An art gallery will in the near future be one of the choice attractions and
                            the workmen were already engaged in the work. Through the kindness of the proprietors we
                            were escorted over the "Poland Spring House," and the journey fell but little short of a
                            trip to "Wonderland." The beautiful dining-room for the guests, a smaller one for the little
                            folks, and then another as neat as a parlor for the large company of workmen, and of this
                            class there were but a few less than one hundred. We passed through the laundry and ironing
                            rooms which are amply furnished with the best of machinery, and with the best of
                            workmen,then througl: the bakery and cooking department^ where the men and women were
                            arrayed in garments "clean and white," and had it been ascension day, we might have thought
                            they were preparing to reach their mansion in the skies. Mr. Edward Ricker very pleasantly
                            took us under escort for a short time and pointed out many things of deep interest, but it
                            would require pages if we were to relate the one half we saw while on our visit to Poland
                            Springs. On our return to the little family at New Gloucester, we again enter the loved
                            circle of our gospel relation, whose interest and whose cares and burdens are shared by our
                            whole Community. In the temporal and spiritual blessings our union was with all that adds
                            new life to make of us a Brotherhood and Sisterhood that are working for the good of
                            humanity.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>Henry C. Blinn.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Milk as a diet" TEIform="index"/> MILK AS A DIET.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A medical, man expresses the belief that a person could live
                                        for any length of time and take heavy exercise all the whiie on no other food
                                        than sweet milk. His conviction is the result of personal experiment. He wanted
                                        to establish the fact that persons convalescing fro in sickness may grow
                                        stronger with no other nutriment than sweet milk, and that they are not obliged
                                        to take "something solid" to eat, as so many people imagine. He holds that many
                                        a convalescent has gone into his grave as a result of overtaxing his weak
                                        stomach by putting "solid" food into it; and he maintains that the old belief as
                                        to bread being the first essential of human life is shown by his experiments to
                                        be erroneous. His test was to live thirty days with only sweet milk as a
                                        nourishment. In the whole time he lost five and a half pounds in weight, but no
                                        strength. He even attributes the loss of weight to the warmth of the weather and
                                        to excessive exercise on the bicycle and the daily manipulation of sixteen-pound
                                            <pb n="120" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 120 THE MANIFESTO. dumb-bells and other
                                        heavy weights. He took more exercise than usual, in order to test the thing
                                        fairly. On the seventh day of the experiment he ran several fast races with a
                                        skillful runner, and was beaten in each race. On the thirtieth day he again
                                        pitted himself against the same runner and did the best of the racing, which
                                        certainly would tend to confirm his statement that he lost no strength during
                                        the thirty days' test. He drank four pints of milk daily for the last week. He
                                        thinks a healthy person should take about five pints of milk daily when no other
                                        food is being taken. His practice was to drink milk at intervals of two hours
                                        during the day, commencing at 1 o'clock in the morning and continuing until 10
                                        at night. After that he would take no more until next morning.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York Commercial Advertiser" TEIform="index"/>New York
                                        Commercial Advertiser.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Frying, by which is usually meant..." TEIform="index"/>Frying, by which
                                is usually meant... </head><p TEIform="p">Frying, by which is usually meant the fashionable process of preparing food
                                in fat and grease is always objectionable. In general, we cook too much and cook
                                erroneously. Seasonings for food if applied at all, should never be applied till ' the
                                food is on the table. There is a good story told of a foreigner at a table in New York,
                                one man had besprinkled the plate of meat with pepper, saying,at the same time, "I take
                                it gentleman, you all like pepper." Another added some mustard with the same assurance
                                and the same remark. The foreigner, not a little vexed, took out his snuff-box, and in
                                his turn sprinkled its contents on the food, saying. "I take it gentleman, you all like
                                snuff."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Alcott" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Alcott.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whichever way" TEIform="index"/>
                            WHICHEVER WAY.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">[Contributed by J. Sullivan Wright.]
                                    Whichever way the wind doth blow Some heart is glad to have it
                                    so, Then blow it east or blow it west, The wind that blows, that wind is best. My
                                    little craft sails not alone; A thousand fleets from every zone Are out upon a
                                    thousand seas; And what for me were favoring breeze Might dash another, with the
                                    shock Of doom, upon some hidden rock. And so I do not dare to pray For winds to waft
                                    me on my way, But leave it to a Higher Will To stay or speed me,trusting still That
                                    all is well, and sure that He Who launched my bark will sail with me Thro' storm and
                                    calm, and will not fail, Whatever breezes may prevail, To land meevery peril past
                                    Within His sheltering heaven at last. Then whatsoever wind doth blow Some heart is
                                    glad to have it so. And blow it east or blow it west, The wind that blows, that wind
                                    is best.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Woman's Record" TEIform="index"/> .</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is all-important..." TEIform="index"/>It is all-important...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"It is all-important that you speak the truth when you do speak,
                                    but the fact that it is the truth which you speak is not the only important factor
                                    in your speaking. You must speak the truth in love, in love of the truth, and in
                                    love of the person to whom you speak, for unless you are loving and speak lovingly,
                                    you may have less power for good than one who speaks in that spirit without speaking
                                    the truth. The truth itself suffers in contrast with love-mixed error when the
                                    element of love is lacking in the declaration of truth."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Some individuals build themselves..." TEIform="index"/>Some individuals build themselves...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Some individuals build themselves upon the ruins of other peoples' characters.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rushmore, Henry" TEIform="index"/>Henry Rushmore
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Henry Rushmore, at West Pittsfield, Mass. May 20, 1896. Age 61 yrs. 10 mo.
                                and 4 days. I. E. L. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manluff, Mary" TEIform="index"/>Mary Manluff
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mary Manluff, at Philadelphia, Penn. June 6, 1896. Age 84 yrs. and
                                9 days. Sr. Mary had been a member of the Order for 10 years, and was beloved by all. W.
                                W. G.</p></div3></div2>
                    <!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
statements of this writer. One of the most
charming instances connected with the publication of Dr. Stebbin's volume, is the re.
view of it by Prof. Toy of Cambridge Divinity
school.
One of the leading features of the seventh
annual Recreation Number of The Outlook,
just issued, is a collection of spirited and
exciting true short stories under the genera,
title "Thrilling Moments." Dr. Parkhurst re.
lates an adventure in mountaineering, Dr Van
Dyke one in fishing, General Greely one of
war times, Mr. C. F. Lummis one in Western
life, Mr Poultney Bigelow in canoeing, Mr.
Walter Camp in football playing, and so on.
Eleven "Moments" in all are recalled, and
they are admirably illustrated by the well
known artist Dan Beard. Another out-of-door
feature deals with "Photography on the
Heights," and includes articles on Greenland
by the famous explorer, Lieutenant Peary,
Switzerland by Madame Gozzaldi, and the
Far Northwest by W. D. Lyman; the illustrations are numerous and excellent. 
"The Spectator Awheel" gives an entertaining account
of bicycle trips about New York4 and shows
what may be done with a wheel and a kodak
in the way of having a good time with neither
expense nor great exertion. "The Real
Broadway" describes by text and picture the
lovely rural English village where Mr. Abbey,
Mr Millet, and other American artists have
done much of their best work. Ian Maclaren's
novel continues to give humorous pictures of
Scotch life. A useful article for reference
and information is that giving dates and facts
about conventions, anniversaries, summer
schools, and other coming events. An illustrated review of the just-published "Life and
Letters of Oliver Wendell Holmes" occupies
the principal place among the book reviews.
The editorial departments are full, and give
the weekly history of current events with impartial comment for which The OutlodkIs
noted. ($3. a year. The Outlook Company,
13 Astor Place, New York.)
"The June Skies" receive the first notice in
Word and Works for this beautiful summer
month and of which so many good things are
said. The illustrated heavens have for our
instruction and pleasure a lesson such as
God only could present. Nothing less than
a "wonderful law" could hold these worlds in
mid air, and guide them safely through the
heavens.
The stoim diagram for June was not quite
so furious as for May, and we shall appreciate
the mild improvement. This forecast of
weather changes comes fearfully close to the
prediction, but we are forced to accept it.
The two pages devoted to Practical notes,
are very interesting,  and will  awaken new
lines of thought for a large class of readers.
Every department of Word and Works
abounds with matters of interest from which
every class of readers will gather much valuable information.
WHAT   HAVE   I   DONE?
[Julie M. Lippmann, in The Sunday School Times
of April 11, 1896.]   \
Day after day Heaven, listening, hears men
cry:
"What have I done that such a fate as this
Should follow me? What have I done amiss
That clouds of care should darken all my sky?
That Pain should pierce, and that shrewd
Poverty
Should pinch me in that grievous grip of his,
What time I tremble over the abyss,
And long for death, yet, longing, dare not die?
But when does Heaven, listening, hear men
say:
"What have I done that in the blue-domed
skies
The evening star should shine, the spring
clouds move,
The world be white with innocence, that May
Has set afield, and God in children's eyes
To win our hearts to wonder at his love?
"Mount Lebanon Cedar Boughs" is the title
of a beautiful book of poems sent out by the
North Family of Shakers. The poems have
been written from time to time by members
of this spiritual family, They impress one
with the clean, sweet and soul pure influence
of these good men and women, who are doing
so much in a quiet, unselfish way for the welfare of humanity. One can not read these
spiritual poems without being the better for
it. The book is for sale by the North Family
of Shakers, Mt. Lebanon, Columbia County,
N. Y. Price $1.00; 314 pages.From, the World's
Advance Thought.
m shaker
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS    OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES  and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION     AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
the same time, afford instruction to all inquiring  minds.    Price 5  cts. each,  postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
COVENANT
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
Largest circulation of any scientific paper In t'ae
world. Splendidly illustrated. No iiitellijfpnt
man should be without it. Weekly, ftS.OOa
year; $1.50 six months. Address, MTJ'NN & CO,,
Publishers, 361 Broadway, New York City.
For information and free Handbook write to
MUNN & CO., 361 Broadway, New York.
Oldest bureau for securing patents in America.
Every patent taken out by us is brought .before
the public by a notice given free of charge iu the
AND
SHAKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the United   Society  of   Believers  in   Christ's
Second Appearing.    Illustrated.
By Giles B. Ayery.
Price,  15cts.
A cream of tartar  baking   powder.
Highest of all in leavening strength.
Latest   United   States   Government
Food report.
Eoyal Baking Powder Co., New York.
WANTED
Good reliable men, to sell
our Choice and Hardy
Nursery Stock such as Fruit
Trees, Roses Shrubs and Ornamentals. Ladies make this business a success. 
Easy work, pleasant, light and profitable. Outfit Free. Apply at once, with references, and secure choice of territory.
F N.  MAY   COMPANY,
IINTtii-serymen  and.   Seedsmen,   Rochester, N. Y.
BBIEF EXPOSITION
OF  TEE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
"INTERPRETING PROPHECY"
AND  THE
"Appearing of Christ,"
is the title of a neat little pamphlet of
some forty pages, just sent out by A. G.
Hollister of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
The many at the present time who are
interested in the fulfillment of prophecy
and in its mathematical calculation, will
find themselves by the side of the good
old prophet Daniel, and with him illustrating the Coming of Christ so clearl
that no occasion can arise for the least
doubt.                             Price, 10 cts.
Tea and Coffee Pots that pour by the lid without lifting or tipping.     Simple beyond belief.
Practical and artistic.   Send for pamphlet.
THE ASBURY-PAINE MFQ. CO., Phila., Pa.
Thia i* a good thingEd.
POUR
By Pressing the Lid.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>