<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0305" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><date value="18730501" TEIform="date">May 1873</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">33-40</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="33" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
                    <p>Vol. III. No. 5. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. MtLebanon, Col. Co. N. Y. May, 1873 Fifty Cents per annum.
                        EXCHANGES. PUBLICATION OFFICE, MT. LEBANON, N. Y. ADDRESS SHAKER & SHAKERESS, Not F. W. Evans.</p>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mediator, part II" TEIform="index"/>MEDIATOR. PART II</head><p TEIform="p">That system, institution, or individual, who possesses the most light and truth and the
                            purest inspiration, is the best prepared for, and the nearest to, the " kingdom of heaven."
                            To such were the oracles and promises and prophecies committed. The children of Abraham, by
                            natural generation, had many important advantages over those whose parents disregarded the
                            natural sciences that were practically operative in the Mosaic economy — godly agriculture
                            and physiological knowledge relative to nutrition and reproduction — that has no parallel in
                            history. "The land is mine, saith the Lord" — the Hebrew God. And the priesthood divided the
                            land to each tribe, family, and person; while the historian of the future, — the Prophet, —
                            caused the " meek to inherit the earth," and allotted to each one a " vine and a fig-tree "
                            growing thereupon. The Jew gloried in his superior physical organization; but his eyes were
                            inverted, turned back, while staying himself upon the spiritual gifts of his ancients, — the
                            saints, Prophets and Prophetesses, Noah, Abram, Moses, Elias or John the Baptist,— and upon
                            their wonderful works, great faith, and their sufferings and self-denial, yet he exalted
                            their personalities just as the same spirit to-day exalts Jesus and Ann. " Whom makest thou
                            thyself? Art thou greater than our great ones ? " The Jew was blind, and " knew not" of the
                            saints and saviours then in Jerusalem. These had to be their own witnesses, by their works,
                            to which they appealed. Who worship the persons of the dead past will persecute the persons
                            of the living present. Idolaters "hate him who reproveth in the gate " of the new city that
                            is coming down fr'Tn God, through Christ, out of the inner heavens. It was their own doings
                            when the people of Israel, through faith in Moses and in the God of Israel, — the spiritual
                            Being who inspired him and constituted him God of Egypt, and of Pharaoh, its king — allowed
                            themselves to be led into a wilderness where there was none of the food to which they had
                            been accustomed, and they had the consequences to endure. The righteous were self-denying
                            with occasional murmurings and some backslidings. But they frequently rejoiced and triumphed
                            in the prowess of their great national guardian spirit, " their" God; while the rebellious,
                            during the " ten temptations" that befell them, often, in their hearts, turned back into
                            Egypt. They all died in the wilderness. Their progressed children, raised upon a vegetable
                            diet and under strict observance of the propagative law (common to all the inferior animal
                            creation), went into the land of Canaan under the guidance of the only two of the righteous
                            who remained, out of the million who came up out of Egypt. Could they have done any more
                            under the guidance and lead of the original million? Was not the end of their faith attained
                            ? Each individual did now "possess the land," they had their portion. They had also a
                            perfected order of generation. No money, no monopoly; neither speculation nor commerce;
                            riches nor poverty; merchant princes nor railroad kings. No rings nor Credit Mobiliers; no
                            police, nor magistrates, nor courts of justice, except the temple and its Levites. " Of
                            doctors " — quack or regular — Adam Clarke says " they had none; " for " the Lord their God
                            had taken from them all sickness," by keeping them from the causes that induce it. It was "
                            Church and State," with the Church left out. This Mosaic civil government bears the same
                            relation to the present worldly civil governments, that the Jewish Pentecostal primitive
                            Church bears to the present churches of Christendom. With the help of the " spirit of
                            prophecy," these two governments are straight edges, to show the crooked ways of Church and
                            State in Babylon. Worldly, selfish communism seeks to level wealth and poverty; to disband
                            the twenty million soldiers of civilization, by arbitration ; and to legislate the social
                            evil and drunkenness out of existence; when it is only the Christ Spirit that can accomplish
                            these good deeds, and give to mankind the Millennium. For the poor would gladly be rich, and
                            the slave would be pleased to become the slaveholder. From many babel pulpits the cry
                            ascends, Alas! alas ! ye are taking away our gods and our priests, and what shall we have
                            left ? Even the " Word of God — our holy Bible" — is undergoing revision! Is not this the
                            point when the "holy Inquisition should again come in, to exterminate heretics ? Can we not
                            get our Jewish fighting God, and our marriage-attending Saviour, " the chief Ruler of all
                            national conduct ; and the holy Bible, as the supreme Ruler of all national conduct" into
                            the Constitution of these United States, to save us ? "A tree is known by the fruit it
                            bears; " and, when any system of theology stimulates the evil passions of its advocates,
                            making them "hateful, and hate one another," (as they do all through the six hundred sects
                            of Christendom, and that too on mere points of belief) where both parties are wrong, is it
                            not evident to every honest, thinking mind, that these are believing the theology, and
                            practising " the doctrines of devils " ? They (each of them being a " natural enemy " to all
                            the rest) never agree, except (like Pilate and Herod) when it is to plot some mischief
                            against the only civil government on earth that does not interfere with liberty of
                            conscience ; and upon whose soil the profes- sors of all the thousand theologies of earth
                            can meet as human beings, in perfect equality. And, seeing that the Government of these
                            United States is not any more a Christian than it is a Mahometan, Hindoo, Jewish, or Chinese
                            government, any one of the thousand sects in the nation has the same right to put its God,
                            and Avator, and Bible, into the Con- stitution, as has any and every other one. How. much
                            better it would be, if they would " put away all sectarian bitterness, and wrath, and anger,
                            and clamor, and evilspeaking " against unbelievers, who do not "put bread into their
                            mouths," and learn to be " kind one to another, tender-hearted, forgiving one another," as
                            the best way to promote "pure andundefiled religion." Jesus and Ann said they were " the
                            way, the truth, and the life; " and, when persecuted for it, they proved it, by praying for
                            and doing good to their persecutors. Those persons of to-day who are anointed with the
                            Christ Spirit, and who bear the sins of the people, and minister the power of protection and
                            forgiveness, are as really Jesuses and Anns — Saviours — as were any persons in the past.
                            And we should feel as free to respect, honor and love them, as we think we should have
                            respected, honored, and loved those of former times, had we lived when they were upon earth.
                            " If ye had believed in Moses, ye would, also, have believed in me," for I obey Moses. The
                            spirit of antichrist leads to the worship of the man — the person of Jesus ; but denies
                            that, in our own time, the Christ has, or can " come in the flesh " of other persons, as
                            Mediators.</p></div2><pb n="34" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Treasure" TEIform="index"/>TREASURE</head><p TEIform="p">" Where your treasure is, there will your heart be also." — Matthew&gt; 6 :21. In
                            whatever we take an interest, wherever our affections are placed, to whatever object or
                            enterprise our feelings are attracted, and there we give our solicitude and care, there is
                            our heart and soul, there are our riches — treasures corresponding with the amount of
                            affection and labor bestowed. Such objects are liable to become idols, permanent idols of
                            the heart, gods of worship. Unto such, we infer philosophically, we give our strength and
                            support, not only while the soul is tabernacled in earth, but they being treasures of the
                            soul, we cling to them when mortality is put off. Is not man the mind ? Hence man is the
                            soul, which changes only as it becomes degraded and lowered, or as it finds progress. It is
                            therefore ignorance, or a weakness of the human heart, to suppose that physical death
                            converts the soul, and that then man becomes another, or a " new creature." " In the place
                            where the tree f alleth, there it shall be ;" and Job tells us, there is hope in it. The
                            mortal is dropped and cast off; the immortal eternally lives, and, wherever it exists, is
                            capable of the reception of increasing light, and consequently progress. Otherwise, why the
                            mission of Jesus to the souls of the departed, that " were disobedient in the days of Noah ?
                            " 1st Pet. 3 : 19. That service implies progress ; his mission was to preach salvation in
                            those prisons to the ignorant and wicked ; to enlighten them, elevate them, evincing that
                            they were capable of receiving his testimony, and also of being saved by it. Otherwise, the
                            mission of Jesus must have been not only fruitless, but foolish. Those antediluvians,
                            realizing their lost condition from disregard to the preaching of Noah, found justice
                            incorporated in the character of the Almighty, as He did not leave them in their ignorance,
                            without providing a means of rescue from wrath and judgments eternal, by and through the
                            saving Gospel of Jesus. Here they became interested in light, which attracted their minds ;
                            and they sought relief in giving their hearts to his testimony, which began to furnish their
                            souls with treasure. In this we see not only the wisdom, but the infinity of God, leaving
                            not even the prisons of darkness beyond the grave so closed as to prevent the visitation of
                            mercy, and thereby deprive the ignorant of light and means of protection. God, our Heavenly
                            Father and Mother, is a rational Being, just and merciful, abounding in every consistent
                            means to meet the rightful wants of his creatures ; so equitable in the distribution of
                            justice, that He will bestow nothing unearned, as a permanent blessing. His laws are
                            immutable: obeyed, they yield a just recompense, affording freedom of spirit, and
                            protection, and j ustification of soul; disobeyed, man reaps the fruit of condemnation, his
                            soul is brought into slavery, on every side his way becomes hedged, his path is strewed with
                            perplexing and troublesome obstacles, and his life is sold to bondage and suffering. Thus,
                            of all earthly means of rescue or relief he becomes stripped, he loseth the control of that
                            which he seemeth to have, and it becometh not his own; therefore even that which he hath not
                            is taken from him. Matthew 4: 24. Thus, left to himself to pay the utmost farthing for
                            transgression, he finds little, within or without, but weakness ; and, being robbed of
                            strength, the power of attraction acting upon goodness is measurably lost, and those
                            energies calculated for the exaltation of the soul, are still weaker for action. Man's only
                            alternative in this condition, however powerless and weak, is humiliation, and cries to the
                            God of Heaven for help. Eealizing, when brought to destitution, that salvation is not found
                            in an arm of flesh, he discovers that his only reliable strength is in God; his only refuge,
                            in heaven. His interest being awakened in that direction, he seeks a treasure there; and,
                            deriving an evidence of unfolding truths, his soul becomes convicted. Learning therefrom,
                            that Gospel riches are obtained only by sacrifice, only by closing the senses against the
                            admission of ungodly influences, giving no place in the heart to selfishness, allowing no
                            indulgence of appetite or passion that would stain his moral or religious purity — that
                            would animalize his soul or lower his condition or character in the sight of angels ; and
                            learning also that he is not his own, he resolves, whatever the circumstances, and however
                            great the sacrifice, to become a Christian, that his life and all pertaining thereunto must
                            be and shall be consecrated wholly and forever unto God and the maintenance of truth. This
                            is the " narrow way, and few there be who find it."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, A." TEIform="persName"/>Elder A. Perkins, Enfield, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Theology vs. religion" TEIform="index"/>THEOLOGY vs. RELIGION</head><p TEIform="p">Modern ideas and conceptions of Religion and Theology are so inextricably mixed and con-
                            founded together, by education and custom, that the terms seem identical, or synonymous, so
                            much so, that Theology has become surrounded with a halo of holiness, and is credited with
                            the generous and noble promptings of our better feelings, to the sanctification of the most
                            absurd and meaningless forms, formularies, and ceremonies in the worship of God. Theology is
                            of the intellect; while Religion has its root in the affections. " God is Love." Hence, "
                            pure and undefiled Religion," expresses itself in good works ; Theology, in words and
                            believings. Heligion is constantly seeking for more light, evolving new truths from all
                            sources, wherewith to benefit humanity, without any regard to creedal Theology. For her love
                            is universal — God expressing Itself through creation. Theology has installed herself as
                            dress-maker in chief to Religion. But Religion gives her a great deal of trouble, as she is
                            constantly outgrowing her raiment; nor will she be clothed by rule, or wear the costly
                            garments cut out for her, except for a short season. That which Religion plants, she soon
                            plucks up ; and that wliich she builds, in her next mode of change, she pulls down. While
                            Theology is stationary — stereotyped — always looking back, and going backward for
                            perfection. Theology insists that religion shall take the best of human souls to heaven, to
                            praise the Lord in glory, and sing psalms to all eternity. While Religion persists in
                            remaining upon earth, being intent upon redeeming its inhabitants ; is anxious about our
                            moral characters, and spiritual welfare; would fain look after our poor mortal bodies, and
                            save them from the doctors ; is deeply interested in the laws and rights of property, and in
                            a proper and equal disposal of land. She would gladly exterminate all the vices so prevalent
                            among mankind, and which produce armies and navies, that, in their turn, breed slavery,
                            poverty, and destitution of the elements of existence. When, by the inspiration of the
                            Almighty, Religion succeeds in elevating some one individual as a Reformer, Leader — a doer
                            of good — "above his fellows," like Noah, Abraham, Moses, Jesus, or Ann, back comes Theology
                            ingreat haste to " kill" and embalm the Avator, for all future generations, in coming ages,
                            to idolize and worship. Religion toils and works forever, to make us rational, comfortable,
                            and happy here. She would condescend to teach us what and how to eat, to dress, and sleep;
                            how to work, how to build well-lighted and ventilated houses and barns ; and how to
                            cultivate our land, so as not to raise disease-creating produce therefrom ; how to meet the
                            thousand and one conditions of life with common sense. But " Piety " becomes offended, and
                            old Theology is horrorstricken ; and so we languish to-day, vainly hoping for the " coming
                            man" (or woman), the opportunity of to-morrow. The world needs men and women whose hearts
                            are full to overflowing with religion, who will heed her behests; those who can walk the
                            streets of life nerved and unmoved, while the finger of ridicule is pointed at them ; when
                            malice, scorn, and misrepresentation assail them, who can forego — pass by — gold, pleasure,
                            and ambition, untainted, while loving and seeking to help and uplift humanity ; and who dare
                            to worship at other thrones than that of dead Theology. It was Theology, not Heligion, that
                            caused human beings to malign, persecute, burn, and crucify each other in the name of God or
                            Christ. It has not been Religion, but Theology, that has held and practised the " doctrines
                            of devils ;" sacrificing and embittering the lives of millions of earth's inhabitants.
                            Whereas, Religion molds the hearts of her adherents, in all races and nations, into a unity
                            of purpose and action, breathing peace and good-will, and recognizing the equal rights of
                            all peoples, and of both sexes. Thus, by its fruits, proving its Divine origin from the one
                            Fountain — God — who is Wisdom and Love. The Theology of a past cycle distracts the human
                            mind, by conflicting with the inspiration and revelation of the present cycle. It drives men
                            into antagonisms and animosities for mere difference of opinion ; making them " hateful, and
                            hating one another." It is the sensual gratification of the animal appetites and perverted
                            passions, so common among men and women, that causes the extreme ignorance of physical and
                            spiritual truths that almost everywhere abounds. Therefore it is, that " light is sown only
                            for the righteous"—those who practice selfdenial. Indeed, it is effete Theology — not
                            Religion — that is now seeking to restore the cruelty and horrors of the past " dark ages,"
                            by putting its imaginary Trinitarian God, and the man-made Bible, into the Constitution of
                            our common country. This insidious attack upon liberty all good citizens should unite to
                            resist and to counteract.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Thomas Smith, Canaan, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Generosity during life is a very different thing from generosity in the hour of death..." TEIform="index"/>Generosity during life is a very different thing from generosity in the hour of death...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Generosity during life is a very different thing from generosity in the hour of death ; one
                            proceeds from genuine liberty and benevolence ; the other from pride or fear.</p></div2><pb n="35" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker and shakeress" TEIform="index"/>"SHAKER AND SHAKERESS."</head><p TEIform="p">Many thanks and blessings on you, dear friends, for sending out into this benighted,
                            confused, strife-mongering, lust-polluted world your precious paper. Your pointed testimony
                            against selfishness, lust, and other vices, which the churches of the world tolerate, is
                            opening the eyes of honest truth-seekers, and strengthening and encouraging the weak and
                            faint, who have been made so by the high professing and low prejudices of those who claim to
                            be the Churches of Christ. Were it lot for the " Shaker and Shakeress," the rising
                            generation would grow up in ignorance of the true Christian spirit and principles, being
                            taught as they are, by their own divines, that God is a God of war; and that, instead of
                            being saved from sin and its consequences here, they must wallow on through filthiness till
                            death places them in better conditions. Thousands who have been seeking the truth, and have
                            sunk almost into despair at the practices of the fashionable churches, but know not where
                            else to look for good, are now blessing you for the plain truths and teachings sent forth to
                            them in your paper. For, while others are blinding and bewildering the world with creeds,
                            theories, and mysteries, which neither they nor anybody else understand, you are making the
                            highway of holiness so plain that a child may understand it. You confine or apply religion
                            to daily life. " Turn from that which is evil, and cleave to that which is good, in all your
                            thoughts, words and acts," is the true Christian and the true Shaker doctrine ; and, when
                            people obey, they will soon see the absurdity of sinning all their lives, and then asking to
                            be made clean and whole by the blood of one who died eighteen hundred years ago. We shall
                            all find just as much salvation from sin and its consequences, here and hereafter, as we
                            work for, and no more. The death of a thousand men called Jesus, or Christ, never will
                            entitle us to salvation, here or hereafter, one whit further than we possess in ourselves
                            the Spirit of Christ, and work it out in our daily lives. Teaching people that Christ
                            suffered for our sins, that we may spend our lives in transgression, and then, on our
                            death-beds, make a dodge by the devil, and land in heaven pure and perfect saints, all
                            fitted for immortal glory and happiness, is one of the greatest sins or errors ever
                            committed, as it gives liberty to travel through life in sin, and to enter, without pre-
                            paration, a state of existence whose very beginning requires that all the faculties and
                            powers of our souls should be trained to the highest perfection. If men had ever been taught
                            the great truth that salvation and happiness, here and hereafter, depends on our own
                            individual efforts in our daily lives to purify ourselves from all sin and wrong-doing, we
                            should now have a very different state of society. The " Shaker and Shakeress," is now
                            teaching these blessed truths ; and may the Father and Mother of all that is good, and all
                            the holy angels, aid in impressing the importance of these truths on the world, and the
                            Churches of the world, which a false theology has covered with almost Egyptian darkness. I
                            rejoice to see that you are bearing a testimony against putting God and Christ into the
                            Constitution, which would be opening the door for the union of Church and State, which would
                            finally lead to the rekindling of the fires of persecution, that were extinguished with the
                            tears and blood of millions of those who were the real salt and light of the earth, and, for
                            want of whose lighteous teachings, the world has been groping in spiritual darkness ever
                            since. Man, without a Divine spirit to control and guide him, is the same in all ages ; and,
                            if we give graceless priests, who believe in pauperhouses, prisons, the gallows, and in war,
                            power to lord it over the world, they will persecute those who cannot conscientiously
                            indorse them as severely now as did their brethren in the ages that have passed. And then,
                            what mockery, what rank blasphemy, to put the name of God, who is Love, and of Christ, " the
                            Prince of Peace," into the Constitution of a Government whose country is filled with forts,
                            arsenals, powder-houses, with a standing army and navy, and which is now spending thirty
                            millions a year for war purposes in a time of peace I Would God and Christ accept the office
                            and honor which these ignorant fanatics are endeavoring to force upon them ? Go on in your
                            good work : the holy angels, and the hearts of all pure men and women, must be with you.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hacker, Jeremiah" TEIform="persName"/>Jer. Hacker, Berlin, N. J.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Government" TEIform="index"/>GOVERNMENT</head><p TEIform="p">" Where there is no government there is no God." There is some inherent virtue in all the
                            various forms of human government. An empire, or despotism, under the direction of one will,
                            capable and good, is vastly more happy in its conditions than is a democratic State without
                            self-control. An aristocracy is but another name for government by the best minds. And who
                            will say it is not better than misgovernment by a rabble. Wild tribes elect their own
                            chieftains, and these chiefs are governed by a council of their wise old men. True republics
                            embody the best qualities of all human governments. When a people have become sufficiently
                            enlightened to protect themselves from being ruled by designing knaves, they should govern
                            themselves. Their first step may be to elect an aristocracy, composed of their most able
                            minds, to make the laws; then to elect an officer, or officers, to execute them; these,
                            answering to the executive head of an empire, enforce the laws made by the people through
                            their aristocracy; but, under bonds to administer for the common good of all. For the
                            misrule of a mob is no worse, in principle, than that of a despot; but is more showy. A
                            theocracy, or government by the Infinite, through the finite-—the spiritual through visible
                            channels — is evidently what the perverseness of man's nature requires. It is becoming a
                            question, whether, in this country, man has not, already, more liberty than he will use
                            aright. Uncontrolled, unregulated license, will as assuredly pervert all government in the
                            future as it ever has in the past. In his lowest condition, man needs protection against his
                            fellow. In his intelligent state, he needs protection against his own sinful pleasures.
                            Uncivilized, he is incapable of a true spiritual government, as it would soon degenerate
                            into a superstition. Enlightened, he becomes voluptuous ; for the means of sensuous
                            satisfaction, have far outgrown the only power which can curb the desires, and hold them to
                            their legitimate use — the present and future good of hims If and his fellows. Believing
                            that God overrules human affairs for the final good of the race, Ave perceive design in
                            bringing those wandering Arabs, or sons of Jacob, to dwell near the highly civilized
                            Egyptians for four hundred years. Could they live for so many generations in close contact
                            with the most enlightened people of the day, and not have the truths of civilization born in
                            them ? And what could better fit them for a theocracy, and to be led by the one man who had
                            the noblest spiritualistic development ? It is safe to predicate, from the lessons of
                            history, and from the result of stern facts in the present, that the race cannot — will not
                            — unaided from above, govern itself with justice. For no material or intellectual forces can
                            ever reach the spiritual nature, which, alone, has power to subdue those desires and
                            passions of the earthly man, which, defying all law, is termed " that laivless." Hence, when
                            man can see the Infinite in the finite, he will have a government manifested in human
                            beings, who possess the highest spiritual development of the day and time ; and the governed
                            will realize that their freedom of desire and action may be greater than their power of
                            restraint, and so yield obedience to God, as seen in his " image." Thus, the culmination of
                            human government will be spiritual, which takes into the account man's highest attributes
                            and wellbeing. It will be of God, through the people, and for the people, and of their own
                            free will.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, G. H." TEIform="persName"/>G. H. Hollister, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union of church and state" TEIform="index"/>Union of church and state
                        </head><p TEIform="p">[From the Albany Morning Express.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">UNION OF CHURCH AND STATE. VIEWS OF A PROMINENT SHAKER. Mt. Lebanon, Columbia
                                    Co., N. Y., March 15, 1873. Editor Morning Express: Respected Friend : I send you a
                                    copy of my St. George's Hall lecture, and a pamphlet. I hope your life may be spared
                                    until you can look through them. It may be that you will be the better prepared for
                                    the interesting change, after digesting their contents. If good came " out of
                                    Nazareth," why may not light come out of Shakerdom? If we must have a union of "
                                    Church and State " in this nation, I propose that the Shaker Church be the one to be
                                    thus united to the Civil Government. There are grave reasons why this union should
                                    be consummated. The President has already extended a fraternal hand toward the
                                    Shakers' Order, saying, " I believe that our great Master is preparing the world, in
                                    his own good time, to become one nation, speaking one language, and when armies and
                                    navies will be no longer required." This is his language ; it is ours. Here is a
                                    basis of union with our Church not to be elsewhere found. It is self-evident that a
                                    Civil Government, having such a " high and holy faith" in Millennial principles,
                                    that will eventually exterminate sensuality, poverty, slavery and war, can form no
                                    permanent union with any of the churches of Babylon, Christendom—churches who
                                    believe in, and have, for 1260 years, practised war — holding their prisoners as
                                    slaves — thus creating poverty, rich and poor, bond and free, male and female, Jew
                                    and Gentile, who, vociferously denouncing the brotherhood of Humanity, never agree
                                    except when baptised into, and whilst bathing in the stagnant waters of the " Social
                                    Evil: " in thai they are one flesh. " What concord hath Christ and Belial, or what
                                    fellowship hath light with darkness ? " What union can there ever be between a civil
                                    Government that " believes" in the Powers of Peace —the Millennium — and fighting
                                    churches, who carry the " Bible in one hand, and Sharp's rifle in the other? " By
                                    all means, let us have a union of Church and State. But let it be between a
                                    peace"believing" Government on the one hand, and a peace practising Church, on the
                                    other. This will follow: The Shaker Church, "rendering unto Caesar the things that
                                    are Caesar's," will let the Civil Government, then to be composed equally of male
                                    and female officers, the executives of laws protective of person and property,
                                    without discrimination of sex, color or nationality, attend to all civil matters
                                    between one citizen and another, relating to " the life that now is," and the Shaker
                                    Church will, under the influence of Spiritualism, regulated by religious
                                    inspiration, occupy itself with the far more important afFaiijs of " the world to
                                    come." And at the same time knowing, <pb n="36" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> as none others can know,
                                    that the "price" of good, once gained, is "eternal vigilance," it will see to it
                                    (geese did once on a time save the Roman citadel), that no one of the adulterous,
                                    worldly churches, that "believe" in war, its causes, and sequences, shall ever
                                    intervene between itself and the Civil Government of these United States, which is a
                                    home for persons of all kindreds, tribes, peoples, tongues, nations, and races, with
                                    all their antagonizing theologies and diversities of Bibles. "Let us have Peace."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Albany morning express" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shepherds" TEIform="index"/>SHEPHERDS</head><p TEIform="p">" I am the good Shepherd, and know my sheep, and am known of mine; and they shall hear my
                            voice. I CAN indeed testify to the truth of these words. Christ's Spirit is " known" and
                            felt by my hungry soul. I rejoice to find him in so many. Some time back, he was not to be
                            found in any man or woman upon this earth. But now we are blessed with the presence of the
                            heavenly Bride and Bridegroom. The kind, loving Shepherds in Zion, possess the pure Gospel
                            of Jesus Christ and Mother Ann, and are worthy of their inheritance, because they have lain
                            down their lives just as did Jesus. They are true followers of Christ. They do not go
                            behind, and drive their sheep, but they go before, and all the good sheep follow. It is
                            something of a cross to follow Christ; yet I rejoice that my lot is cast among faithful
                            cross-bearers.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Erickson, Larz" TEIform="persName"/>Larz Erickson, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Does the world move?" TEIform="index"/>DOES THE WORLD MOVE?</head><p TEIform="p">As a whole or a part, is humanity moving on an up-grade 1 Much depends on the standpoint from
                            which the view is taken. Go down into turmoils — the scrambles for place and for pelf — go
                            down into the condemned little difficulty yclept " the social evil"— stay there long enough
                            to get your perceptives obfuscated—and should you be asked, Does the world move ? you might
                            say, as did Ezekiel when asked, " Can these dry bones live 1" " 0 Lord, Thou knowest." But
                            here let us quit these regions and go up — higher up — up to the highest parts of the earth
                            — the parts that come nearest to the heavens — nearest to angels and God. Now cast about,
                            and what do we see ? We see some splendid specimens of the race Homo — intellectual,
                            political and moral. Compared with the 'homos' of former periods, these specimens we see now
                            are almost divine. Herein lies the grand secret of the differences, to wit: In olden time '
                            homos' got up gods in their own likeness; now, these ' homos' get themselves up in the
                            likeness of God. This makes a difference, we see. What though these approved editions are
                            not yet the many 1 we must confess they are not. They are the few. But they are prophe- cies
                            of the future many — the poetic few. Now just look ahead a few centuries. What do you see ?
                            We see this planet peopled with the likeness of God as the waters cover the sea; this is
                            what we see. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., O." TEIform="persName"/>O. P.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Duke of Somerset in his 'Christian Theology and Modern Skepticism'..." TEIform="index"/>The Duke of Somerset in his 'Christian Theology and Modern Skepticism'...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The Duke of Somerset in his " Christian Theology and Modern Skepticism," thinks that the
                            gender of words has a great deal to do with our religious beliefs. He insinuates thai if the
                            word for spirit, which is feminine in Hebrew, had not become changed to masculine in the
                            Latin, one or more of the Trinity would be of a different sex.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Knowlege vs. religion" TEIform="index"/>KNOWLEDGE vs. RELIGION</head><p TEIform="p">Religion is the salvation or the curse of mankind. What is religion, but the inpourng or
                            ottipouring of the soul — action, moion ? All the actions of a man or woman is lis or her
                            religion. Every action that brings lappiness —heaven — is true religion; while every act
                            that results in unhappiness —hell — is false religion. There may be as many degrees of
                            heaven and hell, as there are of aeat and cold. Knowledge is the saving or Christ principle,
                            which deters human beings from doing what ignorance would leave them to do, wrong. The great
                            cross of to-day, for mankind, is work; to work for their bread, and to work for knowledge
                            that will bring lasting happiness. Men work for knowledge to get money, to obtain land, to
                            secure the notice of other persons, and to be honored one of another; to become politicians,
                            lawyers, doctors, preachers — any thing that is popular with mankind. But to seek and work
                            for that combination of physical, moral, intellectual and spiritual truth, which would
                            result in human happiness — heaven —is a cross that not many can bear. So few are willing to
                            find heaven here upon earth, that they seek not for it; but look away into the future, to
                            some great place above. Friends, heaven is no particular place, but a condition as
                            attainable on earth as in any other place, or sphere, or world. Reason and experience teach
                            me that the only way to heaven is right living; and that the knowledge and practice of right
                            living is religion.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, Aaron" TEIform="persName"/>Aaron Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To know thee, the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom Thou hath sent, is eternal life" TEIform="index"/>To know thee, the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom Thou hath sent, is eternal life
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"To know Thee, the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom Thou hath sent, is eternal life." </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Ed.</byline></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Responsibility" TEIform="index"/>RESPONSIBILITY</head><p TEIform="p">Each Contributor is accountable for his or her own sentiments or ideas. It is the duty of
                            Editors, being responsible to Authors, to prepare matter for the press. Writers should be "A
                            little deaf, a little blind, If happiness they'd surely find," Or, otherwise, write only
                            what has been well thought out. Better write two or three short articles, than one too long.
                            It is no more advisable to " catch the hare before you cook it," than it is to have some-
                            thing to say before you say it. Yet, as the only way to prepare a population for a repub-
                            lic, is to establish one; as there are no means by which a child can learn to talk, except
                            prattling; and as only those who go often into the water, at the risk of going under, be-
                            come good swimmers, so it is with composing— putting ideas into words. Therefore write, that
                            you may learn to write; first being certain that already you do not know how. All
                            Contributors, whatever become of their contributions, have our CORDIAL THANKS. Each one is
                            expected to do better next time. We quote, or copy, for information. And never indorse by
                            implication.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No one who has honestly endeavored to express his thoughts in prose..." TEIform="index"/>No one who has honestly endeavored to express his thoughts in prose...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">No one who has honestly endeavored to express his thoughts in prose, and failed, should be
                            censured too severely for resorting to poetry.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dual" TEIform="index"/>Dual.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The latest originality in the way of newspaper titles is found, of all places in
                                    the world, among the Shakers of New Lebanon. For two years they have issued a
                                    journal called The Shaker, which was the organ of their sect throughout the country.
                                    Lately, however, they have recognized the Woman's Rights doctrine, by terming their
                                    paper The " Shaker and Shakeress." This is certainly a striking, if not a euphonious
                                    title.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Buffalo expresss" TEIform="index"/>Buffalo Express.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Infidels" TEIform="index"/>INFIDELS</head><p TEIform="p">"The new infidels have nothing whatever in common with Voltaire or Paine, probably do not
                            sympathize at all with either the spirit of their writings or the separate opinions they
                            advocated. They are not controversialists any more; they are not theologians. They make no
                            war on particular dogmas —such as Trinity, atonement, depravity, perdition, literal
                            inspirations. Those of them who profess hostility to Christianity, do it on grounds that
                            neither Paine nor Voltaire would have comprehended—that even Parker did not occupy. Those
                            who profess themselves Christians, do so for reasons peculiarly their own; they decline to
                            receive Christianity as a doctrinal system, and but partially accept it as an ethical
                            system. They regard it rather in the light of a symbolical illustration of their own moral
                            sentiments, of sentimental value purely, or as the natural and legitimate development of one
                            line of history. The rest classify Christianity among the great religions of the race, give
                            it its place in history, appreciate what it has done, commend it for what it is doing, but
                            seek elsewhere for their guidance and authority." "Between Trench Infidelity,' therefore,
                            and American Rationalism, there are worlds of difference. They scarcely touch each other at
                            any point. In spirit, method, aim, principle, conclusion, they are essentially unlike. They
                            start from a different goal, proceed along a different track, issue at a different point.
                            The atheist does not copy Diderot; the materialist turns his back on Helvetius; the deist
                            forsakes the ways of Thomas Paine; even the mocker has a fashion of his own, quite unlike
                            Voltaire's. There is no excuse for naming them in the same breath but partisan bitterness;
                            and whether or not that can be accepted as an excuse, we leave our readers to judge."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Twelve reasons why no rational being should use tobacco" TEIform="index"/>TWELVE REASONS WHY
                            NO RATIONAL BEING SHOULD USE TOBACCO</head><p TEIform="p">1. The habit is at war with temperance. Tobacco is an intoxicant. It is a part of the
                            merchandise of dram-shops and an incentive to drunkenness. The toper, rebuked by a professed
                            teetotaler, with a quid or a cigar in his mouth, might pertinently respond : "Physician heal
                            thyself." 2. The habit is a self-indulgence in flagrant conflict with the self-denying
                            spirit of the Divine Founder of Christianity. It numbers among its slaves more than 150
                            millions of human beings. It hinders moral reform, and it impedes progress. 3. The habit is
                            essentially filthy, and "cleanliness," says the proverb, " is next to godliness." Ladies of
                            refinement involuntarily shrink from the man who chews, or snuffs, or smokes, unless custom
                            has rendered them indifferent to these vile practices. 4. The lips of a tobacco chewer, or
                            habitual smoker, are swelled and saturated with a disgusting poison, the gums are spongy and
                            tender, and the whole mouth and throat affected by its use. 5. The habit of using tobacco is
                            inconsistent with the character of a Christian gentleman. " St. Paul," Bishop Hooker tells
                            us, " was emphatically a gentleman." Would he have poisoned the air with sickening smoke, or
                            deluged the floor with liquid fllthiness ? Never! 6. The habit injures the voice. The smoker
                            articulates huskily. The chewer often croaks. The snuffer speaks through his nose. 7. The
                            habit is costly. Official statistics show that more money was spent for tobacco in the
                            United States during 1871 than for bread —the staff of life. $350,000,000 for tobacco in its
                            various forms. $200,000,000 for flour within the year! 8. The habit often lowers the
                            self-respect of those who practice it. "I love my pipe," said a clergyman, "but I despise
                            myself for using it." 9. The habit disturbs the regular pulsation of the heart. Tobacco
                            users are thus in constant danger. Many fall dead suddenly. 10. The habit weakens the mind.
                            It enfeebles the memory, paralyzes the will, produces morbid irritability, diseases the
                            imagination, deadens the moral sensibilities, and is, therefore, an " assault and battery "
                            on the nervous system, the intellect and the soul. 11. The habit is a rebellion against
                            Conscience. Those who indulge in it know that it wastes time, money, strength, and life, and
                            tramples on the laws of Nature, which are the laws of God. Hence it is a sin. 12. The habit
                            is as contagious as the cholera. Every mature smoker or chewer infects dozens of youths with
                            a desire to follow his pernicious example. Thus the evil spreads. Bondsmen of " tobacco,"
                            break your chains! After a month of abstinence you will not care for the poison, and within
                            a year after your selfemancipation, you will loathe it. It is God's command that you do
                            yourself no willful harm. For this reason, added to those already placed before you, give up
                            the use of tobacco forthwith and forever. Ex.</p></div2><pb n="37" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: prophets" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: PROPHETS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">Modern prophets have read and re-read the predictions of the ancient Seers, and inhaled the
                            breath of inspirational life from them; and have so much admired the high-toned eloquence
                            and purity of thought and language flowing through them, that they have bowed and done them
                            reverence. Many, while perusing the touching Bible story of Abraham, when he journeyed with
                            his beloved son Isaac from Beersheba to mount Moriah, have honored him for his firmness of
                            purpose in yielding obedience to the call of God to him, and have admiringly followed him at
                            a distance, and beheld his courage and faith, when he set his face toward the land to which
                            his God was about to lead him. Slowly, but firmly, step by step, he ascended the mount,
                            ready to sacrifice his dearest loved one on earth, to evidence the greater love that he felt
                            to his God, whom he professed to serve. But how many, in our own time, possess faith enough
                            to sacrifice their Isaacs, when called to do so ? Ah! says one, " We have fallen upon
                            different times! Our God is tender and compassionate ! He saw Abraham's faith and felt his
                            sore trial and grief, while proving his integrity to principle." And God said "/ will make a
                            great sacrifice once for all! " And He sent his only Son into our world as a ransom for the
                            race of man, and thus released us from the performance of such painful duties. Now, all that
                            remains for us to do is to believe on his Son, and rely upon his atoning blood that was shed
                            on Calvary, and chant requiems of praise to him, and all will be well; for he loves us so
                            well, he will wink at all our transgressions, and cancel all our debts for us. Our
                            earth-life is short, and we purpose getting all the pleasure out of it that we possibly can,
                            and trust to his merits for the future." Many have revered the character of the Leader and
                            Deliverer of ancient Israel, as they have traced the history of his travels through the
                            wilderness, and his patient endurance and perseverance with that murmuring and oftentimes
                            rebellious people. He was possessed of human frailties as well as they ; and was a partaker
                            of all the trials and temptations to which they were subject, which he resisted, and
                            encouraged his people to do the same; and he became a practical law-giver by carrying the
                            principles and laws, which he enunciated, into effect in his own life. There is grandeur and
                            beauty in the account of his approach to mount Sinai with the seventy elders, who were
                            commanded to worship afar off, while Moses, alone, was allowed to draw near; how, in vision,
                            they saw the God of Israel, whose feet were placed upon sapphire stone like unto the body of
                            heaven in clearness ; and the communings of the Spirit with Moses on the Mount, the burning
                            bush; the voice of the trumpet; the thunderings and lightnings, and the cloud which rested
                            there. But we would ask: Have those signal manifestations of power any particular bearing
                            upon the people of this generation? Have we nothing to do but to read, wonder, and admire?
                            Or, were the dealings of the God of the Jews with the people, at that time, written and
                            preserved for the admonition and benefit of succeeding generations? How much easier it is to
                            think well of covenants that were made with our fathers, a long time ago, than it is for us
                            to make new covenants, which require new sacrifices. The code of laws given through Moses,
                            still possess great power; and there is a spirit at work, seeking to infuse new life into
                            them, that they may take practical effect in a physical and moral point of view upon the
                            habits and lives of the people of our own time. The Mosaic Dispensation is the basis upon
                            which the Christian Dispensation must rest. If we destroy the one, and render it
                            ineffectual, we shall do the same by the other. And, when we acknowledge God's power in ages
                            past, and profess to believe in the fulfillment of prophecy in the future, yet are unwilling
                            that those prophecies should be fulfilled in our time, and take effect in us, because of
                            some sacrifice that we must make, and a cross that would follow as a sequence, then we give
                            evidence of the want of living practical faith and true honesty of purpose. God will not be
                            mocked with vain and empty professions. If we cry " Lord ! Lord! " we must have
                            corresponding works, or He will not know us in the covenant of redemption. He will own and
                            honor only those who, through a spirit of unselfish devotion, honor Him.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear sister Capen:" TEIform="index"/>Dear Sister C'apen:</head><p TEIform="p">How do you and yours prosper, and how in particular does your soul prosper ? For I do not
                                believe you are one who ever can become so absorbed in worldly cares as to forget its
                                interests; although, like all human beings, you may mistake in the manner of protecting
                                and advancing those interests. You and I were well acquainted in time past, as you may
                                remember, holding in common much experience and many opinions; but it is a long time
                                since we met. You thought at that time (if I mistake not), that you, by a transient
                                visit, knew some little about Shakers, sufficient to justify you in rejecting their
                                principles and practices. Since I became acquainted with both the one and the other, I
                                have not ceased to be astonished that so many good, honest, piouslydisposed people, as
                                far as I can see or know, decide about and pass over this important question: " What can
                                this people mean by their profession and practice ?" On my first and last visit to
                                Dorchester, my old and muchloved home, I called upon a sister occupying a prominent
                                position in the Church, expressing to her the delight I felt in finding a people who
                                were really Christians. She said, " Oh, wait, sister, till you have lived with them a
                                while ; you will not stay long after you really find them out." Well, I have tried it
                                twentyfive years, and have failed to find any thing of what she darkly hinted. Do you
                                remember what you once thought of a married life, as to its effect upon the spiritual
                                life, and the text you gave me, when I urged you to take care of Brother Capen's
                                children ? You told me very truly and wisely, that Paul said, a married woman would care
                                for the things of the world, how she might please her husband, but the unmarried was
                                free to care how she might please the Lord, and keep herself holy in body and spirit.
                                You also reminded me how women, we had both known and honored, had counted themselves as
                                having fallen from their high state of holiness, when they entered on a married life, or
                                at least as maintaining their profession with increased trial and uncertainty. Yet, with
                                all this, how slow have I and others been to discern the truth. It would ill become me,
                                who have been in darkness so dense, to fault my friends because they may be slow to see
                                light; for notwithstanding my zeal and earnestness in those days, looking back upon them
                                it is plainly to be seen, that, in spiritual things, I did not know my right hand from
                                my left; and can only be thankful that I had as little influence and did so little evil.
                                Whatever may be thought by those who count themselves good and wise, it will be seen in
                                the end, to be a great attainment to really know the flesh from the spirit, and to which
                                we are really giving in our adhesion; for the word is, if we sow to the spirit we shall
                                reap life eternal: but, if we sow to the flesh, we shall of the flesh reap corruption.
                                If, instead of crucifying, we will persist in cultivating, the crop will be abundant and
                                sure ; for, whatever man may be, God is not mocked or deceived. You, my dear sister, may
                                think it passing strange that I should name this plain scripture to one who has quoted
                                it so often in public and in private, as I have heard you. Still you are aware that it
                                is the experience of yourself and others, that we may read and quote Scripture and
                                imagine ourselves familiar with its meaning. Yet, after awhile, the heavens may open and
                                a ray of light fall upon the subject in question, giving it a significance and
                                importance not seen before. What, let me ask, in all humility, are the affections of the
                                flesh, if not those originated and fostered by its ties ? And how came we to be so blind
                                as not to see it? I think no soul can understand this matter until they clearly know
                                that the light and call of the Gospel concerns the body as well as the soul; the former
                                called to be a fit temple for an indwelling holy spirit. This (it seems to me) must be
                                something very different and opposed to the uses to which the flesh consigns it, i. e. a
                                prey to the lusts of men, I grant you, in many cases, a willing prey. Justice requires
                                that we admit this truth, but does this fact lessen the degradation ? Surely not! On the
                                contrary, it has been maintained, by wise men and thinking women, that the darkest
                                feature of slavery was that it rendered some of its victims willing to remain slaves!
                                There, sister dear, I have written what was in my mind, and prayerfully hope it may do
                                no harm. It is a blow aimed at the root of all sin ; and, in this day of the world's
                                history, it seems not best to spend much time or strength lopping branches, if one has
                                any hope of reaching the root. A more pleasant subject upon which to write might be
                                found : could there be a more important one ? The loss and consequent misery of humanity
                                is a sad subject, but it looks to me that, if tongue and pen be consecrated to the
                                highest use of this hideouslyfallen world, delicacy and modesty, which have been so long
                                and persistently ignored in the commission of sin, must of necessity be laid a little on
                                one side, while we grapple with the deadly monster. If the vail cast over the face of
                                all nations is ever effectually rent, every son and daughter of the second Adam should
                                feel like contributing their mite dismissing forever overweening delicacy and worldly
                                mock-modesty.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fairbanks, Nancy" TEIform="persName"/>Nancy Fairbanks, Harvard, Mass.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Now that woman begins to protest..." TEIform="index"/>Now that woman begins to protest...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Now that woman begins to protest, she will not be so much, oppressed as heretofore by her
                            stronger half.</p></div2><pb n="38" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Meditation" TEIform="index"/>MEDITATION</head><p TEIform="p">David said, " the meditation of my heart shall be of understanding." Many benefits are
                            derived from serious and candid meditation, and much is lost for the want of it. Those who,
                            without due reflection, eagerly rush forward in pursuit of pleasure are often surrounded by
                            difficulties and dangers from which they cannot extricate themselves. Bitter regrets and
                            remorse of conscience have fallen to the lot of those who have yielded to the impulse of
                            evil passions instead of giving place to calm deliberation upon caw.se and effect. A proper
                            use of the reflective powers of mind would prevent atrocious crimes, would stay the
                            murderous hand, restrain the fraudulent heart, and lead to works of virtue and love, which
                            would not only give individual happiness but would be a blessing to others. How often we see
                            the young and inexperienced, who are self-reliant, move on in their own will, regardless of
                            the counsel of parents and the cautions of their dearest friends, until they plunge
                            themselves into irretrievable ruin, bringing guilt and shame upon themselves and blighting
                            the fond hopes of their best friends. 0 that all would learn to heed the voice of
                            conscience, and reflect and consider wisely, and let the monitor within warn them of danger,
                            and assist them to examine the motives which prompt to action ! In thus doing, integrity
                            might be maintained, unblemished morals preserved, and direful effects averted. There is
                            peace and serenity in calm meditation. In the hour Of reflection and contemplation, we
                            enlarge our conceptions of the Creator of the universe, and of the laws which govern the
                            creation. Those who are thus exercised can say, as did one anciently, " 0 how I love thy law
                            ! it is my meditation all the day." The beauty and harmony of God's works unfold to the view
                            as we study his laws, from which we learn the practical duties of the present life, and how
                            to prepare for that life which is eternal. Hallowed and blest is the hour of meditation! Our
                            hearts would expand, and our conceptions of the Divine would be enlarged, were we to
                            frequently consider his unbounded beneficence in giving to mortals a rational, understand-
                            ing mind, capable of infinite expansion and reflecting the likeness of our Eternal Parents.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sears, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName"/>Elizabeth Sears, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fulfillment of prophecy" TEIform="index"/>FULFILLMENT OF PROPHECY</head><p TEIform="p">Inspiration from the higher spheres should be ever welcome to our hearts, whether per-
                            taining to the work of the present time or to the greater glory of the advancing Millennial
                            Day. In this way, how often do we feel the Spirit witnessing with our spirits that the
                            promises of God are sure, and that to the increase of his work there will be no end. He hath
                            purposed to have a people on the earth who will do his will, and live in obedience to, and
                            in harmony with, the original laws of their own being, and keep pace with increasing light,
                            and who will from principle perform every duty. Prophets in all ages, when under the
                            guidance of true inspiration, have pointed to such a people and work. How earnestly did the
                            prophet Isaiah testify of a coming people, who should be washed from all filth and be purged
                            by the spirit of judgment, and be refined by the spirit of burning, until all that remained
                            in Jerusalem should be called holy, and have the"r names written among the living. And, for
                            her glory and defense, the cloud should overshadow and form a covert by day from the heat
                            and storm, and the fiery pillar should be her defense by night; and a tabernacle should be
                            formed, whereunto those who were weary of the conflicts of life, and (through prolonged
                            struggle) had battled against error, could flee for safety and find rest. Why should we fear
                            to meet the shaking work promised through the same Prophet, and flee to the cragged rocks
                            for a hiding place ? The strongholds of sin are destined to be shaken, and Babylon must
                            fall! Her walls will crumble; the elements are already at work, and the process of
                            disintegration is going on. And, as human efforts cannot thwart the purposes of God, would
                            it not be wiser and better to co-operate with the Divine will, and bless the agencies sent
                            to pull down the false, and to establish the true; and thus help to hasten the time when
                            science and religion will walk hand in hand, that order may be established in the world of
                            mind and matter, and that pure and undefiled religion, which will mold the character, and
                            fit the soul for the society of redeemed spirits in regions supernal, may triumph over all ?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Knight, Jane D." TEIform="persName"/>Jane D. Knight, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Frugality" TEIform="index"/>FRUGALITY</head><p TEIform="p">How infinitely wise and bountiful, is the great Creator of the world; yet in all his bounty
                            He allows no waste. Of the four elements earth, air, fire, and water, of which the world is
                            composed, there is nothing wasted. Man may make use of these elements, but he cannot destroy
                            them. The decomposition of matter in the vegetable kingdom is a preparation for giving life
                            to another growth. The majestic trees of the forest derive strength and vitality from their
                            own foliage, and in all the works of Nature we see this important truth verified, that
                            nothing is lost. Jesus when on earth went about distributing blessings. His example of
                            feeding the five thousand with five loaves and two fishes, and when the meal was passed, of
                            commanding them to " gather up the fragments, that nothing be lost; " is one worthy of
                            imitation and attention. Mother Ann was remarkable, both in principle and practice, in
                            regard to prudence and economy. She was frequently known to wait until others had finished
                            their meal, then go to the table and make her repast of the fragments, and say, "It is good
                            enough for me; it is the blessing of God, and must not be lost! " Her counsel to her
                            children was, " You must be prudent and saving of every good thing." Let us follow her
                            beautiful example of frugality, and gather up the fragments. For this was the pattern which
                            Jesus did set, and his good example we should not forget. The practical Believer in Christ
                            will heed the counsel of the Apostle, who said, : Whether ye eat or drink, or whatsoever ye
                            do, do all to the glory of God." A modern poet says : " We find of those bounties which
                            Heaven does give, That some live to eat, and some eat to live ; That some think of nothing
                            but pleasing the taste, And care very little how much they may waste."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Irving, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Eldress Anna Irving, Enfield, Ct.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Virginity" TEIform="index"/>VIRGINITY</head><p TEIform="p">We hail the "Shaker and ShaTceress," as a Li fe Boat to the shipwrecked mariner, giving to
                            eveiy honest passenger a safe passport to a higher and still higher sphere. I beg a seat in
                            some corner, for I am a life passenger, bound heavenward. May'st thou plough on and o'er the
                            surging billows of darkness, bigotry, and superstition, until thou hast reached a haven in
                            the great universal heart of humanity. I realize that I am enjoying the great privilege of
                            being one of the Latter-Day virgins, and am called to form a true Christian character, to
                            live pure, as do the angels in heaven. In sincerity of heart, I pray, " Thy kingdom come ;
                            thy will be done on earth as it is done in heaven." Virginity, Honesty, Chastity, and
                            disinterested Benevolence, are the great and good principles which rule in that kingdom, and
                            they whose characters are conformed to those principles, will possess it. Virgin Purity is
                            the first principle upon which the Christian or Shaker Church is based; but it is not
                            gained, nor maintained, without heart-struggles and soul-sufferings. The natural man is
                            groveling and selfish. His tendency, without spirituality and the cross, is downward ; but,
                            in a true virgin state, he is continually reaching forward, looking upward, aiming higher.
                            To great heroes and conquerors of nations, what a shocking disappointment, when, by
                            self-examination, they learn the important truth, that " the least in the kingdom of
                            heaven," who govern themselves, are greater than they. Though the greatest of sages and
                            heroes of fame, Have left on record an immortalized name. Yet the greatest achievement that
                            mortals can gain, Is over themselves in victory to reign. And such of all nations, from
                            beggars to kings, The Lord hath decreed shall inherit all things. " Blessed are the meek,
                            for they shall inherit the earth. Also, " the pure in heart, for they shall see God." Those
                            who are truly meek, and form the pure virgin character, realize the truth of those beautiful
                            promises. Such are able to see the source from "whence come wars and fightings;" that those
                            who are " pure " will be " peaceable." The only way to become true subjects of the kingdom
                            of heaven is by an honest confession of all sin, accompanied with repentance ; and to
                            crucify the sensual nature, in thought, word, and deed, by denying every animal appetite. By
                            thus doing, the soul is clothed in vestal robes, and the Christian, virgin character is
                            formed, whose love is pure, unselfish and neverfailing ! O, I will prize my glorious call,
                            For life eternal give up all, Make straight my path in purity, For truth alone can make me
                            free. If I possess superior love, 'Twill elevate me far above The vain and transient ties of
                            earth, Where I can find the second birth. But, where is one of common sense Who would, but
                            for a recompense Of life eternal, peace and joy, Their carnal life and loves destroy ? No
                            others can; 'tis those alone Who make the cross of Christ their own, Who daily in his
                            footsteps move ; Such reap the fruits of virgin love. "And the earth helped the woman."
                            Triumphant at last, O, frail portion of man, Herald thy vict'ry through God's holy plan ;
                            Earth shall assist thee ; thy virtue shall reign; Stand by man 's side and its power
                            maintain, Hearest thou not the wise Prophet declare, Arise, Virgin Daughter, thy garments
                            prepare! Kings shall adore thee, thou heavenly Bride : Emblem of Purity, stand by his side.
                            Riches and honor, with blessings unseen, Emanate from thee, thou glorious Queen. Sound it
                            aloud, —"Now saltation hath come!" Seek it through Father and Mother as One. Although
                            seasons vanish, flowers perish, Luminaries disappear, Other flowers will bloom as fragrant,
                            Other lights will shine as clear. And those past and present seasons Tell of others yet to
                            come, Bringing with them untold blessings, Far surpassing those now flown. Time is passing ;
                            but Progression Moves along with lightning speed : Though great nations live, and have
                            lived, Others yet will those exceed. Yea, the long sought-for Millennium, Though its star we
                            dimly see, Soon o'er earth will spread' its mantle " As the waters do the sea." May we leave
                            to our successors Foot-prints on the shores of time, Of good deeds and noble actions : Be
                            their mission more sublime.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rupe, Nancy L." TEIform="persName"/>Nancy L. Rupe, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dialogue" TEIform="index"/>Dialogue
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The serial Dialogue, in tract form, price ten cents, single. Five dollars per hundred.
                            Address Editor.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manire, William" TEIform="index"/>Elder William Manire
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Manire, William" TEIform="persName">Elder William Manire</persName>, Pleasant Hill, Ky.,
                                March 25, aged 73.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Horten, Lucy" TEIform="index"/>Lucy Hokten
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Horten, Lucy" TEIform="persName">Lucy Hokten</persName>, Watervliet, aged 81.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pierce, Nancy" TEIform="index"/>Nancy Pierce
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Pierce, Nancy" TEIform="persName">Nancy Pierce</persName>, West Glouster, March 7, aged
                            75.</p></div3></div2><pb n="39" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Family relation" TEIform="index"/>THE FAMILY RELATION</head><p TEIform="p">It has always been surprising to me that Bible Christians — those who profess to take the
                            Bible for their rule of life and practice, should be so tenacious of minor points, while
                            this subject — the Family Relation — on which so much of their own happiness, and that of
                            their posterity depend, is treated with such neglect. When a child is born into this world,
                            it comes under the law of its parents. The first commandment given to the child is," Honor
                            thy father and mother " — "Children obey your parents." The law of the parents is binding on
                            the child while it is a minor. If the parents are law-abiding, and bring up their children
                            in the fear of God, if they provoke them not, if they forbear threatening, and set a godly
                            example, then they may with confidence look for a blessing to crown their efforts. When
                            children arrive at maturity, they come under another law, which frees them from the law of
                            their parents. By mutual agreement, they take the relation of husband and wife. Now the man
                            is to " forsake father and mother, and cleave to his wife, and they twain shall be one
                            flesh." In the book of Malachi, the question is asked and answered, " Wherefore one ? That
                            he (God) might seek a godly seed." If none had children but those who produce " a godly
                            seed" surely there would not be so many more mouths than bread to fill them. The race has
                            become wonderfully degenerate ; and, as the curse comes not causeless, would it not be well
                            to seek for the cause, and if possible find the remedy ? Are men and women living according
                            to either Law or Gospel, in their family relations ? If not, will they not be held
                            accountable ? Suppose you, that there was a requirement made which it was of no consequence
                            whether it be complied with or not ? Let us see what the requirement is. (I am speaking to
                            those who acknowledge Bible authority). St. Paul said, " Wives submit yourselves to your own
                            husbands, as unto the Lord, for the husband is the head of the wife, even as Christ is the
                            Head of the Church. Therefore, as the Church is subject to Christ, so let wives be to their
                            own husbands in every thing. Husbands love your wives even as Christ loved the Church and
                            gave himself for it." The Apostle, after stating what Christ has done for the Church, and
                            for what purpose, goes on to say, " So ought men to love their wives as their own bodies;
                            and let their wives see that they reverence their husbands." And St. Peter tells them " not
                            to let their adorning be that outward adorning of plaiting the hair, and wearing gold and
                            putting on of apparel, but let it be the hidden man (woman) of the heart, even the ornament
                            of a meek and quiet spirit. Likewise ye husbands, dwell with them according to knowledge
                            [according to science — scientifically], giving honor unto the wife as unto the weaker
                            vessel, and being heirs together of the grace of life, that your prayers be not hindered."
                            References could be multiplied to a much greater extent, bat these may suffice, to show the
                            vast difference that exists between the Bible requirements, and the practice of those who
                            profess to be governed by Christian principles. The above are some of the requirements by
                            which people should be governed in the natural or generative order; and were these precepts
                            religiously observed by both parties, we should soon see a very different state of thing8.
                            Divorces would be less frequent. And if the results of divorcement, as stated by one
                            superior to Moses, were observed, there would be but few who would be willing to marry her
                            who had been put away: " I say unto you, whosoever shall put away his wife, except it be for
                            fornication, and shall marry another, committeth adultery. And whoso marrieth her that is
                            put away, doth commit adultery." But there is a holier state than that of matrimony; for
                            even those who were said to be " holy women of old," when in the works of generation, had to
                            bring their sin offering after being excluded from the congregation for a prescribed length
                            of time ; thus showing the need of regeneration and obedience to a higher and holier law.
                            But so long as the wife's desire [lust] is to her husband, so long will he rule over her;
                            for this is the marriage covenant, and is and will be binding so long as she remains on that
                            plane. The " law of Christ makes us free from the law of sin and death." There was a " new
                            covenant" spoken, which was to supplant " that which was old and ready to vanish away." It
                            was said of Christ's second appearing, " that to those who look for him, he will appear the
                            second time without sin unto salvation." In that day, they who were not able to bear a full
                            cross were tolerated; but the Apostle said that he " could not speak to them as spiritual,
                            but as carnal." And he told them that the time was short when this indulgence could be
                            allowed. " It remaineth that both they that have wives be as though they had none. I would,"
                            says lie, " have you without carefulness. He that is married careth for the things of the
                            world, how he may please his wife. He that is unmarried careth for the things that belong to
                            the Lord, how he may please the Lord. There is a difference also between a wife and a
                            virgin. The unmarried woman careth for the things of the Lord, that she may be holy both in
                            body and spirit. But she that is married careth for the things of the world, how she may
                            please her husband." Now, those who have lived up to the requirements given to those in the
                            natural order, have had a discipline which will be of great benefit to them when they
                            advance to the higher (or spiritual order), or to the work of regeneration, where it is
                            required to give up all, and make an entire consecration, according to the words of Jesus
                            Christ, when he said, " Except a man forsake all that he hath, he cannot be my disciple." On
                            one occasion, the disciples said to him : " We have left all and followed thee, what shall
                            we have therefor ? He replied that they who had followed him in the regeneration, should
                            have " a hundred fold more in this world; and, in the world to come, eternal life." Under
                            the first law the man was to " forsake father and mother, and cleave to his wife, and they
                            twain were to be one flesh," with the injunction, that "what God had joined together let not
                            man put asunder." Let us consider how they were joined together. They mutually agreed to
                            live together as man and wife, and were pronounced such by the officiating party. Now, have
                            they not the same right to agree to live no longer as husband and wife, but as brother and
                            sister, that they may rise to a higher plane, and, by the cross and self-denial, devote
                            themselves to the cause of God and humanity ? Where is the " putting away f " By the first
                            agreement they became one flesh, by the second, one spirit, by being joined to the Lord.
                            When we have consecrated our substance, time, and talents, to the cause of God, and the
                            salvation of our own and other souls, then can we with confidence pray, " Thy kingdom come,
                            thy will be done on earth as in heaven ;" for then our prayers and efforts will correspond,
                            showing that we pray in faith.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, Ruth" TEIform="persName"/>Ruth Webster, Union Village</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Waste basket" TEIform="index"/>WASTE BASKET</head><p TEIform="p">I am pleased to learn through the " Shaker and Shakeress " that there is a waste basket ready
                            to receive contributions, and I am encouraged to make an offering therefor, lest it may not
                            be well filled. Were I able, I would gladly aid the little sheet on its mission, for I feel
                            a deep interest in it. It is always welcome as it makes its monthly visits to our mountain
                            home, so richly laden with treasures of wisdom, and good, wholesome truths, so essential to
                            the life and growth of all true Believers. It has come to us as a bright-winged Angel of
                            Peace, and the mature thoughts and new ideas, fresh from spirit spheres, which have found
                            expression through its columns, have given strength, hope, and comfort to many weary but
                            patient travelers up progression's steep ascent. And, when I reflect that the " Shaker and
                            Shakeress," on its errand of love, is visiting so many towns and hamlets, and is read by
                            thousands of people, not only in our own country, but also in foreign lands, I regard it as
                            the most important missionary enterprize ever engaged in by Believers, and one that all
                            should feel an interest in sustaining by every means within their power. If, by
                            self-sacrifice and individual effort, we can advance the cause, and aid in the great work of
                            human redemption from the thraldom of sin, and from the blinding and deafening influences of
                            antichristian errors upon the spiritual senses of the unenlightened, how thankful we should
                            be to give our best efforts in this direction. We may plead inability; but shall we, dear
                            Shaker friends, take our ease, and act the sluggard's part, and cast all the responsibility
                            upon others, who are already struggling and toiling to the extent of their powers ? Nay, let
                            us all work together for the upbuilding of the Gospel of Christ, which breathes peace and
                            good will to the sons and daughters of earth. By so doing, we shall manifest our love to God
                            and to humanity, and an appreciation of the noble efforts which many have made, and are
                            still making, to carry forward the work of soul elevation.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Rhoda R." TEIform="persName"/>Rhoda R. Hollister, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress" TEIform="index"/>"SHAKERESS."</head><p TEIform="p">To the " Shakeress," we send Sisterly greetings, acknowledging your important and glori- ous
                            mission. We hail the new Cap(tion) of the " Shaker." It fits admirably. Now the "daughters
                            of Zion have come forth, clothed in needle work, finely wrought with gold ;" and, in those
                            spotless garments of purity, are, by their most glorious " Queen," presented to the King. "
                            The Lord will create a new thing in the earth ; a woman shall compass a man." Glo- rious
                            era! What a theme for reflection! What a realm of light is revealed for exploration !
                            Millions have sought thee in prayer and anguish of soul, but were not thus favored in time.
                            May the blessed " Shakeress " prosper and be true to her most needful duty, which is to seek
                            out her poor fallen sisterhood, and bind up their many wounds, and, upon their sensitive,
                            emotional spirits, pour the balm of hope and consolation, to dry up those numberless unseen
                            tears that are dripping, dripping away the physical lives, and impairing the spiritual
                            growth of their soivh. Up, then, thou favored of the Lord, there is work to be done. The
                            strong must bear the infirmities of the weak, and Heaven requires all your talents. " Where
                            there is no vision the people perish." Virgin daughter, tune the inspirational harp of
                            Purity. May the cords thereof be touched, and the new song of the " hundred and forty and
                            four thousand" be re-echoed from pole to pole. And may the portals of Heaven never more be
                            closed to mortals, or hidden from their comprehension.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rupe, Nancy L." TEIform="persName"/>Nancy L. Rupe</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith is not merely belief..." TEIform="index"/>Faith is not merely belief...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Faith is not merely belief, but it is the confidence derived from love to the Lord. The
                            devils believe, but they have not faith, because they love not the Lord; they are not
                            willing to intrust all to him. There can be no faith without love or charity; and the effort
                            to get into a religious life by trying to believe that God will save us by so-called grace
                            or the atonement of Christ, is not the right way. Learn first to love God, which is to love
                            that which is good, and then you can trust Him, which trust is faith.</p></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kerosene" TEIform="index"/>KEROSENE</head><p TEIform="p">Banger from fire. Never fill a burning lamp. Fill lamps by daylight. If obliged to fill at
                            night, have the light a yard off and not in a current of air. Never pour oil on the fire. If
                            burning oil gets upon the floor, smother with blanket, rug, or clothing. If the clothing
                            takes fire, wrap a blanket or rug about the person, or roll upon the floor. Never run about,
                            or scream more than once; for motion fans the flames, and in screaming they may enter the
                            lungs. Keep the can closed and in a safe place. All kerosene oils (including naphtha,
                            benzine, benzoline, etc.), are highly combustible; as a rule, the high priced oils are less
                            explosive than the cheaper ones ; better pay a few cents more a gallon, and buy of
                            respectabJe dealers, than run the risk of losing life and property.</p></div2><pb n="40" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Call to the weary" TEIform="index"/>A CALL TO THE WEARY</head><p TEIform="p">1. O, when ye think that the earth-life is dreary, And all its burdens seem heavy to bear,
                            When ye are languishing, toil-worn and weary, And all your strife but increases your care,
                            2. Those who are toiling for sel fish enjoyment, Ne'er looking out from their own narrow
                            sphere, Feel not the solace that flows through employment No bly bestow'd for humanity's
                            cheer; 3. And while we're bravely pursuing our duty, Feeling that " labor is worship
                            " and pray'r, Soon in our pathway will seedbuds of beau ty Shed the sweet fragrance of
                            heavenly air. Turn ye, O, turn from the thoughts that depress you; Let the sad spirit
                            aspire to go free, And it will call down the angels to bless you, Bright'ning your vision
                            true pleasure to see. This is the toil that our Zion home blesses ; Hands that are willing
                            and souls that are true Lift up the weight that the lone heart oppresses, Give to the
                            whole life an aspect that's new. Thus we're up lifted, while truest emotion Thrills
                            ev'ry pulse to its loftiest strain; Glad is the thought, that unselfish devotion,
                            Brings to the spirit an eternal gain.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tell me where" TEIform="index"/>TELL ME WHERE</head><p TEIform="p">Many times while attending the funerals of our dear departed friends have I been impressed
                            with the thoughts, Where is the heaven that the spirit enters when death has claimed its
                            mortal part ? Where is the spirit's abode ? From which the following lines were suggested to
                            my mind : Vale of shadows, soon I leave thee : Pleasures false and treasures fair, Lose
                            their power to deceive me; I am going ! going where ? Who, O who, can solve the question ?
                            When we see the curtain fall, Then we know the soul's departing ; But we do not know it all.
                            Earthly hopes and prospects waning, Things divine grow bright and fair; Days but few to me
                            remaining, I am going; tell me where. Sorrow views a far-off heaven, Joy beholds it near at
                            hand, Rapture gives the soul a foretaste Of the blessing in that land, Fair Elysium, who can
                            find thee, Where located, high or low ? They who say The Lord design'd thee, Have not told
                            us where to go. Poets sing of glorious heavens, Myriads chanting praises there ; Paradise,
                            with bowers lovely, Yet they do not tell us where. What is heaven? Where is heaven? Saints
                            and sages, tell me where. I must go! I know I'm going, And I trust it will be there. Christ
                            declared, saith an Apostle, Heaven's kingdom is within. Dear to me is that sweet heaven.
                            Here my hope and joys begin. Like my Saviour, I am dyingConquering every inward foe ; By a
                            life of self-denial, Forming heaven here below. But this transient world I'm leaving, Going
                            to Eternity, Fair and happy clime celestial; Tell me then where it may be. Shining throne of
                            Lord Jehovah, Where the angels doff their crowns. Veil their faces from his brightness,
                            While in rev'rence bowing down. Who hath seen those realms so glorious, Happy myriads
                            dwelling there, Eeigning over death victorious ? Ye who've seen them, tell me where. Satan
                            too, hath he a region Where the evil-minded dwell ? Condemnations burning legions, In the
                            awful pit of hell ? From the Lord and all his angels Banish'd ! doom'd to black despair ? If
                            there is such woe, I'm sorry ; And you will not find me there. There is not where I am going
                            ; I am bound for Eden fair. Sighings hush'd, and blessings flowing, All I ask is, tell me
                            where.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Agnew, Hannah P." TEIform="persName"/>Hannah P. Agnew, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="On Earth peace" TEIform="index"/>"ON EARTH PEACE."</head><p TEIform="p">When war's baptismal scourge was o'er, We heard words blest as evening dew, Reverberating
                            from the halls of State, Till far and near the echo Hew — " Let us have Peace." We heard,
                            and grateful hoped them true, And that the world tow'rd progress turn'd: Our vision was of
                            Peace and Brotherhood; And full of trust our bosoms burn'd, To greet sweet Peace. We saw the
                            other half of man Upraised, and queenly at his side ; Not less he shone, but all the more,
                            That righteousness was not denied, But brought true Peace. In ev'ry trust she took her part,
                            And guided with a helping hand, In lifting to a better state, Those who pollute themselves
                            and land: And help'd grow Peace. But, while we mused, we heard of ships, And increased
                            armaments of war, And fear that swords must still be swords, And nations keep on learning
                            war, Instead of Peace. And then we wonder'd who could dare, To tamper with the dial-plate of
                            time, And turn the hands of progress back, And stay the bright Millennial clime, Which is
                            true Peace. We wonder'd, but we inly thought Of what a wiser one had said: — " First pure,
                            then peaceable !" Is it Corruption that stands between Fair earth and Peace ?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. Webster, Harvard, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Skin" TEIform="index"/>[ From the Irish.] THE SKIN</head><p TEIform="p">There's a skin without, and a skin within, A covering skin, and a lining skin, But the skin
                            within is the skin without Doubled inwards and carried completely throughout. The palate,
                            the nostrils, the windpipe and throat, Are all of them lined with this inner coat; Which
                            through every part is made to extend — Lungs, liver, and bowels, from end to end. The
                            outside skin is a marvellous plan For exuding the dregs from the flesh of man; While the
                            inner extracts from the food and the air What is needed the waste in his flesh to repair.
                            While it goes well with the outside skin, You may feel pretty sure all's right within ; For
                            if any thing puts the inner skin out Of order, it troubles the skin without. The doctor, you
                            know, examines your tongue, To see if your stomach or bowels are wrong ; If he feels that
                            your hand is hot and dry. He is able to tell you the reason why. Too much brandy, whisky, or
                            gin, Is apt to disorder the skin within ; While, if dirty or dry, the skin without Refuses
                            to let the sweat come out. Good people all! have a care of your skin, Both that without and
                            that within; To the first you'll give plenty of water and soap, To the last little else
                            beside water, we'll hope! But always be very particular where You get your water, your food
                            and your air; For if these be tainted or render'd impure, It will have its effect on your
                            blood — be sure; The food which will ever for you be the best, Is that you like most, and
                            can soonest digest; All unripe fruit and decaying flesh Beware of, and fish that is not very
                            fresh. Your water, transparent and pure as you think it, Had better be filter'd and boiled
                            ere you drink it, Unless you know surely that nothing unsound Can have got to it over or
                            under the ground. But of all things the most, I would have you beware Of breathing the
                            poison of once breathed air; When in bed, whether out or at home you may be, Always open
                            your window and let it go free. With clothing and exercise keep yourself warm, And change
                            your clothes quickly if drenched in a storm : For a cold caught by chilling the outside skin
                            Flies at once to the delicate lining within. All you who thus kindly take care of your skin,
                            And attend to its wants without and within, Need never of small-pox feel any fears, And your
                            skin may last you a hundred years.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our joy and hope" TEIform="index"/>OUR JOY AND HOPE</head><p TEIform="p">When Christian faith and love abound, No threat'ning clouds arise ; When grace within the
                            heart is found, All starlit are the skies. Life comes not then in dreary shape, But
                            beauteous, bright, and fair ; The golden sands, as they escape, Most worthy record bear,
                            Safe in our Parents' home of bliss, What glory we shall feel, When deeds of Christian
                            holiness Shall be our spirits' seal. May our account be full and bright, Perfected through
                            Christ's love ; And we be crown'd with holy light, To reign with him above.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Julia" TEIform="persName"/>Julia Johnson, Hancock, Mass.</byline></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>