<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0601" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shakers, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18760101" TEIform="date">January 1876</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-8</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="1" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER Official Monthly.—Published by the United Societies. WHAT IS TRUTH P" "THE ETERNAL
                        RELINQUISHMENT O3T ERROR. VOi. VI. ^ Editor. f OflAJvJlllo, N, I., JAJNUillll, lO/O. MiAlVM
                        VlLLAllJl, a. a, } publisher. ^JNa L'</p><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="1876" TEIform="index"/>1876</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leggett, Ezra T." TEIform="persName"/>EZRA T. LEGGETT</byline><p TEIform="p">Less than one pulse the universe is beating, Less than one wave that breaks upon its shore, A
                            hundred circling rounds of earth, repeating, The lights and shades that make life's varied
                            store: In days of long ago, an angel, sighing, The lives of nations, and of men did write;
                            Their blood-stained fields, their martyred heroes dying, Their broken altars, and their
                            reign of night. Not strange, the angel, from its golden pinions Shook earth's dark dust, and
                            soared to brighter spheres— Not strange its tidings, from earth's dark dominions, Less oft
                            were heard in gladness, than in tears 1 One hundred years! how few of hearts, unbroken, That
                            saw their light, and with their suns went down! How few of hopes, then born, that left a
                            token, That life had conquered victory, or death a crown! Again, the angel, with a brighter
                            pluming, Descends, as dew upon a thirsting world; And barren deserts smile, as gardens
                            blooming, And Freedom's banner is to man unfurled. Not to the east where Freedom's sons were
                            lying, Entombed by despots, in their country's grave; But with its sister sun, the angel,
                            flying, The Promised Land seeks on the western wave. There hills and dales, with life and
                            love are blooming, Where once was hidden nature's solitude; Where night, as queen, with
                            silence sat communing, And bashful stars the murky darkness wooed: There stranger nations
                            coalesce, o'erflowing, The land where once but nature's wild man trod; There stranger
                            tongues together blend, upgoing, In thanks and praise, for liberty, to God 1 Land of the
                            peerless mountain, lake and river — Where all God's sons and daughters dare he free! Where
                            man hath covenant with God, forever, That there shall be the home of Liberty! There
                            Freedom's hosts are heart to heart replying, ' And echo gives the seas and mountains voice;
                            May Freedom's echoes, to the nations flying, Rouse all earth's slumbering millions, to
                            rejoice!</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Henry Vincent on Elder Evans" TEIform="index"/>HENRY VINCENT ON ELDER EVANS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vincent, Henry" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Henry Vincent tells us this story: '' While Elder Frederic W. Evans was holding meetings in
                            England in 1871, one of the Christian brethren became somewhat nervously excited over some
                            of the theological views expressed by the good elder, and called out: ' What did Jesus
                            Christ come into this world for ? I demand of you what Jesus Christ came into this world for
                            ?' Elder Frederic paused in his discourse, and slightly leaning forward to get a better view
                            of his assailant, spoke in his peculiar, clear voice: ' My friend, Jesus Christ came into
                            this world to teach such men as you are how to govern their tempers.' "</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Everyday religion" TEIform="index"/>EVERYDAY RELIGION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stickney, Ascenath C." TEIform="persName"/>ASCENATH C. STICKNEY</byline><p TEIform="p">This is the great necessity of the present age — the one thing needful to develop the
                            Christian man or woman into that noble type of godliness, which characterized our Lord and
                            Savior. Christianity, in its perfection, is unlimited in character, and can never be
                            confined to theories, creeds, nor cramped within the precincts of costly churches. The
                            present state of society demands that now, more than ever, religion be available on every
                            day of the week; that it enter every avenue of intelligence, and penetrate every by-way of
                            civilized life every day. The "Divine" needs it outside of the pulpit; the editor requires
                            it in his sanctum, that, by its influence, his sentiments may go forth to the public, imbued
                            with those elements of divine wisdom which tend to elevate as well as enlighten. The
                            merchant wants it to preside in his "counting-room " over his gains and losses. The teacher
                            should seek it for a monitor in his school, where a pacific influence is so requisite for
                            harmonizing those restless, miniature worlds called pupils. The doctor, the farmer, the
                            parent, the citizen, all need this universal panacea, for the varied ills emanating from low
                            unspiritual conditions. The Shakers, as individuals and as a body, need it, and should have
                            it, regardless of an inherent love of ease, of selfish gain, or any worldly considerations.
                            Finally, the whole world suffers for a religious life and education, broad enough to mantle
                            every day of the week, as completely as the new-fallen snow mantles the hills and dales of
                            our own country in winter. As the new year advances, then, my friends, let us make
                            individual efforts to secure this blessing to our various homes. "Every-day religion " can
                            be truthfully recommended as a " new thing under the sun," and worth more than many
                            inventions for getting gain. It aids labor, increases soul-wealth, and promotes health of
                            body and mind. Therefore, let us resolve that religion, as a mere fact, shall no longer
                            reside alone in church, nor find expression only in pulpit oratory; but that, henceforth,
                            its theories be reduced to practice, and its most difficult problems illustrated by
                            faithfulness in performing the varied duties of life, whether domestic, social or religious.
                            In conclusion, let us endeavor to buy and sell, speak and act, think and live, according to
                            its dictates for one year; and we may anticipate a near millennium for this crimeladen,
                            sin-stricken world, and a rapid advance toward that one condition so much desired, namely,
                            happiness.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Science and religion" TEIform="index"/>SCIENCE AND RELIGION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">Science, in its completest sense, is the knowledge possessed by the Divine Being, which, of
                            course, must be universal. As applied to human beings, it is that which leads to an
                            acquaintance with Deity. What are the various classifications of so-called natural science ?
                            Geology, mineralogy, chemistry, botany, astronomy and zoology, but so many different fields
                            in which God displays his own handiwork. One cannot intelligently and thoroughly study
                            these, without attaining the conviction that they give evidence of an intelligence, power
                            and skill immeasurably surpassing those of man; and whether, like Tyndall, he supposes the
                            power and intelligence to reside within what he calls nature, or, with others, to be outside
                            of it, yet to him there is a marvelous revelation of the supreme life. Chemical analysis
                            discloses to him the processes of creation to a certain extent; geology and mineralogy
                            exhibit the creative power combining the elements, on a far grander scale; botany,
                            displaying varied forms of beauty and splendor, evinces a yet higher degree of intelligence;
                            astronomy, if it does not exhibit infinity itself in the countless worlds it brings to view,
                            yet, like that, gives to the soul the most exalted sensations as it contemplates the scene
                            before it; zoology brings him a step, and a long step farther toward the Divine existence.
                            What multitudes of living beings does he behold in air, earth and ocean! How they confirm,
                            by their ceaseless activity, the words of Jesus: "My Father works hitherto!" It is not a
                            presumptuous conjecture to say of the infinite life, that it never rests. It goes on forever
                            in its work, producing grade after grade of varied existence, from that which requires the
                            aid of the microscope to discover it, up through the creeping, walking, swimming, flying
                            beings to man, savage, barbarous, intellectual and spiritual of the material spheres, and
                            hence on to man immortal and angelic in the celestial worlds. <pb n="2" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHCA.KER. Science, in its most comprehensive sense, lays open, by degrees, all truths to the
                            human mind; but these all, even the minutest, center in the Divine existence. They reveal
                            him to us, not each to the same extent, but yet the revelation is genuine and divine. Why,
                            then, the useless and absurd distinction of sacred and profane, applied to different things
                            that lead us to the knowledge of God? Is any thing profane but that which is perverted from
                            its original purpose by human beings? "God is in history" is language used by the celebrated
                            historian, D'Aubigne, and justly so. God has led the whole human family all the way from the
                            commencement of its existence, just as carefully, and by means of as many of his attending
                            angels as he did the Israelites from Egypt to the promised land. All history, whether that
                            commonly called profane, or that of the Bible — to which we are accustomed to apply the term
                            sacred — shows the divinelyguiding hand. All that is worthy the name of science is sacred,
                            and should be so regarded. That which treats of the Divine life, as manifested in the insect
                            world, may be of a different grade, from that which dis- courses of suns and planets, or
                            treats of the human mind in its intellectual, moral and spiritual aspects, yet really they
                            are all one. When we attain to any degree of the knowl- edge of God, by means of what is
                            commonly called natural science, or by intellectual and moral science, there is as really a
                            revelation as though an angel from the highest heaven conveyed to us the information, or the
                            infinite spirit had imparted it to us. The dif- ference is only in the manner of obtaining
                            it. The inspirations that diffuse through the human soul the life of divine love, may come
                            to it through various mediums, yet are they all divine inspirations, communicating to it the
                            knowledge of the divine life, and preparing it for its upward course to the realms of
                            immortality.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Revivals" TEIform="index"/>REVIVALS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">"Get the revival down," seems to be a very appropriate form of advice, for those who are
                            looking forward for a renewal of the pentecostal spirit, which is said to be so greatly
                            needed in our favored land of civil and religious liberty. Get the revival down into the
                            heart, that it may work for the purification of both body and soul. A general impression
                            pervades the community, that the coming winter is to be peculiarly propitious in aiding the
                            preparatory work, or, may be, in blessing us with the outpouring of a wonderful spiritual
                            ministration. Some of the teachers even in our own church have been anticipating, for some
                            time past, the consummation of a revival that would equal, if not exceed, in the area of its
                            operations, a larger section of country than did the revival of the war spirit during the
                            "great rebellion." Very few would presume to say that the renewal of promises and pledges,
                            that the awakening .into a deeper conviction for truthfulness and honesty, was not needed,
                            and certainly these should be the fruits of a religious revival. Get the revival down into
                            the very springs of life, and help to baptize ourselves into an element that will not only
                            wash externally, but will, as well, burn up all filthiness of the flesh and of the mind. The
                            good old prophet has said that "the knowledge of the Lord will cover the land as the waters
                            cover the sea." All hail to the dawn of this glorious day, when a revival of intelligence,
                            of reason, of faith and good works shall be among us, and all in harmony with the government
                            of Christ's kingdom, to which there is to be no end. God makes the revival. Through His
                            grace and the powerful operations of His spirit .only, will any good be accomplished; but,
                            with all this, God depends upon living active and earnest agents to vivify his work among
                            men. To the people of God —¦ spiritually dead or dying — a revival has a deep significance.
                            Indeed, a revival of the spirit of religious interest should be hailed with more joy than a
                            revival in trade, or a gala day of enjoyments. It is the life element of any order of
                            people, professors or non-professors, and is essential, even, to the happiness of the
                            individual. Our Shaker order dates its origin to the outpouring of the spirit of God; and
                            for its establishment and its continuance in this country, we are indebted to those peculiar
                            seasons which are termed religious revivals.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Question and the answer" TEIform="index"/>THE QUESTION AND THE ANSWER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kenistone, Amanda M." TEIform="persName"/>AMANDA M. KENISTONE</byline><p TEIform="p">When strangers to our faith and life Within our home appear, In answer to their questionings,
                            The truth we would make clear. They ask, " what unseen power attracts And holds in its
                            embrace, So many young, aspiring minds, In this secluded place?" "Is it a cherished love of
                            home — The strength of friendship's chain? The wreath that true affection weaves, For which
                            you here remain? Or have the teachings of your friends So closely twined your heart, That
                            conscience-smitten you would be, Should you from them depart?" "And do you never turn, to
                            seek A part in pleasure's strife? Aspire you not to joys, and loves Unknown to Shaker life?
                            As veiled in mystery you seem, Quite happy, yet at rest; Can you unfold the faith and power
                            Which mind and soul have blest? " A reason of the faith and hope By'which we daily live, We
                            render cheerfully to those Who listening ear will give. Not bound by dogma—barred by creed —
                            Nor held by force of law; The truth hath met our spirit's need, From its pure fount we draw.
                            Surroundings of external caste, However grand or high, The longings of the inner soul, Can
                            never satisfy. 'Tis true, that love of home and friends, Has power the heart to bind; But
                            what can meet the Sowings Of active, reasoning minds ? 'Tis truth in its simplicity,
                            Exemplified on earth, And purity of life, unfolds The germs of angel birth. When these are
                            quickened in the soul, That " ever aching void," Which worldly pleasure never fills, Finds
                            blessings unalloyed. Then faith, with reason is combined Cause and effect to trace: To learn
                            the laws that God designed, Should happify the race. We see that earthly wealth amassed, And
                            learning's garnered sheaves, Unless by wisdom's hand dispensed, The soul still yearning,
                            leaves. True happiness is what we seek; This virtue only yields; We tread the shining way
                            she marks, And love her verdant fields. Gay fashion's giddy throng we leave — Who trifle
                            life away; For hours of bliss, an age of pain Her forfeiture repay. The Christian's part we
                            nobly take, And with the ransomed few, We boldly vindicate, the truth That forms all things
                            anew — The virgin principle uphold That Jesus Christ revealed; This basis of a perfect life,
                            His glorious mission sealed. Though many sects that fill the land, The Christian title
                            claim, And rear their gorgeous temples high, In honor of the name; Yet cant, and mockery
                            within, And loftiness of mien, Fail to express the life, that crowned, The lowly Nazarene.
                            From purity, true pleasure springs; And peace, with love combined, Have power to captivate
                            the soul, And earthly passions bind. Where living faith and works agree, And souls in good
                            abound — A home, from strife and discord free, With truest friends we've found. We hold our
                            union to this band, By deeds of righteousness; And as our spirit powers expand, In light and
                            truth progress. Though many fail to comprehend The truth that makes us free, We claim the
                            boon of lasting peace, And heavenly liberty.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sociology" TEIform="index"/>SOCIOLOGY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>OLIVER C. HAMPTON</byline><p TEIform="p">Man is evidently built on a sliding scale of relative perfections. His lower conditions,
                            contrasted with those higher, of which he is capable, may be called evil for want of a
                            better term. Experience and observation, as well as his past history, prove him capable of
                            progression and gradual but constant improvement, both when viewed in vast proportions as
                            nations, peoples, or our entire world, in its movement in cycles of immense duration; also
                            in regard to individual men, through the experience of a few fugitive years. Man's loves, in
                            his lower rudimental conditions, are largely lusts, having for their object his individual
                            selfish gratification. Yet the law of eternal progression which runs through the universe,
                            gradually improves his conditions, making man less sinister and more generous and
                            benevolent, pure and sincere, until he occupies a serene home among the archangels. At least
                            this is inevitably inferred from the fertile span of ex2 <pb TEIform="pb"/> THE 3 istence furnished us
                            for observation here on the earth. This law of eternal progression is God-given, for man
                            cannot revoke it by any act or incantation, though he may oppose his motion skyward, and
                            even delay his sublime apotheosis for many long years. The more he expands toward higher
                            regions of perfection, the nearer he approaches his fellow man in love and sympathy, until
                            so far developed as to be prepared for a community life. Indeed, along the whole, otherwise
                            gloomy path of human experience, or as far back as we have any history, a few specimens of
                            highly progressed humanity have appeared from age to age, to light the gloom of the dead
                            centuries, and point to higher glories and sublimer possibilities. These have apprehended
                            and practically developed, in a gradual manner, some of the more palpable facts, principles
                            and truths of sociology. But what an immense field of discovery yet remains to be explored
                            in this direction. One curious coincidence connected with sociology is the fact that, so far
                            as we know, every system of society or community which has had any practical success, has
                            had to accept of celibacy as one of the most important, if not the most important, plank in
                            its platform of primal principles. My subject might receive a.curious and ingenious as well
                            as true and valuable exegesis right here, highly'favorable to the doctrine of celibacy and
                            sexual purity, but, having caught but a glimpse of this bright and magnificent thought, I
                            will leave it to the elaboration of those who have traced its logical sequences farther than
                            I have. In reflecting upon man's nature in connection with the subject of sociology, I am of
                            opinion that all men have, or ought to have, perfect, unrestrained freedom of will and
                            choice as to what kind of life they shall live, so long as such freedom and exercise thereof
                            does not interfere with the enjoyment of the same freedom of choice, rights and privileges
                            of others. That all men are positively equal, under precisely the same circumstances, in
                            rights and privileges, to all intents and purposes, until they infringe on those of others;
                            and even then, so soon as by warrantable restraint they can be induced always to respect the
                            rights and immunities of their fellow men and women, they should come into possession of
                            inherent rights. If the above postulates are true, the next inquiry would naturally be, what
                            is the best mode of conducting the polity of a community? that is, the several details of
                            its different departments? In the first place it appears self-evident to me, that just so
                            much dictation and government should be resorted to as to secure the above-named immunities,
                            etc., and positively no more. Any thing more than this does not deserve the name of
                            legitimate and proper government, but of usurpation, which is itself an infringement vipon
                            the rights of others, and no more justifiable in an executive officer than in any other
                            individual. Then if executive administrators of the government of a community can so
                            economize the details of administration as never to transcend the limits here prescribed, it
                            would appear, surely, to shut off all the friction among the elements of community that
                            could come in through the avenue of its administration, and this will be very noticeable and
                            important if it should happily ever be reached; for men, being under the same circumstances,
                            equal in rights and privileges, though not in talents, powers and abilities, feel very
                            keenly any infringement of this law of equality, and can never do otherwise. This
                            unwillingness to be unright- eously and unjustly treated can never be overcome. It is an
                            irresistible, eternal law, inexorable in its demands, the failure to satisfy which, must
                            inevitably produce eternal antagonism. Again, for the stability and smooth running of a
                            community, it seems to me that some method must be pursued in its modus operandi by which
                            every individual must stand, not indirectly, by implication, but directly by immediate
                            affirmation, self-committed to its general interests and behests, and to all of its
                            important movements and business. Without this desideratum, in vain shall we try to secure
                            the hearty cooperation of the members in any enterprise small or great we may undertake. I
                            have here written my views on the subject of sociology, as applicable to a successful
                            community, and I am absolutely sure this subject needs ventilation. I would like to see The
                            Shaker become a medium for the transmission of all kinds of useful knowledge adapted to its
                            field, in all directions calculated to benefit humanity, mentally, physiologically,
                            spiritually, scientifically, temporally and eternally.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bright side of sorrow" TEIform="index"/>THE BRIGHT SIDE OF SORROW</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Neal, Sarah Ann" TEIform="persName"/>SARAH ANN NEAL</byline><p TEIform="p">It is a fact, however strange, that in nearly all human life there is an inclination to look
                            on the darker side of the human heart, brood over its trials, and to live in realms where
                            despondency is germinated, permitted to grow and thrive, at the expense of the higher,
                            brighter and most cultivated elements of our organization. But those whose interior beings
                            have been lighted by the teachings of Christ's life have no occasion to despond, but are led
                            to " look up through the clouds " and behold the "far brighter day," replete with beams of a
                            heavenly light, that are never succeeded by darkening night. It has been wisely said, "
                            every Christian sorrow is the harbinger of a new-bom joy," and truly so; for sorrow, born of
                            earnest endeavors for the right, is soul-elevating, and to be enjoyed, rather than endured,
                            for its beneficent gains; but to obtain and enjoy these gains necessitates the practical
                            exercise of Christ-principles — a sorrowing unto participation of joy in the heavenly.
                            Christ suffered, sorrowed, and those who would be his disciples and follow him
                            "whithersoever he goeth," will joyfully sorrow too. Liberty waved her gilded pinions over
                            him who was "tempted in all points, yet without sin; " and this same signal victory and
                            freedom from the erring nature of humanity await all, who, like our Christian pattern,
                            earnestly, patiently, hopefully work. Such souls are the embodiment of a hope which creates
                            holier aspirations, wakens nobler activity, and causes the soul to rise above the land of
                            shadows into that world of radiant beauty, where all life is inspired by heavenly light and
                            love. Despondency is very unlike Christian sorrow; is the fruit of spiritual indolence,
                            whose tendency is to detract to greater gloom, and all for the want of development in
                            spiritual refinement, through angel purity. While we would eradicate from society all
                            despondency, we would cherish godly sorrow as the harbinger of soul-progress; for the truest
                            feelings of the heart are borne upward — homeward — through the corridors of sorrow to the
                            home of the eternal; and thence, with energies renewed, returning to the pilgrim, who is
                            thereby better fitted for the sterner, fiercer conflicts. But the joy of the real Christian
                            is in that beacon-light of hope, pointing to the end of life's turmoils, and revealing
                            eternal day replete with sweet soul-rest, and the wreath, made of the laurels of victory,
                            achieved through the sorrowful labors of Christian pilgrimage. Life is a labor, and nothing
                            conduces more to health, happiness and real spiritual growth than exercise of both body and
                            soul in all innocent activity. Creation never rests, only as continual growth and change
                            produce rest. Beautiful humanity, like the luscious fruits and brilliant flowers, is one of
                            the higher productions of this ever-creating fountain. Let us remember that our humanity is
                            capable of large development, increasing use and beauty, earthly and heavenly; and those
                            whose lives have felt the baptism of Christ, realize that, while they live, work, and sorrow
                            for the good, the better and best are just beyond.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reward of life" TEIform="index"/>REWARD OF LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, Elizabeth H." TEIform="persName"/>ELIZABETH H. WEBSTER</byline><p TEIform="p">" Blessed are they that do His commandments that they may have the right to the tree of
                            life." John while "in the spirit" on Patmos. " Blessed, or happy and spiritually pros-
                            pered, are those who keep the commandments of Jesus," not merely the code of laws, given to
                            the early Law-giver, but the " new commandment," which surpasses them all in that it
                            comprehends the whole, with greater reaches of love, unity and unselfishness. " The law was
                            a school-master to bring them to Christ;" and by obeying the former they gained the power to
                            fulfill the still higher requirements of the latter. By "denying self," they learn to love
                            the neighbor so well that they can " sing joyfully the song of Moses," " with the Spirit and
                            the understanding," and the still sweeter song of the Lamb, or the Christ-spirit. They are
                            to " have right to the tree of life," because " they are worthy," as the Revelator says of
                            those " who enter into the Holy City through the gates" of confession, justice, con-
                            secration and purity. But what is this tree of life, to which they have right, which " bears
                            twelve kinds of fruit ?" Is it not something of which they may partake continually, as there
                            is a constant succession of fruits, which will afford them cheer, strength, all needful
                            sustentation, and keep them in life and vigor 1 It is a tree of life, not of death. So much
                            so, that those who have not, by obedience to these physical and spiritual laws, gained a
                            right to the fruit, may still find benefit and healing, even from its " leaves," or the less
                            concentrated nutriSHAKEE. <pb n="4" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 4: THE SHAKER. ment of the fruit. If they
                            cannot, by obedience to the whole law, become " every whit whole," body and spirit, they may
                            find a healing principle, even in the leaves, or scattering truths, eliminated by the growth
                            of these germ principles.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prophecy" TEIform="index"/>A PROPHECY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName"/>WATSON ANDREWS</byline><p TEIform="p">The pentecostal wave, many fold redoubled, shall again descend and sweep with giant force
                            throughout the world. No sect, party, scheme nor combinations will avail to quench its
                            fires, nor turn its resistless tide one tittle from its course; but onward, ever onward,
                            o'er thrones and kingdoms it shall roll, when wrong of every name and nature — princely,
                            priestly and pecuniary — shall be swept from the earth. Other Pauls and Peters shall arise
                            on whom the cloven tongues of fire will again descend, and burning words in thunder tones
                            shall leap from off their glowing altars, and set a waking world on fire! Repentant cries
                            shall break the midnight gloom, and tears like rain-drops lay the rising dust. Oh God! be
                            mine so to live now, that love and not repentance shall then melt my soul to tears.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER. Monthly —60cents per annum. A DUAL ADVOCATE OF CHRIST PIUNCIPLES.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker to its readers—greeting" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER TO ITS READERS-GREETING</head><p TEIform="p">With hopeful and happy greetings to universal humanity, The Shaker enters upon its sixth
                            annual volume. Though returning to its original title, it would he understood to amplify
                            rather than detract dual principles, in all things which the name Shaker and Sliakeress
                            could imply. Advocating truths which have their foundation in the belief of God's duality
                            and the duality of Christ, The Shaker will illustrate the fruits of such belief by the
                            presentation to the world of a brotherhood and sisterhood in Christ, where impartiality of
                            rights is fully prevailing — in a perfected Shaker organization. The present management take
                            this early opportunity of bestowing unqualified approval and. commendation upon their
                            earnest and faithful predecessors, who have been so long and favorably known within and
                            without " the household of faith," as unflinching foes of error, and advocates of all that
                            is pure and good ; who have so unselfishly labored for our little Monthly, that they have
                            neglected duties demanded of them by the model organizations at whose heads they preside.
                            Thanking them in behalf of humanity, we believe "all the people will say, amen!" Elder F. W.
                            Evans assumed control of The Shaker at "a time which tried our souls" as by fire, and now
                            that he feels the autumn of his life more real than ever, it seems happily opportune that we
                            relieve him — than whom none could bo more loving, fatherly, nor more practically Christian.
                            We crave his mantle. In the immediate future The Shaker will be conducted in behalf of the
                            United Societies by G-. A. Lomas, as Editor, and N. A. Briggs as Publisher.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our standard bearer" TEIform="index"/>OUR STANDARD BEARER</head><p TEIform="p">Friends, of whatever name, sect, sex, color or condition, "lend us a hearing:" Christ having
                            laid the grandest of foundations, we purpose standing thereon; thence we will move more
                            heavenward, less earthward, and thence lift our Standard upon whose folds is inscribed an
                            undying opposition to the popular inclination — secession from Christ-practices for selfish
                            purposes — against which inclination the Christlife enters a continual and righteous
                            protest. On our Standard we would represent the principles of Jesus '' lifted up," hoping to
                            draw the attention, at least, of "all men and women unto them." Nor would we be chargeable
                            with faults of commission nor omission. If our Standard invites to any thing which, finds no
                            relation to the Christlife, we will reject it as soon as discovered; and if we fail to
                            append sufficient cross, self-denial, or progress unto increasing salvation, we are open to
                            such conviction, and will immediately make the addenda. We have risen in love with the life
                            of Christ — it is our criterion — and The Shaker is our bearer of " glad tidings of great
                            joy." In all our theological reasoning we shall urge the beauties of the Christ-life; and
                            the power that proceeds from true holiness will be the force with which we will attract,
                            invite and convert the world ! It will readily be admitted that The Shaker is pre-eminent as
                            a periodical in its peculiar field, towering '' above all the surrounding hills " of
                            journalism, in its testimony of radical Christianity. This testimony condemns no good thing
                            of nature, but presents, as superlatively spiritual and Christ-like, the following general
                            principles: A Virgin Like, as opposed to all fleshly lusts. It accepts the whole Communal
                            system of the church of pentecost — the model church — adding thereto the grand feature of
                            organization for both sexes. Peace of household and nation is equally advocated by it. It
                            teaches the efficacy of Confession, and the eternal relinquishment of error, and to keep
                            unspotted from the world, by a clean separation of its Church from all State politics and
                            governmental ptlicy. Until there shall appear a publication demanding a purer life than The
                            Shaker advocates, more peace, more "all things in common," less rich and less poor, and a
                            higher degree of unspottedness from all worldly lusts, Brethren, Sisters, be proud of and
                            work for our Standard Bearer. Send it your best thoughts on religion and sci- ence
                            generally, on philosophy, physiology, on cooking and all domestic duties; on farming,
                            gardening, building, mechanical improvements and moral truisms. Illustrate more fully our
                            social life as it is, or should be ; sing blessed songs, and proclaim our terrestrial and
                            eternal advantages in gospel life. Let us tell the whole world from what we are saved, and
                            how ardent we are to save others. Criticise us keenly and as kindly. We believe in the
                            ushering in of a brighter day. We knoiv the gospel in its full presentation " is sure
                            recompense for all we've left behind," and we mean to use it in endeavoring to answer " What
                            is Truth? " Gospel friends, take heart! "There's a light about to beam, "There's a midnight
                            darkness changing into gray ; "Aid its dawning, tongue and pen ; " Aid it, hopes of honest
                            men (and women), "Aid it paper, aid it type, " Aid it for the hour is ripe, " And our
                            earnest must not slacken into play."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute and criticism" TEIform="index"/>TRIBUTE AND CRITICISM</head><p TEIform="p">T. L. Harris says : "The dear and worthy Shakers have seen it (1); they have taken into their
                            hearts the fact that scortation is a serpent that stings even to the second death, and that
                            social antagonism is the result of disorderly sex-relation. They have based a system on the
                            negation of sex (2), and the annihilation of individual interest. Their chastity has been
                            denied by the vile, and their sincerity and honesty doubted by religionists; but upon a
                            ground hedged in by the necessary limitations of their theory, who shall dare say that their
                            work has not (3) been faithful and praiseworthy? Yet starved hearts and lonely lives,
                            affectional want in the midst of material plenty, stamp their system on the positive ground,
                            a failure (4) ! " (1) The author of the above refers, first, to solidarity—a consolidation
                            of interests— and we have seen it and practiced it, moderately successful, for a century!
                            and we believe "scortation"—lewdness — to be fully as effective as he strongly puts it. (2)
                            " Negation of sex! " Never. We fully acknowledge the order and rights of sex. We make one
                            pay tribute to the other in all that concerns Christian life. There are those yet living who
                            believe the Shakers hate each other as sexes; never speak to one another, eat apart and
                            sleep in separate houses. We have yet to see, outside of Shakerdom, the manifestation of
                            Christian love among the sexes, free from scortation, as may be daily witnessed in Shaker
                            societies, where the gospel is kept alive in the soul. A greater free- dom in love, and with
                            equal purity, we challenge the whole world to present. The perfect tense (3) uhas," might,
                            with equal propriety, be supplanted by the present tense "is." There may be '' starved
                            hearts, lonely lives and affectional want," but neither of these are found in a living
                            Shaker. Neither spiritual nor material poverty come in at our doors, while we are exercised
                            in the simplest Shakerism; and, hence, no love needs fly from our windows. We admit that our
                            system is not yet perfectly practiced, neither socially nor in the "annihilation of
                            individual interests," etc.; but, while "w^e will not tarry by the way," we wish T. L.
                            Harris, who has been trying so many years, or some one else, would succeed in establishing
                            an improvement on Shaker societies, where there wyere less " starved hearts " and just as
                            little or less "scortation;" less " lonely lives " and more spiritual protection; much less
                            '' affectional want" and more "material abundance," accompanied by as many or more angel
                            brethren and sisters! Truly, we feel our leanness, but not by comparison with any thing on
                            the earth as yet; and until some better way is established that will make "better Christians
                            of carnal men and women than our system proposes, we should be permitted — knowing no such
                            word as (4) "failure"—to rejoice that "the gospel is full recompense for all we've left
                            behind.''</p></div2><pb n="5" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lost opportunities" TEIform="index"/>LOST OPPORTUNITIES</head><p TEIform="p">That the first mission of the Christ was of an entirely missionary character, while the
                            second was to be solely devoted to organisation, are ideas of too general acceptation by
                            believers, but they are incorrect. They have been the causes of many lost opportunities for
                            human salvation. We are living illustrations of the fact, that the sexes can live on earth
                            in all purity, reflecting the type of the heavenly model; we have evidenced to the world the
                            possibility and Christian necessity of establishing, on a durable basis, a pentecostal
                            commune, wherein we can realize how good it is for Christians to dwell together in unity;
                            and are led by the spirit to confess our sins, and to urge our souls into a living
                            repentance therefrom. We realize, through our temporal and spiritual blessings, that the
                            gospel is very good to us; and we may be, through this realization, fostering a selfishness
                            that loses to us opportunities of telling the good news: "Whosoever WILL, LET THEM COME! "
                            The second advent of Christ teaches evangelism, even at much expense to us; for, if the
                            gospel is so good to us, is it not our duty to use and to make every opportunity serviceable
                            in spreading the gospel? We have been "watching, and waiting, and praying in earnest," that
                            the heavens would do something for us, and without any further expense to us; and we have
                            found that the evangelism that lias cost so little, true to the philosophy of cause and
                            effect, has been equally valuable in its results. The heavens are undoubtedly " waiting in
                            earnest " for us to lose no more opportunities for saving souls and blessing the Cause. One
                            of "the wise men of the East'r sends us a timely warning, in this number of The Shaker, to
                            be on the alert during the season of revivals which is apparently approaching, and to cast
                            in our nets. Bear in mind that a people possessing so many waves of pentecostal influence to
                            baptize souls with, we, as Shakers, have been to the least expense in evangelism of any
                            church in our own or any other land. We know of a people less than one-tenth our number and
                            ability, who, in one line of evangelization, as seems to them good, spend annually more than
                            double the cost of our Monthly for a twelve-month", and for which they desire and receive
                            only spiritual returns. One family of our Order, which has expended most in the diffusion of
                            our gospel principles, testifies that every dollar and exertion have been more than
                            returned. Others, individuals, assert their willingness to give one meal daily; to do with
                            less in several respects, if necessity requires, so that the gospel eagle may continue to
                            fly. Our time and ability, that may be requisite, are given; nevertheless, relying on the
                            generosity of brethren at home, abroad, and ''those not of our fold as yet," we believe we
                            shall be substantially paid. Let us all have sufficient faith in God, and love for humanity,
                            to spend and be spent for the Cause. We will, undoubtedly, receive help from those "
                            without," who would be numbered with those "within." But let us first show all humanitarians
                            that we have a confidence in the truths we preach, equal to our last dollar and exertion,
                            and as God liveth there wilkoe no more lost opportunities, and the returns from every effort
                            will he manifold.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trust" TEIform="index"/>TRUST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Harrison, Elizabeth B." TEIform="persName"/>ELIZABETH B. HARRISON</byline><p TEIform="p">Life seems to be a matter of continual trust — we constantly trust, and are trusted. We are
                            taught to put our trust in God, and truly, we need no other reminders of this necessity,
                            than the ordinary affairs of life. We needfully and thankfully trust one another, and are
                            ever most grateful, when we know that our trust has not been misplaced. We have, by the
                            provisions of the gospel, been placed in trust of large temporal possessions; and if we
                            abuse our trust, we shall be recompensed by an equal feeling of want. There are many effects
                            of mistrust, that will need the correction of the spiritual world. Thank God, I know how to
                            trust my Ministry, Elders, Brethren and Sisters — those in temporal care, and those bearing
                            spiritual burdens. Those who are trusted in largest confidence, will not so easily betray
                            trust, as when suspected. The greatest trust committed to any, is the pure gospel of Christ,
                            and being placed in this trust, even so would I live, not as pleasing self, but God who
                            trusts, yet will try all our hearts.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Light" TEIform="index"/>LIGHT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witham, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>MARIA WITHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">As gentle flowers inhale the dew, So thirsts my soul for light; Each day supplies my wants
                            anew, While e'er I walk aright. And in Christ's gospel there is power To set my spirit free;
                            Its light will lead me, every hour, "Nearer, my God to thee! " It fills me with that perfect
                            peace — Gives me a lowly mind; By it, I learned that sovereign grace, My soul sought long to
                            find.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Golden sayings" TEIform="index"/>GOLDEN SAYINGS</head><p TEIform="p"> "SEE! I HAVE CULLED THE FLOWERS THAT PROMISED BEST." One of the best " confessions of faith
                            " ever devised, is a straightforward, useful, cheery, consistent Christian life, seven days
                            in the week. __I would not give much for your religion unless it can be seen. Lamps do not
                            talk, but they do shine. A light-house sounds no drum, it beats no gong, and yet, far over
                            the waters, its friendly spark is seen by the mariner. So let your actions shine out your
                            religion. Let the main sermons of your life be illustrated by your conduct, and it shall not
                            fail to be illustrious. .... Character is an eternal temple that each one begins to rear,
                            yet death only can complete. The finer the architecture, the more fit for the indwelling of
                            angels. __In deciding questions of truth and duty, remember that the wrong side has a crafty
                            and powerful advocate in your own heart. ... "None were born to command the Golden Rule; but
                            all to obey it." —S. A. Weal. ... The principles of godliness are as old as time, and new as
                            the moment. — Ibid.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Physiological" TEIform="index"/>PHYSIOLOGICAL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER</byline><p TEIform="p">HUMAN SOCIETY, No 1. Looking over the surface of modern civilization, we see that almost
                            every thing is in motion, and that which will not move is left behind, and speedily becomes
                            obsolete. In mechanical matters the displays of adaptations are wonderful. On the one hand
                            there are manifestations of herculean power; on the other, microscopical delicacy of exe-
                            cution. Astronomy, soaring aloft, outstrips her old friend astrology, and actually fore-
                            tells future events. Chemistry no longer confines herself to inorganic matter, but has taken
                            possession of a whole kingdom of vital forces, and has already advanced to, and is now
                            ready, to introduce us to a world of invisible, and, I may almost say, omnipotent forces.
                            Physiology, akin to chemistry, treads also on the confines of spirit life, teaching that
                            obedience to her laws, forms, or mal-forms, civilizations; and that our social standing,
                            intellectual progress, our religious conditions and elevation, must be predicated upon her.
                            Disobedience to physiological law brings upon us bodily disease, early death, distress of
                            mind, domestic distractions, social broils and national convulsions, and associates us with
                            Egypt-loving Jews and with the giant sinners of the antediluvian world. History informs us
                            of the rise of nations and the fall of empires. The rise of a people and their ruin, is but
                            a chapter in physiology. One of the caliphs remarked: "As long as you stick to your plain
                            way of living, you will prosper." In other words, obedience to physiological law is
                            inseparably connected with individual integrity, moral and national power. His people did
                            not stick to their plain way of living; the consequence is, that, at this hour, they are a
                            contemptible? nation, and, had it not been for the interference of two powerful neigh- bors,
                            history would have written ere now, " The Saracenic empire is no more." The foundations of
                            morals, social life, peace, health and heaven, must ever rest upon physiology. It is the
                            ground on which Jacob's ladder stands — the medium by which pure intelligences can reach us
                            with heavenly gifts, and bear joyful tidings back to spirit friends. Turning to sacred
                            history, we find that the first sin was an act of sensuality. Tracing the consequences down
                            through antediluvian times, we read that it was disobedi- ence, first, to physiological law,
                            and then to moral law, which brought the flood, a catas- trophe second only to the entire
                            destruction of our planet. Again, we read that it was obedience to physiological law which
                            saved Noah and his family. It was said of him, '' that he was perfect" in generating Shem,
                            Ham and Japheth, while those around him were disorderly. After the flood, for what reason
                            was the father of the faithful called to leave his pagan home? Was it not that physiological
                            law, and those that rest upon THE SH^KEH. 5 <pb n="6" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 6 THE SHA.KER. it, might be
                            observed? For what end wTere all the wonders in Egypt performed, and why did Sinai shake,
                            but that physiological and moral law might be unshaken? Why did the Israelites forsake the
                            worship of the true and living God for gods of wood and stone; was it not that they might
                            give license to their appetites, and eat, drink and procreate without restraint? Why was it
                            that the God of their fathers threw them off, and left them a reproach before all nations?
                            Because they first violated physiological law, and then they violated every other law. Why
                            are heathens, heathens? Because they have no respect for physiological law. Are there any
                            heathens in Christian countries, so called? Those who have no respect for physiological law,
                            whatever guise they may assume, are heathens; and, being wrong in their outer life, how can
                            they be right in their inner? Why did the Divine man Jesus — the father of the new creation,
                            the captain and pattern of the higher life — solemnly declare that the physiological, the
                            moral, the Sabbatical, the financial, the sanitary, and the other laws given through Moses,
                            should not pass till all should be fulfilled? Because he knew that'the people of the better
                            day, who would live his life, would keep them every jot, not by constraint, but
                        willingly.</p></div2><div2 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Full and careful analysis of the tomato fruit..." TEIform="index"/>Full and careful analysis of the tomato fruit...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Full and careful analysis of the Tomato fruit, recently made, explodes the growing idea,
                                that it develops, if it does not produce cancer. Packed in cans, it is not so wholesome
                                as in earthen or glass; but it is wholesome, in any form, unless doctored ex- tensively
                                by the cooks.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Colds" TEIform="index"/>Colds</head><p TEIform="p">Many colds, and extremely bad coughs, originate from so bundling the throat that a
                                perspiration is created, opening the pores, which come in contact with the cold air.
                                Better leave the throat only covered by a loose collar, excepting when going out in the
                                wind or cold; then be particular not to dress the throat so warmly as to perspire. Be
                                fully as particular, about not warming up too quickly after being very cold, as about
                                wrapping up when ready to go out in the cold. Avoid excessive use of grease, and keep
                                the bowels regular.</p></div2><div2 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Americans are gradually waking up to the fact that oatmeal is..." TEIform="index"/>Americans are gradually waking up to the fact that oatmeal is...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Americans are gradually waking up to the fact that oatmeal is by no means an
                                        unimportant article of diet. As a food, the merits of which have stood the test
                                        of centuries, and which is designed to promote the sanitary condition of the
                                        nation by laying the foundation for more ready and vigorous framers for the
                                        coming generation, let us regard its general adoption as an article of diet as
                                        nothing short of a national good. Its phosphorescent qualities act as a general
                                        and healthful impulse to the brain, and on no other food can one endure so great
                                        or so prolonged mental labor as on oatmeal porridge. Properly cooked, it is not
                                        only a most healthful and nutritious food, but it is fully attested by its
                                        wonderfully rapid adoption as a popular diet by the very fastidious palaces of
                                        our American people.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="American working people" TEIform="index"/>American Working People</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Boston Journal of Chemistry regrets that the millers use all their finest..." TEIform="index"/>The Boston Journal of Chemistry regrets that the millers use all their finest...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> The Boston Journal of Chemistry regrets that the millers use all their finest, soundest
                                wheat for fine flour, and the poorest for graham or brown bread, a general name given to
                                mixtures of bran and spoiled floui\ "What we need is good, sweet, whole wheat flour,
                                finely ground and put up securely for family use, and any Western miller who will give
                                his earnest attention to furnishing such flour will realize a fortune speedily; securing
                                the most nutritive principles the Creator has stored up for man's food."</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Supposing your age to be fifteen, or there-abouts..." TEIform="index"/>Supposing your age to be fifteen, or there-abouts...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Supposing your age to be fifteen, or there-abouts : You have 200 bones and
                                        500 muscles; your blood weighs twenty-five pounds, your heart is five inches in
                                        length and three inches in diameter, it beats seventy times per minute, 4,200
                                        times per hour, 100,800 times per day, and 36,792,000 times per year. At each
                                        beat a little over two ounces of blood is thrown out of it; and each day it
                                        receives and discharges about seven tons of that wonderful fluid. Your lungs
                                        will contain a gallon of air, and you inhale 24,000 gallons per day. The
                                        aggregate surface of the air-cells of your lungs, supposing them to be spread
                                        out, exceeds 20,000 square inches. The weight of your brain is three pounds;
                                        when you are a man it will weigh about eight, ounces more. Your nerves exceed
                                        10,000,000 in number. Your skin is composed of three layers, and varies from
                                        one-fourth to one-eighth of an inch in thickness. The area of your skin is about
                                        1,700 square inches. Each square inch contains about 2,500 sweating tubes or
                                        perspiratory pores, each of which may be likened to a little drain tile
                                        one-fourth of an inch long, making an aggregate length of the entire surface of
                                        your body of 88,541 feet, or a tile ditch for draining the body almost 17 miles
                                        long.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Science of health" TEIform="index"/>Science of Health</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit of the farm" TEIform="index"/>SPIRIT OF THE FARM</head><p TEIform="p">Experiments in milking cows, twice and thrice a day, were sufficiently in favor of the third
                            milking to more than double the value, over the extra cost. An analysis of the milk in
                            summer, also proved the third milking favorable to health. __ From careful experiments, made
                            under the supervision of Lord Kincaid, of Scotland, we have most valuable conclusions
                            concerning manures* covered, or lying in open yards: Potatoes treated with barnyard manure:
                            One acre produced 272 bushels. One acre produced 292 bushels. Potatoes manured from the
                            covered sheds: One acre produced 442 bushels. One acre produced 471 bushels. The next year
                            the land was sown with wheat, when the crop was as follows: Wheat on land treated with
                            barnyard manure: One acre produced 41 bushels, 18 pounds (of 61 pounds per bushel). One acre
                            produced 42 bushels, 38 pounds (of 61 pounds per bushel). Wheat on land manured from covered
                            sheds: One acre produced 55 bushels, 5 pounds (of 61 pounds per bushel). One acre produced
                            58 bushels, 47 pounds (of 61 pounds per bushel). The straw also yielded one-third more upon
                            the land fertilized with the manure from the covered stalls than upon that to which the
                            ordinary manure was applied. ... A western farmer, raising and keeping on his estate, a
                            stock of three thousand kine, testifies that his experience proves that cornstalks, cut into
                            pieces, similar to chaff, and made into slop, produce more milk, and keep the stock in
                            better condition than the best of hay. Sheep, also, thrive better on stalks, of sweet
                            variety, when cut very fine, than on clover! Is not this why milkmen use so many? __Farmers
                            growing onions may be assured, that hen manure and ashes, thoroughly mixed, and freely sown
                            when onions begin to "bottom," will insure a finer crop than aught else "in the world." ....
                            Coal ashes, though pronounced useless by " studied " scientists, are found to be very
                            valuable by practical gardeners, when used freely on potatoes, tomatoes, cabbages and
                            vegetables generally. .... An intelligent farming insect — the spelling beel __"I thought
                            agricultural editors were intellectual beings, said a Missouri hotel-keeper, "but — but—,"
                            and then he stood back and surveyed the immense pile of bones he had left. __To test the
                            quality of a pear, take pen and ink; if it will bear writing well, it is a good pear, so
                            says the best pomological authority, the Revue de V Horticulture Beige. __The less salt you
                            feed any kind of stock, including human, the better. Salt, in abundance, will soon dry a
                            good milch cow! __ The cheapest and best manure combined is found to be clover, sown with
                            oats. Plough in, first of June, the following year, and plant roots for first crop. Sow
                            clover seed liberally. __Ticonderoga farmers have converted their church into a cheese
                            factory, and their race course into a cow pasture. ----To ripen cream best, set the milk at
                            64°, and skim in 36 hours; this is the best; next best, keep at a temperature of 60°, and
                            skim in 48 hours. Milk, set deep, is most approved. __It is not generally known that the
                            famous " Mother " apple was named by A. J. Downing, after Mother Ann Lee, and presented to
                            the Shakers by him. .... Instead of rowing contests for the Centennial, we propose that
                            collegians try which College can raise the most corn or potatoes on a given number of acres.
                            ----Weak soft-soapsuds have "fixed" the green worm on cabbage the past season.</p></div2><div2 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Starting an apple nursery" TEIform="index"/>STARTING AN APPLE NURSERY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Briggs, Nicholas A." TEIform="persName"/>NICHOLAS A. BRIGGS</byline><p TEIform="p">Select a good, rich soil and well drained. If not already rich, make it so by a generous
                            application of well-decomposed barnyard manure; none of your patent fertilizers. Late in
                            autumn sow pomace from selected apples, in drills three feet apart, and cover with one inch
                            of earth. But a small portion of the ground intended for the nursery will be required the
                            first year. When the young trees appear in the spring, thin them out, leaving them one inch
                            apart. A few wTeeks later thin to four inches, taking care to reserve the largest and
                            healthiest plants; for the superior thriftiness manifest at this stage of growth wrill be
                            likely to continue with the growth of the trees. Hoe frequently during the season. As winter
                            again approaches, dig up the young trees; pack them with sand in small boxes, place them in
                            a cellar, and occasionally sprinkle the sand to keep it moderately moist. At any time during
                            the winter the trees may be engrafted as follows: Obtain good, thrifty cions of the previous
                            season's growth from trees of the desired variety, cutting them into pieces of two or three
                            buds each. Make a cement of pitch or resin and tallow, sufficiently soft to spread with a
                            brush while warm. Spread a thin coat of this material on tough paper, and cut into strips of
                            about one-fourth of an inch in width. Now take from the sand one of the little trees, and
                            with a sharp knife cut it squarely off above the root, at the place indicating the surface
                            of the ground while growing. Make a transverse incision in the root portion an inch below
                            the first cut, inclining the knife slightly downward. Split the stock lengthwdse, so as to
                            remove one-half. Select a cion of corresponding size, and prepare it in the same manner, so
                            that when the twTo pieces are joined they will nicely fit each other. Now take a strip of
                            the prepared paper, and, commencing below the incision, wind it spirally, so as to
                            completely cover the joined parts and hold them firmly in place. Replace the trees in the
                            sand, cover fully the spliced section, and in the spring the pieces will be found to have
                            adhered, ready to growT, when again placed in the sand. Care should be taken, particularly
                            during the first season after engrafting, to keep the splice covered with earth.</p></div2><pb n="7" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trimming apple trees" TEIform="index"/>TRIMMING APPLE TREES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">Now, not in the spring, is the time to trim apple trees. Limbs, of any size, cut off the
                            sooner after the crop is gathered, the better, will heal kindly, and the stump will remain
                            clean and white. At this time, the strength of the whole system will be turned to repair the
                            wound, and to perfect buds for another season's crop. If the orchardist understands his
                            business, he will, as soon as possible after removing the fruit, take off every dead limb,
                            and superfluous branch; scrape the body, and wash it with strong soap suds, or lye that will
                            nearly float an egg. Dig round the trees and manure them. Then, if the borer, the
                            caterpillar, or any thing else deters the trees from bearing next season, charge it to
                            Providence! Who will demonstrate the best time for trimming, by cutting off a block from
                            limbs, the first of each month, and present to some agricultural society's museum? The
                            pieces will vary, from a bright wood color, to a black canker, unsightly, and yet
                            conclusively passing the verdict.</p></div2><div2 type="science" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Philosopher's branch" TEIform="index"/>PHILOSOPHER'S BRANCH</head><p TEIform="p">What is the Sun? Professor Rudolph, in a lengthy paper on the sun, says: A molten or white
                            hot mass, 856,000 miles in diameter, equaling in bulk 1,260,000 worlds like our own, having
                            a surrounding ocean of gas on fire, 50,000 miles deep, tongues of flame darting upward more
                            than 50,000 miles, volcanic forces that hurl into the solar atmosphere luminous matter to
                            the height of 160,000 miles; drawing to itself all the worlds belonging to our family of
                            planets, and holding them all in their proper places; attracting with such superior force
                            the millions of solid and stray masses that are wandering in the fathomless abyss, that they
                            rush helplessly toward him, and fall into his fiery embrace. And thus he continues his
                            sublime and restless march through his mighty orbit having a period of more than 18,000,000
                            of years. ... Prof .Walker, a Cincinnati scientist, has allowed himself to be stung once a
                            day for three weeks by bees to ascertain the effect He says that after about the tenth time
                            the pain and swelling were slight, the body seeming to become inoculated with the poison.
                            ... A new process of refrigeration, by the use of ammonia brought by great pressure to a low
                            temperature, has been introduced in New York from Paris. It is applicable to cellars,
                            packing-rooms, compartments in ships, etc., and is intended to keep the air in the rooms
                            pure, dry and very cold, without the use of ice. __An inch of rain is of more consequence
                            than would be generally supposed. On an acre of ground it amounts to 6,272,640 cubic inches.
                            This gives 22,622.5 gallons of water, which would fill a cistern capable of holding 360
                            hogsheads. Reducing it to weight, it would amount to over 113 tons. A trough 121 feet long,
                            10 feet high, and 3 feet wide, inside measurement, would just contain an inch of rain from
                            an acre of ground. __How to count interest: Four per cent— Multiply the principal by the
                            number of days, separate the right-hand figure from the product and divide by nine. Five per
                            cent — Multiply by number of days and divide by seventy-two. Six per cent — Multiply by
                            number of days, separate right-hand figure and divide by six. Eight per cent — Multiply by
                            number of days, and divide by forty-five. Nine per cent — Multiply by number of days, sepa-
                            rate right-hand figure and divide by four. Ten per cent — Multiply by number of days and
                            divide by thirty-six. Twelve per cent — Multiply by number of days, separate right-hand
                            figure and divide by three. Fifteen per cent — Multiply by number of days and divide by
                            twenty-four. Eighteen per cent — Multiply by number of days separate right-hand figure and
                            divide by two. Twenty per cent — Multiply number of days and divide by eighteen. __How to
                            make glass that is not brittle, recently discovered for the second time, was discovered for
                            the first time when Tiberius was Roman Emperor, as recSrded by Pliny; but Tiberius feared
                            the invention would deprive gold and silver of their value, and, having learned that the
                            inventor was the sole depository of the secret, he caused him to be decapitated. .. A French
                            machinist has discovered that, by keeping his turning tools constantly wetted with
                            petroleum, he was able to cut metals and alloys with them, although when the tools were used
                            without the oil, their edges were soon turned and dulled. The hardest steel can be turned
                            easily if the tools be thus wet with a mixture of two parts of petroleum with one part of
                            turpentine. .. .A useful composition is made by dissolving old rubber with benzine; this
                            will effectually mend rubber shoes, by using the composition to paste patches. __It is a
                            fact, that can be learned.by investigation and visit, that the first buzz, or circular saw
                            ever made, was manufactured at Mt. Lebanon Shakers, and the original deposited in the Museum
                            of the State Geological and Agricultural Society, at Albany, N. Y., by Bro. George
                            Wickersham. We were present at the presentation. __The "wonderful liquid glue" is common
                            glue dissolved in strong vinegar. A good and non-moulding paste is made with rye flour and
                            strong vinegar. ... Scientists have at last found out what tobacco smoke is—a mixture of
                            cyanhydric, sulphuretted hydrogen, formic, acetic, propionic, butyric, valerianic and
                            carbolic acids, half a dozen kinds of alkaloids and creosote. We don't wonder the humani-
                            tarians declare that it is killing people.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Judgement" TEIform="index"/>JUDGMENT</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Religiously born and religiously educated, we have a high appreciation of sacred history.
                            Jonah, as appears, was a prophet of the Lord — unwillingly so. The whale was elected or ap-
                            pointed, to teach the prophet the way of submission. But really, what have we to do with
                            Jonah, or with his whale ? With the people of Nineveh, we have something to do. They rise up
                            in judgment. Where, in the world's history, find we a nation, a people, a city, against whom
                            the Ninevites rise not up in judgment? Religious organizations, in special manner, stand
                            condemned before high heaven, by the example of Nineveh. The nearer right a religious
                            organization has been, when it departs from the principles of its organization, the more
                            inveterate the power behind the throne, that runs the government machine, against the
                            prophet of the Lord, against the voice of reason. The Lord God of Heaven is about to deal
                            with the dwellers of his little planet; first with Organization, Political and Religious—
                            such as are found wanting in the virtues of their founders — such as hold not fast the good
                            of the past, and lay hold of the good of the increasing degree of Light and Life, will be
                            found, if found at all, among the things that were, but are not. Let those who occupy high
                            official station, beware of the power behind the throne. Let them heed the voice of the
                            Living God, by messengers sent unto them. Let them remember the people of Nineveh. Let them
                            purge themselves and their people of the accursed thing ; for, behold I come quickly — have
                            come — to give unto every man and every woman, according as their works shall be.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Truth Seeker" TEIform="index"/>Truth Seeker</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Incense" TEIform="index"/>INCENSE</head><p TEIform="p">...Little words are the sweetest to hear; little charities fly furthest and stay longest on
                            the wing; little flakes are the stillest; little hopes the fondest, and little farms the
                            best tilled; little books are the most read, and little songs the dearest loved. And when
                            nature would make any thing especially rare and beautiful, she makes it little—little
                            pearls, little diamonds, little dew. Agar's is a model prayer, yet it is but a little one,
                            and the burden of the petition is but for little. The sermon on the mount is little. Life is
                            made up of littles; death is what remains of them all. Day is made up of little beams, and
                            night is glorious with little stars. __ "Religious controversy is the gates of hell." —Elder
                            F. W. Evans. __Be careful: A certain Shaker preacher, expatiating upon the beauties, and
                            Christian necessity, of the "all things common" doctrine, attempted a "golden saying" thus:
                            * * * " So closely do we attempt to follow this Christian rule, that we fain disown a
                            dollar's worth of property. Nothing that we have is our own, but Society's ; even the
                            clothes I have on my person arenot mine.'''' A lady in the audience, hearing the address,
                            complimented the young man freely, and then added : " If the clothes he had on were
                            borrowed, he borrowed them of some body who was just of his size!" Shaker preachers, be
                            careful of what you say.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>SOCIETY RECORD</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Mt. Lebanon : The new " Zion's " House is still an all-absorbing theme of the Church
                                Family. They purpose finishing only the Sanctuary this winter, which will be ready for
                                use by the early part of the new year, at least—warmed by steam, lighted by gas. Some
                                minor, but necessary, buildings are now being built. The North Family have been doing a
                                wonder. A large reservoir capable of holding more than 7,582 hogsheads, or nearly a half
                                million gallons of water, has been built about 600 feet from the dwellings, and at a
                                hight sufficient to throw, by its own weight, over the highest of their buildings. The
                                reservoir is fed from a pond a quarter of a mile distant, and conveyed from the
                                reservoir through iron pipes five and six inches in diameter. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, New York" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Watervliet, N. Y.: It is ever pleasant to record a free use of paint. The Church Family
                                of this place looks almost new, some seven or eight large buildings having been
                                re-covered with paint. An external observer remarked : " They are making Zion shine 1"
                                Jesse Wells, nearly a hundred years old, the last of the famous family of that name, is
                                the oldest man in Albany county.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hancock, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Hancock, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Hancock : 300 rods of stone wall, and halfstone wall, have been built recently; several
                                new buildings erected, and much painting done. Several roofs of slate and tin have been
                                applied. A pamphlet on " The Origin of Life and Species" has just been published here.
                                Few places can report znore enterprise than Hancock.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H.: The most noted feature we learn from here is the departure for superior
                                heaven of Mother Abigail Bowdoin, whose death will be found in our obituary section. She
                                was sixteen months old when Believers first opened their testimony in N. H., 02 years
                                and 9 months previous to her death. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shirley Village, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Shirley, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">SniRLEY Village : A large reservoir is being erected here also. Water is brought from a
                                never-failing spring three-fourths of a mile. After removing about 2,000 loads of muck
                                for the bed of the immense cistern, a kind of clay was reached, which, when burnt, sur-
                                passes the famous Bath brick, commonly used for cleaning cutlery.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p">Enfield, Conn. : Cemetery here vastly improved by marble headstones. Church lately
                                painted ; canal banks strengthened at much cost. Crops abundant. Six bushels of pine
                                (white) seed planted ! New railroad, running, within 125 rods of buildings. Notice to
                                Societies : Early advices, in items, of general interest, solicited.</p></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>REST FROM THEIR LABORS</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Twiss, Albert" TEIform="index"/>Albert Twiss
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Watervliet, N. Y., <persName reg="Twiss, Albert" TEIform="persName">Albert Twiss</persName>, aged
                                79.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miller, Moses" TEIform="index"/>Moses Miller
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Union Village, 0., <persName reg="Miller, Moses" TEIform="persName">Moses Miller</persName>, aged 76,
                                    Oct. 26, 1875.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Duffy, Mary Ann" TEIform="index"/>Eldress Mary Ann Duffy
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Watervliet, O., <persName reg="Duffy, Mary Ann" TEIform="persName">Eldress Mary Ann Duffy</persName>,
                                    aged 82, Nov. 9, 1875.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bowdoin, Abigail" TEIform="index"/>Abigail Bowdoin
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H., <persName reg="Bowdoin, Abigail" TEIform="persName">Abigail Bowdoin</persName>, aged 94,
                                    Nov. 7, 1875.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Annis, Harvey" TEIform="index"/>Harvey Annis
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Canterbury, N. H., <persName reg="Annis, Harvey" TEIform="persName">Harvey Annis</persName>, aged 67,
                                    Nov. 5, 1875. Average age, with fractional years added, 80 years!</p></div4></div3></div2><pb n="8" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Song of praise" TEIform="index"/>SONG OF PRAISE</head><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H. Break forth into joy. Sing together ye waste places of the earth. For the Lord
                            hath comforted His people. He hath beautified Jerusalem. I f| y MM II I Rejoice, rejoice
                            all ye living things that move, For all the ends of the earth shall see the salvation of
                            God.</p></div2><div2 type="music" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Music, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>MUSIC (No. 1)</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>James G. Russell</byline><p TEIform="p">To the Editor of The Shaker : As a sincere lover of the beautiful gift of singing, which
                            forms such a conspicuous part of religious services throughout almost the entire Christian
                            world, the humble writer would seek to portray his feelings upon this interesting topic
                            through the medium of the pen. Doubtless, other minds more active and talented would do far
                            greater j ustice to the subject, still this article may do no less than to enter, as a
                            befitting contribution to our little missionary paper, bespeaking the feelings and views of
                            an honest advocate of musical truths. First, music, according to the general acceptation of
                            the term, may be defined as " instrumental or vocal harmony"—a combination of sounds
                            agreeable to the ear. But the question arises, how are these sounds to be made agreeable to
                            the ear ? Are they the productions of an unqualified or untutored performer? Admitting the
                            fact that within the human organism are found the germs of this beautiful talent, it is only
                            through culture that we attain to that degree of development, that the rendering becomes
                            agreeable and pleasing to the listener, or easy and unaffected to the performer. Hence, it
                            is evident that, for the accomplishment of this end, scientific appliances must be brought
                            to our aid. The laws of one of the primary divisions of the musical department known by the
                            term melody, require that the various sounds entering into a musical performance, be
                            recognized as bearing a certain relation to each other. This relation or arrangement called
                            the scale, or gamut, discloses the proper intervals that must be given in music. These
                            intervals are known by the general terms. Major seconds and minor seconds require, on the
                            part of the singer, a great deal of care to be given correctly, and thereby sustain the
                            proper pitch of tone. If, for example, in attempting to give the tones designated as the
                            fourth and fifth from the first note of the gamut, the voice should disclose an imperfect
                            major second ; the effect must, of necessity, be very unsatisfactory to a sensitive and well
                            cultivated ear, and the same may be said of any interval throughout the entire range of the
                            musical gamut. This defect, when apparent either in harmonious or simple melodies, results
                            in what is generally termed "flatting from the key." In order to remedy this defect so
                            generally prevalent among the untutored songsters of our day, many facts must be considered
                            and taken into account. First, the voice must be correctly and thoroughly trained to the
                            proper intonations of the scale, which may be accomplished best by a thoroughly qualified
                            teacher — a living, practical example in vocal music. It is an established fact in the minds
                            of many musicians, that the ear may become so accustomed to imperfect intonations, that
                            false tones may be taken for true ones, and vice versa. An apt illustration of this fact
                            recently came under the writer's observation. It was related to him by a prominent musician,
                            who was also officiating quite extensively in the tuning of instruments, that on going his
                            rounds for that purpose, he observed a certain piano to be quite out of tune. The player,
                            who was first troubled with its imperfections, but at last became accustomed to them,
                            remarked that " it had been out of tune, but had got again all right of itself!" Is this not
                            too customary? Such seems to be the case with many untutored singers. From a neglect of
                            proper training, the tone is given quite below its proper posi- tion, and the ear having
                            become accustomed to the imperfection, fails in its responsible office and takes the false
                            tone for the true one. Another important fact to be taken into account is, the difference in
                            the extension or compass of human voices. While some are capacitated to reach an exceedingly
                            high point, but unable to go very low, others are able to go very low but unable to go very
                            high Still another class of voices finds its great field of effect between the two extremes,
                            unable to go very high, and equally unable to go very low, yet having a greater compass than
                            either of the other classes, as its compass embraces all the intermediate portion between
                            the two extremes. From this fact, arises the necessity of arranging music, in a style that
                            will meet best the capacity of these different classes of voices, and when the means are
                            neglected to accomplish this, we find each class of voices in its turn striving beyond its
                            proper limits, and by so doing we experience the dissatisfactory result of flatting from the
                            key. It is just as unreasonable to suppose that a low, bass voice is to do justice to a
                            musical performance, or to itself, even, while lamely groping up in the chambers of a treble
                            or tenor part of music, as to suppose that a voice naturally light and high should be able
                            to find its desirable effect down in the cellars of an alto or bass, and yet all of this is
                            presupposed, whenever a piece of melody is congregationally attempted. And furthermore, in
                            connection with this all-important point of voice training, there is a physiological side to
                            be viewed and considered, which must find its place for commentation in a future chapter
                            upon the subject of music.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Carry the news" TEIform="index"/>CARRY THE NEWS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Go, little Shaker — fly over the land and waters—carry the good news, that the Lord is come,
                            and the power of the Christ. " Shake all nations"; and fill every house with glory, through
                            the brightness of thy coming. Visit the fatherless and motherless; teach them of their
                            Father and Mother, God. Comfort the mourner ; feed those who hunger after an increasing
                            righteousness ; give hope of better days to the prisoner, and sound the trump of gospel
                            freedom to every creature. Friends of the truth, help us to extend it. Subscribe liberally,
                            for others than yourselves; and may every Sixty Cents so consecrated, meet you with untold
                            gratitude in the eternal world. Jgp Bear in mind, subscriptions are to be sent to N. A.
                            Briggs, Shaker Village, N. H. Exchanges and contributions to The Shaker, Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>