<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2804" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">28</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><date value="18980401" TEIform="date">April 1898</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">49-64</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="28" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
 1898.
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
with large type and on excellent paper.
It contains  130 pages and has
ILLUSTRATIONS
of the Shakers and their
The work gives quite an extended account of the  Several SOCIETIES, their
organization and general management.
Price,  50 cts.
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF  THE
MILLENNIAL   CHURCH,
OR
"United   Society   of  Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price, 50 cts.
THE ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all their
property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley, 1719 Franklin Ave, St. Louis, Mo.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
or the
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OTP  BELIKVKB8.
Price, 10 cU.
AND
SHAKE1IIISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the United   Society  of   Believers   in   Christ's
Second Appearing.    Illustrated.
By Giles B. Avert.
Price, 15cts.
APRIL,
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
m mm mum.
This work sets forth the. form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several                          '
ORDERS    OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of*, the
DEDICATION    AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
the same time, afford instruction to all inquiring minds. Price 5 cts. each, postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
HUMAN NATURE
is an illustrated Monthly, now only 50 cts.
per year, devoted to PHRENOLOGYPHYSIOGNOMY,  HEALTH,   MEDICAL
& SOCIAL REFORM.
Would you like a copy?
Send 5 cts. for Sample to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Francisco, Gal.
A Visit to the
of EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
BY
LLOYD H. CHANDLER.U. 8. W
Liberally Illustrated with half tone
pictures of persons and places.
The Village of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the loveliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price, 15 cts.
I       Address   H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
WITHOUT   DOUBT
THE BEST FAMILY PAPER  PUBLISHED
IS   THE
NEW   YORK  WEEKLY   WITNESS.
16 Pages,   Only   $1 a year.
Has'a very wide scope, comprising as it
does the following departments:
Editorials,:
Spirit of the Press,
Scientific ami Instructive.
The Odd and Uncommon,
Our Country's Hope,
Foreign News,
A Talk With the Doctor,
Around the Hearth,
Iiittle Men and Women,
Weekly Articles ly Georg-e It. Scott
Talmag-e's Sermon,
m            d Business,
World-Wide Field,
Our Family Story,
Farm and Garden,
Market Reports,
SABBATH READING.
16 Pages.   Only 50 cents a Year.
An Inter-denominational Weekly Paper.
Sabbath Reading is solely religious.
No news; no politics. A grand paper
for the truth-seeker.    It contains:
Editorial.
Christian Endeavor Topic,
Xpworth Leag-ue Topic,
Saltbatn-School Iiesson,
Choice Poetry,
Crood Stories,
Reports of Missions,
mothers'  Sabbath Afternoon
With the Children,
And a mass of matter carefully  selected.
Send for free sample copies of Witness
and Sabbath Reading. And send for
free sample pages of our Bagster's Bible.
Address
JOHN DOUGALL & 00., 150 Nassau Street, New York.
strange REVELATIONS,
DANIEL'S & STJOHN'S
PROPHECIES.
48 page pamphlet.    Price 10 cts.
13 for $1.00.               ;-;'
Address,   H. B. Beak, Pkeston^ pHro.
WONDERFUL
EXPLAINING--><pb n="49" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our mission--its authority" TEIform="index"/>OUR MISSION-ITS AUTHORITY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, Jessie" TEIform="persName"/>By Jessie Evans.</byline><p TEIform="p">THE ministry of Jesus, as recorded in the four gospels, is acknowledged universally to be the
                            guide and pattern for the entire Christian world to-day; it has been the stake to the
                            martyrs of old; and we believe that it will ever be the formula, by which all the
                            difficulties which beset humanity may be wisely and peacefully adjusted. This, then, should
                            be our primary study, as professed disciples of Christ. Much in the memoirs of Jesus
                            impresses us concerning his love, his sympathy, his tenderness for the children, his
                            forgiveness, and his charity; but there are sterner qualities, too, in the character of
                            Jesus, which should not be lightly passed over by the student of Christian biology. Let us
                            pause for a moment, and with careful scrutiny mark the bearing of our Savior, when
                            surrounded by the haughty Scribes and Pharisees. He has just left the presence of the
                            feeble, the halt, the leper, the blind; at his bidding the deaf ears catch the music of his
                            loving voice, and at his gentle touch the unclean spirit, reminded of its legitimate place,
                            instantly seeks it. In the hearts of the proud Pharisees rises the thought: ' 'Is not this
                            the carpenter's son ? is not his mother called Mary ? and his brethren * * * and his
                            sisters, are they not all with us? Whence then hath this man all these things ? " The
                            stilled tempest, the resurrected Lazarus, the liberated ones who were but lately so
                            grievously afflicted, are not accounted for on these lines. Nay, the spiritual mission of
                            the Christ is as distinct from the personality of Jesus <pb n="50" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 50 THE
                            MANIFESTO. as is heaven from earth; yet how perfectly the heavenly manipulated the earthly
                            in his case! Ah, herein lies the secret of success ! "If a house be divided against itself,
                            that house can not stand," he said to his followers. With the majority of so-called
                            Christians to-day, the trouble comes from this division. Conscience demands what the
                            physical refuses to expresshence the discords, the failures, the sufferings, so world-wide.
                            The ties of consanguinity should lay no bias upon the soul. He who preached that eloquent
                            sermon on the Mount was not the "carpenter's son." Long years after the carpenter first
                            claimed him as son, came the voice of the Divine, which said, "This is my beloved Son, in
                            whom I am well pleased." After this spiritual relationship was established, Jesus ignored
                            the plane of nature, not as an evil, but as a stage from which he had risen, as a bud
                            forgotten in the full blossom, as the home nest to the bird that has plumed its wings and
                            taken its flight into the broad heavens of God's watchful provident care. He had been "born
                            again." Henceforth his parentage was in God ; his brotherhood, man; and this admitted no
                            circumscribed ministrations. "Whosoever shall do the will of God, the same is my brother,
                            and my sister, and mother." They who judged from nature's stand-point reiterated the
                            inquiry: "Is not this the carpenter's son? From whence hath this man these things? And what
                            wisdom is this which is given unto him ? " Enumerating the physical relatives of the
                            messenger, however, far from answering the questions, only added doubt to doubt concerning
                            the spiritual message, with which the soul of Jesus was burdened; but they who were
                            spiritually awakened, when asked by the Savior who he was, replied, "Thou art the Christ,
                            the son of the living God," and divine commendation sealed the truth. All through the career
                            of Jesus the line is distinctly drawn by him, disassociating the workman from the work. When
                            the tribute money was discussed, how wise was the reply : "Render to Caesar the things that
                            are Caesar's, and to God the things that are God's." The human, in obedience to human law,
                            must yield its own, but the spirit"against such there is no law." "Though ye believe not me
                            (the workman) believe the works." Among the sayings of Jesus, little may be traced to merely
                            human origin; when the physical gave utterance, how instantly were the words modified by the
                            superior! Even in the fearful agony of Gethsemane, when the human pleaded : "0 my Father, if
                            it be possible let this cup pass from me," unhesitatingly followed the spirit voice,
                            "Nevertheless not as I will, but as thou wilt." In contemplation of this sublime phase of
                            the Christ character, the questioning arises, Are not we, as avowed disciples of the Savior,
                            oftentimes satisfied to see as "through a glass darkly?" Do we not, as Believers in this
                            Christian authority, too often confound the human with the spiritual? As <pb n="51" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 51 the Christ matured, Jesus as a physical existence became less and less
                            prominent, as the "carpenter's son" was lost to view in the multitudes which flocked to
                            hear, how distinctly rose the Christ tones in that sermon of sermons upon the Mount! The
                            sacred Covenant which we have subscribed, is something more than a legal compact. The Virgin
                            Church is not a Shaker village, however perfectly the material environments may be adjusted.
                            However low and mean we, as workmen, may be when compared with the "carpenter's son"the
                            fruit of obedience to nature's lawour faith, our covenant, our call from the resurrection
                            heavens, bind us to the self-same spiritual mission, which actuated the life forces of Him,
                            who said, "I and my Father are one." The walls of our material homes will crumble as dust to
                            dust, but what of the mission entrusted to us? Any individual or community, whose life
                            currents move in parallel lines with the example and testimony of our Savior, is successful
                            in every sense of the word and at every bend of the way. The individual may be boycotted by
                            his associates, but it is "for my sake and the gospel's" and bitter becomes sweet in the
                            assurance. The community may be reduced in physical membershipis gold of less value because
                            it loses bulk by the subtraction of the dross? Is wheat the worse for the removal of the
                            chaff? Our persecutions as a people have done us goodthey have taught us and brought us
                            precious humility. Our seeming enemies, in passing from our midst, have proved friends in
                            disguise. Their vituperations have revealed pungent truths, perhaps unwelcome truths, which
                            our several Communities have been wise enough and brave enough, thank God, to embrace. In
                            the time of Jesus, the "love of man}7 waxed cold," but the Christian truth gathered
                            followers enough to perpetuate the testimony, which will live despite persecution and
                            obstacles of every name and nature. There are no dying qualities in the essence of the
                            Savior's mission, there are no short-lived phrases in the testimony of eternal truth. We are
                            bound, by our Covenant, as assignees of our suffering founders, to be the "salt of the
                            earth;" we hold in the grasp of our consecrated wills "the pearl of great price." With the
                            unobtrusive yet unflinching authority of the Christ, may we hold our rightful place among
                            the churches of this land! The silver lining of divine goodness gleams through the ebon
                            cloud ; Grod's workings are deep, his designs for us are as yet unfulfilled. Our holy faith,
                            as perfect as God is perfect, will yet be coupled with works, which will attract and
                            convince the whole world of our sincerity; then though they believe not in us, yet the
                            purity of our work shall lead them to glorify God. This is our mission ; who will be the
                            missionaries ? East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Duty faithfully performed..." TEIform="index"/>Duty faithfully performed...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Duty faithfully performed opens the mind to truth.</p></div2><pb n="52" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Saviors" TEIform="index"/>SAVIORS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>By Alonzo G. Hollister.</byline><p TEIform="p">"Saviors shall come upon Mount Zion to judge the Mount of Esau, and the kingdom shall be the
                            Lord's." "I am, I'm your Savior, your friend and protector, I guard o'er my chosen with
                            peculiar care; So fear not, beloved, I'll guide you from danger And thou of my blessing may
                            most freely share. When deep tribulation like a flood is descending, And sorrow like waves
                            of the ocean doth roll, In the depth of affliction rely on my power, And I will preserve you
                            safe from all harm." # Who is the Savior that thus promises safety and consolation, and who
                            is the party addressed? Doubtless it was first given to an individual sufferer for Christ's
                            sake, but it stands equally good for every true disciple of the lowly Nazaiene. The party
                            speaking is evidently some one thoroughly identified with the Spirit of Truth, which is the
                            real Savior. Nothing but the Spirit of Truth can induce free rational beings to sacrifice
                            their own lives and individual interests in a straightforward, persistent, unselfish effort
                            to save and benefit others. It is true that individuals impelled by natural impulse, or
                            sympathy, or love of glory, have sacrificed their physical lives, for a friend, for their
                            country, for honor, ambition, affection or hate, but when such motives are traced to their
                            origin, we believe they will be found in part or wholly selfish. But the spirit which puts
                            by its own will and pleasure to serve not a narrow circle of related individuals, but many,
                            regardless of flesh and blood ties, in a life-long devotion to their highest good, is of
                            divine origin, and is divine. "We have the first and chief example of this in Jesus of
                            Nazareth, who rejected the will of his natural, inferior self, that he might make it his
                            pleasure to do the will of his Father in this respect. The Father loveth me, he says,
                            because I lay down my life for the sheep. His giving his life a ransom for many, did not
                            consist in his death on Calvarybut was given all along in serving, and in the daily cross
                            which he bore for his disciples' sake. Since his time, he has had many imitators, imbued
                            with the same spirit, and making the same sacrifices of self to carry on the good work by
                            him begun. He said, He that believeth on me, the works that I do, shall he do and greater
                            works than these shall he do, because I go to my Father. What does the term, greater works,
                            here signify? It means the growth and increase of the work, which in him was only in embryo,
                            to its mature, fruit-bearing culmination in organized communities of consecrated
                            individuals. There were twelve Apostles, concerning whom, we have the fullest record, by
                            Paul. It is a record which shows him to be a worthy disciple of him who said, I am the Way,
                            the Truth, and the Life. Paul gave his life for the <pb n="53" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 53
                            sheep, in the same manner as did Jesus, altho he received his gospel by revelation, after
                            Jesus had entered the Eternal World. If Paul, or any other disciple did greater works than
                            Jesus did, either they were not recorded, or they were not of the kind commonly supposed to
                            be miraculous. If Jesus was the truth, his Apostles were the truth. For he, or the spirit in
                            him, was the vine, and they, or the spirit in them, was the branches all of one substance
                            and mutual supports to each other and so the branches continued to grow one upon another in
                            regular succession, so long as he had any followers by the daily cross of self-denial. After
                            this cross ceast to be borne among those claiming Christ's name and authority, then came the
                            night which Jesus foretold. Walk while the light is with you, for the night cometh, wherein
                            no man can work, the works of God as he had taught them. This period is known in history as
                            the dark ages, because mankind in those parts of the world which claimed the greatest
                            enlightenment, were so ignorant, so barbarous, savage, lawless and corrupt, contentious and
                            vile, as to distinguish the period between five hundred and one thousand five hundred after
                            Christ, in the eyes even of natural men, from the ages before and since, for its
                            unparalleled brutishness and depravity of conduct. At the close of this distressful period,
                            the Spirit of Life from God, descended again to mortals, (Rev. xi., 11) and the character
                            and title of Savior was revived in Mother Ann, into whom the Spirit of Truth entered to
                            abide. That living Branch of Righteousness which was raised up in her, has put forth other
                            branches that have borne fruit and the succession of branches has been maintained through
                            Apostles to the present time. The life of the Savior is still given, inasmuch as they
                            manifest his spirit of self-sacrifice for the welfare of the body, to all the members who
                            are walking in his steps. We know we have this power, because by it we have been raised from
                            the death of nature and nature's darkness, to life and light and victory over the world. And
                            this is the time we read of in the Prophets,"Behold the days come saith the Lord, that I
                            will perform the good word which I have spoken concerning the house of Israel and the house
                            of Judah. In those days and at that time, will I cause a Branch of Righteousness to grow up
                            unto David, and he shall execute Judgment and Righteousness in the land. In those days shall
                            Judah be saved and Jerusalem shall dwell safely. And this is the name whereby she shall be
                            called the Lord our Righteousness."Jer. xxxiii. And so it is. David means beloved; Judah
                            means praise. This Branch grows up to the Lord's beloved ones, and He is their Savior,
                            operating through mortal instiuments, who have dedicated themselves to praise Him in this
                            service. In Christ's first appearing, this Branch was raised up only in the male order, as
                            proved by the male officered church, which claims to be the continuation, and sole heir of
                            the inheritance left by the Primitive Christians. Woman <pb n="54" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 54 THE
                            MANIFESTO. has been entirely excluded from having any voice in her councils and assemblies
                            for worship, hence the miserable plaint that follows the Prophets description of the Branch
                            of which it is said,"He shall be called The Lord Our Righteousness."Jer. xxiii. This plaint
                            of the Prophet, applies to the church of Antichrist, which ruled after the apostacy from the
                            primitive faith and the cross of Christ, till the time of Christ's second appearing, or for
                            about one thousand three hundred years. After this, the Lord again caused a Branch of
                            Righteousness to grow up unto David and to execute judgment and righteousness in the land.
                            As the only fit sequel and support to the first, this Branch came forth to visibility
                            through Woman,"For this is the name wherewith She shall be called, the Lord our
                            Righteousness."Jer. xxxiii., 15, 16. This Branch being now establisht alike in both parts of
                            manhood, the counsel of peace is between them, and there is no longer any complaint of
                            dereliction from duty, nor of deviation from righteous rectitude and equity and brotherly
                            and sisterly love, but an affirmation of Jehovah, strong as the ordinances of heaven and
                            earth and the covenant between day and night, that the seed of this union plant shall be
                            multiplied as the host of heaven and as the sand on the seashore for multitude, and
                            prosperity shall attend them forever. If Judah was saved and Jerusalem dwelt safely in the
                            time of Christ's first appearing, it must have been chiefly in a spiritual sense. Literal
                            Judah and Jerusalem, were both under the dominion of foreigners. The nation was torn by
                            factions who were saved from shedding each other's blood, by the iron rule of Herod the
                            Edomite, their hereditary enemy. The Jerusalem alluded to, must be the "Jerusalem above,
                            which is the Mother of us all," and which is descending out of heaven, from God, for
                            Mother's children to inhabit, in the Dispensation of the Bridethe Dispensation especially of
                            woman clothed with the Sun of divine righteousness and revelation; shedding abroad that
                            light which makes the New Day perpetual wherever she abides. Compassing man, both masculine
                            and feminine, with light and knowledge of eternal things. Undoubtedly, literal Judah and
                            Jerusalem, what remains of them, when the justice and righteousness of the New Era shall
                            become so expanded in operation as to recover their ancient heritage, will share in the
                            general and mighty renovation. But where on the inhabited earth, after one hundred and
                            twenty years of prosperous growth of this Branch of Righteousness, can the praise of Godr
                            rising from hearts that are saved, that worship Him in the Spirit of Truth, and the Holy
                            Jerusalem inhabited by gentle, peace-loving souls, dwell safelyf but in this liberty-loving
                            land of America, where freedom of conscience is guaranteed by the organic law of the Nation,
                            and maintained by the power of God operating through enlightened public opinion ? Can we see
                            the hand of God in this, to fulfill the word spoken by the mouth of His Prophets, twen- <pb n="55" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 55 ty-five centuries ago. Blessed are the pure in heart,
                            for they shall see their God. The eyes of the blind shall be opened, and the ears of the
                            deaf shall be unstopt when they turn with their whole heart, to seek and to serve the Lord.
                            "For in mount Zion and in Jerusalem shall be deliverance as the Lord has said and in the
                            remnant whom the Lord shall call."Joel ii., 32. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Remarks made at the funeral of our sister, Harriet Hastings" TEIform="index"/>REMARKS MADE
                            AT THE FUNERAL OF OUR SISTER, HARRIET HASTINGS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>By Elder Abraham Perkins.</byline><p TEIform="p">MY acquaintance with our departed Sister has been that of many years. I learned of her life,
                            her character and her principles, during my associations with her in the Ministerial Order.
                            Whatever the circumstances and conditions which existed in our several Societies, requiring
                            the counsel or judgment of the Ministry, I always found her seeking wisdom to enable her to
                            do duty honorable to herself and as became a Christian leader and minister of our Church;
                            that in a case coming before the Ministry for judgment, or before her as a member thereof,
                            in a demand for a verdict, she might do justice and give no cause for suffering through
                            selfishness, partiality or error on her part; that in results there should be no cause for
                            accusation of injustice, and that Zion should not be dishonored by the weakness and acts of
                            its officers. The motto of her life was truth, justice and honesty,loyalty to her Christian
                            faith, to her Communal Covenant and covenantal relations, and just and honest dealings with
                            all people, whether friends or foes. The words of the Psalmist well apply to her life and
                            character, truly demonstrating her trust, her readiness and willingness to be known and
                            judged in the divine order of God, as portrayed in the Twenty-sixth Psalm, "In Thee, O Lord,
                            have I put my trust. Prove me, and judge me. Thy loving-kindness is before mine eyes. I have
                            walked in thy truth. In innocency I washed my hands, so would I compass thine altar. I have
                            loved the habitations of thine house, and the place where thine honor dwelleth. My foot
                            stood in an even place. In the congregations, I bless the Lord." Thus may it be truthfully
                            said of our departed Sister. For many years she has been confined to her room under
                            suffering. Disabled by infirmity of body, she was unfitted for active service, and deprived
                            of many blessings pertaining to the social and spiritual relations of our Church, all of
                            which she has borne with saintly patience. Realizing, as she did, that physical restoration
                            was impossible, she had long desired a passport to that realm and haven for which she
                            faithfully and unremittingly toiled for a fit <pb n="56" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 56 THE MANIFESTO.
                            preparation, trusting to the welcome and embrace of friends who in this life had been with
                            her as Christian laborers and co-workers. With her I rejoice that her releasement has
                            come,that her reward is with her, and is such as we might all covet. East Canterbury, N.
                        H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thought of March" TEIform="index"/>IN THOUGHT OF MARCH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>From Mary to Fannie. By Mary Whitcher.</byline><p TEIform="p">And who can help welcoming Spring with its cheer ? The thought of a spring month, Brings
                            gladness more near. And tho the rough winter Holds light in its grasp Every spring like
                            appearance, We see 'neath the mask A beauty unfolding 'Twill be ours in its day. Its breath
                            may be March, But 'tis spring, same as May. 0 how we love beauty, And pleasure and joy, Then
                            why not let duty Grasp all in employ ? It need not be March, Or April or June, But just as
                            well winter, December as soon. If spring hath a place In the heart and the mind, The months
                            need not vary Our spring life to find. We'll ever keep youthful And pleasant and gay, For
                            nothing that's truthful Has blight or decay. 'Tis roses in winter, All sunshine and noon,
                            For nothing can hinder Uprightness to bloom. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><pb n="57" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Remarks made in church service, March 6, 1898" TEIform="index"/>Remarks Made in Church
                            Service, March 6, 1898.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stratton, Eliza" TEIform="persName"/>By Eliza A. Stratton.</byline><p TEIform="p">TTTE read in the good Book,"Make melody in your heart to the Lord." V V How to do this is the
                            precious thought of the morning, that has come with its brightness and freshness. Outward
                            scenes indeed bring to our lips psalms of thankfulness and gratitude, but the Sabbath of
                            Sabbaths which Believers may every day enjoy should, and does, draw forth unceasingly,
                            melody which wells up in the soul, and will increase as all the keys of our oeing are
                            touched by a sacred purpose that brings with its touch ho discord. The tones which make the
                            purest and richest of melody are love, joy, peace, long-suffering, gentleness, goodness,
                            faith, meekness and temperance. Would not these sounding through our thoughts, our actions
                            and our words make beautiful melody unto the Lord, and perfect harmony with all of his
                            children? Oh ! a life of good service is the richest of melody ! East Canterbury, N. H.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thank you" TEIform="index"/>"THANK YOU."</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> IT is a lamentable fact that the word of hearty thanks is exprest by so few
                                    people. How often is it that we show some one a courtesy, do some friend a favor,
                                    only to find it past unnoticed. The intention of the recipient to say "thank you"
                                    may be of the best, but the fact remains that it is not said. An intention is a very
                                    laudable thing, but when it remains an intention, and nothing more, it becomes the
                                    reverse of being laudable. Too many intentions die with their conception. We mean
                                    well enough, no doubt. We say to ourselves, "I must thank So-and-So," and our
                                    resolution is undoubtedly good. Then something transpires, the "thank you" is
                                    delayed, and what is the result? It is never saidor, if it is said, it is said so
                                    long after the time when it should have been that the saying has lost all its flavor
                                    and acceptance. And yet these delayed "thank you"s, these unexprest thanks, this
                                    acceptance of courtesies, as our right, is fast becoming a fixt habit. It was only a
                                    few days since that a physician was askt by a friend to grant him a favor. The favor
                                    was granted, and the next day came a note of thanks. "There," said the physician to
                                    me, "that is the first time in thirty years of practice that I have ever received a
                                    note of thanks from a man to whom I have shown a favor. And yet in those thirty
                                    years I have given free advice, have lent my time and my services without pay to
                                    hundreds of people." "Odd, isn't it, how people take as their due what they really
                                    have not the remotest right to ask or expect?" Exceptional experience? No, not at
                                    all. On the contrary, it is a most common one.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Ladies' Home Journal" TEIform="index"/>Ladies' Home Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="58" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. APRIL, 1898. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is publisht by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shakes Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all communications
                            to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. TERMS. .50 One copy one year, postage
                            paid. A cross in the margin will show that your subscription has closed. [Remittances for
                            subscription by Money Order should be on the Post Office at Concord, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">February. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Rain. Snow. 1897. 26.5 Min-
                                15.75 in. 1898. 29.5 % " 23 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 50 above 0. Lowest " " " " 8
                                below" Number of rainy days " " 2 " " snowy " " " 7 " " clear " " " 8 " " cloudy" " " 11
                                March, 1898. Lo! The winter is past with its cold chilling blast, With its storm bursts
                                and blizzards distressing We hail the young Spring, for we're sure it will bring The
                                musical birds, and to earth vernal dressing. At the close of the day, February 28, 1898,
                                we gave winter an obituary farewell. Its obsequies were performed with unalloyed
                                pleasure. It is the only death that has taken place worthy of note, for more than three
                                months Health, a prime blessing has been a boon companion attending us in the varied
                                duties of life, through the past winter. It would be a unique innovation of the common
                                methods of humanity, if there should not be any disturbance in the biliary secretions
                                that would produce a complaint. We strive to keep a watch over our spirits, that they do
                                not become incurably diseased with malaria of indifference or any maleficence, so as to
                                lose the divine protection of kind guardian spirits. It is the strife to keep alive our
                                gospel faith; "The faults of all others to freely forgive, but never make peace with our
                                own faults." The Church and North family hold meetings together on the Sabbath whenever
                                the weather will permit. We know that our union is a bond of blessing. Monday morning,
                                Feb. 14, Elder Joseph Holden, Elderess Harriet Bullard, and Sister Emma Jane Neal
                                started for Florida to visit Olive Branch to judge of its future prospects. They reserve
                                their opinions until they return. They have commenct their homeward journey, and will
                                stop in Georgia to view a part of the 46 square miles that the Union Village Community
                                have purchast there. "So we go, to and fro; While we tarry here below, But by and by we
                                shall hie To a dwelling up on high." Calvin O. Reed. South. Family. March, 1898. We're
                                always looking forward For something that's to be But the greatest yet to happen Is the
                                Great Eternity. To-day we're looking forward For spring which is to come, When trees
                                will be in blossom House-cleaning well begun. With gardens renovated To "blossom like
                                the rose," <pb n="59" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 59' And orchards pruned with neatness
                                Where finest fruitage grows, When sidewalks will be minus Of banks of ice and snow When
                                no more danger there will be Of tumbling down, you know. Our ice was nicely gathered
                                They say twelve inches thick, Some was thirteen and a half All solid as a a brick. It is
                                the sixth of March to-day And very much like spring, Roads are good for sleighing yet
                                For sleigh-bells daily ring. But birds outvie them with their songs, We daily hear them
                                sing. We're glad to learn our editor Still dwells upon this side Of that mysterious
                                river which Is called the "Great Divide." 'Tis said no sickness there can come If so it
                                grand must be To dwell apart from all that's ill In that Eternity. Now, kind editor, we
                                hope Some time you'll come this way, And spend a few weeks at our home When summer comes
                                to stay. Genevieve DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">March, 1898. We fully endorse the hope that our beloved editor may not long remain under
                                the bonds of physical affliction, and that the blessed angel that cometh with healing in
                                his wings will be a constant attendant; for there are none to spare, especially in the
                                editorial line, for those who are able to compile a magazine so replete with good
                                things, beneficial to the soul life of earth's pilgrims toiling on their upward journey
                                as was the March number of The Manifesto, must be sustained. This is not mere sentiment,
                                but we believe the voicing of the honest feelings of its readers. One more royal soul
                                has joined the triumphant band. The name of Frances E. Willard rests like a blessed
                                benediction over the lives of those who are struggling to burst the fetters of that
                                demoniac power,the liquor traffic. As President of the International Temperance Union
                                she won immortal laurels. May the mantle of her zeal and consecration rest upon those
                                who are left to continue the battle she so nobly led! March has commenct its record with
                                a quiet demeanor that is not generally ascribed to its character. Hope it may continue,
                                as we are ready to welcome the beautiful spring with its birds and flowers. Hot-beds are
                                being prepared and the sowing of seed and its care will be the business to occupy the
                                mind of your correspondent and his co-laborers. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">March, 1898. Fob all to whose home the hearse of transition called and bore from its
                                shelter a loved one, we send a wreath of loving remembrance and fellow-sympathy. When we
                                heard of the higher call of Frances Willard, we grieved, for we could not say it was
                                well, as she had not reacht the halting place of inability to benefit humanity. Is not
                                her life one of the best testimonials in favor of the Christ work of human elevation and
                                the Christ-like spirit of purity and intelligence that graces our Nation's history of
                                illustrious Christians? She is of those who knew that they must pursue the way in which
                                they would lead others, and school themselves would they teach others how to devastate
                                the wilderness of sin and gloom, and transform it into fruitful fields of active
                                goodness and virtue. As nature contains no useless forces, communities to be garlanded
                                with the vine of success, can not. So we catch the echoes from nature's vast
                                domain,"Toil thou for the future; Tho hidden may be the structure you build by devotion
                                and care, but if founded in virtue its worth will appear." As we turn the telescope of
                                mental sight upon the earth's surface, we see and hear <pb n="60" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> '60 THE
                                MANIFESTO. of "wars and rumors of wars," which remind us of our duty to do what we can
                                to quell the storms of evil about us. As we poise it higher, we see the glorious sun and
                                dome of white and blue, which teach us that the elements of heaven are lifegiving ; and
                                as we put on a spiritual lens we perceive a glorified host of the redeemed, who
                                sing,"Blessed are the peacemakers for they shall be called the children of God." Having
                                lost the work of putting together the Corn Planters, an industry for many years carried
                                on in this place, yet we lose not all profit, as through the successful manipulation of
                                the trade machine operated by Brother John Cummings, we will supply the new company with
                                the necessary lumber for their annual need. It is a general verdict that this winter has
                                been the worst experienced for ten years. The severity of the weather has not resulted
                                in sickness among us, yet we rejoice that soon a carpet of green will have replact the
                                present one of white, and hoes and pruning knives will take the place of shovels and
                                plumbing tools. George H. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoossee, Florida" TEIform="index"/> Narcoossee, Fla.</head><p TEIform="p">March, 1898. Among the things which are of special value to the Southern states may be
                                mentioned the Japan persimmon, of which we have several trees that will come into
                                bearing this year. When ripe the fruit is of a scarlet red color and extremely luscious.
                                It can be depended on as an every year crop, fully equal in bearing to any of our
                                Northern apple trees. In the way of diversity we think the fig comes next in value. This
                                is a little more sensitive to the change of weather when young, but when fully matured
                                it will stand the temperature below freezing. We have quite a number growing on our
                                place. With these we can number six grape fruit, twelve orange, six pear, six apricot,
                                with three hundred peach trees. This with two thousand pine-apple plants sums up the
                                number of fruit-growing trees on our place. Sweet potatoes all through the South have
                                become the poor man's as well as the rich man's luxury, while Irish potatoes are as yet
                                somewhat of a rarity and but very little grown on account of the small yield to the
                                acre. We have on our place ninety-two head of cattle both old and young stock of our
                                own. One hundred and ninety-six head of our neighbors, which we take to pasture. For
                                over a week past we have enjoyed the presence of the Lebanon Ministry accompanied by
                                Sister Emma J. Neal; also Brother Francis Pennybaker, of Pleasant Hill, Ky. They have
                                been like angel visits to us. Tho far away our friends still remember us, and we them.
                                Andrew Barrett.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">March, 1898. Season follows season, and we have only blessings to record. Home in heaven,
                                and heaven in the home makes burdens light and yokes easy. Even in the illness of our
                                beloved Editor, the "silver lining" turns our way, and we are permitted at this date to
                                bridge the chasm lightly and send kind greetings across in behalf of all the readers of
                                The Manifesto from whom we have many anxious words in this connection. The buzz of the
                                saw is making music near by and busy hands and feet are moving in quest of the
                                necessaries of life, which we find indeed a standing necessity. Winter term of school
                                will come to a close on the 17th inst. and while the children chatter about it, the
                                birds chime in from their nature studies in the tree-tops. Beloved Elder Freeman White,
                                of our North family valiantly made way through the drifts some days ago with brothers'
                                help to the Sugar Camp, and is already collecting the sweets of his labor. How like the
                                noble old monarchs of the forest seem such <pb n="61" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. loyal
                                ones in Zion, always yielding profit and sweetness! May God's blessing be upon us and
                                upon "the whole, whole world!" Jessie Evans.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Is the old year dead?" TEIform="index"/>IS THE OLD YEAR DEAD?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rupe, Nancy L." TEIform="persName"/>By Nancy L. Rupe.</byline><p TEIform="p">The old year is dead, is re-echoed around, Out of the calendar, out of the sound Of clamorous
                            voices, of present events, Fulfilled the mission for which he was sent. Gone, ever gone?
                            Nay, his influence still Doth live in the present, and, live ever will; Not one of those
                            years since the great birth of time, But live in some record which they've left behind. O!
                            man hast thou erred in an unguarded hour? Abused and dishonored thy God-given power, Made
                            home desolate, crusht paternal hearts, And trifled with time, as her days did depart? Then
                            none need to tell thee the old year still lives, Nor can his successor, with all that he
                            gives, Erase from thy soul the dark deeds of the past, Or vanish from memory the lives thou
                            didst blast!. Or hast thou been swift with a slanderous tongue? The fame to deface of the
                            aged or young? Or filled up thy coffers by cheating the poor, Then none need to tell thee
                            the old year's no more! It haunteth thy pillow, it stingeth thy heart, Thou may'st argue its
                            absence, or bid it depart! It will laugh at thy anguish, and mock at thy sorrow, Will tell
                            thee it liveth to-day and to-morrow. If imprisoned, some poor fallen mortal doth groan, Thou
                            mightest have rescued by act, word" or tone, The cup of intemperance to others did'st give,
                            Then none need tell thee the old year doth live. Hast thou smoothed the rough pathway of
                            some fallen one, A boon of compassion on others bestown?' In sickness or sorrow a kind act
                            or word, With grateful emotions thy heart's pulse been stirred? Of thy great abundance
                            did'st bountifully give? Then thy heart respondeth, the old year doth live. Thus live the
                            past years, in the depth of the soul, Thus writing their record as vast ages roll; And each
                            living soul will its own record keep. In glory or shame, all will sow what they reap, Then
                            sigh not and say not the old year is dead, Tho' its date from our calendar ever hath. sped,
                            Thus thousands have ended, and millions will come, Frail man but an atom, his race is soon
                            run. Pleasant Hill, K//.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Receipt for a lady's dress" TEIform="index"/>
                            RECEIPT FOR A LADY'S DRESS.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">[Contributed by Eldress Anna E. Charles.]
                                    In looking over some old papers I found in a copy of the "Weekly Register,"
                                    publisht Wednesday, July 31, 1816 a receipt for a lady's dress, and thinking the
                                    fashion would be just as charming to-day as eighty years ago, I venture to send it
                                    to your very interesting pamphlet. "Let your earrings be attention, encircled by the
                                    pearls of refinement, the diamonds of your necklace be truth, and the chain
                                    Christianity; your breastpin charity,, ornamented with the pearls of gentleness; 61
                                        <pb n="62" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 62 THE MANIFESTO. your finger rings be affection,
                                    surrounded with diamonds of industry; your girdle be simplicity, with tassels of
                                    good humor; let your thickest garb be virtue, and your drapery politeness; let your
                                    shoes be wisdom, secured by the buckles of perseverance." It seems such a dainty
                                    conceit that I thought the readers of your pages might enjoy it too.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If we knew" TEIform="index"/>IF WE KNEW.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Could we but draw back the curtains That surround each other's lives, See the
                                    naked heart and spirit, Know what spur the action gives, Often we should find it
                                    better, Purer than we judge we should; We should love each other better If we only
                                    understood. Could we judge all deeds by motives, See the good and bad within, Often
                                    we should love the sinner All the while we loathe the sin. Could we know the powers
                                    working, To overthrow integrity, We should judge each other's errors With more
                                    patient charity. If we knew the cares and trials, Knew the effort all in vain, And
                                    the bitter disappointment Understood the loss and gain Would the grim external
                                    roughness Seem, I wonder, just the same? Should we help where now we hinder? Should
                                    we pity where we blame? Ah! we judge each other harshly, Knowing not life's hidden
                                    force; Knowing not the fount of action Is less turbid at its source. Seeing not amid
                                    the evil All the golden grains of good. Oh! we'd love each other better If we only
                                    understood.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New Orleans Picayune" TEIform="index"/>New Orleans Picayune.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He commands enough..." TEIform="index"/>He commands enough...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">He commands enough who obeys a wise man.</p></div2><div2 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Twine" TEIform="index"/>TWINE.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">few persons have an idea of the enormous consumption of twine in this country.
                                    One of the greatest demands for the article comes from the farmers, who consume
                                    thirty-five thousand tons annually upon the self-binding harvesters. Allowing five
                                    pounds to the mile, this would be equal to a string long enough to go more than six
                                    times round the earth. It takes a length of about three feet of twine to tie a
                                    bundle of straw. The farmer sits on his machine, drives alone through his grain
                                    field, and without any assistance cuts, bundles, and ties twelve acres of wheat
                                    grain per day. The twine used on the self-binder is generally made either of Sisal
                                    or Manila hemp. The Sisal is the cheaper material, but it is not so strong or
                                    durable as the Manila. In some twines a mixture of the two is employed. For binder
                                    purposes, the twine should have sixteen turns to the foot, and a length of three
                                    feet would have a breaking strength of not less than seventy pounds. The twine must
                                    be carefully made, free from swells or knots, or it will not run smoothly through
                                    the knotting device of the binder. The average consumption of twine on a binder
                                    harvester is two pounds per acre. About twelve hundred feet of twine per acre are
                                    required. It costs the farmer about twenty-five cents an acre for his twine. The
                                    Manila hemp makes much the better twine, being stronger, smoother, and more durable.
                                    The raw material costs more, and its twine sells for more than Sisal hemp, but the
                                    Manila twine goes further, and is actually cheaper in use for the farmer; but this
                                    fact, however, is not appreciated by him; and he sticks to the Sisal twine because
                                    offered a little less per pound than the better article of Manila. Then, again, the
                                    Sisal twine breaks much of tener while running through the binder than the Manila.
                                    At every break the farmer must stop his machine, and spend ten or fifteen minutes to
                                    fix up. He never thinks of charging his lost time <pb n="63" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                    MANIFESTO. 63 aga nst his poor twine. As long as he gets it for a cent or two less
                                    than the better article, he is perfectly satisfied, no matter if it does bother him.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Scientific American" TEIform="index"/>Scientific American.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Friendship" TEIform="index"/>FRIENDSHIP.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">[Contributed by Mary Johnston.] 
                                    If there's one thing more than others That emotion always sends To a tired and
                                    weary wanderer, 'Tis the memory of his friends. Time may drift him seaward ever,
                                    Tide may waft his bark away, Homeward turns his better nature, To his friends he
                                    longs to say, Words that burn within his bosom, Thoughts that daily, hourly come Of
                                    life,s friendship oft remembered In the sacred ties of home. Oenius may give power
                                    and plenty, Fit us for important ends, But the drive-wheel of promotion Is the
                                    recommend of friends. As the magnet of the compass Turns the needle to the pole, So
                                    the heart of friendship ever Nerves the impulse of the soul; Sends the warmest,
                                    richest feeling Through the heart, tho sad or gay, Wakens in our inmost nature
                                    Thoughts that live beyond to-day. What are riches, power and plenty, If to gain them
                                    all depends On the risk of health or honor Ever absent from our friends? Often
                                    tender words have fallen On a heart all worn and weak, Driving back the tide of
                                    sorrow, Waking thoughts that none can speak. And our thoughts will span the prairie,
                                    Or e'en fly beyond the sea, Touching tender chords of friendship, Keeping silent
                                    company. Then be brave and own your friendship, Press the hand of friends you see.
                                    One good word or act of kindness Vibrates through eternity.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Harbinger of Light" TEIform="index"/>Harbinger of Light.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Carelessness--forgetfulness" TEIform="index"/>CARELESSNESS-FORGETFULNESS.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The usual excuse of a child for neglect of duty is "I forgot." This may be true,
                                    and yet not be an adequate excuse, for it is a part of one's duty not to forget to
                                    do it. Carelessness and forgetfulness are grave faults in children, which ought to
                                    be corrected lest they grow into habits. They are grave faults because they
                                    represent a selfish disposition, heedless of the wishes of those who have a right to
                                    direct, and one so absorbed in selfish thoughts and aims that all other things are
                                    forgotten. The child forgets to perform some allotted task because he is at play and
                                    his mind is concentrated upon his pleasures. He is careless about his manner of
                                    doing work because he is thinking of something else and anxious only to be releast.
                                    His faults in this respect, tho they may be trivial in themselves, have within them
                                    the seeds of a character dominated by self. The child whose selfishness renders him
                                    careless or indifferent acquires a bad reputation. It is in the interest of the
                                    child to prevent the formation of such habits which may be regarded as, at first,
                                    alternately the results of selfishness and a potent force for the development of
                                    selfishness. Discipline of some kind should be employed to admonish the child that
                                    he must remember what he has been told to do and must do his work well, as otherwise
                                    he will be thinking all the time of his own plans of enjoyment, and grow up not only
                                    careless and forgetful, but selfish.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Angus, Ann Maria" TEIform="index"/>Ann Maria Angus 
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Ann Maria Angus at West Pittsfield, Mass. Jan. 31, 1898. Age 68 years 7 mo. 12 days.
                                Sister Maria came to this Society when eight years of age, and is the last
                                representative of the Angus family, that were so numerous here forty years ago. I. K.
                            L.</p></div3></div2><pb n="64" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological Journal and Science of Health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">All will be interested to read The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health for March.
                                Several character sketches ranging from the devotional mind and benevolent bearing of
                                Rev. Geo. Hanson to the suggestive phrenotypes of some of our unfortunate criminal
                                brotherslead the minds of intelligent readers into channels of profitable thought. The
                                bicyclist is informed "that as long as he can breathe freely with the mouth closed, he
                                is safe, at least so far as heart strain is concerned." Read all about the children,
                                concerning whom much excellent advice is given. in fact, there is something for every
                                age and class in this well freighted magazine. Fowler &amp; Wells Co. 27 East 21st
                                St. New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of Hygeio-Therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy 
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy always has something educational for the
                                public. The Feb. No. is by no means an exception. The Science of Life, by Dr. Gifford;
                                directs attention to rheumatism, so widely prevalent these days. The Influence of Food
                                upon Character,by T. R. Allison, shouldbe read by vegetarians and particularly by all
                                others. Parents and instructors of the young will find pertinent suggestions in the
                                excellent article by E. C. Smith entitled Shall our Children become Drunkards? Only 10
                                cts. a copy. Dr. T. V. Gifford &amp; Co. Kokomo, Ind. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>The Ladies' Home Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The wide range of the
                                circulations of American magazines and the manner in which they penetrate the farthest
                                points of the earth found new evidence last week, when a single list of five hundred
                                subscriptions to The Ladies' Home Journal was received by that magazine from Bulgaria,
                                the list being headed by the name of Her Royal Highness, the Princess Maria Louise.
                                George Kennan, the Siberian traveler, said that he found this magazine in homes in the
                                steppes of Siberia, while Peary met with it in Greenland. It is an interesting fact that
                                The Ladies' Home Journal has subscriptions in fifty-nine of the sixty-five generally
                                accepted civilized nations of the earth. During the single month of December last, for
                                instance, it received subscriptions from Syria, Japan, Uruguay, Turkey, Congo Free
                                State, Transvaal, Liberia, Natal, Sierra Leone, Zululand, Bavaria, Bahamas, Burmah,
                                Brazil, Bohemia, Canary Islands, Honduras, Costa Rica, Nicaragua, San Salvador, Chili,
                                China, Egypt, Cuba, Fiji Islands, Germany, Hawaii, Madras Presidency, Hungary, Korea,
                                Java, Straits Settlements, Malaysia, Siam, Samoa, Palestine, Peru, Portugal, Tasmania,
                                and the Danish West Indies. The American Boys' League is a new organization, combining
                                the good features of the Chautauqua Circles with those of the Young People's Societies,
                                besides a philanthropic department intended to aid neglected, homeless and wandering
                                boys. Its work, except in the philanthropic department, is confined to boys between the
                                ages of 12 and 21 years. These may become members by signing the following pledge: BOYS'
                                LEAGUE PLEDGE. Believing that the use of tobacco and intoxicating drinks and indulgence
                                in profanity, gambling in any form, and licentiousness (including all impure acts,
                                thoughts and language) are all hinderances to my success in life, as well as sins
                                against my Creator, I do of my own free-will, declare that i will constantly try to keep
                                entirely free from all these habits. And, further, it shall be my constant effort to
                                secure a better education, to save a part of my earnings, to keep entirely free from
                                debt, to preserve my health and strength to be always manly and honorable, to maintain
                                our countiy's honor and integrity, to uplift the lowly and to teach others these
                                principles. And fully believing that whatever my surroundings may be. I may still, by my
                                own efforts, improve my condition, I take for my constant and life-long inspiration the
                                motto, "Self-Help." The School is heartily endorsed by the Ministerial Alliance of
                                Denver. Ralph Field, its founder and present Superintendent, is the General
                                Superintendent of the League. The official organ for this great work is a handsomely
                                printed weekly, called Brightside, publisht at Denver. It is bright, crisp and
                                handsomely illustrated with half-tone engravings of pupils of the School, and is issued
                                for $1.00 a year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Outlook" TEIform="index"/>The Outlook
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Among the many attractive features of The Outlook's Magazine Number
                                for March may be mentioned An elaborately illustrated article on "The Background of
                                Wordsworth's Poetry," by Dr. Hamilton W. Mabie, with ten fine illustrations; another
                                installment of Dr. Edward Everett Hale's "James Russell Lowell and His Friends," which
                                grows in interest monthly, and this month has some unusually interesting, heretofore
                                unpublisht anecdotes and chat about Boston in the "forties," and Lowell's social
                                relations while he was at Harvardthe whole illustrated by many portraits and other
                                pictures; an article by James R. Sheffield, ex-President of the New York Board of Fire
                                Commissioners, on the New York Fireman, with illustrations especially drawn by Mr. Chas.
                                T. Hill; athoroughly readable paper by Madame Blanc (Th. Bentsou) on "French Girls in
                                Domestic Life,,' with a portrait and short sketch of the author; a short story by Mary
                                Tracy Earle; another of Dr. Lyman Abbott's series of articles on Paul, which are being
                                widely commented upon; and a personal sketch of the late Frances E. Willard, by Lady
                                Henry Somerset, illustrated. ($3 a year. The Outlook Co., 287 Fourth Ave., New York.)</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Popular monthly" TEIform="index"/>Popular Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">
                                Bicyclists everywhere will be interested in the article on the League of American
                                Wheelmen which appears in the April number of Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly. It is a
                                well-written account of this great organization from its beginning in 1880, told by A.
                                Cressy Morrison, who, until the recent election, was the first vice-president of the
                                League. There are more than twenty very good illustrations, including portraits and
                            64</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
groups of wheelmen.   In the same number
Senator James H. Kyle has an article on "The
Statesmen of Jackson's Period," being the
sixth paper in this magazine's series on Andrew Jackson.  This also is prof u-sely illustrated.   The Island of Martinique is interestingly described by Julius G.' Tucker, IT. S. Consul
at that place.
William Stevens Perry, Bishop of Iowa,
contributes an elaborately illustrated article
on the Episcopal Church in this country.   The
great interest displayed in the Alaska gold
fields makes particularly timely and attractive the paper on Gold Mining in British Columbia, which treats the subject from a geological as well as practical standpoint.   Other interesting articles are The Coastguard of
England, At the Foot of the Pyrenees, by
Maryde Morgan, and April Fool's Day.
There are some excellent short stories, a
striking installment of the new serial, Marie
Tremaine, an illustrated Easter poem, some
fiction for the young people, and a talk about
new books.Frank Leslie's Pub. House, New
York.
The Anti-Tobacco Crusader, by H. L.
Hastings, is a vigorous factor, aiming at the
destruction of a wily enemy.   The writer has
the sympathy and hearty good-will of all interested in moral and physical reform.    Every paragraph in the Apr. No. is a sermon in
itself.   Secure a copy and see if you do not
agree with us.   Single copy, 10 cts.; per. <loz.
75 cts.; per. 100, $3.00; per. 500, $10.00.   50 c-ts.fa
year.   47 Cornhill.'Boston, Mass,
The Feb. issue of Humanity presents A Xew
Version of the Story of the Golden Calf, then
follow Harmony; A Word about Charity, and
othersno doubt just what will interest the
reader.   Price 50 cts. a year.
David B. Page, Ed.   Kansas City, Mo.
Fairy Gold is the title of a new novel by
Christian Reid, publishtby The Ave Maria,
Notre Dame, Indiana.   It is an admirable story and ought to be of special interest to young
people.   It has a lesson of much value which
it will be sure to carry to all its readers, and
will bring a truer outlook over the great
things of social life, which are apt to be regarded as small and trifling by thoughtless
youth.   Certainly it is a very real story.   The
book is neatly bound and in every way very
attractive.   Ave Maria, Notre Dame, Indiana.
Price $1.00.
SHAKEE   THEOLOGY.
A Book of 320 pages.    It contains not
only the Shaker's Faith but explains
Scripture Metaphor.    By H. L. Eads.
Address H. C. Blinn, East Canterbury
N.   II.
Makes $150 Per Month.
A fl" P lit Q can eas*ly make $5,00 to $10,00
A g u 11 I b per day selling my Latest Improved   Lightning   Fire   Kindler   which
starts fires without the use of other kindling.    Lasts for years and sells for a     .
small price.    J: E. Warren, Lafayette, Ind.
writes that he made $17.00 in one day selling them.    J. C.  R.   Neeland,   Vineland,
Minn., writes that he made at the rate of
$2  per hour.    J.   R.   Hudson,   Dickson,
Tenn., writes that he is making $150 per
month.    Ladies or gentlemen either can
sell them.    One good agent wanted in every town.    Write to-day for particulars.
D. F. WALLACE,    Smithville, Tenn.
The Uevr York
Dispatch.. ..
Oldest     and      Best      Recognized
Weekly    Paper     in    the    United
States.
Improved       Management,         and
Methods up to date.            ' .
A   Family   Journal
Of Morals and Public Interests,
Newsy, Literary, - Scientific,
Humorous, Dramatic, Entertaining. Also G. A. R., Masonic
Fire and Society News.
One Copy,  One  Year,  $2.50.
Post yourself on what is going
on in     New   York.     Address
The  Hew  York Dispatch
317 Broadway, New Yoxrli.
HOW TO MAKE MOTET!
If you are out of employment and want
a position paying you from $50 to $100
monthly clear above expenses by working
regularly, or, if you want to increase your
present income from $200 to $500 yearly,
by working at odd times write the GLOBE
CO. 723 Chestnut St. Phila., Pa. stating
age, whether married or single, last or
present employment, and you can learn
how to make more money easier and
faster than you ever made before in your
life.
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
TH& MANIFESTO.
A PRIVATE  SCHOOL
Jj"or Oirls -will "be opened at
M/t. Lebanon. W. Y.
Oct. 1, 1897.
Address       Eldress Anna White,
Mt. Lebanon, Columbia Co., N. Y.
Instructions in English and the Industrial Branches, board, etc., two hundred
dollars a year, consisting of two terms of
twenty weeks each.    Fifty dollars to be
paid at beginning and fifty dollars at close
of each term.
Competent and experienced instructors
at head* 6"f each department.
Location among the beautiful Berkshire
Hills.
Hygienic condition perfect, and all
healthful recreation encouraged.
Careful attention given to moral as well
as mental and physical development.
Here are taught hand and machine sewing, plain and fancy knitting.    With help
of instructors each girl will learn to keep
her wardrobe in repair.   Younger girls
will assist in dining-room, duties about
the house, and light ironing; larger ones
in general house-work; strength and
adaptability being duly considered.
Those who remain long enough will
have unequalled opportunities to becorrie
proficient in the management of households where order, cleanliness and the
best methods are considered of first importance.
No uniform dress required.   Simplicity
in make and durability in material the
chief requisite.   All articles to be laundered should be particularly plain and
simple.    No jewelry allowed.
AUTHOEISED   RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY.
Pric, 10 cts.
Royal makes the food pure,
wholesome and delicious.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure
ROYAL BAKING POWDER CO., NEW YORK.
50   YEARS'
EXPERIENCE
Trade Marks
Designs
Copyrights &c.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain our opinion free whether an
invention is probably patentable. Communications strictly confidential. Handbook on Patents
sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice, without charge, in the
Scientific American.
A handsomely illustrated weekly. Largest circulation of any scientific journal. Terms, f 3 a
year; four months, $1.  Sold by all newsdealers.
MUNN SCo.-New York
Branch Office, 625 F St., Washington, D. C.
Sketches of Shakers and Shakerism. A synopsis of the United Society of Believers in Christ's Second
Appearing. Illustrated. By Giles
B. Avery.    Price 15 cts.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>