<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1312" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">13</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><date value="18831201" TEIform="date">December 1883</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">265-288</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="13" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> VOL. XIII. DECEMBER. NO. 12. SHAKER MANIFESTO. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT
                        SHIRLEY, MASS. 'Blessed are they that hear the word of God and, keep it.' SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H.
                        1883. </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p> [Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
--><pb n="265" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><!--                   <div2 type="none">
                        <p> CONTENTS. Page. Page. Letter.—0. C. Hampton, 265 A Loving Tribute, - 276 Education, No. 2, -
                            266 Giving All, - - . - 277 Angel watches, 268 Religion, - •' Religion, ... » Our Savior's
                            Words, - - 278 Shakers, 269 The Future is Ours, 279 Newness of Life, - 271 Thoughts of
                            Truth, » Vision, Xo. 2, - - » NoTKS, - 280 After Many Teials, - 272 Sanitary, ... 281
                            Petition, House and Farm, -£.82 Self Conquest, Kind Words, - 284Contentment, 273 Collection
                            of Debts, " Reaching the Masses, - 274 Spirit of Thankfulness, 285 Wisdom, 275 Good work or
                            None, 286 j. Music,—Universal Love, 287 Conviction, 276 Books and Papers, - ¦ 288. 3T0K WHAT
                            DO WE LlVE, Deaths, ... Vol. XIII. DECEMBER, 1883. No. 12. </p>
                    </div2>--><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To all whom it may concern; we send..." TEIform="index"/>
                            To all whom it may concern; we send...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Shakers, September 1883" TEIform="index"/> Shakers, Sept. 1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> To all whom it may concern ; we send greeting, in a spirit of true Christian Love and
                            fellowship. We have a true and abiding unitary home, where a solid releasement from the
                            shackles of sin and ruinous habits is to be enjoyed, and where you may be, all the time,
                            engaged in doing good for others ;—the only situation in this or any other life, where one
                            can "see the travel of his soul and be satisfied." Do you want to feel at peace with God and
                            all men ? That boon is to be found iu our Shaker Home, by an honest confession of all sin
                            and heavenly repentance for the same; and subsequently and perpetually by a sincere
                            adherence,— 1, to the principles of Celibacy—Community—and non-resistance.—2, to a practical
                            obedience to the rules and regulations, instituted to restrain the passions and protect man
                            from his continual self-injuries through the prevalence of his selfish, rudimental
                            condition. Nothing is more necessary in Heaven or Earth than some plan of salvation by which
                            man may be protected from himself and here we have it not only in theory, but practically
                            carried out to the comfort and glory of every one who sincerely puts these principles and
                            rules in faithful practical requisition from day to day and year to year. Would you be glad
                            to walk with God in the cool of the day, when all the toils and conflicts are over and gone
                            and peace and consolation alone, reign triumphant, with a superadded assurance of a glorious
                            and supernal home in the halcyon hereafter? Here in our tranquil Shaker Home is to be found
                            these unspeakable blessings and beatitudes as <pb n="266" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/>has been proven and
                            witnessed to, by thousands of Believers within the last ¦century, who have come into this
                            sequestered retreat, sowed the seed of a Holy life—reaped the Harvest and gone to their
                            final rest in the mansions prepared by the Heavenly Father and Mother. There must be many
                            sorrowful ones in the world who, "even as the servant desireth the shadow" (that he may be
                            relieved from his toil—his weariness— his sorrow) who are this instant longing and yearning
                            for the fellowship of peace and rest from the sins and shams of a rudimental world, and
                            waiting for the illuminations of love and mercy from on high to reach, comfort and bless
                            them ; and point them to a Holy Retreat, from the cruel storms and disappointments of life.
                            To all such we say here is that Beautiful Home ; and it is waiting for you, to receive,
                            bless and comfort you. The very place the rapt prophet of old saw, when he exclaimed, "And
                            the ransomed of the Lord shall return and come to Zion with songs and everlasting joy upon
                            their heads ; they shall obtain joy and gladness and sorrow and sighing shall flee away."
                            Therefore come and partake of the waters of life freely.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. Hampton.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Education, no.2. its importance" TEIform="index"/> EDUCATION, No. 2. Its Importance.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reed, Calvin G." TEIform="persName"/>CALVIN G. REED.</byline><p TEIform="p"> As to what shall constitute a correct system of education, can be ascertained, only by
                            acquainting ourselves with the order and number of the particular faculties and their
                            requisitions which are the constituents of a perfectlv organized rational being. Having
                            tabulated this analysis to the extent of our ability to comprehend, we have the area and
                            elements which our educational system must include, and amply provide for. Any system that
                            does not embody and fill all these requisitions, is defective and should not be accepted as
                            sound. When a curriculum as nearly perfect as can be arranged, is adopted, to be successful,
                            competent teachers must be employed to carry the system into effect. As no stream can rise
                            higher than its source, so ignorance cannot impart wisdom. Small vessels cannot hold the
                            contents of large ones. In making an analysis of a properly organized rational being we
                            discover four distinct, yet correlated harmonious systems, or divisions, comparable to the
                            four points of compass, or the four parts of a harmony, viz : The physical, the
                            intellectual, the moral, and the spiritual or intuitional. The physical, holds us in
                            relation to, and in connection with the earth and animal life. The intellectual unites us
                            with the realm of cause and effect. The moral renders us conscious of our duties,
                            relationship, and obligations to our fellow men and to society. The spiritual or intuitional
                            gives us conceptions of God, and of our duties and obligations to the supernal, the eternal,
                            and the infinite. Any system that does not include these four grand divisions and make ample
                            provisions for them in its methods of tuition, is defective, and should be relinquished, and
                            a better, aye the best obtainable should be substituted in its place. These primary
                            divisions have subordinate divisions, requiring proper attention and culture according to
                            their importance and essential bearing upon <pb n="267" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/>the welfare, unfoldment,
                            and ultimate perfection of our existence. Our physical welfare, demands that we have a clear
                            and explicit knowledge of the laws of health, of the anatomy and structure of the house we
                            live in, and of the proper aliment necessary 'to keep us in a normal state of growth and
                            development, from infancy to the close of our earthly existence. Our physical education,
                            consequently requires that we study Physiology, Anatomy, Hygiene, and Therapeutics, and put
                            in practice their teachings, if we would have sound bodies. As we obtain our living from the
                            earth and her elements, it is necessary to study as a science as well as practice as an a~t,
                            Agriculture, Horticulture, Pomology, Chemistry, Geology. Mineralogy, Zoology, Botany,
                            Entomology etc., so that we may be able to obtain the best results from our labors, and to
                            secure ourselves against the attack and ravages of depredating animals and insects, and foul
                            weeds. Intellectual education, is indispensable to give us ideas, thoughts, compass of mind,
                            sound reason, mental acumen, intelligent acquisition and dispensation of knowledge, the
                            development of social power, which forms and maintains pleasant, useful, and reciprocal
                            relations with others, which is the basis of good society. Thus intellectual culture
                            requires a knowledge of spoken and written language illustrative of the objective and
                            subjective worlds. Hence the study of Elocution, Grammar, Rhetoric, Logic, Chirography,
                            Mental Philosophy, Mathematics, Drawing, Painting etc. are requisite. Moral educatiou,
                            teaches us our duties, relationship, and obligations to our fellow men. How to conduct
                            ourselves with propriety in the varied conditions of life, and explains the proper modes of
                            dealing with others in the general and particular transaction of intercourse and business.
                            Without this guidance and knowledge we are ever in danger of doing amiss, and of rendering
                            ourselves liable of producing unpleasant conditions, resulting adversely to our prosperity,
                            usefulness, and happiness. If we wish success in our social and business relations, we
                            should study Phrenology, Physiognomy, Moral Philosophy, Sociology, Biography, Etiquette,
                            Civil Government, Trade and Commerce, Legal Business Forms, Book-keeping, Domestic Economy,
                            General History and Literature. Spiritual or intuitional education, opens for our
                            consideration conceptions of God, psychical law, spirit communion, and methods of
                            development to fit us to dwell in the Father's House of many mansions, and to mingle with
                            the spirits of the just made perfect through a consistent course of self-culture and
                            treasure knowledge, wisdom, and understanding, in obedience to the divine law. This field
                            embraces Music, Poetry, Sacred History, Analogy, Prescience, Psychometry, Clairvoyance,
                            Revelation, Contemplation, Prayer, and Devotional Meetings, etc. The combined effect of
                            these unfolded powers comprised in these grand departments of our being, forms the true and
                            substantial basis to sustain the temple of pure and abiding religion. Pursue either
                            exclusively to the neglect of the rest, like the* poet's chain : "Whatever link you strike,
                            Tenth, or ten thousandth, breaks the chain alike." If we attend solely to the development of
                            the physical, we grow the brute. If it be the intellectual we produce the ma- <pb n="268" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> terialist. If the moral claims the attention, the result is the bigot, the
                            sectarian. If it be the spiritual, we have the enthusiast, the fanatic, the maniac. Either
                            taken separately and developed exclusively , will make an imperfect man or woman, whose
                            judgments and decisions cannot be safely relied on and followed. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Angel watches" TEIform="index"/> ANGEL WATCHES.</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Durant, Horace B." TEIform="persName"/>HORACE B. DURANT.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Earth hath her mysteries, Round which eternal shadows ever blend; And life is mantled in a
                            darksome guise, Mortal can never rend. Could we have vision clear, As one of old, touched by
                            the Prophet's hand, How closely would this world of ours appear Linked to the Spirit Land !
                            We, mortals, see it not, Yet sometimes on imagination's wing, We almost reach some fair,
                            seraphic spot, And hear its music ring. Through golden gates ajar, At times, we hear some
                            broken thrilling strain, That sweetly floats down to this world afar, To soothe its grief
                            and pain. We seem at such a time Akin unto that brighter world that lies Beyond the misty
                            river's marge—that clime Unseen by mortal eyes. Oh ! when the lonely heart Grows weary of
                            earth's hollow hopes and fears When all its clinging ties are torn apart, And graves grow
                            thick with years, 'Tis then the soul doth feel A longing for a better world than this ; And
                            shining messengers at times reveal Its dreams of lasting bliss. We never are alone— E'en
                            when bereft, we weep beside our dead, For there is round us many a watchful one, With soft
                            and loving tread.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> To be agreeable to others, we must forget ourselves.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M., E." TEIform="persName"/>E. M.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion" TEIform="index"/> RELIGION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Libbey, William G." TEIform="persName"/>WILLIAM G. LIBBEY.</byline><p TEIform="p"> What is religion? Webster has the following as one definition: "Religion, as distinguished
                            from Theology, is subjective, designating the feelings and acts of men which relate to God ;
                            while Theology is objective, and denotes those ideas of God which man entertains respecting
                            the God whom he worships, especially his scientific and systematic views of God, as
                            distinguished from morality." Religion denotes the influences and motives of human duty
                            which are found in the character and will of God ; while morality describes the duties to
                            man which true religion always influences. What are the facts relating to its operation upon
                            the human race from early times? Evidently, the first religionists, according to our ideas
                            of worship, had a strange way of showing their devotion to the Supreme Ruler of the
                            universe. We have reason for believing that human sacrifices were not uncommon in the days
                            of the Patriarchs. It is but recently that the custom was abolished on some of the islands
                            of Polynesia and in some parts of Hindostan. These people believed it necessary to appease
                            their offended deities. iNovv, if these natives are descended from the Jews, why should they
                            not offer human sacrifices as well as Abraham, Jephthah, or King Saul ? In all of this we
                            can seem to discern a spirit of intolerance in the priesthood until the advent of our Lord
                            and Savior. In short the relations of man to his God are mystified by the priesthood of
                            every nation and people. The Jews from having been one of the most favored, had become the
                            most intolerant. Josephus upbraided them <pb n="269" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> at or about the time of the
                            destruction of Jerusalem for with-holding their accustomed offerings to God in or on the
                            altar of the temple. This is but little better than the Typee savage who places bread-fruit
                            before his idol. To sum it up, there has been great pretense of conferring benefits on the
                            Lord, while men have treated each other as they have found most agreeable to their selfish
                            interest. "How hardly shall they that are rich inherit the kingdom of God." Jesus said,
                            "Clothe the naked; feed the hungry; do good for evil." Finally, the substance of it all is
                            practically to embody the teachings of Jesus of Nazareth, our Lord and Master. Let us grow
                            correct relations, a pure relation ; brothers and sisters ; fathers and mothers, after the
                            order of Jesus and Ann ; then will come the Millennium. It will be an abiding Utopia with
                            all who keep the sayings of the Father and Mother of the new creation,—The heavenly order or
                            the order of heaven which is purity, love, and peace. Every increase in the order of Divine
                            life has been at the sacrifice of the order that preceded it; this is the% fulfillment of
                            the law. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers" TEIform="index"/> SHAKERS.</head><p TEIform="p"> Some one has sent us the following extract from a notice about the Shakers. It is
                            interesting, but not without its quota of errors. Writers are inclined to add to such
                            accounts a few items for their own pleasure. 1. They kneel in the morning by the side of the
                            bed as soon as they arise, and the same before they lie down, and before and after each
                            meal. 2. The brethren and sisters generally eat at the same time, at two long tables, placed
                            in the kitchen, men at one and women at the other; sitting on benches and all silent. They
                            go to their meals walking in order, one directly after the other. The head of the family, or
                            elder, takes the lead of the men, and one, called elder sister, takes the lead of the women.
                            3. Several women are employed in cooking and waiting on the table, being relieved weekly by
                            others. 4. It is according to the gift, or order, for all to endeavor to keep things in
                            order. 5. Indolence and carelessness, they say, are directly opposite to the gospel and
                            order of God. 6. Cleanliness in every respect is strictly enforced. 7. It is contrary to
                            order, even to spit on the floor. 8. A dirty, careless, slovenly or indolent person cannot
                            travel in the way of God or be religious. 9. It is contrary to order to talk loud, to shut
                            doors hard, to rap at a door for admittance, or to make a noise in any respect. 10. Even
                            when walking the floor, they must be careful not to make a noise with their feet. 11. They
                            go to bed at nine o'clock and rise at from four to five. All that are in health go to work
                            about sunrise. In-door mechanics, in the winter, work by candle light. Each one follows such
                            employment as the deacon appoints for him. 12. Every man and woman must be employed and work
                            steadily and moderately. 13. When sick they receive the kindest care and attention. 14. When
                            a man is sick, if there is a woman among the sisters who was his wife before he believed,
                            she, if in health, nurses and waits upon him. BEMA.RKS. Number one could not be changed for
                            the better, as that is a correct statement in reference to the custom of kneeling for
                            prayer. 2. The Brethren and Sisters, generally, take their meals at the same time, but in
                            large families this rule has many exceptions. As some families are <pb n="270" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/>
                            270 THE MANIFESTO. obliged to accommodate from forty to fifty persons at one time, it
                            requires a large hall for the dining tables. There may be families, that still retain the
                            primitive bench, but those that prefer chairs provide them and in many Societies the chairs
                            have been used for more than fifty years. The Shakers do not engage in conversation at the
                            table, but as waiters are in constant attendance, if anything should be wanted it is
                            referred to them. Conversation during the time of eating is open to many objections. We
                            think that order is the first and best law, and that in going to and from meals it should be
                            carefully regarded. Disciplined men and women have a care in this respect, even in private
                            families. A company of forty or more persons, entering the dining room at one time,
                            certainly have need to walk in order, to prevent confusion and disrespect. 8. As no two
                            families may have the same domestic arrangements, this can refer to only one place. 4.
                            Number four is stated very correctly. 5. Too much cannot be said against Indolence and
                            Carelessness, and we are glad to have it known that we are still able to maintain a living
                            testimony against these evils, and in favor of Carefulness and Industry. 6. and 7. It is a
                            sad comment on the manners of the day that the Shakers are obliged to protect themselves by
                            such a rule of discipline. Contrary to order to spit on the floor. We would like to see the
                            same notice in other places besides the Shaker Village, and we may hope that the neatness of
                            a future generation may warrant us in looking for something better. 8. This is very good
                            whether a Shaker said it or not. "A word to the wise is sufficient." A dirty Christian
                            would, certainly, be more objectionable than a Pagan who observed personal cleanliness. 9.
                            This belongs largely to the reporter. The Shakers would teach that the cultivation of gentle
                            manners should be the guide in regard to conversation, opening and shutting of doors, and in
                            rapping for admittance at the doors of other people. A coarse, noisy fellow who may construe
                            all marks of propriety as being subject to some special order, forgets that his crudeness is
                            obnoxious and his p; esence distasteful. 10. Walking is also a matter for cultivation. Heavy
                            walking and scuffling across the floor should be avoided. A man of manners may be known very
                            readily by his walk across the floor of a dwelling. Over the door of the Shaker school-room
                            in Enfield, N. H. is this gentle hint,—"Walt gently and open doors carefully." 11. While it
                            may be correct that in some Societies the hour for retirement is at nine o'clock, it does
                            not follow that every family of Shakers is governed by the same set of rules. The Shakers
                            are expected to use good common sense in the regulation of their families and arrange their
                            hour of retiring to rest and for rising in the morning to meet the best interests of their
                            families. 12. "Hands at work and heart to God," is the Shaker watch-word. All are expected
                            to be industrious and attend to their respective duties as faithful members of Society. Go
                            not in the way of temptation, and to avoid this, find something that is useful in which to
                            be employed. <pb n="271" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> 13. We accept the truthfulness of this remark. 14. The
                            Reporter is responsible for number fourteen, which must be taken with some grains of
                            allowance, as he probably at this time fell into his own states. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Blinn.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Newness of life" TEIform="index"/> NEWNESS OF LIFE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Newton, Agnes E." TEIform="persName"/>AGNES E. NEWTON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The mission of Chi'ist was the fulfillment of the beautiful prophecy of Isaiah : "For
                            behold, I create new heavens and a new earth ; and the former shall not be remembered nor
                            come into mind." Isa. xlv., 17. Paul boldly affirmed, "Therefore if any man be in Christ, he
                            is a new creature." 2 Cor. v., 17. "The outward fulfilling of the law availed nothing." Gal.
                            vi., 15. Throughout the Bible we find many references to a day when all things should be
                            formed anew. Jesus testified, "Behold I make all things new." Rev. xxi., 5. Again, "A new
                            commandment I give unto you, that ye love one another." Johnxiii., 34. Paul very frequently
                            enjoined upon the would-be-followers of Christ, the necessity of obtaining newness of life.
                            We find him at one time exhorting the Brethren to, "Purge out therefore, the old leaven,
                            that ye may be a new lamp, as ye are unleavened." 1 Cor. v., 7. The redeemed were to sing a
                            new song, and have a new name written in their foreheads. To attain to tin's newness we must
                            forsake the old way, nor continue in sin, even though grace abound, for an exceeding
                            righteousness and purity of life in the new birth should much more abound. Can one whose
                            life is hid with Christ, having become, as the text avers, a new creature, continue in
                            trespasses and sins ? How fraught with meaning the following injunction ; "Like as Christ
                            was raised from the dead, (dead works,) by the glory of the father, even so we also should
                            walk in newness of life." Rom, vi., 4. They who would follow Christ, need to arise in the
                            power of the Holy Spirit and put Christ fully on ; living as He lived, thus becoming members
                            of his Church, which is, as the apostle declared "Without spot or blemish or wrinkle or any
                            such thing." The prayer of the Christian should hourly be : "Teach me duty, teach me beauty
                            In the new and living way ; To the surest and the purest I would give my life away."
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vision, no. 2" TEIform="index"/> A VISION. NO. 2.</head><p TEIform="p"> (Continued from last number.) S.—asked me if I wished to see H.— I said I should like to see
                            her. She then took me across the hall to the only room on that side-. On entering, I
                            exclaimed, "Whatsoever a person soweth that also shall he reap." The loom was small but I
                            saw a long flight of stairs in the center, and II.—sitting near the top. H.—said. Is this
                            you? "Of course it is," said she, answering me in a very coarse voice. Her form was
                            emaciated ; her face bore the marks of anguish, and long suffering. Her complexion was quite
                            dark, and her voice much changed. I was startled at her first remark. Why are you here, said
                            I? She answered, quite abruptly, "I have just reached this place. I suppose I shall be
                            obliged to go to the first stair some time." How long has it taken you to get so far? She
                            replied;—"Ever since I came here." I am glad to see you, said I, but sorry that you feel so
                            disagreeable. "I am quite willing you should," said she.. <pb n="272" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/>What makes
                            you look so sickly and poor? She looked up sharply and replied,— "Eat your food and regard
                            the Laws of Health." S.—then whispered to me.—-Ask her if she anticipated comfort after
                            death. "I did," replied H.—':I expected great happiness, but I have been condemned ever
                            since I came." Why did you die while so young? She answered me rather impatiently, "If you
                            regard the advice of friends you will shun much sorrow." I told her that her answers were
                            not wholly satisfactory. She replied, "Humbly acknowledge your faults, maintain the truth
                            and do not live for station, or a worldly name as I have." This was a lesson, O how my soul
                            sorrowed at the sad sight. What do you have for employment? said I. "Learn to be humble. I
                            suppose I must go to the bottom of the stairs," At the foot of them I saw nothing but a
                            small entry. I turned to S.—and said, I would like to go home. I could not refrain from
                            tears, and asked S.— Why is all this? She answered, "You have seen the condition of souls
                            who came to an untimely death. They did not walk in the light of God, nor learn to love the
                            truth. H.—must find her union and relation to the spirit of God by walking in the valley of
                            humiliation and repentance, and these stairs indicate the little steps which every one must
                            take. You must be careful of your health, not go beyond your strength, attend regularly to
                            your meals, for you need health of body and mind to be able to bear the cross of Christ. I
                            want you to be a permanent pillar in the Zion of our God. I then asked S.—to pray with me,
                            and I poured forth my feelings of thankfulness to my Heavenly Father that I have been
                            blessed to see these things while in this life.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">I would not think evil of any one, for that is the germ of evil speaking; and I would not
                            speak evil of any, for that proceeds from an impure heart.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="D." TEIform="persName"/>—D. </byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="After many trials" TEIform="index"/> AFTER MANY TRIALS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> We would a providence discern In all the seeming ills of life ; But if foreseen we might not
                            learn To trust the Father in the strife. Some things transpire for want of care. A power
                            that's given for our use; The ills arising we should bear, And own the penance of abuse Our
                            God is light, and gives us day Wherein to labor and be wise; His paths are strait, but in
                            his way The only course of safety lies. Let us arise and walk with God, And shun the
                            heedless paths of ill; He cannot alter, but our good Lies in accordance with his will.
                            Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Petition" TEIform="index"/> PETITION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hall, Susan C." TEIform="persName"/>SUSAN C. HALL.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Search Thou and try me, Lord, and see If all my powers are turned to Thee; If all my
                            motives, aims and strife, Tend only to a noble life. Search Thou and try me, Lord, and find
                            If in all cases, I'm resigned To be, to do, to act or share The burdens which are mine to
                            bear. Search deeper still my heart, I pray, Until the record of each day Meets thy
                            acceptance fully, Lord, In thought and purpose, deed and word. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self conquest" TEIform="index"/> SELF CONQUEST.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tatterton, Matilda J." TEIform="persName"/>MATILDA J. TATTERTON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> A triumph in the Christian's battle field, is a theme for a grand poem, a beautiful
                            painting, or for one of the most solid facts in the history of the world ; for there are
                            victories won by men and women over themselves, with which the honors achieved in war, are
                            not to be <pb n="273" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> compared. Of these silent successes we seldom hear, but if
                            written they would make a literature which would inspire its readers to greater conquests
                            than the heroism of a Napoleon or the capture of a. Richmond ! . The conflict is often waged
                            in the midst of friendships and pleasurable surroundings, when the exterior bears no
                            evidence of the fearful struggle ; again it is enacted in the calm hours of meditation, when
                            some subtle foe suddenly appears, and challenges the fullest test of our strength. No
                            witness is there save the unseen, who, when the tempter finds us fortified by purpose and
                            principle, are able to "bear us up, lest at any time we dash our foot against a stone." All
                            honor to the man or woman who fights hatred, revenge, envy, selfishness, or whatever form
                            the demon may assume, back to its last covert in the heart, and thence expels it forever !
                            Although no outward show of honor is given the victors in this good cause, they have their
                            reward, one greater than Fame can bestow. They come out from the combat self-ennobled,
                            though humbled before Him unto whom should be given all honor and glory, as being the Source
                            from whence they derive all their strength. Canterbury,N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Contentment" TEIform="index"/> CONTENTMENT.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">CONTENTMENT. Very much of the evil of life is imaginary, not real. Our fears, our
                                    disquietudes, very much modify our joys, and alloy our pleasure. We fail to
                                    appreciate the blessings which surround us. The expectations of the future prevent
                                    our present enjoyment. It is what we are to be, what we are to have, not what we
                                    are, or now have, which lays the foundation for our joys and pleasures; we are
                                    constantly anticipating without necessarily realizing. We very rarely fully realize
                                    our hopes ; many of our fondest expectations are but bubbles which 'disappear at the
                                    touch. Life is fruitful in suggestions of the future ; youth looks forward to
                                    manhood with the most pleasant anticipations—the realization does not furnish the
                                    satisfaction that was fondly hoped for. There is much of the ideal in our mental
                                    structure, and the period of manhood or womanhood, the pleasures of the afterward,
                                    are those which we longingly covet. We live much in the future—what we are going to
                                    be, what we are going to do. The gratification of our desires, when, as we suppose,
                                    we will be more under our own control, is that which inspires our soul with hope,
                                    and nerves us on for the present activities of life. That there are pleasures thus
                                    possessed, none will question. Imagination has its proper place in our mental
                                    constitution, and we would not in any way rob it of its legitimate fruits. It is
                                    pleasant, very pleasant to live in the future, in fond anticipation of future
                                    blessed realizations. But we all fail in much of the enjoyment of this life for want
                                    of a contented spirit, a want of appreciation of the constant occurring, recurring,
                                    and passing events of this life. We have our social, domestic, political, and
                                    religious privileges and blessings, and each and all of these we may enjoy, some
                                    more, .some less, and we are much nearer equalized in the circumstances of our
                                    existence than may at all times seem manifest to us. In the providence of God, we
                                    all have our sources of enjoyment, and they are all adapted to the circumstances and
                                    conditions of our existence. The millionaire, with all his wealth and earthly
                                    treasure, is not, in consequence of his possessions, by any means a happier man than
                                    the humble artisan who enjoys health and has all that is necessary to meet his
                                    wants. Indeed, the common laborer may really be a happier man than the millionaire.
                                    But we constantly covet—and it seems natural we should—the supposed more favored
                                    condition of others, while it, probably, is a fact that a change of condition would
                                    add to our discomfort and misery. It is probable, if not certain, that in all cases
                                    where there is a proper regard for the laws of nature, and the laws of society, with
                                    proper <pb n="274" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> care and industry, that our condition in life is just
                                    what it ought to be to secure our individual good; and th t is the design of a
                                    beneficent Providence, that it should be promotive of our present good and future
                                    well-being. It will he found, upon a careful survey of the matter, all things
                                    considered, that the circumstances of life are much nearer equal thiin generally
                                    supposed. The man who received ir.U one talent from his Lord, had he properly used
                                    it. would have enjoyed life equally as mueli, and been as meritorious, us bo who
                                    received ten. When much is given, much is required, and where little is given,
                                    little is required, and it is as difficult properly to use one talent, when we have
                                    but one as to manage ten, if ten be given us. It is manifest that we cannot all be
                                    millionaires, cannot all lie President.of the United States, cannot all be members
                                    of Congress, or managers of railroads. Now, true philosophy would teach us to be
                                    eont-nted with our lot, seeking always to make the best possible use of all our
                                    resources to improve our condition in life—thus having our contentment a continual
                                    fea.-t, and, to our mind, it was designed that it should be so. There is no reason
                                    why each and all of us may not fully accomplish the special object of our being, as
                                    well as those who seemingly are accomplishing very much more good than we are. The
                                    Bible says: "Godliness with contentment is great gain." What is meant by this great
                                    gain we cannot say; but it is certain that we will escape very much of the sorrows
                                    of life, be very much more joyful, and have very much more pleasure if we learn to
                                    feel contented with our lot, provided we have tried to make it as good as we could.
                                    The experiment is worth a trial.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reaching the masses" TEIform="index"/> BEACHING THE MASSES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Frazer, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRAZER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Mother Ann Lee and her followers reached the masses, by going to them where they lived in
                            their fallen state and condition. Tfrey used the gospel net of the mortifying Gospel of
                            Christ with which to fish for sinners, and none could* escape, great or small. They turned
                            the sinner completely inside out to himself, showed him the unreasonable and foolish
                            opposition of his proud fallen nature to the saving gospel of the Son of God. They taught
                            them to bring their deeds to the light by a full confession, and repentance. They taught
                            them to right every wrong, pay their honest debts, and make the best restitution in their
                            power. They taught them to take up a full cross against the morbid and evil propensities of
                            a fallen and corrupt nature, honestly, and with full purpose of heart, and in naming the
                            name of Christ to depart from all iniquity in thought, word, and deer], and then they would
                            know for themselves that this Faith did overcome the world within and without, and was a
                            present salvation in a loving obedience to the same. They taught that religion of the heart
                            meant something, it was allegiance to God and His Christ, with implicit faith in the same.
                            His Wisdom, His Grace, His Power was sufficient to regenerate, to resurrect into newness of
                            life by putting off the old man with his deeds, and by putting on the new spiritual man even
                            Christ, and by so doing we would become New Creatures. Without a doubt, for God and His
                            Christ with the Holy Angels with Believers who are just men and witnesses of this Covenant
                            of Grace and security for its saving power. "As far as sin hath reigned And souls have been
                            enslaved; As far as they've awakened And would be truly saved, As far as they're convicted,
                            To feel the loss of man, So far shall be esteemed The name of Mother Ann. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><pb n="275" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wisdom" TEIform="index"/> WISDOM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Collins, Sarah A." TEIform="persName"/>SARAH A. COLLINS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> O Wisdom, thou art lovable ; thou art beautiful. U that thou mayest be sought after more and
                            more. Thou art strong, for thou canst calm the troubled waters of life and keep us in the
                            right way which is for our prosperity and well being. When we hearken to thy voice, how much
                            smoother is our path through the journey of life. It has been said by one of old, Wisdom is
                            the principle thing, therefore get Wisdom. Wisdom is better than rubies and all the things
                            which may be desired are not to be compared with it. The simple word itself is beautiful,
                            and how much more beautiful are those who are adorned and by it are daily guided. How can we
                            but admire it, and participate in it while it comprises so much that is praiseworthy? What
                            are we without it?—like a vessel without a beacon-light to guide by night, or like a ship
                            without a helm. We need it every hour in the daily walks of life, in times of rejoicing and
                            in times of adversity. Where we see it exemplified the most we find the most perfection. The
                            older we grow, the more clearly we see (or ought to see) the necessity of cultivating this
                            most beautiful virtue. If we seek after Wisdom, earnestly, we will find a measure of it and
                            it will help to keep us from a great deal of unrighteousness. "Wisdom's ways are ways of
                            pleasantness, and all her paths are peace." Without her we are ever straying from virtue's
                            path. If we seek Wisdom now we may some day rejoice to know that in early life we began to
                            find the pearl of great price. Only a barque that is broken, Only a dark, dreary way, And a
                            life of condemnation For those who from virtue stray. Happy the thought that comes o'er me,
                            In Christ there's no dread nor fear; But joy in a life that's holy, And peacH with a
                            conscience clear. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to live" TEIform="index"/>HOW TO LIVE
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bonar, Horatio" TEIform="persName"/>BY HORATIO BONAR
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">He liveth long who liveth well! All other life is
                                    short and vain ; He liveth longest who can tell Of living most for heavenly gain. He
                                    liveth long who liveth well! All else is being flung away; He liveth longest who can
                                    tell Of true things truly done each day. Waste not thy being; back to Him Who freely
                                    gave it, freely give ; Else is that being but a dream; 'Tis but to be, and not to
                                    live. Be what thou seemest! live thy creed! Hold up to earth the torch divine; Be
                                    what thou prayest to be made, Let the great Master's steps be thine. Fill up each
                                    hour with what will last; Buy up the moments as they go ; The life above, when this
                                    is past, Is the ripe food of life below. Sow truth, if thou the truth wouldst reap;
                                    Who sows the false shall reap the vain; Erect and sound thy conscience keep ; From
                                    hollow words and deeds refrain. Sow love, and taste its fruitage pure; Sow peace,
                                    and reap its harvest bright; Sow sunbeams on the rock and moor, And reap a harvest
                                    home of light. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> If it is never too late to repent of evil, it is also never too early to guard against it.
                            One evil temptation withstood gives far greater power over the tempter, than ten confessed
                            and sorrowed over.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., E." TEIform="persName"/>—E. B. </byline></div2><pb n="276" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Conviction" TEIform="index"/> CONVICTION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Danforth, Nancy G." TEIform="persName"/>NANCY G. DANFORTH.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "No man can come to me, except the Father which hath sent me draw him." There were great
                            multitudes who came to hear the teachings of Jesus and to witness the miracles performed by
                            him ; therefore this coming to him must mean something more than to come as one man comes
                            to, or meets another. The spirit of anointing rested upon Jesus thus constituting him the
                            Christ, the Son of God, and it was the voice of the spirit that spake, saying, "No man can
                            come to me except the Father draw him." The drawings of the Father are the whisperings of
                            the spirit of God through the conscience, persuading us to leave all wrong and sinful
                            habits, and live a holy, godly life. It is the spirit of long-suffering love, that
                            constantly follows us, and pleads again and again to be heard, though often slighted and
                            refused. Yet this voice can be hushed for a while by willful disobedience and continually
                            slighting its monitions; still the time will come when it will awaken with redoubled
                            condemnation to the evil-doer. Therefore it is a fearful thing to reject the drawings of the
                            Father given for our salvation. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If we wish to make a renewal of spirit..." TEIform="index"/>
                            If we wish to make a renewal of spirit...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> If we wish to make a renewal of spirit power, a thing to be prized, valued and truthful
                            among the people,—make it so by bestowing confidence and love upon those who are and will
                            be, targets for the scorn of the infidel and unbeliever. Accepting new truths honestly and
                            candidly given is the path to true progression. Truth is eternal. God's truths are forever
                            the same, but the modes of presenting them may vary somewhat with each age. Languages
                            change, human condition changes, and while meeting these changes, the true, the pure, the
                            good will never surrender any part oi the principles of truth. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barrett, Andrew" TEIform="persName"/>Andrew Barrett.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For what do we live?" TEIform="index"/> FOE WHAT DO WE LIVE ?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ervin, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>ANNA ERVIN.</byline><p TEIform="p"> What do we live for? Is it to be The sport of earthly power; To launch our bark on fortune's
                            sea, And float perhaps an hour; To waste our time in idle dreams, Of what may be to-morrow;
                            To glean with care from present scenes, The source of future sorrow? Nay, we were formed to
                            search for truth, Through paths made plain by reason ; To hail the light in earliest youth,
                            Which shines in every season ; Yea, we were made to win below The boon hereafter given, To
                            calmly smile at earthly woe And find our home in heaven. Enfield, Conn. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Loving tribute" TEIform="index"/> A LOVING TRIBUTE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Boyle, Katy" TEIform="persName"/>KATY BOYLE.</byline><p TEIform="p">Written in remembrance of Helen Vanzandt.—See Nov. Manifesto. While yet in youthful, tender
                            years, The Reaper spared her not; Mid many seeming riper plants, 'Twas her the Reaper
                            sought. The reason why is all a mist— We cannot understand, But, Lord, we'll trust her to
                            Thy care And say "Thy will be done." 'Tis hard to part with one so loved, In time's
                            uncertain vale, Who in our joys and sorrows shared And with us stemmed life's wave. Our
                            earthly nature would complain And murmur at the change, But yield when recollections rise,
                            This change we too must make. We have a solace by and by, We'll meet beyond time's shore. To
                            part no more what may betide, When earthly strifes are o'er. Again, we say, "Thy will be
                            done," We'll trust in Thee alway, And strive to reconcile ourselves, That all with her is
                            well. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><pb n="277" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Giving all" TEIform="index"/> GIVING ALL,</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fitts, Ednah E." TEIform="persName"/>EDNAH E. FITTS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "Thou shalt love the Lord with all thy heart, mind, might and strength." True love brings
                            forth the fruits of service, and when our time, talents, possessions and affections are
                            given to God, there is nothing left with which to feed selfish love and interest. Yet, how
                            often do those who claim to be followers of Christ, limit the bounds of sacrifice, thus
                            acting the part which brought death to Ananias and Sapphira. From early records to those of
                            the present day we have evidence of the proneness of human judgment to exalt itself above
                            the guidings of the power it claims to serve. When the spirit call comes to the soul:
                            "Arise, slay and spare not," how quickly we calculate upon a reserve of what we hold dear,
                            and laying aside our pledge of full consecration, take the judgment into our hands, saying
                            it is neither wisdom nor justice to surrender all. Acting from this standpoint, when we seek
                            the blessing, we may be asked, ''What meaneth then this bleating of the sheep in mine ears,
                            and the lowing of the oxen which I hear ?" I. Sam. xv, 14. Why the ruling of earthly
                            elements and passions where the spirit of love, truth and purity should alone bear sway ?
                            When the young man came to inquire of Jesus, what he should do to inherit eternal life,
                            Jesus said, "If thou wilt enter into life, keep the commandments." The young man told Jesus
                            he had kept these from his youth, but Jesus said, "If thou wilt be perfect, go and sell that
                            thou hast, and give to the poor ;" share with others the blessings of this life which thou
                            hast inherited more than they, and "thou shalt have treasure in heaven, and come and follow
                            me." But the young man went away sorrowful thus proving the truth of the Savior's words, "Ye
                            cannot serve God and mammon," for "where the treasure is, there will the heart" or motive
                            power of the life, "be also." As the seed we sow produces after its kind, so the principle
                            ot consecration will yield to us the fullness of blessing promised by our Savior, "an
                            hundred fold now in this time, and in the world to come eternal life." Canterbury, N.
                        II.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion" TEIform="index"/> RELIGION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Emily" TEIform="persName"/>EMILY OFFORD.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Much has been said and written upon this subject, and many explanations have been given ;
                            still we reach forth, inquire, investigate and search for deeper knowledge; for something
                            more reliable and satisfactory. The human heart is ever aspiring, constantly desiring and
                            hoping for something better in the future than the present reveals ; and this ceaseless
                            yearning is the great motor which drives forward the car of human progress. St. Paul said,
                            that pure and undefiled religion, was to visit the sick, the widow and the fatherless. Very
                            plain and practical doctrine, and one that people are more willing to accept, when in want,
                            than the dry husks of theological creeds and ceremonies. True religion consists in purity of
                            heart, and holiness of life, and they who possess it strictly observe the golden rule, and
                            thus fulfill the law of love in all their dealings toward their fellow creatures. Its design
                            being to purify the heart, and give health and strength to the body, the extent of its
                            influence may be estimated by its legitimate effect in producing a life of practical
                            righteousness. But the human mind, prior to experience and development, is weak and
                            fluctuating, when the current of life flows deep and strong, and surrounding circumstances
                            are such as tend to heighten ambition and intensify zeal, then the fire of enthusiasm burns
                                <pb n="278" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/>brightly, and the soul is impelled rapidly onward. But, during our
                            earthly existence we are liable to meet with reverses of fortune, the tide of life ebbs as
                            well as flows, fires consume and floods destroy; and there are times when every effort for
                            advancement seems baffled by some opposing force visible or invisible, and what shall
                            sustain the soul under these circumstances ? Nothing short of the power of true religion is
                            able to do it,such as imbued the character of our blessed Savior, and which was so perfectly
                            exemplified by him when at Gethsemane, "0 my Father, if it be possible, let this cup pass
                            from me :" and then buoyed up by this blessed power he added, "nevertheless not as I will,
                            but as Thou wilt." But how is this obtained? Amid the din and busy hum of life, and the
                            great and over-reaching demands of mortals for material tilings, the accumulation of which
                            takes so much strength and time, that very little if any is left for spiritual culture and
                            growth, although there has ever been a desire, growing out of the necessity thereof for such
                            time. Hence, the institution of the Sabbath, and the provision made for the assembling
                            together of persons desiring such privileges. Various modes of worship have been devised by
                            the human race, all of which undoubtedly have been intended to give expression to the
                            deepest religious feelings of the soul, for the purpose of producing a better character. It
                            may fall short of this when it leavens into a dry sentimentality, destitute of the spirit.
                            Like a shell devoid of the egg, or the husk without the kernel, it lacks the substance and
                            therefore fails to satisfy the immortal part, the soul. The same causes produce the same
                            effects in every place however often they may be repeated. God's laws are immutable and no
                            person or community can escape the operation of them. Religious observances are
                            indispensable to spiritual growth. True worship is independent of time and place, arising as
                            it does from the pure in heart at all times and in all places. Forms, ceremonies and
                            external arrangements when so conducted as to be the true exponents of the inner life,
                            afford blessed opportunities for the expansion of the divine, and give a foretaste of that
                            bliss which we may enjoy when our whole being is brought under perfect subjection to the
                            higher or spiritual part; or, as it may be expressed, where the law of love predominates,
                            and the "blessed power of true religion" prompts every thought, word and action. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our Savior's words" TEIform="index"/> OUR SAVIOE'S WORDS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tiffany, Amanda" TEIform="persName"/>AMANDA TIFFANY.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Our Savior said, "I am the way the truth and the light," also, take up a daily cross and
                            follow me. Now as mankind in general confess Jesus Christ, as their pattern, in him centers
                            their religion. Why not follow his example, live out his teaching in a daily, practical
                            life. It has truly been said, "faith without works is dead." Now, if we claim to be his
                            followers we must live as he lived, fasting from a carnal, sinful life, and as he was
                            baptized in the river Jordan confessing his sins, so must we be baptized with the holy
                            spirit confessing our sins. Herein we receive power to forsake them. Our Savior also said,
                            "love one another," "do unto others as you would have others do unto you," "render good for
                            evil," and live in peace. Beautiful teachings ! If all mankind would remember, and live out
                            those teachings strictly, what a Paradise our earth would be. How different from the
                            condition now existing; where sin and crime rages from pole to pole, causing sorrow, misery
                            and suffering without end; peace, joy and happiness might reign supreme. Would it not be
                            well for all professing Christians, to examine their lives, and see if in their daily works
                            they honor the name and profession they hold so dear? I know there are those who do live out
                            Christ's teachings in a great degree, though few in number, yet their influence shall be
                            felt and their glory shine forth to the nations of earth, that those who seek the way of
                            life and truth may find it in God's holy temple on earth. Here the weary may find rest, and
                            the sin-sick soul rejoice in the power that cleanses and saves from sin. Let all who wish to
                            be true followers of Christ enter his fold, where there is power to live the self-denying
                            life he taught, free from the sorrows and burdens of sin. Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><pb n="279" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Future is ours" TEIform="index"/> THE FUTURE IS OURS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Annie R." TEIform="persName"/>ANNIE R. STEPHENS</byline><p TEIform="p">I stand entranced upon the mount of vision, And watch the shadows ilowly disappear, I catch
                            bright glimpses of that land elysian Where Truth hath triumphed in its grand career. The
                            mists of time like darkening clouds impending Now vanish in the glow of morning light, I
                            feel that God His heralder is sending, To usher in the glorious dawn of right. There have
                            been those upon this earth of ours, Who still are here, though numbered with the dead, Their
                            memories rise like softly breathing flowers, Whose fragrance lasts when life and beauty's
                            fled. From sordid gain and honor backward turning, They sought on earth a higher joy to
                            find, They nobly toiled, all selfish impulse spurning, They lived to God, to truth, and all
                            mankind. And now we see 'twas no utopean dreaming, That fired their souls unto a holy flame,
                            (ing, They saw the twilight through the midnight gleamWe see the sunrise, and the shadows
                            wane. 'Tis now for those who feel earth's needs and losses, Unflinchingly to live God's laws
                            divine, To raise Truth's standard through opposing forces, And speak the true word in the
                            storm and shine. The sins of earth, of ignorance and error, That long have chained the soul
                            in thraldom's might, Shall quell beneath Truth's conquering power with And flee before the
                            coming golden light. (terror: O bright the future as it flows toward us! Diffusing glory,
                            sweeping sin away; With radiant hope the heavens are beaming o'er us, Now is the sunrise of
                            the perfect day. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thoughts of truth" TEIform="index"/> THOUGHTS OF TRUTH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M'rae, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>THOMAS M'RAE.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Each person has his ideal of happiness, and seeks it in his own way. We need frequently to
                            be reminded, that the basis of real happiness is the practice of virtue. It is wise in us to
                            gain the mastery of our passions and appetites. Our emotions are easily excited, and should
                            be properly controlled. There are emotions either of tenderness or anger, either gentle or
                            strong, either painful or pleasing. Agitations may be bodily or mental, and are frequently
                            attended with violence. Human affections, human likes and dislikes, are changeable. The soul
                            raised over human passions and affections, beholds eternal truths, beholds tranquillity. The
                            soul of man is not an organ, but animates all the organs. It is not a mere faculty, but a
                            light. It is not intellect nor the will, but master of the intellect and the will. It is
                            very important that we should believe that we have souls, superior to mere intellect, more
                            noble and more interior than reason itself. Reason is a noble faculty, and should be
                            exercised in inquiries concerning Truth and concerning everything else. Without reason,
                            there can be no religion. Religion d es not forbid the right use of reason. Impulses must
                            not rule us; they must obey the higher reason. Our whims, caprices, and evil thoughts must
                            be brought under the power of a strong will. Self-discipline requires of us to fix the
                            wandering thoughts, to compel the reluctant mental energies, and to concentrate the power
                            upon the performance of duties. Without this discipline, we will driit. liable to be carried
                            away by currents of passion, and into whirlpools full of danger. Purity and virtue are
                            conditions of the soul. They give us a steady purpose, and a perpetual calm. We cannot be
                            too often reminded that the triumph over passions and lusts, over worldliness and
                            selfishness, is more important than mere money making. Selfcontrol is more valuable to us
                            than applause, than fame, than office, popularity, ease, or indulgence ; worth more than the
                            cattle upon a thousand hills. Gold, pleasure buys ; but pleasure dies, For soon the gross
                            fruition cloys ; Though raptures court; the sense is short, But virtue, kindles living joys.
                            South Union, Ky.</p></div2><pb n="280" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES.</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="This number of the Manifesto..." TEIform="index"/>This number of the Manifesto...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">This number of the Manifesto remind us of the end of another year, and a the same time of
                                the closing of Vol XIII. Our swift passage through th varied changes of the twelve
                                months ha kept busy, willing bauds and hearts, in the multiplied duties of life. Whethe
                                we have done much or little in our ef forts to diffuse light in the world, mus be left
                                for some future date to deter mine. To have done our duty faithfully, in accordance with
                                our best understanding of right is all that heaven or earth can reasonably expect. The
                                Manifesto will, certainly, anticipate a favorable report from all its readers, for where
                                much is given, much in return will be required. That our little paper in its simplicity,
                                in its truthfulness and in its loving kindness has preached and prayed aud sung to the
                                joy of thousands, is on" ly saying that to which so many have already borne witness. And
                                yet we may not at all times and in all ways be able to accomplish even what our hearts
                                desire. We can, however, in our simplicity give ft eely to God and to humanity, our best
                                gifts, trusting that like the seed of the sower, of which we read in the parable, some
                                will most assuredly fall on good ground and in God's time spring up unto everlasting
                                life. "Cast thy bread upon the waters, for thou shalt find it after many days." Even
                                these assurances of reward from nature, should stimulate the Christian worker to renewed
                                efforts and awaken new life with more zeal and strongerconfidence in the spirit of God,
                                to accept every opportunity to publish the good news of peace and righteousness
                                throughout the earth. Since the first number of the first volume of the Shaker paper the
                                Believers have published a testimony which has its foundation in the spirit of Christ,
                                and in the practical and self-denying life of Jesus. Certainly we have no need to be
                                ashamed. Articles have been brought forward that are the embodiment of truth, full and
                                sound to the center. The writers have been blessed in their sacrifices and in their
                                offerings of good gifts, while the readers have been abundantly blessed in their rich
                                and bountiful harvest. Even the children have enjoyed the pleasure of a department in
                                our paper and their labors for the good of the cause have not been in vain. With a
                                little care, a little patience and a little self-denial they have afforded us many a
                                pleasant page. Expecting more and more we shall not for a moment think that the youth
                                and children can ever disappoint us. Some beautiful articles, selected from Books and
                                Papers have been received Prom time to time. Care should be taken to mark all such
                                contributions that due credit may be given to the authors or to the publishers. We
                                should wish to do by others as we would that they should do by us under like
                                circumstances. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We are advocates of Christianity..." TEIform="index"/>We are advocates of Christianity...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> We are advocates of Christianity only in lie proportion that we live in the spirit of
                            elf-denial that Christ lived and taught. The nfluence of our lives contain the most powerul
                            sermons.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., E." TEIform="persName"/>—E. B. </byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth, like fire, will consume..." TEIform="index"/>Truth, like fire, will consume...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Truth, like fire, will consume every comjustible thing.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M., E." TEIform="persName"/>—E. M. </byline></div2><pb n="281" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scarlet fever" TEIform="index"/>THE SCARLET FEVER
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">It is as unnecessary for a child to die of the scarlet
                                        fever as it is that it should be blind with a cataract. Let us see. At any time
                                        before the body has finished its effectual struggle we are able to help it, not
                                        by wonderful medicines, but the knowledge of anatomy, and the application of
                                        common senseWe consult the sympathetic nerve, and do what it commands us to do.
                                        We must give this child salt when it wants it; we must give it acid when it has
                                        fever and anxiously craves it—not vinegar, but lemon juice, because the first
                                        coagulates albumen, and the other does not, on account of the surplus oxygen
                                        which it contains. To imitate the soothing mucus in the intestines, which is now
                                        wanting, and to give some respiratory food at the same time, we add some gum
                                        arabic. To restore and relieve the injured nerve, we apply moist warmth. In
                                        practice we can fulfill all this with the following simple manipulations :
                                        Undress the child and bring it to bed at the very first sign of sickness. Give
                                        it, if it has already fever, nothing but sourish warm lemonade with some gum
                                        arabic in it. Then cover its abdomen with some dry flannel. Take a well folded
                                        bed sheet and put in boiling hot water; wring it out dry by means of dry towels,
                                        and put this over the flannel on the child's abdomen. Then cover the whole, and
                                        wait. The hot cloths will, perhaps, require repeated heat. According to the
                                        severity of the case, and its stage of progress, perspiration will commence in
                                        the child from ten minutes to two hours. The child is then saved; it soon falls
                                        to sleep. Soon after the child awakes, it shows slight symptoms of returning
                                        inclination for food; help its bowels, if necessary, with injections of oil,
                                        soap and water, and its recovery will be as steady as the growth of a green
                                        house plant, if well treated. Of course, if the child was already dying, nothing
                                        could save it, or if it has already effusions in the lining of the heart or
                                        brain, it is much better it should die. But if the above is applied in due time,
                                        under the eyes and direction of a competent physician, I will guarantee that not
                                        one in a hundred children will ever die of scarlet fever. I know this will
                                        startle some of my readers, especially those who have lost children already, but
                                        I shall go still farther. I maintain that a child will never get the scarlet
                                        fever if properly treated. If a child has correctly mixed blood, it will not
                                        catch the disorder if put in bed with a sick child. This is still more
                                        startling, but nothing is easier of proof.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Good health" TEIform="index"/>Good Health.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Salt and leaven injurious" TEIform="index"/>SALT AND LEAVEN INJURIOUS
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A correspondent residing in N. J., writes in
                                        regard to her experience in diet. She is a lady physician, judging from her
                                        signature, and therefore what she says is entitled to respect. She says; "I have
                                        often thought I would acknowledge my obligation to you for much useful
                                        information gathered from your valuable Journal. I have found after nearly forty
                                        years experience, that very much ot the early decay of the teeth and a large
                                        portion of our nervous diseases, are engendered at home by the use of common
                                        salt, and the fermented food which forms part of meals. These cause irritation
                                        and inflammation, to cure which, a poultice of stimulating food or drink is put
                                        into the stomach, or a narcotic is used to deaden the sensibility. The final
                                        outcome of such cures is a worse condition; inflammation extends throughout the
                                        alimentary canal and may threaten its beautiful structure with ruin. I was
                                        tormented with toothache until I learned that salt was unnecessary. I contrive
                                        to live without it, and found that I could relish my food without salt, and
                                        found many exquisite flavors in food which I had never tasted before, and to my
                                        astonishment my teeth stopped aching, and have never ached since. The teeth
                                        which did not exfoliate are firmer and look better than ever. Other members of
                                        my family have been benefitted in the same way" Accompanying the above
                                        statements are some recipes for the hygienic preparation of some of the cereals,
                                        which we shall hand over to the kitchen department for proving.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Phrenological journal" TEIform="index"/>Phrenological Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div3><pb n="282" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="healthe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Give up medicines" TEIform="index"/>Give up Medicines
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="L." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> How precious is health! Wealth, hono-, luxury,
                                        associations and friendship are of less value than health ! Thousands of highly
                                        educated persons exclaim; "I wouli give all for health." Multitudes who can talk
                                        intelligibly of nebula, leucocites, moriads and of equations have become a trial
                                        to themselves and their friends, are fretful, hysterical, sensational and even
                                        lax in morality ! What is to be done? First, stop medicines of all sorts! Give
                                        up the gauntlet of tonics, stimulants, alteratives, sedatives, diaphoretics,
                                        antispasmodics, diuretics and narcotics, which have been applied in every
                                        conceivable way to the gastropulmonary and genito-urinary surfaces, to the nasal
                                        and serous membranes and external skin. Give up your liver pads, supporters,
                                        specifics and relate yourself properly to nature's materia medica! Give up your
                                        blue mass, quinine, iron, ipecac, opium, chloral and bromides and you have made
                                        the right start! Now try to take hope in your soul! Believe you may become well
                                        and vigorous and useful, for it is true, the most of you are curable. Second,
                                        Put yourselves in proper relation to "deep breathing," sun-light, food, dress,
                                        sleep, motion, rest, water and selfhood ! Do this at home or in the best
                                        institution you know, it will make no difference, only as you continue and
                                        persevere in doing it. L.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl">in <index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>Herald of Health.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Do something" TEIform="index"/> DO SOMETHING.</head><p TEIform="p">If the world seems cold to you, Kindle fires to warm it! Let their comfort hide from you
                                Winters that deform it. Hearts as frozen as your own To that radiance gather; You will
                                soon forget to moan, "Ah ! the cheerless weather !" If the world's a "vale of tears,"
                                Smile till rainbows span it; Breathe the love that life endears— Clear from clouds to
                                fan it. Of your gladness lend a gleam Unto souls that shiver ; Show them how dark
                                sorrow's stream Blends with hope's bright river! </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>House and Farm</head><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Professor Threadwell, of Massachusetts..." TEIform="index"/>Professor Threadwell, of Massachusetts...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Professor Threadwell, of Massachusetts, found that a half-grown American robin in
                                confinement ate in one day sixty eight worms, weighing together one ounce and a half, as
                                much as the bird himself, and another had previously starved upon a daily allowance of
                                eight or ten worms, or about twenty per cent of his own weight.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In troublesome bleeding from the nose..." TEIform="index"/>In troublesome bleeding from the nose...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> In troublesome bleeding from the nose, snuffing up powdered alum will generally control
                                it. It will also almost always stop excessive hemorrhage from a cavity caused by the
                                extraction of a tooth, by being placed in it. It is not wise to go out in the early
                                morning air before eating at least a few mouthfuls. Especially ought this precaution to
                                be strictly observed in malarial sections, and in seasons when much sickness is over the
                                country. Nothing can be more unwise than to go into a sick-room fasting, and when the
                                sickness is contagious, the result may be dangerous if not fatal.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Smell of paint" TEIform="index"/> Smell of Paint.</head><p TEIform="p">—To get rid of this most objectionable odor, slice a few onions and put them in a pail of
                                water in the center of the room; close the doors, leave the window open a little, and in
                                s few hours the disagreeable smell will have almost gone. Another method is to plunge a
                                handful of hay into a pailful of water, and let it stand in the newly-painted room over
                                night.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Household hints" TEIform="index"/> HOUSEHOLD HINTS.</head><p TEIform="p">Ceilings that have been smoked by a kerosene lamp should be washed off with soda water.
                                Hellebore sprinkled on the floor at night destroys cockroaches; they eat it and are
                                poisoned. A tablespoonful of turpentine boiled with your white clothes will greatly aid
                                the whitening process. Paste for labels is made by soaking glue in strong vinegar, then
                                heating it to boiling and adding flour. <pb n="283" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> Good fires should be kept
                                up during housecleaning time, even though the doors and windows be kept open. A piece of
                                stearine candle,, spermaceti or white wax as large as a robin's egg will give a nice
                                gloss. A teaspoon of salt to each pint of starch prevents sticking. When silk has lost
                                its gloss and becomes limpsy it may be restored by sponging with a solution of half an
                                ounce of gum tragacanth in a pint of hot water. Painted woodwork is washed with soap and
                                water, or a little ammonia and water on white paint. On grained work cold tea is
                                sometimes used. Very little if any soap should be used on varnished work. In washing
                                woodwork do not use so much water that it runs down and streaks the wood, and wipe
                                thoroughly dry. Before re-papering a wall it is best to remove the old paper. This is a
                                troublesome operation. Moisten a portion of the wall at a time to soften the paper and
                                paste and then scrape it off. When it is desired to paper over a whitewashed surface,
                                first scrape off the loose lime, fill cracks with plaster of Paris and apply with a
                                brush a sizing made by adding eight ounces of dissolved glue to a pailful of hot water.
                                Hard-finished walls may be washed with soap and water and wiped dry. Grease spots on
                                wall-paper can sometimes be removed by applying a thick paste of boiling hot starch
                                spread thickly on the spot, then allowed to dry and rubbed off with a soft cloth. Other
                                stains may be cut out with a sharp knife and a piece of clean paper matched on.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to tell good eggs" TEIform="index"/>HOW TO TELL GOOD EGGS
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A good egg will sink in water. A boiled egg which is
                                        done will dry quickly on the shell when taken from the kettle. The boiled eggs
                                        which adhere to the shell are fresh. A fresh egg has a lime-like surface to its
                                        shell. Stale eggs are glassy and smooth of shell. Eggs which have been packed in
                                        lime look stained, and show the action of the lime on the surface. Eggs packed
                                        in bran for a long time smell and taste musty. With the aid of the hands, a
                                        piece ot paper rolled in funnel shape and held toward che light, the human eye
                                        can look through an egg, shell and all. If an egg is clear and golden in
                                        appearance when held to the light, it is good, if dark or spotted, it is bad.
                                        The badness of an egg can sometimes be told by shaking it near the holder's ear,
                                        but the test is a dangerous one. Thin shells are caused by lack of gravel, etc.,
                                        among the hens laying eggs.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Ex." TEIform="index"/> Ex.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Things worth knowing" TEIform="index"/>THINGS WORTH KNOWING
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Castor oil will soften leather. Any tree or plant
                                        whipped by green elder branches will not be attacked by insects. Thoroughly
                                        wetting the hair once or twice a week in a weak solution of salt water will
                                        prevent it falling out A pint of mustard seed put in a barrel of cider will
                                        preserve it sweet for several months. To whiten ivory boil in lime water. Tepid
                                        water is produced by combining twothirds cold and one-third boiling. A mixture
                                        of oil and ink is good to clean kid boots; the first softens and the latter
                                        blackens them. Carelessness in changing the underclothing at night accounts for
                                        the coarse complexion of many girls. No person in health should drink more than
                                        two or three pints of any liquid daily. A solution of cyanide of potassium is
                                        the best poison to kill insects of any kind. Faint should be varnished, because
                                        it is then more easily cleaned Sprigs of wintergreen or ground ivy will drive
                                        away ants ; branches of wormwood will serve the same purpose for black ants.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Truckee republican" TEIform="index"/>Truckee Republican.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hope for the deaf" TEIform="index"/>HOPE for the DEAF
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> In another column will be found an advertisement with the above
                                head. We have seen the descriptive book coming from this house, and judge from the
                                testimonials therein contained that it is a very successful device to restore hearing.
                                The book is sent free. It will well repay a perusal. Send for it. </p></div3></div2><pb n="284" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/> Kind Words for the Year 1883.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I welcome the Manifesto with delight..." TEIform="index"/>I welcome the Manifesto with delight...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Enfield, 1883" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, Conn., 1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p">I welcome the Manifesto with delight. It is better every number. I can scarcely wait from
                                one number to another. I read it all, and find many articles worth four times its cost;
                                they are exceedingly interesting, and such as I put away to review often. Gladly would I
                                deprive myself of other privileges for its pleasant companionship, bringing as it
                                does—bright truths to cheer Miy heart, and teach me that the lessons learned here,
                                however bitter, are but stepping stones to the higher life. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manifesto is improving, growing..." TEIform="index"/>Manifesto is improving, growing...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Shirley, February 1883" TEIform="index"/> Shirley, Feb. 1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p">"The Manifesto" is improving, growing better every month. The article on Consistency, I
                                like very much, it is good and timely. I think that the music is an important item of
                                interest.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wetherbee, W. H." TEIform="persName"/>W. H. Wetherbee.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="July Manifesto a down right good number..." TEIform="index"/>July Manifesto a down right good number...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="July 1883" TEIform="index"/> July, 1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> July Manifesto a down right good number. We bless you for labors in the good cause we
                                love so well.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whiteley, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Whiteley.</byline></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We have received the Mar. No. of The Manifesto..." TEIform="index"/>
                                We have received the Mar. No. of The Manifesto...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">We have received the Mar. No. of The Manifesto, published by the United
                                        Societies, at Shaker Village, N. H. It is a neat little monthly full of
                                        religious reading.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Amer. farm and home" TEIform="index"/>Amer. Farm &amp; Home. </bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hold your head up like a man" TEIform="index"/> HOLD YOUR HEAD UP LIKE A MAN.</head><p TEIform="p">If the storm winds should rustle, While you tread the world's high-way, Still against them
                            bravely tussle, Hope and labor day by day; Falter not, no matter whether There is sunshine,
                            storm or cloud, And in every kind of weather, Hold your head up like a man. If a brother
                            should deceive you, And should act a traitor's part. Never let his treason grieve you, Jog
                            along with lightsome heart; Fortune seldom follows fawning, Boldness is the plan, Hoping for
                            a better dawning Hold your head up like a man. Earth though e'er so rich and mellow, Yields
                            not for the worthless drone, But the bold and honest fellow, He can shift and stand alone;
                            Spurn the knave of every nation, Always do the best you can, And no matter what your
                            station, Hold your head up like a man.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Collection of debts" TEIform="index"/>COLLECTION OF DEBTS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> All laws enforcing collection of debts might safely be rescinded. The money paid out to
                            collect the debts of the American people equals in amount the sums collected. Why then not
                            let the debts go and save all the Law machinery and personal vexation that attends the legal
                            collection of money loaned ? Let each person who lends money see | to it that it is repaid
                            or lost. Whose business is it but that of the parties interested ? If the loaning is a
                            matter of friendship—a favor conferred, law sho.uld not intermeddle. If it be a business
                            transaction it may safely be left in the hands of the parties concerned. The lender assumes
                            the contingency that the borrower will be in better financial condition in the near or
                            remote future. If he miscalculates, it is his business, not anothers. Hear what Horace
                            Greeley says, "I hate Lawyers ; they do more mischief than they are worth. They cause
                            disorders, demoralize every form of equality and are the chief obstacle to good government.
                            If A lets B have his property without payment, I do not see why C, D, F and all the rest of
                            the alphabet should be called upon as a police force to get it back. No such thing should be
                            attempted by Law. It is the most monstrous innovation upon man's honor ai.d .<pb n="285" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> integrity that was ever forced into the commerce of the world. Let a man
                            trust another at his own/isk. Even the gambler pays his debts contracted at the gambling
                            table. He is not obliged to pay, but he considers them debts of honor. Abolish all Laws for
                            the collection of debts, and thus abolish the whole credit system ; this is the only safe,
                            true basis ; that would abolish moot Lawyers and all of the broker's trade which now
                            controls the commerce of America." To my mind that is good morality and sound logic. Mount
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit of thankfulness" TEIform="index"/>SPIRIT OF THANKFULNESS
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> How few are those persons who rightly appreciate and feel
                                    truly thankful for what are termed common blessings. The loss ot hearing or of sight
                                    is rightly considered a great calamity, a grievous affliction, yet how many pass
                                    through life who suffer from one or the other of these crosses, or perhaps have
                                    crippled limbs, or even are fc without them! A philosopher who was complaining
                                    because he had no shoes to his feet was immediately cured of his murmurings of a
                                    kind Providence, by meeting with a poor fellow who had no feet at all. We can be
                                    placed in but few situations in life where we shall not find others worse off than
                                    ourselves, giving us reason for being contented with our lot. Laura Bridgeman, well
                                    known as the blind, deaf and dumb girl few would imagine could be satisfied with her
                                    hard lot: Yet she is contented and happy, reads, writes and converses with those
                                    around her, and teaches a lesson of patience, meekness and humble submission to the
                                    will of Providence that we would all do well to learn and imitate. If a person
                                    deprived of the use of one of his faculties had reason to complain, how much greater
                                    reason has this poor girl who has lost all that to us makes life desirable ! Yet she
                                    can be cheerful, playful and resigned. Then let us never murmur at the dispensations
                                    of a kind Providence, knowing that we all receive greater blessings than we deserve.
                                    Milton was blind many years before his death, but instead of mourning and repining,
                                    he considered the affliction in the light of a blessing, and God made it a blessing
                                    to him, May we be more thankful for the common blessings of life, for the air we
                                    breathe and the flowers that open in our path, the blue sky above, and the rich
                                    verdure beneath our feet. Let us rejoice that we have eyes to see and drink in all
                                    the beauty around us, and ears to hear the melody of the birds, the music of the
                                    winds among the bows of the trees, and the gentle voices of much loved friends, and
                                    that all our faculties are kindly preserved to us. Thank God for all. these
                                    blessings lest He deem us unworthy of them, and take them from us. When gone forever
                                    we should regret we had not prized them as we ought when they were ours.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/> Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lift the gates of heaven..." TEIform="index"/>Lift the gates of heaven...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Horton, Lewis" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> "Lift up your heads, 0 ye gates; and be ye lifted up, ye everlasting doors; and the King of
                            Glory shall come in. Who is the King of glory? The Lord strong and mighty." LEWIS MORTON.
                            Lift the gates of heaven, I would enter in, Bearing all life's burdens, Free from taint of
                            sin. Lift the gates of heaven, Angels guide my way; Illume the path I enter, To eternal day.
                            Lift the gates of heaven On the pilgrim's sight; Lead me, guide me, Father, In the way of
                            right. Lift the gates of heaven, Joy and peace are there, Where the soul reposes In His
                            tender care. Bless the King of Glory, The gates are open wide, Everlasting hills sing,— Joy
                            on every side. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><pb n="286" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good work or none" TEIform="index"/>GOOD WORK OR NONE
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">It is a rule that a workman must follow his employer's orders,
                                    but no one has a right to make him do work discreditable to himself. Judge
                                    M---------, a well known jurist, living near Cincinnati, loved to tell this anecdote
                                    of a young man who understood the risk of doing a shabby job, even when directed to.
                                    He once had occasion to send to the village for a carpenter, and a sturdy young
                                    fellow appeared with his tools. "I want this fence mended to keep out the cattle.
                                    There are some unplaned boards— use them. It is out of sight from the house, so you
                                    need not take time to make it a neat job. I will only pay you a dollar and a half.
                                    The Judge went to dinner, and coming out found the man carefully planing each board.
                                    Supposing that he was trying to make a costly job of it, he ordered him to nail them
                                    on at once just as they were, and continued his walk. When he returned the boards
                                    were all planed and numbered ready for nailing. "I told you this fence was to be
                                    covered with vines," he said angrily. I do not care how it looks." "I do," said the
                                    carpenter gruffly, carefully measuring his work When it was finished there was no
                                    part of the fence so thorough in finish. "How much do you charge?" asked the judge.
                                    "A dollar and a half," said the man, shouldering his tools. The judge stared. "Why
                                    did you spend all that labor on the job, if not for money?" "For the job, sir."
                                    "Nobody would have seen the poor work on it." "But I should have known it was there.
                                    No, I will only take a dollar and a half." And he took it and went away. Ten years
                                    afterwards the judge had the contracts to give for the building of several
                                    magnificent public buildings, but the face of one caught his eye. "It was my man of
                                    the fence," he said. I knew we should have only genuine work from him. I gave him
                                    the contract and it made a rich man of him." It is a pity that boys are not taught
                                    in their earliest years that the highest success belongs only to the man, be he
                                    carpenter, farmer, author or artist, whose work is most sincerely and thoroughly
                                    done.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Living age" TEIform="index"/>Living Age.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="By attempting to appropriate a good without..." TEIform="index"/>
                            By attempting to appropriate a good without...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> By attempting to appropriate a good without paying its price, and without the consent of the
                            Almoners thereof, the actor becomes a "thief and a robber." A thief cannot long enjoy his
                            ill-gotten gain—persistency will inevitably lodge the actor in "prison, from whence he shall
                            in no wise escape until he has paid the utmost farthing" by suffering, with the added loss
                            of time, and the irretrievable loss of treasure, blessing and happiness which would have
                            been his, if he had wisely improved his opportunities. This is according to the law of
                            recoil.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., A. G." TEIform="persName"/>A. G. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="At a silent, invisible loom..." TEIform="index"/>At a silent, invisible loom...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">At a silent, invisible loom, Always, morning and night, With tender care wrought
                                    One, Who was hidden from human sight. Tangled and broken threads wrought He, And his
                                    finished web was fair to see, For he gathered the hopes that were broken in twain,
                                    And wrought them into His web again.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Exchange" TEIform="index"/>Exchange.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Those beautiful church bells" TEIform="index"/> Those Beautiful Church Bells.</head><p TEIform="p">It is both a gratification and pleasure to note the great and general satisfaction which the
                            McShane Church Bells give wherever sent. Following is a letter published by pel-mission of
                            the firm, and it speaks for itself; after stating that he was glad that his Bill was
                            settled, he says, "Sow, I have another Bill to square and settle; 1 mean the Bill of honor
                            with respect to your Bell. It is for me a duty, both of justice and courtesy to acknowledge,
                            as highly as possible, that you have fully and entirely settled your obligation towards me.
                            Your Bell, is very nice, very strong, and very sonorous, giving general and entire
                            satisfaction. its way to the church from the Kailroad Station (some ten miles,) was a
                            triumphal one. The people, as it passed along, being roused by i:s mighty voice. The day it
                            was fixed up in its steeple was a feast day, the whole parish was gathered all around to see
                            and to hear, and the satisfaction goes but increasing. Now, this Bell is spoken of to its
                            praise in every part of this country. I am sure that no other company could do better than
                            you did. I shall not fail to praise and commend your Bells at every opportunity, and the
                            next time I want a Bell,, I shall not fail to apply to you again." There is a good, and true
                            ring in this letter, and demonstrates that the Henry McShane &amp; Co., Bell Foundry,
                            Baltimore, Md., can supply the world with superior and perfectly satisfactory Bells,
                            possessing, as they do, the most complete facilities for furnishing the most satisfactory
                            and superior Bells in every respect.</p></div2><pb n="287" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Universal love" TEIform="index"/> UNIVERSAL LOVE</head><p TEIform="p">Canterbury, N. H. Whose source in God is found above All narrow human claims. The principle
                            which purilies And elevates the race. O'er earthly loves and tendencies, In action, word and
                            way. As towers the lofty mountain top Above the distant sea, The love which seeks the good
                            of all, In ev'ry land and clime, Then let us join this noble band And seek the joy, the
                            hope, So stand the merits of this lore In its divinity. Which vitalizes, cheers, forgives
                            Andrenders life sublime. The freedom which this love will bring, Found always "Higher up."
                            1. Blest be that universal love For which the Christian aims; 2. Be lifted up O virgin
                            throng, With open hearts embrace 3. Its real subjects, grandly rise Superior in their sway
                        </p></div2><pb n="288" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Battle of the books" TEIform="index"/>"Battle of the Books."
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"Battle of the Books." The "Literary Revolution" wiiich caused such a sensation a few
                                years ago, and which was supposed to have been thoroughly overthrown and done for, seems
                                to be "ablaze" again, more fierce and flourishing than ever. Its "100-page catalogue,
                                free" and "books sent to any one to be paid for after receipt and examination, evidence
                                of good faith being given," are now being advertised in thousands of papers, and it
                                opens one's eyes to see the books offered—this time thoroughly beautiful typography and
                                the best of paper, presswork and binding, instead of small type and cheap work, as
                                formerly. And one must acknowledge that they are indeed "the lowest prices ever known."
                                We quote a few samples, the books being always unabridged, and in large type :
                                Tennyson's Enoch Arden, 2 cents. The Cotter's Saturday Night, 2 cents. Csesar's
                                Commentaries. Cicero's Orations, and numerous other "Ancient Classics for English
                                Readers," reduced from $1. to as low as 15 cents each. Bacon's Essays, 15 cents to 40
                                cents. Dore's famous Bible Gallery, $2. Irving's Sketch Book, 25 cents to 60 cents.
                                Irving's "Works, in 6 large and most beautiful volumes, $4. Ancient Egypt under the
                                Pharoalis, reduced from $15. to $1.25. Scotts's Waverley Novels, reduced from $30 to
                                $7.50. George Eliot's Works, reduced from $12. to $3.75. And a whole host of the great
                                poets of the world, ranging from 40 and 50 cents upwards; also plenty of other books
                                equally interesting and astonishing to the old-time book bu}-ers. The books are sold
                                only to buyers direct, and not through booksellers. Those who would be inclined to
                                believe such claims fabulous, are confronted with the "privilege of examination before
                                payment," and the witness of one's own neighbors on every hand who have already received
                                their books. It is certainly worth a postal card to get the "catalogue free." "For that,
                                address John B. Alden, Publisher, 18 Vesey St., New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>The Herald of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Herald op Health. Nov.
                                Contents. Visit to a Swiss Condensed Milk Factory; Prohibition from a business Point of
                                view; How to Preserve the Eyesight; Xo Bee without a thorn; The Treatment of Paupers;
                                Tight Collars; Effect of Tobacco on Children; Studies in Hygiene for women, etc., etc.
                                M. L. Holbrook, M. D. Publisher, 13 &amp; 15 Laight St. N. Y. $1.00 a year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>The
                                Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The
                                Phrenological Journal and Science of Health. Nov. Contents : Joseph K. Barnes, the late
                                Surgeon General U. S. A., with portrait; In the Right Place; The Eye of the Baltic,
                                Illustrated; The Lake Dwellers of Venezuela, Illustrated; General Observations on
                                Amativeness, No. 2; Get out of yourself; The use of Big Words; A Rocky Mountain Pioneer;
                                Comus, Illustrated &amp; Notes; Phrenology in Calcutta; Effects of Alcohol upon the
                                Human Body, No. 2; Out of Doors; The Fashionable Doctor; Editorial Items; etc., etc.
                                Fowler &amp; Wells Pub., 753 Broadway, N. Y. $2.00 a year.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Roth, George" TEIform="index"/>George Roth
                            </head><p TEIform="p">George Roth, Apr. 1, at Pleasant Hill, Ky. Age 61 yrs. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nelson, Clarissa" TEIform="index"/>Clarissa Nelson
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Clarissa Nelson, Apr. 18, at
                                Pleasant Hill, Ky. Age 71 yrs. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Small, Addie" TEIform="index"/>Addie Small
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Addie Small, Aug. 6, at Alfred, Me. Age, 26 yrs.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hopkins, Elizabeth S." TEIform="index"/>Elizabeth S. Hopkins
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Elizabeth S. Hopkins, Aug. 28, at Union Village. Age, 66 yrs. 8 mo. and 25 days. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sonburgh, Aaron" TEIform="index"/>Aaron Sonburgh
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Aaron
                                Sonburgh, Sept. 2, at Watervliet, N. Y. Age. 38 yrs. 10 mo. and9 days. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shain, Lucinda" TEIform="index"/>Lucinda Shain
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Lucinda Shain,
                                Sept. 18, at Pleasant Hill, Ky. Age 81 yrs. In her life was manifest the fruits of the
                                spirit as set forth by the apostle in Gal. v., 22, 23. "But the fruit of the spirit is
                                love, joy, peace, long-suffering, gentleness, goodness, faith, meekness and temperance."
                                B. B D. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brewster, Cassandana" TEIform="index"/>Cassandana Brewster
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Cassandana Brewster, Oct. 10, at Hancock, Mass. Age 91 yrs. 6 mo. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Augur, Jeannette" TEIform="index"/>Jeannette Augur
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Jeannette
                                Augur, Oct. 24, at Hancock, Mass. Age 79 yrs. 9 mo. and 15 days. Two of our worthy
                                mothers in Israel have gone on before us. They also have a "Crown of Life." B. J.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Upham, Cynthia" TEIform="index"/>Cynthia Upham
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Cynthia Upham, Oct. 22, at Enfield, N. H. Age 83 yrs. 7 mo. and 13 days. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Carnahan, Prudence" TEIform="index"/>Prudence Carnahan
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Prudence
                                Carnahan, Oct. 23, at Pleasant Hill. Age 92 yrs. She was appointed an Eldress in 1812
                                and remained in that order till quite advanced in age. It was a living testimony of her
                                long and useful life, by which she has gained the pearl of great price. B. B. D. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vedder, Eleanor" TEIform="index"/>Eleanor Vedder
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Eleanor Vedder, Oct. 28, at Watervliet, N. Y. Age 94 yrs. 8 mo. aud 12 days. She was truly a
                                mother in Israel and one of the tried and true.—I. A. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beware of ill will..." TEIform="index"/>Beware of ill will...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Beware of ill will, hatred, and false judging, for these cannot dwell with the pure in heart.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., E." TEIform="persName"/>—E. B. </byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The book to be read..." TEIform="index"/>The book to be read...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"The book to be read," says Dr. McCosh, "is not the one which thinks for you, but the one
                            that makes you think."</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He who promises runs in debt." TEIform="index"/>He who promises runs in debt
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">He who promises runs in debt.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Talmut" TEIform="index"/>—Talmud.</bibl></cit></p></div2><!--
                        <pb
                        id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]<pb id="p30"/>
                            <pb id="p31"/>
                            <pb id="p32"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>