<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2906" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">29</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><date value="18990601" TEIform="date">June 1899</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">81-96</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="29" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
MANIFESTO
WONDERFUL strange REVELATIONS
DANIEL'S & ST JOHN'S
PROPHECIES.
48 page pamphlet.    Price 10 cts.
13 for $1.00.
Address,    H. B. Beak, Pkeston, Ohio.
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF  THE
MILLENNIAL  CHURCH,
OB
"United   Society   of  Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price, 50 cts.
Sketches of Shakers and Shakerism. A synopsis of the United Society of Believers in Christ's Second
Appearing. Illustrated. By Giles
B. Avery.    Price 15 cts.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF   THE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
THE ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all their
property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. It now has 5,000
acres of land in Southeast Missouri on
which it offers a home and employment
for life to all acceptable persons who may
wish to  join it.            50  cents  a year;
specimen copy free.    Address A. Longley, 2819 Olive St. St. Louis, Mo.
THE
JUNE,    1899.
EXPLAINING
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
Egypt in History and Prophecy, by Robert Patterson,   The opening paragraph of the
book gives a better illustration of what might
be expected, than anything that we might
write.   "Pharoah has risen from his tomb
and ascended the pulpit at Alexandria.   The
Lord lias summoned the nations by the roar
of forty-ton British cannon, and the telephone
and telegraph have repeated tin sound around
the globe.    When God sends such a summons
to the church, and puts such a preacher in the
pulpit, the nations had better listen to the
sermon."   Published by H. L. Hastings, No.
47 Corn .ill, Boston, Mass.
Teapot Philosophy, by Walter L. Linton,
Price 25 cts.   The author says that Teapot
Philosophy whs suggested by a Chinese teapot that he sent to his sister.   The book also
contains "A Pita for Humanity."    lublished
by the author, 45 Rush Street, Chicago.
The following pamphlets, dealing with various phases oi Vegetarianism have been received.    Religion and Vegetarianism, 5 cts.
each, per doz. 50 cts.   A Doctor's Idka of
Vegetarianism, 3 cts each, per doz. 30 cts.
Saline starvation and How to Avoid it, by
Charles I). Hunter, M. 1).   5 cents each, per
doz. 50 cts    Clerical Sportsmen, 5 cts each,
per doz. 50 cts.   Publi lied by the Vegetarian
Co. McVieker's Bklg. Chicago, Jill.
Word and'Work is a monthly magazine
published by the Christian Worker's Union,
and edited by Abbie C. Morrow of New York,
editor of the "Sunday School Lesson Illustra
tor."   The May number contains by the Editor "Christian Science;"   It is Un-Christian
and Anti-Christian."      It contrasts extracts
from Mr.-, lu.i.y's principle book with the
Bible,   "(aid's Logons," and Other articles,
. "Going Without Breakiast," by George Pentecost, "Proofs of Humble Love," by George D.
Watson, "Persecuted," by Seth Rees, "Saved
from Death," by Chas. W. McCrosson, etc. It
has a full page photoengraving of the editor
with her autograph and is filled with spiritual
. reading for old and young.   Send five cents
(stamps accepted) for a sample copy to S. G.
Otis, Springfield, Mass.
, "Unbelief a Sin" by Rev.Edmond Hill, C. P.
Price 5 cents. Address, Notre Dame, Ind.
When and where the first attempts in the
art of printing were made can not be with
certainty ascertained because the earliest
work printed by Gutenberg bore neither date
nor name.   The reason for this was obvious.
The earliest printed books were made to resemble writing and sold as such.   This much
is certainthat movable wooden types were
first employed by him about the year 1438.
In 1443 he returned to Mayence and formed
a great friendship with Johannes Fust.or
Faust, who agreed to loan him eight hundred
guilders at six per cent for five years, but four
years passed before the wealthy goldsmith
would advance the money because Gutenbei'g
would not admit him into the secret of his
business.     In  1449 the   first money was   advanced and a printing office set up.   It was
necessary to have assistance in the printing
office, and one Peter Schoeffer was engaged,
"lie being mechanical."   Peter kept his eyes
open and soon found that wooden types were
too slow to make, and he discovered the art of
cutting the characters in a matrix so that the
letters might be cast singly.   Instead of telling Gutenburg, his employer, he went to the
money lender and persuaded him to advance
more money so that Schoeffer might work at
his invention apart from Gutenberg.     So
pleased was Faust that he gave Peter his
daughter Christina in marriage.Dotiahoe's
Magazine for May.
Cardinal Gibbons, in answer to the question,
Is the face of Christ as depicted in art a strong
one? says, (as reported in The Outlook,)
The face of our Lord which I am most accustomed to see expresses both strength and
kindness."   Bishop Potter, on the contrary,
thinks the art portrait* "weak and inadequate," while Dr. Parkhurst says that they
are "not only disappointing but repulsive."
Rabbi Gottheil declares;     "I have never seen
a picture of the being called Saviour of the
world in which strength was a marked feature, or even indicated.   Naturally so, because
the being was not a man of flesh and blood,
but the creation of theological fancy and dogmatic const ruction."     Many other clergymen
of note join in the discussion of this question
of The Outlook.
r
The Rev. Newell Dwight Hillis, D. D. pastor
of Plymouth Church, Brooklyn, has become a
contril utor to The Ladies' Home Journal, and a
number of articles from his pen will appear
in that magazine during the year.   He is introduced to the Journal's leaders through his
article, "The Secrets of a Happy Life," in the
May issue, which shows him to be a most
forceful writer whose present essay one can
not read without getting a better and more
wholesome view of life.   The worst antagonism to a happy life, Dr. Hillis believes, is
modern pessimistic literature, "for unhappy
indeed must be the community that feeds upon misery and daily takes its dose of pessimism."
Hon. John D. Long, Secretary of the Navy,
is the author of a very notable contribution
to the forthcoming (June) number of Frank
Leslie's Popular Monthly, now a giant
among the ten-cent magazines.   It is entitled
The Building of the New Navy; and is illustrated with nearly forty elaborate pictures
and official plans, showing types of all the
classes of United States war vessels, from the
torpedo boats and destroyers to the most formidable first-class battleship, such as the new
Maine, the Kearsarge and the Kentucky.     In--><pb n="81" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let your light shine" TEIform="index"/>LET YOUR LIGHT SHINE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder Henry C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">t4~y~ ET your light so shine before men, that they may see your good works I J and glorify
                            your Father which is in heaven." Jesus. This testimony of Jesus is without doubt the light
                            of the world. Above all, he wants the disciples to make a good use of it. It is wrong, after
                            having accepted it of G-od, to hide it away. Those who live in the light are made very
                            conspicuous, and all that they may do is easily seen. Jesus knew that his doctrine was of
                            God and that it would save his people from their sins. He was anxious for his disciples to
                            be stimulated, to let the light which they had received, so shine in their lives, in
                            practical righteousness, that others not of his church, might be made better, by seeing
                            these good works. This new life required a special spiritual light which would harmonize
                            with the life of Christ, and be a blessing to all who saw it. A little light is much better
                            than none, and even this small amount may have cost the owner a great deal of burden. If you
                            have but little light, and with this have been able to deny yourself of a little
                            ungodliness, have been able to govern the tongue two or three times during the week, or so
                            modified the temper that the voice has not risen above the normal key, then you can let so
                            much light shine, and God will see all such good, commendable works, and our friends and
                            neighbors will also see the same. There may be those who actually hate the light, and
                            instead, may prefer to abide in darkness. Of that class we can only repeat the words of
                            Jesus ; <pb n="82" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 82 THE MANIFESTO. "Verily, I say unto you, they have their
                            reward." This reward, or the result of wrong-doing, must be very unsatisfactory even to
                            those who have received but a very few rays of light. It is quite evident that the disciples
                            were to occupy a new position in the religious world. Their place in the Jewish church was
                            in common with the wThole nation and no special reference had ever been made to them. Now
                            all had changed. They had become the recipients of a new spiritual light, but had not, as
                            yet, learned how to use it. Possibly they ma}' have been diffident, or may have been ashamed
                            to be known as the followers of the Nazarene. It must have been a deep struggle in the minds
                            of those illiterate, simple fishermen, to leave their life occupation and become the
                            disciples of a refined, religious Teacher, who would lead them into the City of Jerusalem,
                            and into the company of the Pharisees and Sadducees, and even into the company of the chief
                            priests. We need not wonder that they drew back from such an ordeal, or dreaded the
                            publicity to which their new life had introduced them. Without doubt they did draw back from
                            this public investigation, and hesitated to speak of the "good news" of the gospel. At this
                            moment, Jesus meets them and says,Let your light shine that others by seeing your good works
                            may be able to glorify God. He knew to whom he was speaking and that the disciples were able
                            to testify to the truth of God with confidence. Those among whom they dwelt could hear their
                            language and knew quite well that it was chaste, and its influence upon other minds was for
                            the promotion of good. Their general character wras also well understood, and these were the
                            good works so open before all people. This would inspire others so readily to glorify God,
                            that it seemed but a simple lesson to learn. Let your light shine, can not be repeated too
                            often, and especially among those who have accepted the mission work of the Christ. East
                            Canterbury, N. H. .</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reign of truth" TEIform="index"/>REIGN OF TRUTH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whiteley, John" TEIform="persName"/>By Elder John Whiteley.</byline><p TEIform="p">God bless the hope and longing for A gift so much desired By every child of Mother Ann. And
                            may he teach us what it is In us that is required To do, the best and all we can While by
                            his love inspired. <pb n="83" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 83 Or patiently to wait and see His
                            will and work, divine. The great salvation from our God We know 'twill come in his good
                            time. Nor would we once repine, To hope is joyto wait is gain; Till then, we'll kiss the
                            rod. The world hath need,who hath not need? Of love and life divine. The fount of good still
                            overflows ; There is enough for every one That wish Christlike to shine. Let's do our best,
                            and meekly say, Thy will, O God, be done. Shirley, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Know thyself" TEIform="index"/>KNOW THYSELF.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>By Elder Abraham Perkins.</byline><p TEIform="p">OUR days, weeks and months are rapidly passing away, but they leave an impress, a concern for
                            properties not attained. Unto mortals, what are the benefits of life? Just what we make them
                            in conformity to rectitude and truth. In the work of the Eternal, there was a design in
                            bringing into existence man, and also all other creations. Evidently it was for greater
                            glory, for celestial honor, for completion of perfection of the heavens. The earth with its
                            creations were for man's use, and, held in possession, provisional means calculated to
                            qualify him for the enjoyment and happiness of the heavens. So long as man is a tenant of
                            earth, the things thereof are for his instruction and use ; his rights thereto, depending
                            upon the acts and character of his life, the manner of use he makes of the provisions
                            designed for his wants and his happiness. Our powers should be given to work out the problem
                            of life in a manner to bring peace and justification to ourselves, and so universal our
                            interest, that our labors be also devoted to the interests and blessing of others. Our
                            existence is not alone for self-pleasure; our duties are not merely for personal beneGts;
                            but as a link in the great chain of the universe, there is a responsibility to be manifested
                            in life and a dependence upon the exercise of our powers for the maturing of the plan in the
                            design of the All-Wise to accomplish a purposed end. With Deity man was to be a co-worker,
                            obedient to the light and vision of duty revealed. Inability in man to conceive of all the
                            devices of the Almighty, incapacity to fathom his creation and beginning, is without
                            foundation of plea in favor of delin- <pb n="84" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 84 THE MANIFESTO. quency in duty
                            or argument in support of our wills or any selfish passion. It is enough, (absolute
                            requirement if we would become heirs of the kingdom) to make our meat and drink in doing the
                            will of our Father in heaven, as from day to day we learn the true and protective lessons of
                            life. Into our hands a sacred trust is committed; may we never be found to fail in loyal
                            service. To study our personal creation that we may know ourselves, opens avenues to find
                            that which we seek, to give entrance where we knock, and a baptism of the spirit through
                            repentance, confession and consecration. The hand of the Lord is not shortened, that He is
                            not as able to-day as in the past to lead and deliver Israel. All power is his to control
                            and consummate his purposes and settle the destiny of man, when cometh the end of all iule,
                            authority and power put down by the Messiah, and the kingdom delivered up to God. I Cor.
                            xv., 24. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian communism" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN COMMUNISM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gardner, Blanche L." TEIform="persName"/>By Blanche L. Gardner.</byline><p TEIform="p"> apparently had its origin in the days of Abraham, for in that early period men dwelt in
                            tents and held their property in common. In Ancient History is recorded many instances where
                            communities have been organized on some form of communistic principles. Among this number we
                            find Chrislma, the Hindoo Christ. He was very successful as a communist and had many devoted
                            followers. They held all their property in common and drew their expenses from one general
                            fund, thus, all shared alike having equal rights. He taught many wise maxims which are
                            worthy of remembrance,"There should be no disagreement between your lives and your
                            doctrine." "Above all things cultivate love for your neighbor." "A good, wise, and
                            benevolent man can not be rich." And many more that proved he guided his people in wisdom,
                            teaching them to love and have a care for the welfare of their fellow-men. Moses sought to
                            introduce the spirit of communism among the Israelites when he instituted the year of the
                            JubiLee. "Ye shall hallow the fiftieth year and proclaim liberty throughout all the land
                            unto all the inhabitants thereof it shall be a Jubilee unto you; and ye shall return every
                            man unto his possessionthe land shall not be sold forever." This prevented poverty among the
                            people, for at least once in fifty years the property was divided and returned to the
                            original owners. The Essenes were another sect of Communists. It is supposed that they
                            existed for thousands of ages. They are first mentioned one hundred and sixty years before
                            Christ. Although they were the descendants of the Jews, they separatCOMMUNISM <pb n="85" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 85 ed themselves from their nation and formed themselves into a
                            community. Their fundamental principle was purity of life, and they did not countenance the
                            marriage relation, yet there were some among them that were unable to live "as the angels in
                            heaven" consequently they were allowed to marry, but they could not be considered of the
                            highest rank, and were obliged to observe special laws. Each person that joined the
                            community was required to consecrata all he possessel for the support of the society. All
                            expenses were drawn from the one treasury. Accordingly they shared equally, having neither
                            rich nor poor in the community. There seems to be a similarity between Essenism and
                            Christianity. Many have supposed and believed that Jesus received his early education among
                            the Essenes. After Jesus was baptized he began the formation of a community. He selected
                            twelve for his disciples who were willing to forsake all and follow him in the regeneration.
                            One of this number was chosen to take charge of the "money-bag" and keep account of the
                            buying and selling of this little community. Jesus Christ was the origin of Christian
                            Communism. When the rich young Ruler came to Jesus desiring to know what he should do to
                            inherit eternal life, stating that he had observed the commandments from his you^h, Jesus
                            replied, "One thing thou lackest, go thy way, sell whatsoever thou hast and give to the
                            poor, and thou shalt have treasure in Heaven; and come follow me." Was not this communism?
                            All who became members of the Apostolic Church "sold their possessions and goods, and parted
                            them to all men as every man had need" for they "had all tilings in common." There were
                            seven deacons appointed to look after the temporal affairs of the church. Many attempts of
                            recent date have been made to establish societies upon a communistic principle with some
                            form of religious belief as the bond of their union. Some have tried to maintain community
                            of interests while retaining the marriage relation, but to date it has proved a total
                            failure. The Shaker Church owes its success to the maintenance of these two
                            principles,Virgin Celibacy and Community of Interests, according to the example of Jesus
                            Christ. Communism, without the religious life combined, haw always proved a failure. Natural
                            inclinations lead us to seek for ourselves pleasures, wealth and worldly honors but those
                            who enter the Christ life rise above these selfish ambitions and seek to love and serve
                            others, consecrating all they possess to the welfare and good of others, as did the Christ
                            who went about doing good. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Repentance, however difficult to be practiced..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Repentance, however difficult to be practiced...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Repentance, however difficult to be practiced, if it is explained without superstition, is
                            easily understood. Eepentance is the relinquishment of any practice from the conviction that
                            it has offended God. Sorrow and fear and anxiety are properly not parts, but adjuncts of
                            repentance; yet they are too closely connected with it to be easily separated, for they not
                            only mark its sincerity, but promote its efficacy.</p></div2><pb n="86" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Smith, Eliza R." TEIform="index"/>In Memory of Eldress ELIZA R. SMITH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Walker, Mary Ann" TEIform="persName"/>By Mary Ann Walker.</byline><p TEIform="p">"In the midst of life, ice are in death." A sheaf fully ripened for the house of the Lord.
                            The Harvest Angel has . gathered it home. Our loved mother has entered her heavenly home,
                            bearing palms of victory, and rejoicing in the conquest won. She counted no sacrifice too
                            great that would enable her to h'lp other sou s toward God. Hers has been a long life of
                            usefulness in the gospel cause. We loved her for h.?r many noble, Christian virtues. lier
                            kin I and charitable disposition toward all, won for her many friends. Those who were
                            privileged to live under her blessed ministration, know that she was a safe counselor, true
                            and faithful in every duty. How we shall miss her cheerful smile and her kind words ! For us
                            she has toiled with unselfish devotion, that we might gain an inheritance in the kingdom of
                            God. Dearest mother, words can not express the love and gratitude which we feel for the
                            parental love and care you have bestowed upon us. You have been to us a wall of protection,
                            through the days of youth, and guided our feet in the path that leads to peace. Still be
                            with us, to cheer and comfort us while on the journey of life. Take our pledge that we will
                            wo.k tor the principles of truth. Alfred, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Smith, Eliza R." TEIform="index"/>TRIBUTE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gowen, Stephen" TEIform="persName"/>By Stephen Gowen.</byline><p TEIform="p">BE thou faithful unto death, and 1 will give thee a crown of life." Rev. ii., 10. This is the
                            promise to the faithful, and I know that our beloved sister, Eldress Eliza R. Smith, who has
                            just passed from our sight, has been faithful unto death, and will receive a crown of life.
                            She has given her life through faithfulness and prayer, to assist others in obtaining the
                            pearl of great price. Her interest was the temporal and spiritual interest of the gospel
                            home, and her anxiety was that the young Brethren and Sisters might become steadfast in the
                            life of Christ. Her advice to those who had set out to win the prize, was to gain it by
                            being true and honest. I ti ust we shall bear in remembrance, this worthy example that has
                            so kindly been placed before us for so many years, and thus honor the memory of our beloved
                            El dress. We read of those who leave large sums of money for some good cause, and we think
                            of them as being very kind, but how much better has been this life to God, which our dear
                            Eldress has given for the protection and happiness of other souls. Let us be faithful unto
                            death, that we also, may win a crown of eternal life. Alfred, Me.</p></div2><pb n="87" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kindness" TEIform="index"/>KINDNESS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Farmer, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>By Henry C. Farmer.</byline><p TEIform="p">THE Christian religion enjoins, not only the loftier and move rigid excel lences of the human
                            character, bat also those which are delicately amicable and tender; not only the masculine
                            virtues, but also the feminine graces. It not only prepares its possessor to be a patriot in
                            the great theatre of his country; a spectacle of heroic martyrdom to God, to angels, and to
                            mankind, but a sympathizing friend in the social and domestic circle. Love can either expand
                            benevolence to the claims of the whole human family, or concentrate its emotions on one
                            individual object of pity or affection. Love is kind. Kindness means, a disposition to
                            please; an anxiety manifested to promots the comfort of our species. Pity commiserates their
                            sorrows ; mercy relieves their wants and mitigates their woes, but kindness is a general
                            attention to their comfort. Kindness expresses itself in words that are calculated to please
                            and to be useful. As not only our words, but the tones of our voice are indicative of our
                            thoughts and feelings, it is important that we be careful both as to what we say, and how we
                            say it. Half the quarrels which disturb the peace of society arise from unkind words, and
                            not a few from unkind tones. We should sedulously avoid a sour, morose, chiding mode of
                            speech, and adopt a soothing, conciliatory and affectionate style of address. A surly tone
                            is calculated to wound, and offend, and love, which carries the law of kindness on its lips,
                            will, consequently, avoid it. A snappish, petulant, scolding address is in the highest
                            degree repulsive and dissonant in the intercourse of society. We may not have, it is true,
                            the music of sound in our voice, but it is our own fault if we have not the music of love.
                            We need not employ grimace, fawning, sycophancy, hollow and unmeaning compliments, but we
                            may be courteous and affectionate, and we ought to "let our speech be seasoned with salt,
                            that it may minister grace to the hearers." What a fascinating character is that of the man
                            or woman of distinguished kindness; they are invested with indescribable loveliness ; they
                            may not. have the glory in which the patriot, the hero, or the martyr are enshrined, but
                            they are adorned, in no common degree, with the beauty of holiness. They carry about with
                            them the majesty of goodness, if not the dominion of greatness. The light of their
                            countenance is the warm sunshine to which the spirits of grief repair from their dark
                            retreats to bask in its glow, and their gentle words are like soft melody to chase away the
                            evil thoughts from the heart of melancholy, and to hush in peace the troubled reflections of
                            the distempered mind. As they move alone, distributing the pleasant and efficient
                            expressions of their regard, it is amidst the blessing of those who are ready to perish, and
                                <pb n="88" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 88 THE MANIFESTO. the notes of the unfortunate which they have
                            turned to joy. When tley come unexpectedly into the company of their friends, every
                            countenance puts on the appearance of complacency, and it seems as if some good genius had
                            come among them to bless the party. As they look around the circle with a smile of
                            beneficence that has found an abiding place on their brows, they present the brightest
                            resemblance to be found, in our selfish world, of the entrance of the Savior among his
                            disciples, when he said"Pence be unto you" and breathed upon them the Holy Spirit. Although
                            they neither seek nor wish an equivalent for their many acts of benevolence, their gentle
                            spirit receives, in a full tid'1, the stn am of consolation which has ebbed from their own
                            breasts to fill the empty channels of their neighbor's happiness. Who can be unkind to those
                            who are kind to all ? What heart is so hard ; what mind so cruel; what spirit so diabolical,
                            as to wound those who never appear among their race but as ministering angels? There is a
                            magic in their tears to melt to sympathy the stubborn soul of cruelty itself, which has a
                            tear for no one else; and no less a magic is found in their smiles, that will relax and
                            soften the hard features of envy, and reflect for a moment the sunshine of their joy. While
                            they live, every man and woman is their admirer. Wlvn they die every man and woman is their
                            mourner. While they are on earth, the.r names have a home in every heart, and when they have
                            passed away thi y have a monument in every memorythe record of their praiseand the
                            ininscription is "Kindness brings peace and happiness toothers than yourself.'' Mt. Lebanon,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Culture" TEIform="index"/>CULTURE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="McKechnie, Frederic" TEIform="persName"/>By Frederic McKechnie.</byline><p TEIform="p">rTlHERE is such a thing as the lust of the mind. When intellectual JL activity is engaged in,
                            for the sole purpose of enjoying the sensation it provides, without any regard to its effect
                            upon the general welfare, and with no desire that it should do anything save provide this
                            pleasurable sensation, we have what may fairly *be termed the lust of the mind ; and have,
                            moreover, that which distinguishes beyond anything else, the educated classes of today. The
                            activity of the press in providing the desired pabulum for these classes, is enormous. Every
                            year sees thousands of books published, which have no other object than the gratification of
                            this appetite, the desire for a fresh sort of emotion, a new species of intellectual
                            delight, and their readers busy themselves all the time in cultivating a keener and keener
                            susceptibility to the emotions arising from the contemplation of new phases of human
                            relationship, or in develop- <pb n="89" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 89 ing the faculty of
                            enjoying the cunning arrangement in words of the old phases. Such is what they caU
                            "'culture," and in the minds of the vast majority, there is no notion that culture need
                            include anything more. But it is a mistake. We know what culture for a flowering plant,
                            means. It means the perfect development of the perfect blossom. For an edible plant it means
                            the perfect development of a perfect fruit. For both it is simply the bringing into perfect
                            outward form, the best of which they are each capable. What then does the term culture mean,
                            when applied to man? In his case, it can only mean what it means in the case of the plant, a
                            full and perfect development of the best that is in him. And what is that best? Is it
                            intellect, with its power of seizing and distinguishing the forms of the world of thought?
                            Assuredly not. Those who have narrowly observed the workings of this principle, can not have
                            failed to notice how arrogant, combative ana self-assertive it is. Its tendency, in all
                            cases where it has sway, is to divide men, never to unite them. Nay, that in man, which is
                            highest, is not intellect, but something that includes intellect and is superior to
                            intellect, the Christ. The only culture that can rightfully be called culture, is
                            Christ-culture. Intellectual culture may supplement this, but can never be a substitute for
                            it, the perfect fruit of the human race is not a gigantic intellect, but a Christian, yea, a
                            Christ. All the various phases of what the world calls culture, are significant, only as
                            they indicate movement toward this standard. All the various products of modern
                            civilization,railways, bridges, churches, ocean steamships, are of value only as they
                            provide outlet for energies which will one day be turned toward the ideal. They have no
                            value i-.i themselves. "The cloud-capped towers, the gorgeous palaces, the solemn temples,
                            the great globe itself, * * * * shall dissolve, and, * * * * leave not a wrack behind." "The
                            grass withereth, the flower fadeth, but the word of our God shall stand forever," and whoso
                            hath that word in his heart, he shall not perish though all around him pass away. And so,
                            when the world brings before us, as it frequently does, in these days, its many shining
                            examples in the domains of literature and art, while we can not in justice withhold the
                            praise, that in many cases is so well deserved, as disciples in the school of the Christ, to
                            our word of admiration yet this other word we must add, "one thing thou lackest." Yea, one
                            thing thou lackest, and that, the one thing best worth having, to gain which the world is
                            well lost. "Everything has its price, and if that price is not paid, not that thing, but
                            something else is obtained." Are we willing to pay the price? Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obedience is better than many oblations" TEIform="index"/>Obedience is better than many oblations
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Obedience is better than many oblations.</p></div2><pb n="90" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. JUNE 1899. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is publisht by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Obdek and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all communications
                            to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Her. Co., N. H. One copy one year, postage paid. .50 A
                            cross in the margin will show that your subscription has closed. for subscription by Money
                            Order should be on the Post Office at Concord, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">April. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Rain. Snow. 1898. 42. 3.5 in 8 in.
                                1899. 47. % " 2 . " Highest Temp, during this mo. 80 above 0. Lowest " " " " 20 Number
                                of rainy days " " 3 " " 'snowy " " " 1 " clear " " " 16 " " cloudy" " " 10 May, 1899. At
                                present we breathe in the aroma of vernal bloom which forms the interlude to summer and
                                autumnal fruits. Since the opening of April, we have had but seveneights of an inch of
                                rain. Although the clouds are dry, giving but a sprinkling of rain, yet the vegetable
                                creation is donning iis imperial costume. Although the winter and early spring were very
                                trying to the human constitution, yet they proved a mantle of protection to the
                                vegetable constitution. Strawberry vines are strong and vigorous. If the season is
                                propitious we shall have an unusually heavy crop. Much depends on that little word "If."
                                Cherry and pear trees are in full bloom. Farmers and gardeners are plying their vocation
                                with might and main. If the weather is auspicious they should reap an ample harvest. It
                                is excellent weather for killing weeds; clear, warm days cause them to shrivel and die.
                                We had our first clipping of asparagus this year, May 2nd, a fortnight earlier than last
                                year. We have cool nights and warm days. As warmer weather displaces the cold, the
                                health of the people keeps pace. There is not anybody in the family at present
                                registered on the sick list. Our Ministry anived at our station Thursday, May 4th, where
                                they conclude to stop for a few days. A large company of men and teams are working on
                                the New York State Road. The piers for supporting the iron bridge are well on the way.
                                The Berkshire section is not commenced yet, Calvin ff. Heed. North Family. May, 1899.
                                Spring has now fairly arrived. Winter tarried long, and departed as one loath to go,
                                with tardy step, but there was no tardiness in Spring's movements. At the end of April
                                she was far away, apparently. Then, one morning, the bare trees of the day before, were
                                showing the least tint of green. A few days later cherry trees all about, fairly sprang
                                into bloom, and now along with apple blossoms, make a right TERMS. <pb n="91" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/>
                                THE MANIFESTO. 91 brave show of beauty around our hill-side home. We are very busy,
                                getting gardens ready for planting, and putting in a few early crops; repairing old
                                fences, and building new ones; planting numerous fruit trees and bushes, the gift of a
                                generous friend; destroying tent-caterpillar nests in the orchards. All these things
                                claim our attention and help us to maintain our balance as inhabitants of a physical
                                world. In addition to the ordinary spring work this year, we have had to make various
                                re-arrangements of our water pipes, owing to the operations of the contractor who is
                                building the New State Road that runs through our lands. It has been "quite a job" for
                                Brother Daniel to attend to this work, but the greater part of the work is now
                                accomplished. We are trying bee-keeping once more, and have made a beginning with five
                                hives. Further progress in this direction will be duly chronicled. Frederic McKechnie.
                                South. Family. May, 1899. Birds, bees and blossoms, Blossoms, birds and bees, Form a
                                merry trio Our old earth to please. Merry-making May month, Glad it now has come; Sad to
                                part with April For the good it's done. Thirty days we've known it, Known it by its
                                rain, But it glided onward With its loss and gain. We again record the departure of a
                                veteran of our glorious cause; one more valued member of the household of faith has
                                joined the ransomed army,Sister Lai ra Dole, another of God's noble women, has entered
                                the immortal home, and heard the welcome "Enter thou into the joy of thy Lord." Sister
                                Laura was one of the Sodus pioneers; she united with that Society in 1826. There are at
                                present three surviving representatives of that Community, Br. Horace Holoway, Eldress
                                Polly Lee, and Sr. Elizabeth Dell. And though feeble in body Their spirits are strong,
                                They hope soon to join With the justified throng. They are anxiously waiting The time to
                                draw near When angels will waft them To the bright spirit sphere; Where sickness and
                                sorrow And all earthly pain Can never, oh never Afflict them again. The precepts of
                                Jesus They love to obey; They testify plainly It is a sure way To keep us from evil, And
                                help us increase In heavenly beauty, In union and peace. Br. John Strover is at present
                                basking in the sunshine of Enfield, Conn. He left home Tuesday, the 2nd inst., for a
                                visit among his old friends, the Canaanites. Sister Florence Staples, a member of that
                                fraternity, is visiting her Mt. Lebanon friends. Joy and great gladness go with them.
                                General good health attends our family, and all are active in securing the eternal
                                riches. Gen.eviere DeGruw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 1899. On this beautiful Sabbath morning everything is smiling, for Nature is fully
                                awake having taken a long sleep and now she is busy renewing her robes of verdure and in
                                like manner the inmates of our home are making ready for the coming seasons; preparing
                                gardens, etc. Brother Washington Jones is at work among us in the fruit business,
                                setting out trees and raspberry bushes, also assisting the Sisters in setting out a new
                                strawberry bed of over 1500 plants. We find in him a faithful, interested worker, and
                                although his tarry with us be long or <pb n="92" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 92 THE JvANIFES TO. short he
                                has reared monuments of good- j will in the trees and vines which he has planted for our
                                future benefit. The flowers, too, form an important industry. The Sisters have a large
                                piece already planted to sweet peas, which, with favorable weather, we hope will yield
                                an abundance of bloom. Later the seedlings asters, pansies, verbenas etc. which wrere
                                planted in March in the greenhouse will be placed in the ground. The tomato business is
                                pushing, and orders for the plants come in thick and fast. Luckily Brother Delmer Wilson
                                has enough to supply the demand, that is, if the orders do not exceed over eleven
                                hundred dozen. Brothers Chellis Wing and John Dorrington are busy planting early
                                vegetables for market and home use. Brother Pliny Worcester is filling Brother Thomas
                                Noyes' place in providing wood etc. for the cooks, and last but not least our good
                                faithful Elder William Dumont has been assisting the Bicker Bros, in running the lines
                                between the farms. The summer term of school is in progress with twelve pupils. Ada S.
                                Gummings.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoossee, Florida" TEIform="index"/> Narcoossee, Fla.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 1899. A better condition of things seems to be coming to the state of Florida. The
                                present Legislature (styled the Iron Clad) have gone to Tallahassee fully clad in their
                                armor, and determined to break down or make a change in the financial part of the
                                Kailroad monopolies. The fare has been 5 cts. per mile and many think it should be only
                                three. Express charges have been reduced. Now we think there is some hope for Florida.
                                With all the floods and blizzards there seem to be ten righteous souls found to save the
                                state. On the 17th of April, the writer of these Notes, visited our gospel friends at
                                White Oak, Ga. I remained eight days, and found the little Community, like ourselves,
                                struggling to establish a Communistic home on the basic principles, "Purity of Life,
                                Equality of the Sexes, and a United Interest."' Our cause needs assistance. Needs
                                members who are willing to be harvested from the generative order, and become as
                                Brethren and Sisters. But with all our needs we do not propose to take any backward
                                steps by coming down from the cross of Christ. On the 2nd inst. Br. Benjamin Gates and
                                Br. Egbert Gillette, visited Jacksonville, to attend the Horticultural Convention,
                                hoping to get a few notes of interest on the subjects of Horticulture and Agriculture in
                                Florida. On May 3rd the mercury stood at 94 deg. Fahr. Amtreiv Barrett.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1899. "Be it ever so humble, there's no place like home" floats out upon the spring
                                air to the rhythm of the scraping and scouring, the dusting and draping, the painting
                                and polishing, which regularly succeed one another in the sweet symphony of our home
                                life at this special season. We have indeed stirring strains in every sense of the term,
                                muscular Christianity holds full sway six days in the week. The principle of godliness
                                is evidenced by the practice of cleanliness; and we above all other people, purpose to
                                prove its existence among us. Vegetation has risen to the occasion, and bud and blossom
                                are up to date. Six acres of potatoes, two early and four late varieties, are now
                                planted. Green peas were sowed on the 20th ult. Asparagus fell under the knife the 11th
                                inst., and rhubarb will, no doubt, be the next victim. The spring term of school opened
                                on the 2nd inst. under pleasant auspices. There are twenty-one pupils registered, and
                                all have our kind encouragement in their important work. Our good Editor has just
                                establisht an interesting little institution near the child- <pb n="93" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                MANIFESTO. 93 ren's dwellinga veritable summer-house for the birds. The purple martins
                                are the invited guests, but the white-bellied swallows were present at the raising,
                                watched the proceedings with keen interest then hastened to take the new quarters and
                                would not be driven out though measures i were promptly taken for evacuation. They
                                pugnaciously hold the fort by right of discovery and the invited guests are happily
                                unaware of the gross insult. Kind greetings in advance we send to our good friends at
                                Enfield, Conn., who have at last evolved the idea that intervisiting is a good
                                foundation-stone in our church work. We recommend the idea for universal adoption.
                                Jessie licuns.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 18(19. The rhymster who undertook a transposition of Bryant's "Autumn," to the tune
                                of "The melancholy days have come, the saddest of the year,'" House-cleaning time is
                                near; was certainly very wide of the mark in estimating what constituted melancholy
                                days. House-cleaning time can not be classed in that category. Imagine the condition of
                                our domiciles if it were not for that periodical renovation! As it is in the material
                                life so it is in the moral and spiritual house. How refreshing it is to enter into a
                                habitation that has been through the cleansing, the very atmosphere seems fraught with
                                the suggestion; keep clean,keep clean. And how blessed it is to meet the individual life
                                whose spiritual atmosphere reveals the condition of a house that is clean. At present
                                some are turning things topsy-turvy and with paint and kalsomine, our old house begins
                                to shine. And some are on the farm and in the garden preparing the soil and planting the
                                seed, hoping for the blessing of a bountiful harvest. Each one in the task assigned
                                faithfully performs his duty, and receives the reward of well done. At date of writing
                                we have with us in the form only three of those veterans who united with the society at
                                Port Bay, Wayne Co., N. Y. All the rest have passed over to the evergreen shores.
                                Heavenly F.ither and Mother, we know that the ancients of the city are passing on; we
                                miss them from our sight, but many times when walking in the shadow we feel their
                                blessed presence, and we know they have laid up treasures where motli can not corrupt,
                                nor thieves break through and steal. Hamilton De Cf rain.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Easter messages" TEIform="index"/>EASTER MESSAGES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Estabrook, Fidella" TEIform="persName"/>By Fidella Estabrook.</byline><p TEIform="p">The blest Easter is dawning in glory, Its quickening life the vale tills, It touches the
                            hiil-tops with beauty And wakrns the long sleeping rills. It brings 'uo the earth living
                            power, It wafts to our hearts richest love, To each one it bears a sweet message, To all,
                            renewed life from above. "Christ is risen,'1 this is the glad message, "Christ is risen,"
                            for you and for me. Oh wonderful gift to us given, Oh bountiful love, so free. 'No inure in
                            the grave, then seek him, For behold, he dwells not there; He is risen, and reigning in
                            glory, He is risen,go seek hi in with care. Ye bells that are joyously ringing. Tell it now
                            to hearts lone and sad; Bid them leave the ways of sorrow, And arise, by Christ's blessing
                            made glad. For lie all the journey has traveled, ! lie knows every trial you bear, ! His
                            comfort shall daily sustain you, j Fur he every burden will share. Are you lost in sin's
                            darkened pathway, Groping long 'mid the shadows below? Look above, there's a light held for
                            you, Angels bend a word to bestow. Then listen, the voice sweet and tender Calls,Arise,
                            leave the doubts of the past, <pb n="94" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 94 THE MANIFESTO. "Come to me," to your
                            true, waiting Savior, I will help, I will guide, to the last. Has your lamp grown dim, my
                            brother? Does its light burn feebly and low? The light of the world beams around you, Touch
                            it now, 'twill make your own glow. Are you fainting and weary, my sister? Take heart, your
                            Savior is near, And to you, as of old, he whispers, I am with thee, my child, do not tear.
                            Oh ring bells, ring the glad story, And swing lilies tall and fair, Tell the whole world
                            "Christ is risen" He is reigning in love "over there." "Over there?" not alwaysnot ever, But
                            here with us now, to-day, For he said, 1 will come again surely, I will come and abide
                            alway. Then list, for the message is sounding, There's a word for each needy one, A comfort
                            for each saddened spirit, For the faithful a joyous "Well done." What word have you from the
                            Father? What gift so precious and true? 'Tis coming, this wondrous blessing, 'Tis coming to
                            me and to you. There are treasures of strength and of courage, There are measures of love so
                            free, There is grace for the tried and tempted, There is mercy as wide as the sea, There is
                            peace, heavenly peace for the worker, Toiling each day for the King, There is joy unbounded,
                            eternal, For those who to his cross cling. There is tenderest love for the erring, Who
                            repentant cries, "Save, Lord, Ipray," There is comfort, and blessing, and glory, And love,
                            endless love, alway. For from out of earth's dreary prison, Christ arose, the once
                            crucified, That we too may rise in his spirit, In his likeness awake, satisfied. And in that
                            house of bright glory, A mansion he has gone to prepare, A place which each faithful toiler
                            In his blest presence shall share. Then let not your heart be troubled, Nor fear your spirit
                            e'er know, For he is ever beside you, To guide wherever you go. West Pitt afield, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible Class" TEIform="index"/>From the Bible Class.</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blessings of the gospel" TEIform="index"/>BLESSINGS OF THE GOSPEL.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pineo, Sadie J." TEIform="persName"/>By Sadie J. Pineo.</byline><p TEIform="p">We read that God sendeth his rain on the just and on the unjust and maketh the sun to
                                shine on the evil and the good. So it is with the gospel. Salvation is offered freely to
                                all souls who will come and drink of the waters of life, no discrimination being made
                                between high and low, rich and poor, for our Savior said, "I caine not to call the
                                righteous, but sinners, to repentance." Souls having a knowledge of the higher life but
                                being unwilling to walk in the strait and narrow way, realize the fulfillment of the
                                text, "If the light that is in thee be darkness how great is that darkness." But those
                                who accept Christ and willingly become his disciples, leaving all for his sake, become
                                participants in the joy promised to the pure in heart, the meek, and those who hunger
                                and thirst after righteousness. "E'en though stricken 'neath the rod," the true child of
                                God is confident that the hand that chastens deals in tender mercy, for a divine
                                parentage knoweth that we have need of these things. The gospel takes souls from
                                nature's garden and transplants them into the garden of Grace, where they are nurtured
                                by the rain and the sunshine of Heaven. As the spotless lily comes up from the blackest
                                mud, so the soul, touched by the power of the gospel, rises from the mire of a fallen
                                nature, and blooms in fragrant beauty, having struck its roots so deep that neither
                                storm nor flood has power to destroy it. <pb n="95" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 95 The
                                Christ spirit says"Every plant which my heavenly Father hath not planted shall be rooted
                                up," hence the necessity of the injunction, "Watch and pray," lest while men sleep the
                                enemy comes and sows tares, which, when grown will choke the good seed. East Canterbury,
                                jV. H.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Food we eat, no. 4" TEIform="index"/>THE FOOD WE EAT. NO. 4.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder H. C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">The Zulus use for food many of the wild, as well as, some domesticated animals, and should an
                            elephant be captured very little of this wonderful beast would be thrown aside. After
                            cutting a passage through the side of the huge creature, several men crawl inside and pass
                            out everything as they can cut it away. The hot sun helps them in their work as they seem to
                            prefer the meat after reaching the tirst stages of putrefaction. The intestines are emptied
                            of their contents and then filled with blood and subsequently made into a pudding. That is
                            quite like more civilized nations who on slaughtering the swine, clean the intestines and
                            then fill them with scraps of meat and eat them as sausages. "The trunk of the elephant is
                            cut into slices and baked, and the feet are taken off and roasted." "The stomach of the
                            rhinoceros is considered a delicacy. It is cleaned and then filled with scraps of meat, fat,
                            blood and other ingredients and then cooked. Scotch travelers say it is like a dish of their
                            native land. Corn and millet are also included in the articles of food. Locusts are steamed
                            in a kettle and then put in the sun to dry. They are then shaken till the wings and legs
                            drop off when they are stored away in baskets, the same as they would corn. These locusts
                            are eaten whole, and as a luxury they add a little salt." "Several of the tribes in South
                            America are omnivorous eaters. They make no discrimination of the animals which they eat,
                            and the carniverous are devoured as readily as are tlie others. Many of these tribes have no
                            use for salt or spices in the preparation of their food." The Fijians and New Zealanders
                            were cannibals, and yet obtained much of their food from the ocean. They were not especially
                            nice, as the Fiji chief invited us to dine with him and each person was served to a whole
                            baked iguana or lizard. Shrimps are placed between pieces of bread and eaten as sandwiches.
                            One account speaking of the Brazilians, says, they eat snakes, monkeys and iguanas. To dine
                            on snakes and monkeys, might seem to be an her tic effort, even though they were served by a
                            first-class cook, but an iguana pie or iguana steak, so much relished by the Brazilians
                            would evidently be a little too much for a civilized stomach. The iguana belongs to the
                            family of lizards and sometimes grows to a large size, measuring some four feet in length.
                            This repulsive reptile, is quite at home either on the land or in the water. Rev. J. G. Wood
                            writes;"From the aspect of this long-tailed, dewlapped, sealy, spiny lizard, most persons
                            would rather recoil and the idea of eating the flesh of so repulsive a creature, would not
                            be likely to occur to them." They eat small fish, alive, without the trouble of removing any
                            of the parts. They also eat rats and sharks, as they think their idol god dwells in them."
                            "Dr. Kane in his arctic expedition says fiat Esquimaux take the stomach of the reindeer,
                            just as it comes from the animal and cutting it into slices, place it upon the table." An
                            African king was invited to dine with some white people, and was presented a dish of
                            beautiful strawberries with cream and sugar. This was a new dish for the King and he
                            expressed his pleasure by saying, "This, is very nice," but as he thought of his rare dish
                            at home, he remarked, "But did the white man ever eat any baked ants?" <pb n="96" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/>
                            96 THE MANIFESTO. In the above we find two dishes of delicious flavor, and it is a matter
                            for custom and the nerves of taste to decide which s all be acci pu'd. We copy some notes
                            from the valuable work on '"Health," by Dr. R. D. Mussey. This eminent physician was a
                            professor of anatomy and surgery at Dartmouth College, N. H. and a professor of surgery in
                            the Medical College of Ohio. 'Man is omnivorous by practice. Probably not a single species
                            of animal was ever found that has not been tried for the food of man. Beasts clean and
                            unclean, serpents, lizards, toads, grubs and spiders have all contributed to make out the
                            variety, regarded as a necessity of the human appetite. Humbolt in South America saw the
                            centipedes or "thousand legs" as we should call them, some of them a foot and a half long,
                            dragged from their holes and eaten alive by the children. The white ants of Africa are put
                            alive into a dry kettle or frying pan, and when duly roasted over a slow fire, are eaten by
                            handf uls as we eat parched corn. Spiders are eaten by the inhabitants of New Caledonia, and
                            Lalande" a famous French astronomer ate the spider as a delicious morsel. Rattlesnake soup
                            has furnished a rich and savory repast for the hunters of North America. The eating of much
                            fatty food tends to corpulency, and this condition may be regarded as a form of disease. It
                            was a divine injunction to the Israelites, that, "It shall be a perpetual statute for your
                            generations throughout all your dwellings that you eat neither fat nor blood." Large eaters
                            have become large men, and Krocher of Berlin weighed 450 lbs. Ultimately he became too fat
                            to walk or stand alone. In our own country the annual feasts of Thanksgiving and Christmas,
                            it may be presumed, seldom or never pass without extra work for the physician if not for the
                            undertaker. Dr. Foote says,"Mexicans eat a large yellow worm found on the Maguey plant, and
                            they call the dish Maguey butter. The Africans eat elephants, hippopotamus, giraffe, zebra,
                            antelope, wild ants, leopard, lion, alligator, crocodile, eggs of reptiles, lizards, wild
                            cats, panthers, wolf, opposum musk rat, porcupine, spiders, rats, locusts, biids' nests, and
                            nearly every insect." In Alaska the people are as saving of the whole reindeer as the A trie
                            ins are of the elephant. The flesh is dried or smoked and can be kept indefinitely in Mich a
                            climate The blood is drunk warm aud every part of the body utilized in some way. The surplus
                            blood is preserved by freezing and then used for puddings. The stomach and contents are
                            frozen foi special delicacies.Scientific American. (To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hart, Charlotte" TEIform="index"/>Charlotte Hart
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Charlotte Hart, at Enfield, N. H. April 3, 1899. Age 83 years, 5 months and 23 days. A
                                true, sweet, loving Christian woman, gone to her eternal treasure. R. C. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dole, Laura" TEIform="index"/>Laura Dole
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Laura Dole, at
                                Shakers, N. Y. April 20, 1899. Age 79 years, 3 months and 19 days. Sister Laura came
                                into the Society when a child seven years of age. She has spent a long and useful life
                                among the Believers, and has occupied positions of care and trust. She was a faithful
                                burden-bearer, being for many years a nurse, and afterward, family Deaconess. E. E. W.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Smith, Eliza R." TEIform="index"/>Eldress Eliza R. Smith
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Eldress Eliza R. Smith, at Alfred, Me. April 20, 1899. Age 68 years and 1 day. "Many
                                daughters have done virtuously, but thou excellest them all." F. C. C. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bullard, Marcia M." TEIform="index"/>Marcia M.
                                Bullard
                            </head><p TEIform="p">
                                Marcia M.
                                Bullard, at Ayer, Mass. May 7, 1899. Age 76 years, 10 months and 26 days. Sister Marcia
                                was led in early life to espouse a cause she deemed best for her spiritual unfoldment.
                                She has given a long and eminently useful life to its service. Always true and steadfast
                                to principle, Sister Marcia is well known, as she has long filled places of trust, and
                                with unfailing integrity. Her worth is approved by all who know her, and her rest is
                                well earned. M. Me. L.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE    MANIFESTO.
POPULAR SCIENCE
Nature, Inventiin,
IlLflaChemistry, Mineral  g/.ntALi ll
Heaith, Hygiene, Medicine.
Formerly  Boston  Journal  of Chemistry
ENLARGED and IMPROVED.
This popular inonthly contains a larg'e n nnber of Short, Easy. Practical, Interesting ami
Popular, Scientilic aiticlvs. that can be Appre
ciated ami Enjoyed by any intelligent reader,
even though he^knew little or nothing' of Science. It is intended to interest those who think
Profusely illustrated and Free
from Technicalities
Entirely Different from an I much   superior to
other  papers   with a similar name.
Monthly,   $1.60 per year.    ITawsdjalers,   15   cts.
Largest Circulation of any
Scientific Paper.
LILLARD & 00.,
108 Pulton St., New York.
4gf-Mention this paper for a sample copy
IN
Eldresses
Dorothy A, Durgin,
Joanna J, Kaime,
The book contains photographs of the
Sisters, and also a short biographical
sketch.    A notice of the Memorial Service
including several pieces of music.      Many
letters of sympathy  from  friends   not  of
the Community.
A copy of the book may be obtained by
addressing Hart & Shepard,
East Canterbury, N. H.
Price, Cloth, 75 cts.    Boards 50 cts.
WITHOUT   DOUBT
THE BEST FAMILY  PAPER   PUBLISHED
IS?   THE
MEW   YORK   WEEKLY   WITNESS.
16 Pages,   Only   $1 a year.
TM
Has a very wide scope, comprising as it
does the following departments:
Editorials,
Spirit of the Press,
Scientific and Instructive,
Foreign News,
A Talk With the Doctor,
Around the Hearth.
Little Men and Women,
Weekly Articles by George R. Scott
Taimage's' Sermon,
Money and Business.
World-Wide Field,
Our Family Story.
Farm and Garden.
Market Reports.

SABBATATH READING.
16 Pages.   Only 50 cents a Year.
An Inter-denominational Weekly Paper.
Sap.p.atii Reading is solely religious.
No news; no politics. A grind paper
for the truth-seeker.     It contains:
Editorial.
Choice Poetry,
Good Stories,
Reports ot Missions,
Mothers' Sabbath Afternoon
With the Children,
And a muss of matter carefully selected.
Send for free sample copies of Witness
and Sabbath Reading. And send for
free sample pages of our Bagster's Bible.
Address
JOHNBOUGALL& 00., 150 Nassau Street, New rork.
MEMORIAM
the course of this elaborate and comprehensive paper, .Secretary Long' reviews, in a most
appreciative manner, the work or his distinguished ]ire<l  cc.-.ois in officeSecretaries
Hunt, Chandler, Whitney, Tracy and Herbert
whose efficient and patriotic energy in the
building (it the new 1 avy led up to the gloriou.i results consummated under the present administration.
The Odd and Uncommon,
Our Country's Hope
Christian Endeavor Topic
Epworth League Topic,
Sabbath-School Lesson
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
ROYAL
Baking
Powder
Absolutely Pure
Makes the food more delicious and wholesome
ROYAL BAKING POWDER CO., NEW YORK._____________________________
50   YEARS'
EXPERIENCE
SHARER HAMAMELIS
(W1TCHHAZEL,)
A. remedy for Cuts, Burns, Scalds,
Headache, Sore Throat and all
cases of external inflammation
Taken internally- for Bowel
Complaint, Bleeding of the
Lungs or Bowels, and for
all aches and pains.
For use externally, bathe the parts and
lay on a cloth wet with the Extract,    Internally, take one half teaspoont'ul three
times a day.    Use hot or cold.
Ask your druggist for it or send your
order to Akthtjr Bbxjce.
East Canterbury, N. H.
Trade Marks
Designs
Copyrights &c.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain our opinion free whether an
invention is probably patentable. Communications strictly confidential. Handbook on Patents
sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice, without charge, in the
Scientific American.
A handsomely illustrated weekly. largest circulation of any scientific! journal. Terms, $3 a
year; four months, f 1.  Sold by all newsdealers.
MUNN & Co.361Broadwa^ New York
Branch Office, 625 F St., 'Washington, I). C.
AUTHORISED   RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY.
The religious basis of the Order must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
The exponent or West Gate Philosophy.
A.  new occult; system.An unlimited field of labor open to teachers, lecturers
and healers.   Address,
The ORACLE, Sta. A.    Boston, Mass,
HOW TO MAKE MONEY!
If you are out of employment and want
a position paying you from $50 to $100
monthly clear above expenses by working
regularly, or, if you want to increase your
present income from $200 to $500 yearly,
v by working at odd times write the GLOBE
CO. 723 Chestnut St. Phila., Pa. stating
age, whether married or single, last or
present employment, and you can learn
how to make more money easier and
faster than you ever made before in your
life.
HAVE YOU ''COMMON SENSE?"
If not, send at once for a free copy of this
liberal-minded advocate of advanced
thought, which brings health and
success.    Address
"Common Sense," M. O. 55 State St.
Chicago, 111.
to advanced thought peoplesample copy of the most original and
practical occult journal of the age.
FREE
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>