<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1211" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><date value="18821101" TEIform="date">October 1882</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">241-264</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1">
                    <!-- <pb n="t.p." id="p1"/> <p> VOL. XII. NOVEMBER. NO. 11. SHAKER MANIFESTO Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT SHIRLEY, MASS. "Blessed are those that hear the word of God and keep it." SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H. 1883. </p> <pb id="p2"/> <div2 type="section"> <head> <index level1="Advertisements"/> </head> <p> [Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/> <pb id="p4"/> </p> </div2> --><pb n="241" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/>
                    <!-- <div2 type="none"> <p> CONTENTS. Truth not Personalities Religion, Signs of the Times, Angel Help, Prayer, November, Happiness only Within, Pleasure, The City of Light, Benjamin Whitcher, Content, Wisdom, An ti- Vaccination , Today and Tomorrow, Vol. XII. Page. 241 - 242 242 245 245 245 246 247 248 250 250 250 252 Gene rosity, Blessings, Notes, Schools,—Harvard , Schools,—Enfield Conn. Visit to Boston, Deaths, Juvenile, Letter Box, House-hold, Farm and Garden, Books and Papers, Select, Music,—Captain's Call, Page. 252 - 253 254 - 255 257 - 257 258 - 258 259 - 259 260 .- 262 263 - 264 NOVEMBER, 1882. No. XI. </p> </div2> --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth and personalities" TEIform="index"/> TRUTH, NOT PERSONALITIES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">The soul who sincerely hungers for truth, seeks the nutritious kernel only ; all
                            wrappings of busks, or chaff of the personal ambition, pride of discovery, and pedantry of
                            manifestation exhibited in its advocates are obnoxious to the sincere truth seeker, and
                            adverse to the dissemination and reception of truth. Wisdom's truth, either in science, art,
                            or religion, rides no hobby ; has no respect to personalities ; is neither magnified nor
                            diminished by the idiosyncracies of individuals ; yields not to preferences of nationality,
                            race, color, or sex, but, where she can find a vessel pure, and emptied of selfish pride,
                            ambition for distinction and consequence,—a simple lover of, and seeker after her treasures
                            for their own intrinsic worth, she bestows with a liberal hand. Humanity has such a
                            shimmering display of vanity in the effort to disseminate truth, that its professed
                            advocates seem often mantled more in the shrouds of self-love, than panoplied with truth ;
                            thus it often comes to us in patches and shreds, smutted, or belittled Avith the dross of
                            humanities follies. It is rare to find an article on truth, especially religious truth, that
                            is not either so studded with theology, stuffed with professional pride, or dwarfed by the
                            huge cage of human ambition and pride it is squeezed into, so that the sincere seeker after
                            truth seems perishing with hunger, before being able to untumb it; and the sailor on the
                            ocean of inquiry and investigation tears to board its craft, finding so little wind in its
                            sails. Friends of humanity, and lovers of godliness. Is it not possible, by the aids of
                            truth committed to our trust, so to eliminate ourselves from the narrow confines,
                            belittlements, and chaffy wrappings of self, as to present, each one, our modicum of truth,
                            as a golden nugget, pure from the celestial mine ? May <pb n="242" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/>
                            242 SHAKER MANIFESTO. we not hopefully anticipate the dawn of a heaven-born day, when, at
                            least, the advocates of religious truth may meet each other as brothers ^nd sisters of the
                            one family of Christ, on the level of divine universal love ; and, freed from the biases of
                            human creedism, and scholastic theology, interchange the coin of religious truth,
                            unadulterated with the dross of human pride, and ambition to be recognized as the
                            discoverer, or to see who shall be the greatest, wisest, or most scholastic, or even who
                            shall attract to their standard of wisdom the greatest number of followers ? Truth's
                            successful followers are a simple people, free of utterance, and as enchantingly sweet as
                            the song of Philomela. The prating of the multitude does not silence them ; the creeds of
                            theologians do not bind them ; human theologies do not darken their counsels ; nor doth the
                            fear of opposition turn them from their path of duty. Love to God and love to man graces
                            their diction, and renders mellifluous their sternest declarations ; the human soul
                            instinctively bows in acquiesence to their revelations, and honors with approval, though,
                            not always, for the moment, strong enough to bend the human will in conformity. But, truth,
                            love, and purity, conquers the world. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion" TEIform="index"/> RELIGION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Martin, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName"/> ELIZABETH MARTIN</byline><p TEIform="p">The human mind was created with antagonistic elements,—a two-fold nature, the one
                            aspiring to the angelic life, a rest in God, the other burying its interests, and seeking
                            its happiness in the sensuous and earthly. Hence, the strife in cultivating the one and
                            subduing the other. We comprehend that system of religion as best which best develops the
                            faculties of the soul; which leads the mind away from the narrowness of merely selfish
                            interests, into paths of Christian benevolence and universal love, from the elements of
                            discord, into harmony of action with godly principles ; from darkness of the earthly and
                            human, into light of the spiritual and divine. The work of the future will be to religionize
                            the social practical life; to cease wrangling over the isms of sects, and teach men and
                            women in their relations with each other, how to speak and act the truth, void of malice and
                            hate, clad in Christian love. The true seekers after righteousness, are heart-sick of
                            theories', creeds; and dead forms ; they thirst for living practical realities. If they turn
                            from worldly pursuits, reject its relations and interests, they want nothing less nourishing
                            than the very bread and wine of the heavenly kingdom. This they rightfully expect to receive
                            in the church, through the agency of spiritual teachers ; from professors of Christianity ;
                            from the unfolding of the mind as they obey higher principles ; and from the influx of
                            divine ministrations which is the sure meat of the earnest Christian worker. They want the
                            social life so purified from the very appearance of guile, that they may enjoy a legitimate
                            companionship, as sons and daughters of God in the spirit, free from the jealous eye and the
                            slanderous tongue. They want that interchange of pure thought, which emulates virtue in men
                            and women, and shoots its arrows of righteous indignation into the very heart of sensualism
                            ! <pb n="243" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 243 They want that charity which
                            "hideth a multitude of faults," by considering the traditions, circumstances and influences
                            which have moulded the characters of individuals, making them so diverse in manners,
                            customs, theories and practice ; the charity that will shut the mouth of slander, and bless
                            the effort of our neighbor, rather than curse his failure. They want the perfect seal of
                            discipleship made manifest in being "kindly affectioned one to another, in brotherly love
                            preferring one another." These principles destroy the selfish life, and build a stable
                            Christian happiness which worldly antagonists can never overthrow. Who cares whether one
                            believes in a unity, duality or trinity of the Godhead, if he weave his life after the
                            pattern of these principles ; regarding humanity as one common brotherhffcd, the children of
                            an all wise creative Power. Jesus wrought out his religion through all the relations of his
                            daily social life ; he not only taught in the temple confounding the learned doctors, but
                            the most of his time was spent among the common people doing good, in the streets, on the
                            mountains, by the seashore, in ships, in the houses of his friends, in the kitchen of Martha
                            and Mary, at the bed-side and the tomb,— delivering precepts of heavenly counsel; sowing the
                            seeds of,eternal principles; and opening the wells of living truth, which are to-day
                            springing up unto everlasting life in the hearts of all who listen to the voice of the
                            spirit, with a willing, obedient ear. "The pure in heart shall see God," said he, what a
                            sermon is contained in that one beautiful beatitude ! When exalted above the sensuous, in
                            thought, word and deed, how clear the spiritual atmosphere becomes ! The soul indeed sees
                            the Divine ; its perceptions readily discern between the unclean and the clean, the false
                            and the true. In contemplating the subject of religion, our reason decides that the
                            Christian platform is the sure foundation, and Christian precepts the safest guide. We
                            believe that if we live by them, we embody their effects in our character, which is the only
                            treasure we can take with us to the immortal land. Justice, truth, mercy, goodness, purity
                            and love,—attributes of the Divine incorporated in the human, are the germs of immortality.
                            Let us grow in the likeness of our God, by actualizing more fully, these Christian
                            principles in our life and character. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Signs of the times" TEIform="index"/> SIGNS OF THE TIMES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Collins, Elvah F." TEIform="persName"/>ELVAH F. COLLINS</byline><p TEIform="p">(Continued from last number.) Another sign, perhaps still more prominent is the
                            disintegration, evinced in the condition of the family circle,—an order claimed to be
                            God-given and sacred, and, strongly held forth as a duty to be discharged by all mankind, to
                            form, and sustain those relationships, which should .create homes attractive to their
                            inmates, where parental care is bestowed in wisdom, and love that knows sacrifice for the
                            good of the young household, and where that love is returned, through implicit obedience and
                            respect, on the part of the children. Is it thus today? Are there.- homes where father and
                            mother, and children profess to comprise <pb n="244" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 244 SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. the happy family circle, strangers to those disturbing elements, which take
                            effect upon young minds, and draw them out to seek fortune in some romantic and startling
                            career ? We do not say there are no such homes to be found. The history of one unhappy
                            family, may be that of thousands. Marriage ties formed through rashness and ignorance or by
                            the immature, mentally and physically, are steps leading to blighted hopes, betrayed
                            confidence, and intemperance. Children are born with a predisposition to crime, homes are
                            void of the warmth of love and affection, property squandered in riotous living, and aged
                            parents thrown upon the mercy of &amp; cold world. Divorces, and re-unions, made with a
                            view to better fortune, followed by successive failures, prove to the discerning, how far
                            astray human beings have wandered, from the laws of God, and Nature, which should have kept
                            the natural order of creation in the beauty and perfection of the Designer. Then comes the
                            cry for community, community ! Seeing the benefits and advantages derived by co-operation of
                            individuals, many efforts are made to start Colonies ; taking some one or more points, for a
                            basic principle ; financial economy, hygiene, polygamy, asceticism or social beuelits ; but,
                            the records of the past, show that a lack of something, has caused the most sanguine and
                            devoted, to fail of success ! What is wanting to make their work enduring, is one of the
                            many problems to be solved through experience. We believe, a community, that has not for its
                            foundation a sacrifice of the selfish, private, family relationship, like a house divided
                            against itself, cannot stand with permanence. Inward fires of controversy, soon causes a
                            conflagration, too rapid to be stayed by the wisest heads, and the practicalness of their
                            themes, is thereby made void. When we have studied these, and other signs of the decay of
                            the many systems, it calls forth the query. What is to be the outcome of the whole ? As
                            effect is sure to follow cause, conviction of error, is sure to lead the soul to search
                            after the right. Sinning humanity tired of the husks of prodigal living, are awaking to a
                            sense of the fullness in the Father's storehouse, for the obedient and law abiding. The
                            light of truth, theoretical, is scaling mountains of doubt, ami flooding vallies long shaded
                            by ignorance, and superstition ; and when people are convinced through reason of a better
                            way, strong religious aspirations, and the demands of conscience will supply required
                            strength for the selfdenial, necessary to be practiced in the New Creation, which shall
                            restore health to body, and soul. And what of Zion, the loved of our hearts, over which God
                            watches with a jealous eye? Shall she sit forever by the streams of Babylon, to mourn over
                            present afflictions ? Nay. The hand of the vine-dresser shall clothe her vineyards in the
                            beauty of order, and many shall tread the wine press, which will yield a rich supply of the
                            wine of the new kingdom. Her barren wastes shall bud and blossom, her pastures teem with
                            verdure, streams that have become dry shall swell to overflowing with waters from
                            inspiration's, fathomless ocean, and rivers shall flow beneath the dome of her temples, :'or
                            the purification of all souls. Look up ! ye whose eyes are downcast ; Lay aside the
                            sackcloth of mourning, ye who have fasted in sorrow, for <pb n="245" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/>
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. 245 behold ! the day Cometh, when the people oi God shall clap their hands
                            for joy, because of the great victory achieved through faith and prayer! Mount Lebanon, N.
                            Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Angel help" TEIform="index"/> ANGEL HELP</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Randall, Joanna" TEIform="persName"/>JOANNA RANDALL</byline><p TEIform="p">Floating upon the balmy breeze, And where the evening zephyrs play, Are hovering
                            angel visitants To cheer life's troubled way. They sing to us in purest strains And seek a
                            listening ear. To raise our wayward thoughts, into A holier atmosphere. Welcome sweet
                            guardian ministers, Come nearer to our souls ; Inspire us to nobler deeds Through daily
                            self-control. O'er shadow with baptismal fire Which burns with "Truth and Light, Forming a
                            principle within,— The maintenance of right. At breaking dawn at dewy eve And noon-day's
                            resting hour, We'll heed your gentle whisperings, Your presence still implore. Stay with us
                            loving spirit friends, For selfish cares intrude Without your chastening influence, So rich
                            in heavenly food. 0 bless us still with living faith Which makes us brave and strong, To
                            meet the seeming ills of life With charity for all. And in this strength we'll soar aloft
                            From selfishness and strife A resolution oft renewed, To live the "Angel life." Shirley,
                            Mass. A clergyman on his way to church, one Sunday, was overtaken by a heavy shower of rain.
                            On arriving at the vestry, he exclaimed, rather impatiently, "I wish, I were dry." Never
                            mind said his colleague, you will soon be in the pulpit, and there you will be dry
                            enough.—Frank Leslie, Ill</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/> PRAYER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Clark, George" TEIform="persName"/>GEORGE CLARK</byline><p TEIform="p">It seems to me that prayer has a very significant and deep meaning. It is not
                            merely the uttering for a few moments several times a day a list of words learned by rote,
                            for the sake of conforming to some outward rite or ceremony, or for apparent internal
                            sanctih'cation, when in reality the thoughts and feelings of the heart are in au entirely
                            different direction, thus impressing one with an outward sense of piety. This, to my mind,
                            is hypocritical. True prayer is the soul's deep earnest yearning and desire to God for His
                            holy spirit to enter into, and have constant access to the heart, that it may cleanse and
                            purify it from all error even from impure thoughts, that His perfect truth may have an
                            abiding place to illuminate the whole spiritual being. And the soul, like the gold, after it
                            has passed through the refiner's fire, becoming purified, stands on the sea of glass in
                            resplendant beauty an exact likeness of its Maker. True desires of the heart go out to our
                            heavenly Father and Mother in our every day life, seeking for love and wisdom to cheer and
                            guide us in all our motives and actions ; that we may live and act, not from the promptings
                            of a selfish spirit, but to do good to all around us. and to feel kindly and affectionately
                            toward humanity at large. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="November" TEIform="index"/> NOVEMBER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER</byline><p TEIform="p">The last Hose of Summer," ah more we would say, The last leaf of Autumn that's
                            fair, <pb n="246" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 246 SHAKER MANIFESTO. How swiftly the seasons pass
                            on and away, And leave nature faded and bare : But one cometh after whose mantle is peace,
                            So Dove-like why should we repine? We've drank in the Harvest and shared the increase Of all
                            in their season and time. The Spring in its beauty, the summer its bloom, The Autumn its
                            fruit ever rare, And now we may rest and enjoy the return, Which heaven has blessed us to
                            share. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Happines only within" TEIform="index"/> HAPPINESS NLY WITHIN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>ALONZO G. HOLLISTER</byline><p TEIform="p"> Happiness is the desire of all sentient beings. Most young people think it can
                            be found in outward conditions. They are apt to fancy that if they could have companions
                            like themselves, freedom to act as they have a mind to, with no care of duty or labor to
                            burden them, and as much money as they would wish, they imagine that with such conditions
                            they would be completely happy in the pursuit of pleasures that have no real existence
                            without the mind, and amusements that weary without remunerating. The arrangements of the
                            Universe makes it impossible for more than a very few to obtain these conditions, and those
                            who are so unfortunate as to have them nearly, do not find the happiness they seek, and by
                            pursuing such a course become the most dissatisfied and discontented class of mortals. When
                            not under the fever of excitement they are miserably unhappy, and are made more so by every
                            round of pleasure. By violating the laws of happiness they run in debt to the future ; by
                            foolishly spending their time and wasting their powers upon trifles that yield no
                            substantial return, they are^gradually and surely subjecting themselves to the law of
                            recoil, which will severely exact the utmost farthing of pleasure, and every kind of natural
                            enjoyment, before the individual can be liberated to begin again on as good footing as in
                            the commencement. None, even in the natural, earthly state of man. »*re so happy as those
                            who industriously toil for a determined object. The patient toiler for subsistence who is
                            able to keep want from his door, and lives morally, enjoys existence and possesses more real
                            happiness than the pleasure seeker who rolls in wealth, the product of other people's labor.
                            And the humble toiler'is easier prepared to receive a knowledge of the more excellent way
                            revealed in the gospel of the Kingdom of God. The domain of heaven and the real causes of
                            happiness and misery exist within the individual, hence the poet sings,—uTis not the outward
                            state, but temper of the soul by which we rate sadness or joy." Jesus says, "The Kingdom of
                            heaven is in you ;" we say it is never without. As that which is within is in our own power,
                            while that which is without lies partly in the power of others, we see that God has placed
                            within the power of each individual to create their own heaven ; to make their own happiness
                            or misery according to how they use the time and faculties He has bestowed upon them. We are
                            not born into this world with all the elements of happiness within us, therefore there is a
                            work for each one to do to acquire the remainder, or whatever is necessary to fill their
                            complement. We are born with elements of unhappiness, and a liability to death and
                            corruption. In these elements lies a way which<pb n="247" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 247 however right it may seem to men, the end thereof is death. Hence there is a
                            work for each one to bind, and purge out these, that good may come in their place. Ami
                            though we postpone this work a thousand years, and roam through all spheres of life
                            accessible to us, we never can find true rest nor the happiness we seek unti. we have done
                            this work of destroying within us the elements of unhappiness, and unrest, by self-denial
                            and the daily cro.ss, and by cultivating good qualities in their place. Mt. Lebanon, N.Y
                        </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasure" TEIform="index"/> PLEASURE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Williams, Flora" TEIform="persName"/>FLORA WILLIAMS</byline><p TEIform="p">"Let the heart of them rejoice that seek the Lord." 1 Ghron. xvi-10. The heart
                            has very little if any share in the common enjoyments of life ; the varied scenes called
                            pleasures merely satisfy the senses, and captivate the imagination. "Even in laughter the
                            heart is sorrowful; and the end of that mirth is heaviness." While in religion the heart
                            finds rest, sweet satisfaction and abiding joy. It is written, "Eye hath not seen, nor ear
                            heard, nor hath it entered into the heart of man to conceive the good things which God hath
                            prepared for them that love Him." Inexperienced persons are inclined to place too much value
                            on present surroundings and associations that tend to present happiness ; while all should
                            realize that felicity depends alone upon the state of the mind, and not upon external
                            condition. "Paul* was happy in prison, while Nero was miserable in a Palace." The powerful
                            Monarch that exclaimed "O that I had the wincrs *of a dove, for then I would fly away and be
                            at rest,"—portrays very clearly the restless condition of the multitude who having been
                            surfeited with the riches and pleasures of this life, are yet dissatisfied and long for a
                            haven of peace and rest; the promised reward of those who take up the cross and follow
                            Christ in the New Life—the life of regeneration. One may possess every blessing that wealth
                            and friends can bestow ; but without the balm of true religion, life will have been deprived
                            of its crowning glory, and bereft of that peculiar charm found only in the grace and beauty
                            of a religious character. This is a soul beauty all can possess by careful cultivation of
                            the spiritual sentiments. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="City of light" TEIform="index"/>THE CITY OF LIGHT
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Adler, Felix" TEIform="persName"/>Prof Felix Adler
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Have you heard of the Golden
                                    City Mentioned in the legends old? P&gt;verlasting light shines o'er it,
                                    Wondrous tales of it are told. Only righteous men and women Dwell within its
                                    gleaming wall; Wrong is banished from its borders, Justice reigns supreme o'er all.
                                    Do you ask : where is that city Where the perfect right doth reign? I must answer, I
                                    must tell you That you seek its site in vain. You may roam o'er hill and valley, You
                                    may pass o'er land and sea, You may search the wide earth over— 'Tis a city yet to
                                    be. We are builders of that city ; All our joys and all our groans Help to rear its
                                    shining ramparts ; All our lives are building-stones. Some can do but humblest
                                    service— Hew rough stones, or break the soil: <pb n="248" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/>
                                    248 SHAKER MAN IFESTO. While the few alone may gather Joy and honor from their toil
                                    : While the few may plan the arches. And the fluted columns fair, And immortal
                                    thought embody. And immortal beauty there. But, if humble or exalted, All are called
                                    to task divine, All but aid alike to carry Forward one sublime design. What that
                                    plan may be we know not; How the seat of justice high, How the city of our vision
                                    Will appear to mortal eye— That no mortal eye can picture, That no mortal tongue can
                                    tell, We can barely dream the glories Of the future's citadel. But for it we still
                                    must labor, For its sake bear pain and grief. In it find the end of living And the
                                    anchor of belief. But a few brief years we labor; Soon our earthly day is o'er,
                                    Other builders take our places And "our place knows us no more." But t-he work that
                                    we have builded, Oft -with bleeding hands and tears, And in error and in anguish,
                                    Will not perish with our years. It will be at last made perfect In the universal
                                    plan; It will help to crown the labors Of the toiling hosts of man. It will last and
                                    shine transfigured In the final reign of right; It will merge into the splendors Of
                                    the city of the light.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Religio P. J." TEIform="index"/>Religio P. J.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="From home" TEIform="index"/> FROM HOME</head><p TEIform="p">How we see the parting distance When we've traveled from our home ! Cannot wing
                            it or dissolve it, Steps alone make the return. Thus it is in Christian travel, When we've
                            gone from truth and light, A returning by repenting Are the needed steps to right.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Benjamin Whitcher" TEIform="index"/> BENJAMIN WHITCHER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">So long as "our home in Canterbury" is favored of God to remain a-consecrated
                            abode for Believers, ho long will the name of Benjamin Whitcher be held in pleasant
                            remembrance by the Brethren and Sisters. The dedication of all his esta:e to the church of
                            God, was not from the enthusiasm of the moment, but after the experience of some ten years
                            in the maintaining of a community relation with those whom he accepted into his own private
                            family. It was a free will offering, given without the shadow of a reserve, and to which no
                            reference was ever afterwards made, save that of thankfulness ior the privilege. His father,
                            whos;- name also was Benjamin bought the tract of land in Canterbury where the Believers now
                            live, while it was a dense wilderness ; for his son Benj ,min. Other sons had other tracts
                            of land in the wilderness, some being located i'u the town now called Northfield. and others
                            in Gilm nton. Benjamin Whitcher 2nd, the subject of this sketch, was born in the town of
                            Stratham, N. H. Mar. «, 1750. At the age of twenty lour he went alone from his father's
                            house into the wilderness and worked on the land, felling trees and cultivating the soil for
                            somo two years previous to the ma1-ing of it a permanent habitation for his family. During
                            this time he cleared several acres, and with the help of others who came at a later date, he
                            was able to build a house and a barn. In 177a he moved his family to his new home, and as
                            carriages were not known in that section of the country, <pb n="249" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/>
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. 249 and as they had paths only, leading from one settlement to another,
                            they were all obliged to make the journey on horseback. Joseph Shepard, a brother of Mary
                            accompanied them to their new home, and took charge of their little daughter Zilpha, on the
                            back of his horse ; while the father had the burden of some household articles on his horse
                            ; thus relieving the mother of all care except to take charge of the animal upon which she
                            rode. At this time there were less than three hundred inhabitants in what is now the town of
                            Canterbury, and the nearest neighbor was some five miles distant. Speaking of his early life
                            he says ; "Although I was not brought up under the religious discipline of any organized
                            society, yet the principles of strict morality were ever enjoined upon me, by my parents.
                            And though I often felt strong convictions for sin, even from my childhood, I did not join
                            any religious order till I was twenty six years of age. At this time there was a remarkable
                            religious revival, and in 1776 I became a member of the Free Church. As my conviction
                            increased my prayer to God was that he would open some way of deliverance ; "that he would
                            send by whom he would send," and work by means of his own choosing. My wish was to know and
                            to do his will. I also became deeply interested in the account of the Shakers which I had
                            learned from Benjamin Thomson who had visited them in the state of New York. After listening
                            to the reports of this man I soon made arrangements to visit the Shakers and see for myself.
                            The church at the same time became very much interested in the subject and commissioned two
                            of our preachers to visit the Shakers, and thoroughly investigate the order of their
                            religious life, and on their return to make a faithful report of the same. These preachers
                            confirmed all that we had previously learned, and farther, that "the Shakers taught that God
                            required man to confess and forsake all sin, and to take up a full cross against every evil
                            propensity. That their testimony was attended with that power of God which effectually
                            searched the heart and appealed to the conscience of every enlightened mind." In the mean
                            time, two of the Brethren from the Shakers in N. Y. visited Canterbury and the adjacent
                            towns, where they appointed meetings, and opened the dispensations of God's grace to man,
                            which had taken place in a past age. They also testified that Christ had now made a second
                            appearance, by his spirit, without sin unto salvation. Benjamin Whitcher was one among the
                            many, of the members of this Free Church who accepted the advanced light from God, and of
                            this he says, "Through obedience thereto I have found salvation from sin and a justification
                            in my conscience, for which I had been praying." This was in the fall of 1782. The family
                            now consisted of the parents, Benjamin and Mary Whitcher, and the children, Zilpha, Joseph,
                            Benjamin and John. (TO BE CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In a couple of hundred years from this, if the Bible is again revised..." TEIform="index"/>
                            In a couple of hundred years from this, if the Bible is again revised...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">In a couple of hundred years from this, if the Bible is again revised to suit the
                            times, the passage in the parable of the ten virgins, which reads thus, "Give us of your
                            oil, for our lamps have gone out," will be changed to, "Give us of your electric lights, for
                            our circuit is temporarily broken."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leslie, Frank, III" TEIform="persName"/>Frank Leslie. III</byline></div2><pb n="250" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Content" TEIform="index"/> CONTENT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gibbs, Sarah A." TEIform="persName"/>SARAH A. GIBBS</byline><p TEIform="p">Beyond the hills that shut me in I heard the sounds of labor. World's work and
                            pain and sorrow too Seemed struggling with its neighbor. And love seemed dead, and peace had
                            fled Far off to fields elysian, And might was right, and strength was law; Such was the
                            earthly vision. My soul was stirred; I prayed,—"Letme Do some great work so purely, To right
                            life's wrongs, that I shall know That I have loved thee surely." My lips send forth the
                            eager cry, The while my heart beat faster, "For some great deed to prove my love, Send me,
                            send me,—my Master !" But every road was hedged with thorns, My hands were torn and
                            bleeding; Each gate was barred, and hope ill-starred Was in my heart receding. Night came ;
                            within the valley's rim The sounds of pain and sorrow Grew faint; with idly folded hands I
                            waited for the morrow. From out the silence came a voice Saying, "If God thou fearest, Rise
                            up and do, thy whole life through, The duty that lies nearest. The friendly word, the kindly
                            deed, Though small the act in seeming, Shall in the end, unto thy soul Prove mighter than
                            thy dreaming. The cup of water to the faint, The rest unto the weary, The light thou givest
                            another's life, Shall make thine own less dreary. And boundless realms of faith and love
                            Will wait for thy possessing; Not creeds, but deeds—if thou wouldst win Unto thy soul a
                            blessing." And so I wait with peaceful heart, Content to do His pleasure; Not caring if the
                            world shall mock At smallness of the measure. Of thoughts, or deeds, or daily life, He knows
                            the true endeavor To do His will, to seek His face; And he will fail me never. —Benson,
                        Vt.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wisdom" TEIform="index"/> WISDOM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Collins, Sarah A." TEIform="persName"/>SARAH A. COLLINS</byline><p TEIform="p">Few and sweet are the words which the lips of wisdom utter." How true and how
                            full of meaning is this thought of the poet. All would do well to bear this in mind, and
                            especially in the presence of children. Then, more than at any other time, our words should
                            be choice and sweet; as children are so susceptible of influences, that they accept and
                            retain that which may dwell with them through a long life. We are often led to regret the
                            temptations that are open to their views, and to find that their immature minds are so wide
                            awake to see and hear all that is passing. It would give us great pleasure to have our
                            children grow up in paths of wisdom, in that innocence which harmonizes with their age and
                            experience, which will afford them a foundation, upon which to build an honorable and a
                            spiritual manhood and womanhood. Great care should be exercised lest we awaken their minds
                            to unprofitable matter, by carelessly repeating before them that which they should never
                            know. Rather let us study the preservation of their innocence, that their youthful days may
                            be as bright and beautiful as the month of June, and by this means avoid the experience of
                            the preacher, "lest the evil days come and the years draw nigh when thou shalt say, I have
                            no pleasure in them." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Public health and compulsory vaccination" TEIform="index"/>THE PUBLIC HEALTH
                            AND COMPULSORY VACCINATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tebb, William" TEIform="persName"/>William Tebb.</byline><p TEIform="p"> [TO THE EDITOR, MANIFESTO.] THE PUBLIC HEALTH AND COMPULSORY VACCINATION. Three
                            years ago I had the pleasure of visiting the original Shaker settlement near Albany, N. Y.,
                            and I there learned that the members and elders were interested in all questions that
                            related to the physical health of the community, that with Dr. Benjamin W. Richardson the
                            celebrated hygienist you held that "pure blood and a healthy life would banish all disease."
                            May I therefore venture to address you on a subject of great and increasing importance. <pb n="251" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 251 who have given the subject serious
                            consideration. The most ardent pro-vaccinators have been reluctantly compelled to confess
                            that small-pox cannot be got rid of in this way. Dr. Ballard, one of Her Majesty's
                            Inspectors of Vaccine, in his Essay on Vaccination, page 3G, says : "Dr. Jenner's prediction
                            has not been fulfilled; experience has not verified it; small-pox is not eradicated.
                            Scientific observations lend no countenance to the belief that it ever will be eradicated,
                            even from civilized communities." Mr. Ceely, who devoted forty years of his life to the
                            study of the subject, said at the London Calf-Lymph Conference in December, 1879 : "They
                            would not be able to annihilate smallpox by vaccination, and he defied any one to show that
                            he had claimed such a result; from the experience he had had, no such thing could, or ever
                            would happen." And more recently, Dr. Charles Cameron, M. P., avers in his letter to the
                            Times, May 24th, 1880 : "Since 1836 our statistics have been compiled so as to enable us to
                            compare the mortality not merely in small-pox occurring in all classes of vaccinated
                            persons, at different periods, but in each separate class of vaccinated persons, in persons,
                            that is, with one, two, three or four good or indifferent marks. I have gone into these
                            details and found that not merely has the mortality in small-pox occurring after vaccination
                            progressively increased, in the aggregate, but it has increased in each class of cases, and
                            increased enormously in the best vaccinated class of cases.'1'' Nor is the testimony in the
                            Lancet for August 27th less precise on this the corner-stone of the edifice upon which
                            vaccination is enforced by the State. That journal furnishes a report of the recent
                            small-pox epidemic at Bromley, London, by Dr. Fraser Nicolson, the medical officer in charge
                            between April 25th and June 29th, comprising forty-two cases in all, of which sixteen were
                            confluent; the whole of these were vaccinated and three re-vaccinated. Dr. Nicolson further
                            says, "That the chief element of success lay in the high, open, bracing locality in which
                            the temporary hospital was placed, together with the cool, dry winds during the time that
                            the worst cases were in the hospital." Here again, the beneficial effects of sanitation are
                            In order to keep up a useful small-pox panic in England and the United States, and to compel
                            frightened citizens to submit to the risks and penalties of the unphysiologica practice of
                            vaccination, it has become^ cus tomary with officers .of Boards of Health, anc public
                            vaccinators, to attribute the death o every unvaccinated small-pox case to the absence of
                            vaccination. Such medical experts carefully withhold the fact that in every small-pox
                            epidemic in European States under obligatory vaccination, the municipal government
                            statistics prove that from seventy-five to ninety-six per cent of small-pox cases have
                            received the pretended benefit of the cowpox. One of the leading statisticians in Europe,
                            Dr. G. F. Kolb, of Munich, member extraordinary of the Royal Statistical Commission of
                            Bavaria, says in a recent letter published in the London Echo. "In the Kingdom of Bavaria,
                            into which the cow-pox was introduced in 1807, and where for a long time no one except the
                            newly-born escaped vaccination, there were, in the epidemic of 1871, no less than 30,742
                            cases of small-pox, of whom 29,429 had been vaccinated, as is shown in the documents of the
                            State Department. When, with these stern proofs before us of the inability of vaccination to
                            protect, we reflect upon the undeniable and fearful mischief which the operator so often
                            inflicts upon his victims, the conclusion forces itself upon us that the State is not
                            entitled, either in justice or in reason, to put in force an enactment so directly
                            subversive of the great principle of personal right. In this matter, State compulsion is, in
                            my opinion, utterly unjustifiable." Dr. Farr, Mr. Edwin Chadwick, Dr. Southwood Smith. Dr.
                            B. W. Richardson and other well-known sanitarians, have clearly demonstrated that small-pox
                            is the outcome of filthy conditions, bad drainage, impure water and overcrowding, and can
                            only be avoided by the observance of .proper hygienic precautions. Prof. Playfair has said,
                            "that no epidemic can resist thorough cleanliness." The sooner these facts are appreciated
                            and acted upon the sooner will all zymotic diseases be abolished. That small-pox can be
                            prevented by vaccination is an untenable position, which has been abandoned by all <pb n="252" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 252 shaker manifesto. allowed, while no mention is made
                            of vaccination, as a,i favorable or modifying factor in the attacks, nor could there be,
                            seeing that this so-called prophylactic did not prevent sixteen of the cases becoming
                            confluent. The late Iioyal Commission of Inquiry into the origin of the dreadful epidemic in
                            Fiji has reported that they occurred among populations who were habitually drinking water
                            from ditches contaminated with sewage, and that the mortality has fallen "enormously since
                            the discovery of the cause. The existing small-pox epidemics at Nottingham and Leicester are
                            not amongst the unvaccinated. The cases are to be found among the vaccinated poor, and their
                            vaccinated children, and the local press contains letters of complaint of bad ventilation,
                            bad smells, foul pig-stys and sewage effluvia. How can vaccination protect against the
                            sewer, the pig-stys, the mews, the polluted water? Were it not trespassing too much upon
                            your space, it would be easy to furnish the evidence of eminent medical men, like Dr. Jules
                            Guerin of Paris, tending to^show that vaccination not only fails to prevent small-pox, but
                            in many cases actually excites it. Cow-pox matter is admitted by the profession to be
                            variolous in its origin; it ought therefore to be held in a certain degree responsible, in
                            company with noxious exhalations and sewage and bad ventilation, for the survival of
                            small-pox and similar diseases in civilized and hotly sanitary boarded communities. Permit
                            me to suggest, that having regard to the accumulation of evidence, showing the failures of
                            vaccination to prevent even the severest attacks of smallpox, or to prevent small-pox in the
                            best vaccinated cases, whether it would not be wise on the part of American Boards of Health
                            and European legislatures to abandon its compulsory enforcement and devote the large
                            expenditure, amounting in the aggregate to many millions per annum paid by the State for
                            public vaccination, to the more scientific and less objectionable prophylaxis of all zymotic
                            diseases—Sanitation I am, sir, your obedient, servant, William Tebb. 7 Albert Road, Regent's
                            Park, London, August 21st, 1S82. P. S.—Some of your readers will be terested to hear that
                            arrangements are now in progress for holding the third International Anti-Vaccination
                            Congress at Berlin in January nexi. It is expected that delegates will attend from all
                            countries where vaccination is enforced, either by municipal regulations or State laws. A
                            report of the proceedings at the Cologne Congress has been published in German, and [another
                            in the French language by Dr. Hubert Boens B Sc. Charleroi Belgium entitled "La Vaccine au
                            point de vue Ilistorique et Scientiftqve," in which the whole question is impartially
                            discussed with great lucidity and ability.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To-day and to-morrow" TEIform="index"/> TO-DAY AND TO-MORROW</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witham, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>MARIA WITHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">Don't tell me of tomorrow; Give me the one who'll say, If good can be effected
                            I'll do the deed today. We may command the present, Then act and never wait; llepentance is
                            the phantom That often comes too late. Don't tell me of tomorrow ! There's much to do today,
                            That never'll be accomplished If thrown the hours away. Each moment has its duty, Who can
                            the future tell? Then why defer till next day What this can do as well ? Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Generosity" TEIform="index"/> GENEROSITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catherine" TEIform="persName"/>Catherine Allen</byline><p TEIform="p">Why should we not always be kind and generous ? If through cold indifference, or
                            intended selfishness, we withhold from others that sympathy and love which is in our power
                            to bestow, and express in deed and word, or sometimes in little gifts of material things, we
                            may perhaps pass more hours of this fleeting existence in comparative ease; may have<pb n="253" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 253 more time for arranging little
                            articles of personal convenience and taste; and may accumulate for individual keeping, a few
                            more of the things that perish. But what can these avail the soul? At best we can only hold
                            them through our brief span of time, and all that we gain at the expense of another's
                            comfort, will become as a gnawing canker worm to consume the gift of peace that should
                            attend the hours of meditation. The soul is really impoverished by every effort of selfish
                            grasping, or keeping. Nothing can be of benefit to us beyond that which we can put to actual
                            use ; and just as surely is true wealth increased by every act of self-denial, especially of
                            Christian sympathy and mercy toward others. We cannot do anything through personal sacrifice
                            to promote another's weal, without at the same time enriching our own souls. Mt. Lebanon, N,
                            Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blessings" TEIform="index"/> BLESSINGS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sutton, Elizaette" TEIform="persName"/>Elizaette Sutton</byline><p TEIform="p">Count the blessings that surround us, And the mercies that we ¦ share, Are they
                            few, and numbered to us? Or as boundless as the air? As the dews are scattered to us, And
                            the sunbeams 'round us play, Bounties are unmeasured to us, By our Father day by day. And
                            the stars that stud the heavens, Are they numbered every one? Pearly drops from Crystal
                            fountains, Can we count them as they run? So are blessings showered on us, By our Father's
                            loving hand, Dropt along life's highway to us, Blessings free thro' out the land. Could we
                            always see our blessings, And the least one learn to prize, Consecrate them in our feelings,
                            Tho' they're often in disguise. Pleasures that are sweet and savory, Would along our path be
                            strewn, Brightly, beautifully, lovely, Worth and beauty would attune. What are all our
                            life's endeavors, If we know not wisdom's ways? Utilize Clod's gifts and favors; Dreaming
                            must not fill our days. Greet the morning and it's burdens With a thankful, cheerful heart,
                            Tho' the cloud is dark that saddens, 'Twill divide and from us part. Smile or frown, is at
                            our option, Gloom, or sunshine to impart, We can have a sweet affection, Or, a cold
                            forbidding heart. Which, the cup of life be filling? Which, be anchored in the soul? Let us
                            choose the greater blessing, Let true wisdom have control. For the blessings thus provided,
                            Earthly, moral, spiritual, Gratitude to God be rendered; For he doeth all things well. Wise
                            and merciful His nature, With a weight and balance true ; He will give to every creature,
                            All that justice claims as due. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If" TEIform="index"/>IF</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">IF. If all the pity and love untold Could scatter abroad in coins
                                    of gold, There would not be, on the whole round earth, One hungry heart, nor one
                                    wretched hearth. And oh, if the kind words never said Could bloom into flowers, and
                                    spread, and shed Their sweetness out on the common air, The breath of heaven would
                                    be everywhere.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian Union" TEIform="index"/>Christian Union</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A good word is an easy oblation ; but not to speak ill requires only our silence : which costs us nothing" TEIform="index"/>
                            A good word is an easy oblation ; but not to speak ill requires only our silence : which costs us nothing
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A good word is an'easy oblation ; but not to speak ill requires only our silence
                            : which costs us nothing.</p></div2><pb n="254" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publication" TEIform="index"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. Office of Publication</head><p TEIform="p">The "Shaker Manifesto" is published at Shaker Village, Mer. Co., N. H. All
                            business matters connected with the financial department of the paper will be directed fr
                            Rbe Publisher of Manifesto, Shaker Village, N. H. All other communications may be addressed,
                            Editor of Manifesto, Shaker Village, N. H. One Copy per. year, Postage paid, .60 six months,
                            " " .35 Enclose a two cent stamp for a specimen copy. To avoid mistakes, those who send
                            money, should write the name of their Post Office, County and State. TO ADVSXt.TISSB.S. One
                            inch, one insertion $ 1.00 " " three " each .75 " " six " '•' .65 " " twelve" " .50 " column
                            ¦ 6.00 Larger spaces, rates in same proportion.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/> NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jesus was our great teacher..." TEIform="index"/>Jesus was our great teacher...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Jesus was our great teacher, His lessons were full of instruction. He wasted
                                neither time nor words, nor neglected a proffered opportunity when he could impress the
                                minds of his disciples with a spiritual truth. They were able to foretell that the
                                harvest would be in the course of a few months, and to them it would be a special season
                                for the gathering of God's bounteous blessings. Jesus would inspire them with a deeper
                                thought having reference to the gathering of souls into the Kingdom of God. Lift up your
                                eyes, said he, and look on the fields for they are already white to harvest. While the
                                disciples, as natural men, were thinking only of the harvesting of the wheat fields of
                                Palestine, and of their well filled garners, Jesus changed the conversation to a
                                religious form and told them that the minds of men were now waiting to be enlightened
                                with the spirit of Truth and to be harvested into the work of regeneration. It now
                                became the duty of the laborers to stimulate themselves to enter upon their mission.
                                They were to be sent into the world to preach the gospel of good news and to take
                                therefrom those who heard the word of God and were able to keep it. Shall we not learn
                                wisdom from these life lessons which have been placed before us? Admitting that our
                                gospel has been vitalized by the spirit of the Living God, and that a testimony has gone
                                forth which has been as the waters of salvation to many thousands, yet, is there not
                                some danger of losing this precious gift while we are so very anxiously caring for the
                                things of this world ?</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="After an experience of some thirty four years..." TEIform="index"/>After an experience of some thirty four years...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">After an experience of some thirty four years in spiritual phenomena, many of
                                the leading minds of the order seem to think it quite as essential, even at this date,
                                to caution those who seek after the spirits, as it did in the commencement of that work.
                                We may very reasonably expect more or less of the false in our search for that which is
                                true, but the ability to discriminate, often makes us the dupes of a designing mind. In
                                the Religio of Aug. 12th, we have a scientific analysis of Spiritualism by W. E.
                                Coleman. He does not hesitate to <pb n="255" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                                255 write plainly and clearly his views on the phenomena which seemingly astonishes so
                                many persons at the present day. Although a believer in the instantaneous appearing and
                                disappearing of the inhabitants of the spirit world, and made this by "proof palpable"
                                from individual experience, he then says ;— "Probably nine tenths, or it may be ninety
                                nine hundredths of all so called materializations are fraudulent," and many that he had
                                witnessed were unmitigated frauds. It is highly commendable in the managers of the
                                Journal that" they do not fear to publish the whole truth, or to expose that which is
                                deceptive or absolutely false.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What a pity it is..." TEIform="index"/>What a pity it is...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">What a pity it is that those who love the Lord and are denominating
                                themselves the true light to a wicked world, should stop on their heavenward journey and
                                dispute over the fastenings of their Sunday go-to-meeting-coat or the acceptability, to
                                the Lord of an uncultured voice in preference to the tones of a good instrument. And yet
                                we are informed that such is the fact. One church is being divided because some of the
                                members choose to fasten their coats with buttons instead of hooks and eyes. And the
                                other church is becoming divided because a certain class forbid the use of an organ in
                                the time of religious service. It is surprising how much talk and confusion such
                                trifling nonessentials will create. "Behold how great a fire a little matter
                            kindleth."</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Synopsis of reports of the Shaker school for the three years, last past, as
                                forwarded by Br. Elijah Myrick. The Superintendents have made collective reports of the
                                general condition of the several schools, hence as a rule have omitted any remarks
                                except on the one in our Society. The following may serve as an index to the relative
                                merits of the school at Haivard. Winter session of 1880. Teacher, Ella Russell. Length
                                of term ten weeks. Wages of teacher $30 per month. Whole number of pupils, 11. Average
                                attendance 10,15. Tha teacher is thorough and keeps the. best of order, a d is always
                                ready to as.sistand instruct her pupils. This little school is worthy of a visit from
                                all interested in the education of our youth and children. Session op 1881. Mary Kelley,
                                Teacher. She has had the charge of the school during the year. Number of pupils, 12.
                                Average attendance, 11. Wages of Teacher, $30 per month. The Teacher has devoted herself
                                to her work with much earnestness, and has labored faithfully and successfully for the
                                advancement of her pupils. The closing exercises were highly interesting and most
                                creditable to teacher and pupil. The clear and distinct reading of the pupils in the
                                Shaker school is deserving of special mention. Report of 1882. Length of school, 6
                                months and 2 weeks. Number of pupils, 13. Average attendance, 13. Wages of the Teacher
                                $30 per month. Marj Kelley taught this school during the spring and summer te:ms. She
                                carries with her an earnestness and force of character that compels the respect and
                                attention of her pupils. Her success Iris been complete, bringing her school well up
                                towards the front ranks. <pb n="256" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 256 SHAKER MANIFESTO. The
                                Winter Term was taught by Marcia Bullard, a teacher of large experience.. Our committee
                                have not made special reports of each school, wishing to avoid invidious distinctions.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="While on our recent visit to the society..." TEIform="index"/>While on our recent visit to the society...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">While on our recent visit to the society at Harvard, Mass., we were
                                privileged, through the kindness of our beloved friends to spend a few hours in their
                                district school. There were present, Brother Elijah Myrick one of the school committee ;
                                a brother and two sisters from Enfield, N. H. ; a brother and two sisters from
                                Canterbury, N. H. ; th# Elders of the Church Family at Harvard, and several other
                                members of the society. The school numbered some fourteen pupils, who were all nicely
                                arranged in respective places when . we entered the room. The teacher, Mary Kelley,
                                conducted the exercises and they were managed with all the care and kindness of a good
                                shaker sister. The ready response of the pupils to the every Avish of the director, was
                                a clear manifestation of their affectionate regard, and to this we attribute much of the
                                success of the school. The house has been built some three score and ten years, and was
                                arranged for the accommodation of twenty-four pupils. The desks are ample and well
                                preserved, and were, no doubt, of excellent construction as well as of superior
                                accommodation at that early date. Each desk was arranged for the accommodation of two
                                pupils. The stationary board seats have, however, been removed, and a nice little chair
                                of modern manufacture and well adapted for the comfort and convenience of the pupil, now
                                takes its place. The room was well furnished. The teacher's desk was of an antiquated
                                pattern, bearing the same age of the house, yet it was quite convenient and liberally
                                supplied with books and whatever an active teacher might find necessary to use. The room
                                was furnished with a limited supply of black-boards, and, indeed it would be difficult
                                to provide too much space for this indispensible aid to both teacher and pupil. Several
                                mural maps were suspended, and also two or three, large steel engravings. The pupils
                                seemed to be abundantly supplied with books and with everything that was necessary for
                                their protection and education in the school room. The exercises began by the singing of
                                a select piece by the whole school. The recitations in reading from the book, as well as
                                from memory were very superior. Even the smallest pupils made their recitations so
                                clearly and so naturally that it became a pleasure to be a listener. The class in
                                Physiology, History and Mental Arithmetic seemed to understand the value of their
                                studies and rendered them accordingly. The system of spelling was novel and interesting.
                                The first word given out was distinctly pronounced by the pupil, after the teacher, and
                                then spelled. The pupil then spelled three or four more words without assistance from
                                the teacher. Each pupil in turn gave the respective definitions to their words, and then
                                thoroughly analyzed them, as their authors directed. The writing books and art books
                                were kept in nice order, and were a commendation to both teacher and pupil. The quiet
                                and yet potent influence which governed the school, and the gentle, good order of the
                                pupils was one of <pb n="257" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 251 the marked
                                and pleasant features. From the appreciative remarks of the several visitors at the
                                close of the exercises, we learned that all had enjoyed the season with much
                                satisfaction.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p"> Summer Term of 1882 commenced April 25th, and closed August 12th. Teacher,
                                FinettaB. Wells. Number of weeks 16. Number of pupils, 11. A good attendance was
                                continued throughout the season. Interest,and perseverance on the part of the teacher,
                                inspired the pupils with a love 'f application, requisite to the acquisition of each
                                lesson. Fifty nine visitors, who witnessed the exercises, reported a well disciplined
                                school, with a cheerful compliance of the pupils. Winter Term of 1881 and 1882. Taught
                                by Arthur Bruce. Number of pupils, 14. Length of term, 17 weeks. This school is strictly
                                private being entirely out of the jurisdiction of the School Committee, consequently we
                                have no Committee's report to offer. We endeavor to have the standard of the school as
                                high as that of any of the district schools in the town. From the opinions of the many
                                who visited the school last winter we inferred that the standard both in deportment and
                                scholarship was maintained.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whoever lives looking for pleasure only..." TEIform="index"/>Whoever lives looking for pleasure only...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Whoever lives looking for pleasure only, his senses
                                        uncontrolled immoderate in his enjoyments, idle and weak, the tempter will
                                        certainly overcome him, as the wind blows down a weak tree. Whoever lives
                                        without looking for pleasures, his senses well controlled, his enjoyments
                                        moderate, who is faithful and strong, the tempter will certainly not overcome
                                        him, any more than the wind overthrows a rocky mountain.</quote></cit><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Alpha" TEIform="index"/>—In the Alpha.</bibl></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Buddha" TEIform="persName"/>-----Buddha. </byline></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Visit to Boston" TEIform="index"/>VISIT TO BOSTON
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> I have pleasant memories of the friends I met in Boston, and
                                        the sights T there saw have left bright pictures on memory's wall. The last day
                                        of my stay I went through Prang's vast chromo factory. I had always a curiosity
                                        to know how it was possible to manufacture such lovely pictures at so cheap a
                                        rate. But I had never once dreamed of the work it took. When I went in and saw
                                        long rows of desks, and at each one seated an artist bent intently over a
                                        picture, faithfully copying line by line, dot by dot, each little stroke or
                                        speck, and saw the pictures transferred one by one to lithographic stones, and
                                        then printed on paper or card-board, shade by shade, color by color, a little
                                        more red, a little more yellow, a little more brown, till it passed through some
                                        twenty or thirty impressions, going from hand-rollers to powerpresses, from room
                                        to room, I then realized that even the tiniest chromo was a work of far more
                                        toil than a grand painting in oil colors. But the rapidity of the reproduction
                                        makes them cheap and plentiful, and I saw some as high as twenty-five dollars in
                                        price, and others only a cent or two in value. We saw one large room containing
                                        two or three hundred girls, all putting fringes on valentines, chromos, and
                                        holiday pictures, and counting, folding, and arranging them; and we saw the
                                        Christmas cards for the coming season in process of being made. One. large room
                                        way down in the cellar was called the "stone library." It was filled with
                                        shelves of lithographic stones, containing plates from which the pictures had
                                        been printed. These stones are all brought from Bavaria, and many of them cost
                                        twenty-five and fifty dollars apiece. We went in the engine room and saw the
                                        power that moves the great machinery of the factory, and the engineer touched
                                        one of the great belts and lighted a gas-jet with his finger, and also
                                        transmitted a spark to each of us from it, by touching the tip of his finger to
                                        ours.</quote></cit><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Truth Seeker" TEIform="index"/>in Truth Seeker</bibl></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Elmina" TEIform="persName"/>Elmina</byline></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There is no restraining men's tongues..." TEIform="index"/>There is no restraining men's tongues...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">There is no restraining men's tongues or pens when charged with a little
                                vanity.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Washington" TEIform="persName"/>— Washington</byline></div3><pb n="258" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>DEATHS</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sawyer, Prudence" TEIform="index"/>Prudence Sawyer
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Sawyer, Prudence" TEIform="persName"> Prudence Sawyer </persName>at North
                                Union, Ohio, Sept. 30. Age, 65 yrs. 4 mo. and 26 days.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Knowles, Betsey" TEIform="index"/>Betsey Knowles
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Knowles, Betsey" TEIform="persName">Betsey Knowles</persName>, at
                                Harvard, Mass. Oct. 4. Age, 80 yrs. She is one of the few who renounced the world and
                                gave her life and strength to the gospel cause without reserve. So pass our aged friends
                                away.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>JUVENILE</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wasp and the bee" TEIform="index"/> THE WASP AND THE BEE</head><p TEIform="p">A wasp met a bee that was just buzzing by, And he said, "Little cousin, can
                                you tell me why You are loved so much better by people than I? My back shines as bright
                                and as yellow as gold, And my shape is most elegant too, to behold : Yet nobody likes me
                                for that, I am told." "Ah cousin" the bee said ''tis all very true; But if I had half so
                                much mischief to do, Indeed, they would love me no better than you. Ycu have a fine
                                shape and a delicate wing, They own you are handsome; but there is one thing, They
                                cannot put up with, and that is your sting. My coat is quite homely and plain, as you
                                see, Yet nobody ever is angry with me, Because I'm a humble and innocent bee." From this
                                little story let people beware, Because, like the wasp, if ill natured they are They
                                will never be loved, if they're ever so fair.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Taylor, Jane" TEIform="persName"/>Jane Taylor</byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obedient child" TEIform="index"/> AN OBEDIENT CHILD</head><p TEIform="p"> No object is more pleasing than a meek and obedient child. It reflects honor
                                upon its parents for their wise management. It enjoys much ease and pleasure to the
                                utmost limit of what it is fit. It promises excellence and-usefulness, to be, when age
                                has matured the human understanding, a willing subject in all things to the government
                                of God. No object, on the contrary, is more shocking than a child under no management.
                                We pity orphans who have neither father nor mother to care for them. A child indulged is
                                more to be pitied; it has no parents; it has its own master—peevish, forward,
                                headstrong, blind, born to a double portion of trouble and sorrow above what fallen man
                                is- heir to; not only miserable itself, but worthless, and a plague to all who in future
                                will be connected with it. An honest boy.-—In a" country school a large class were
                                standing to spell. In the lesson there was a very hard word. I put the word to the
                                scholar at the head, and he missed it; I passed it to the next, and the next, and so on
                                through the whole class, till it came to the hut scholar—the smallest of the class— and
                                he spelled it right; at least, I understood him so, and he went to the head, above
                                seventeen boys and girls, all older than himself. I then turned round and wrote the word
                                on the blackboard, so that they might all see how it was spelled, and learn it better.
                                But no sooner had I written it than the little boy at the head cried out, "Oh, I didn't
                                say it so, Miss W------; I said e instead of i" and he went back to the foot, of his own
                                accord, quicker than he had gone to the head. Was not he an honest boy? I should always
                                have thought he spelled it right if he had not told me; but he was too honest to take
                                any credit that did not belong to him.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Forest's snake story" TEIform="index"/> FOREST'S SNAKE STORY</head><p TEIform="p">One day when I was coming up from the island, I saw a black snake. He was
                                coiled around a tree. I was bare footed. Two other boys were with me ; they had on
                                shoes, and each one had a hoe. When we -rere pretty near him, he began to run The other
                                boys were afraid to touch him with their hoes, so he went home in the wall of the
                                garden. I t )ld the boys that were with me, if I was not barefooted and if I had a hoe,
                                perhaps, I could have killed him, but as I did not have a&gt;~y shoes on I did not
                                kill him because I thought he might ooison me. When the snake went into the wall, I ran
                                home to tell the other boys. Now the garden is ploughed up and I have not seen the snake
                                since, but I suppose he is there now</p></div3></div2><pb n="259" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>LETTER BOX</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Children ;—Doubtless you have learned by..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Children ;—Doubtless you have learned by...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Enfield" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, Conn.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Children ;—Doubtless you have learned by pleasant and unpleasant
                                experiences, that happiness waits on no selfish demand, but it dwells in every heart
                                that, unmindful of its own ease and comfort seeks to comfort and bless others.
                                Selfishness is an enemy that should be fought relentlessly. Some persons expect a great
                                deal of attention and kindness from others, but think little about being kind in return.
                                Shall I tell you the secret of a happy life? Think mofe of others and what you can do
                                for them than of your own dear selves. A kind, self-denying person seldom fails to find
                                real happiness; but one who lives for self, regardless of the welfare of others is
                                miserable enough. Have you ever experienced anything of this? Be kind, be modest and
                                unassuming, be pure in heart,|be ready for any little service, give to others, as you
                                would that others should give to you, and sunshine and happiness will flow into your
                                spirits. Let selfishness form no part of your characters. To enjoy life yourselves is
                                not sufficient; selfish enjoyment is always incomplete. Brighten your lives by
                                lightening the loads of your over-laden companions. There is solace in an unselfish
                                thought and deed. "Good deeds are the stepping stones to heaven." Try the pleasant
                                self-denyingway, and see how delightful j^ou'll feel. Try it every day. It is good at
                                the beginning of the year, good throughout the year, good at its close. Life is made up
                                of small things ; therefore do the small things that spread gladness and joy along your
                                pathway, and my word for it, you will be happy. Be unselfish, be virtuous, having for
                                example, the Divine Model, Jesus Christ, who said, "Love thy neighbor as thyself." Your
                                brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/> Daniel Orcutt.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Editor;—I thought as you told me one day..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Editor;—I thought as you told me one day...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Shaker Village" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Village, N. H.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Editor;—I thought as you told me one day, that you liked pictures of
                                roses better than you did lillies, I would give you one, because I had a pretty rose, if
                                you will look at the top of this letter you will find one. One Friday afternoon there
                                was no school, so the little girls with Nellie, Bertha, Laura and Mary went out into the
                                woods to pick strawberries and checkerberries, we had a good little ride, and a good
                                little walk; while we were riding, we had a peppermint as large as three inches long and
                                three wide, it tasted very sweet, and I felt as if I could eat ten more. Nellie found a
                                little toad, she gave it to me and I carried it home. I gave all my checkerberries and
                                strawberries to sister J, she ate the checkerberries and gave me back the strawberries.
                                I will close. Your little girl</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="D., L." TEIform="persName"/>L. D.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>House-hold</head><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Taking grease out of carpets" TEIform="index"/>Taking grease out of carpets
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The following mixture is recommended for taking grease out of carpets : Aqua
                                ammonia two ounces soft water one quart, saltpetre one teaspoonful, shaving soap one
                                ounce, finely scraped. Mix well, shake and let it stand a few hours or days, before
                                using, to dissolve the soap. When used pour on enough to cover any grease or oil that
                                has been spilled, sponging and rubbing well and applying again if necessary; then wash
                                oft" with clear cold water. It is a good mixture to have in the house for many things;
                                is sure death to bedbugs if put in the crevices which they inhabit ; will remove paint
                                where oil was used in mixing it, and will not injure the finest fabrics.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Liquid glue" TEIform="index"/> Liquid glue</head><p TEIform="p">Dissolve the best glue in good cider vinegar. Or, pure glue, 1 lb; water, 2
                                pts. Dissolve in a covered vessel; cool and add gradually 7 oz. of acetic acid</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whitewash of cheap paint" TEIform="index"/> Whitewash or cheap paint</head><p TEIform="p">Four oz. lime10 lbs. whiting; 4 qts. skim-milk; 1 pt. soap suds. Color to
                                suit. Put the lime in a stone jar ; pour on hot water to slack the lime, and then add
                                milk enough to make it look like cream. Add the whiting and the remainder of the milk.
                                Then stir in the soapsuds and the coloring matter. If to be used without coloring, a
                                small teaspoonful of bluing will make it whiter. </p></div3><pb n="260" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To prevent the scent while cooking" TEIform="index"/> To prevent the
                                scent while cooking</head><p TEIform="p">Kitchen odors may be overcome by throwing ;i few pieces of charcoal into the
                                pots, kettles or pans, while cooking. Try it with cod-fish, ham or cabbage</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Never iron a calico-dress on the right side..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Never iron a calico-dress on the right side...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Never iron a calico-dress on the right side ; if ironed smoothly on the wrong
                                side there will be no danger of white spots and gloss, which gives a new dress "done up"
                                for the first time the appearance of a time-worn garment</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mending chinaware" TEIform="index"/> Mending Chinaware</head><p TEIform="p">A very ready and efficient means of mending broken chinaware is to take a
                                very thick solution of gum-arabic and stir into it as much plaster of paris as will
                                bring it to the proper consistency. Apply it with a brush to the edges of the fractured
                                parts and stick them together, holding them in place for a few moments until they
                                adhere. In a few days it will be impossible to break them in the same place</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Purify the house" TEIform="index"/> Purify the House</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Purify the House. A house which lias been unoccupied for even
                                        a week should never be moved into without kindling fires to burn day and night
                                        for several days, with doors and windows opened so as to allow all odors and
                                        gases to escape, and to dry all the walls and wood-work most thoroughly ;
                                        especially ought this to be done if beads of water are noticed on the plastering
                                        anywhere ; the least observant know that the rooms of a house have a damp,
                                        musty, heavy, dead atmosphere, even if shut up for a very few days in the finest
                                        weather</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Domestic journal" TEIform="index"/>Domestic Journal</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Composition tea" TEIform="index"/> Composition Tea</head><p TEIform="p"> This almost universal remedy of the Shakers, and which has been sought for
                                by so many thousands as a panacea for colds, coughs, lung irregularities and
                                inflammations, is now made public: Take two pounds of bayberry root bark, one pound of
                                the inner bark of hemlock, one pound of ginger, two ounces of cayenne pepper, all
                                reduced to a powder and sifted through a fine sieve. Mix well together. Dose : one
                                teaspoonful in half a teacup of hot water. Add milk and sugar to please the taste, and
                                drink as warm as consistent.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker fish and egg" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Fish and Egg</head><p TEIform="p"> In a common sauce-pan heat one pint of new milk, or thin cream" if you have
                                it, season with salt and let it simmer for a few minutes. Remove a small portion of this
                                gravy into another vessel and dissolve therein a small piece of butter. Into the
                                sauce-pan slice a layer of boiled potatoes, making the slices say three eighths of an
                                inch thick; to this add a little salt codfish, boiled and picked very fine, then a layer
                                of boiled eggs, each egg cut in four or five slices. Alternate with another layer of
                                potato, fish and egg, until the desired quantity is obtained. Now pour on the reserved
                                gravy and cover over for a few minutes, or until ready to place upon the table. When
                                dished up. place upon the top some of the sliced eggs. The eggs should be boiled six
                                minutes, and then immediately immersed in cold Avater. This prevents them from becoming
                                too hard, and also toughens the shell, thus rendering it more easily removed. For four
                                persons, about eight eggs and eight medium-sized potatoes are required. This quantity
                                will require, of salt fish, about three tablespoonfuls, when nicely prepared. This is
                                really a delectable dish, and very greatly esteemed</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Farm and Garden</head><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Work on the farm: seasonable hints" TEIform="index"/>WORK ON THE FARM.
                                SEASONABLE HINTS.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">WORK ON THE FARM. SEASONABLE HINTS. There is work that is
                                        important at this season which may be done when plowing cannot. The looking
                                        after the small repairs that are needed upon every farm, or upon every set of
                                        farm buildings before winter sets in. Very few of us can spare the time in the
                                        busy seasons to get hammer and nails or the other tools necessary every time we
                                        see some little place that is out of repair, and if we can take a few days now
                                        and do them thoroughly we may make up for some of our little neglects in the
                                        past times. A latch broken from a door; a gate off its hinges or nearly so ; a
                                        loose board upon the side of some building or along some fence ; a square of
                                        glass gone from some window; a broken bolt in the mowing machine ; a broken <pb n="261" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 261 strap in the harness ;
                                        these, and such things as these, are but trifles, and when first noticed we can
                                        let them go, "make them do" as they are until we are not in such a hurry; but we
                                        are too apt to continue to let them go until the trouble spreads and we cannot
                                        make them do any longer. Perhaps it would be better if we would attend to all
                                        such things when we first notice them ; but we do not so let us take a little
                                        time now to make up for past carelessness. Then we need to bank up our buildings
                                        to keep the frost but, unless they are so built as not to need it. Piggery,
                                        hennery and stables need it as much and perhaps more than dwelling-houses. Then
                                        let us see whether a double door here and double window there will not pay
                                        themselves by keeping out co'd weather. Extra fuel in the house, extra grain in
                                        the stables, piggery and poultry house, are certain to be needed to keep life
                                        and healthy, thrifty growth, in their inmates, if the temperature falls in the
                                        building as rapidly as it does out of doors in a December day. Let us,
                                        therefore, try to so arrange our buildings that they may be as we can
                                        conveniently make them, if we value the health and thrift of those who live in
                                        them. Another job now will be the covering of the strawberry beds with a light
                                        coating of mulch of some sort. Hoi'se manure, straw, corn stalks or pine limbs
                                        make about as good mulch as we can find for this purpose. I prefer the two
                                        latter, as being less likely to fill the land with weed seeds. The horse manure
                                        does not hurt the strawberries, I suppose, but I prefer to give the land a good
                                        dressing of it before the plants are set, and in the first season's hoeing I can
                                        nearly destroy the weeds that spring up from it, then mulch with that which will
                                        not supply more weed seeds and manure with a good artficial fertilizer, also
                                        free from seeds. Forest leaves are apt to pack too closely over the plants, for
                                        which reason I do not like them unless I have time to pack them in among and
                                        around a bed of young plants without covering the crown of the plants. Then put
                                        the limbs or corn-stalks upon them and they may be allowed to remain on the
                                        ground in the spring to enrich the ground. But around young trees there can be
                                        no better mulching than a good coat of forest leaves. If we would mulch our
                                        trees in the fall with a liberal coat of leaves, put on soon after the ground
                                        freezes, we should not lose so many of them from winter-killing, as they would
                                        make a much better growth the next season. There can scarcely be a better
                                        fertilizer for growing trees than would be found in the decaying leaves and the
                                        leaf mold of our hard wood forests. I have been pleased this fall to see many
                                        farmers gathering and drawing home leaves from the wood, as well as shaking up
                                        the accumulations under the shade trees around the house. Many have done so that
                                        I never knew to do such work before. Good advice and good example lias not been
                                        lost on them. I prophesy that their stock will winter better this winter than
                                        ever before, because of the comfortable beds they will have, and their crops
                                        will be better next year than usual, because of the manure they will make by
                                        using the leaves for bedding.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Tribune and farmer" TEIform="index"/>Tribune &amp;
                                    Farmer</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cabbages" TEIform="index"/> Cabbages</head><p TEIform="p">may be kept in a dry cellar by simply hanging them to the joists, stalk up.
                                The coarse leaves should be pressed close around the head.—Ex</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Guernsey cattle" TEIform="index"/> GUERNSEY CATTLE</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">GUERNSEY CATTLE. There has been a feeling widely prevalent
                                        that milk and beef were antagonistic qualities, that a g°od milch-cow would
                                        necessarily make poor beef. Tacts do not sustain this notion. Shorthorns are
                                        often great milkers, and such cows, when dry, fatten well. The Dutch cattle
                                        fatten well also, and so do the Devons, and yet both, especially the former, are
                                        famous for milk. The Guernseys have been bred for milk and butter, and at the
                                        same time for beef points. The yellow color in the skin and in the butter has
                                        also been cultivated, so that it is exhibited in an extraordinary degree. The
                                        cows average fully one fourth and possibly one third heavier than tke Jerseys,
                                        and give on an average a proportionately larger quantity of milk. After they
                                        have been longer tested, no doubt there will be found many cows which will
                                        compete closely with the famous Jerseys so well known as great milk and butter
                                        cows.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="American agriculturist" TEIform="index"/>American
                                    Agriculturist</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><pb n="262" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Homiletic monthly" TEIform="index"/>The Homiletic Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">With the October number, The Homiletic Monthly enters upon its VII volume.
                                The following are among the contents of this interesting number: Sermonic—"Retributive
                                Justice,' by Rev. Joseph S. Van Dyke; "TheEffects of Gospel Preaching," by Joseph
                                Parker, D. D.; "Gallio," by Samuel W. Duflield, D. D.; "Having One's Reward," by Canon
                                Liddon; "Opportunities of youth," by Rev. Henry Ward Beecher; "Healthy Religion," by T.
                                De Witt Talmage, D. D.; "Concealing the Words of God," by Rev. C. H. Spurgeon. Then we
                                have the following papers : "A Specimen of Welsh Preaching," by Rev. John Waugh;
                                "Methods of Sermonizing," by Rev. A. McElroy Wylie; "Hints to Young Preachers," by Prof.
                                James M. Hoppin, of Yale College; "Misq.-.oted Texts," by Talbot W. Chambers, D. D.
                                There are also many articles under "Sermonic Criticism," "Preachers Exchanging Views,"
                                etc., etc., full of interest to Preachers and Bible Students. Price, $2.50per year;
                                single number, 2b cents. Funk &amp; Wagnaixs, 10 and 12 Dey Street, New York.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="City and country" TEIform="index"/>City and Country
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> .—The October number of this valuable publication comes to our table filled
                                as ever with good things. As illustrations it has "Chock-full of Mischief "—a full page
                                plate, "A Festival in a Shanghai Tea Garden," "The Lan- * sing Evaporator," "City and
                                Country Homes," and "The Hansell Raspberry," "Honor's Debt" is concluded this issue and
                                a short serial, "A Strange Discovery," is commenced by Miss Josib C. Mal- ' ott. The
                                editorials cover every ground, and the one on "Politics in Ohio" is able and will be
                                largely quoted. "Articles on Farm Law" by Hon. Edmund H. Bennett still continues. This
                                valuable publication .should be a regular visitor at every fireside. Only 50 cents per
                                year with choice of two premiums. Will C. Tubneb, Editor. A. W. Lincoln, Associate. City
                                and Country Co., Publishei-s, Columbus, Ohio.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="History of the English people" TEIform="index"/>History of the English people
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Green" TEIform="persName"/>Green</byline><p TEIform="p"> THE BEST ENGLISH HISTORY. So
                                History of England, since the publication of Macaulay's famous work, has more promptly
                                and deservedly won the very highest reputation, than Green's "History of the English
                                People." Ranking fairly with Macaulay in the brilliancy and interest of its style, and
                                superior to it in its accurate delineation of events, it covers the entire field of
                                English history, from the earliest, to recent times, (and giving the history of the
                                people, rather than of the conflicts ot the kings ou,y,) while Macaulay's history is
                                limited to a very brief period. Green was first published in this country by the
                                Harpers, in four octavo volumes, for $10.00, but The Useful Knowledge Publishing Co.,
                                New York, have issued very handsome editions, at prices ranging from $1.00 for an octave
                                cloth-bound volume, to $2.50 for a five volume Elzevy half Russia edition. It ought
                                promptly to find a place in every home library, as, upon the whole, the best as well as
                                the cheapest history of England. For sale at the Manifesto Office.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>the Phrenological journal and science of health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological
                                Journal and Science of Health for October deserves special commendation, being more than
                                usually rich in matter connected with its particular sphere, and in general reading. A
                                full and appreciative sketch of Miss Clara Barton, the American Apostle of the "Red
                                Cross," is given, together with a very fine portrait. The series on "Comparative
                                Phrenology" is continued by a discussion of the structure of the human spinal column,
                                and the racial peculiarities of the Negro. A well-illustrated description of Alexandria.
                                A sketch of the great scientist Newton, and a very encouraging prophecy of what the
                                world will have attained a thousand years hence, are noteworthy. Besides, for
                                entertain-, ment and solid instruction the contribution entitled "Mrs. Bowman's
                                Neuralgia," "Beautiful HomtSi" "National Reverenei ," "The Pollution and Purification of
                                our Rivers and Harbors," a paper our legislators at Washington should have read before
                                passing the notorious bill which the President vetoed. "Kitchen Leaflets," sound advice
                                for our cooks, and the numerous notes, items, paragraphs, and responses of the
                                well-arranged departments are all worthy of more than passingcomment. Price only 20
                                cents; subscription price, $2.00 a year, with the last three months of this year free to
                                new subscribers. We note the publi-hers are making other special premium offers, and
                                that all may have a chance to see what the Phrenological Journal is like, now it is
                                offered "on trial" three months, including this October Number, for only 25 cents, which
                                may be sent in postage-stamps to the publishers, Fowler &amp; Wells, 753 Broadway,
                                New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>Herald or Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Herald or Health; Oct. Pub. by M. L. Holb book, 13 &amp; 15 Laight St., N.
                                Y. Contents. Malaria &amp; Malarial Diseases, Life Strength, Tape Worms, Bread, Milk
                                and Eggs, for the insane, Food for the Old, Cellars, Hygienic Progress, Food of
                                Japanese, Vegetable Butter, How Singei s should Live, Worrying the Girls, etc. etc.
                                Terms, $1.00 per. year. Single copy 10 cents. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Saint Louis magazine" TEIform="index"/>The St. Louis Magazine
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The St. Louis Magazine for September is a
                                splendid number containing 26 pages of illustrations, Stories, poems and timely reading.
                                A sample copy will be sent to any address for two 3 cent stamps. Address T. J- Gilinore,
                                213 N. Eighth Street, St. Louis, Mo.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Golden Rule" TEIform="index"/>THE GOLDEN RULE
                            </head><p TEIform="p">TIvY Best unsectarianReligious
                                Family Week____ ly; 8 pages, illustrated. On trial to Jan. ixilS it only 25 cts.
                                Address, Golden Rule, Boston, Mass.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If you would not have affliction visit you twice, listen at once to what it teaches" TEIform="index"/>
                            If you would not have affliction visit you twice, listen at once to what it teaches
                        </head><p TEIform="p">If you would not have affliction visit you twice, listen at once to what it
                            teaches.</p></div2><pb n="263" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Short rules for long comfort at home" TEIform="index"/> SHORT RULES FOR LONG
                            COMFORT AT HOME</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">SHORT RULES FOR LONG COMFORT AT HOME. Put self last. Be prompt at
                                    every meal. Take little annoyances out of the way. When any good happens to anyone,
                                    rejoice. When others are suffering, drop a word of sympathy. Tell of your own faults
                                    rather than those of others. A place for everything and everything in its place.
                                    Hide your own troubles, but watch to help others out of theirs. Take hold of the
                                    knob and shut every door behind you without slamming it. Never interrupt any
                                    conversation, but wait patiently your turn to speak. Look for beauty in everything
                                    and take a cheerful view of every event. Carefully clean the mud and snow from your
                                    boots before entering the house. If from any cause you feel irritable, try the
                                    harder to do little pleasant things. Do not keep your good manners for company, but
                                    be equally polite at home and abroad. When inclined to give an angiy answer, press
                                    your lips together and say the alphabet. Always speak politely and kindly of your
                                    help, if you would have them do the same to you. When pained by an unkind word or
                                    act, ask ourselves, "Have I not done as badly and desired forgiveness?"</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Canadian Presbyterian" TEIform="index"/>Canada Presbyterian</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Somewhere" TEIform="index"/> SOMEWHERE</head><p TEIform="p">Somewhere await the treasure we have strewn Which idle hands and feet have rudely
                            shattered; And tenderest love shall gather as its own The pearls thus scattered. Somewhere,
                            the doubtful seed that we have sown, Shall we disprove a cold uncertain rootage, And
                            vindicate the hope we now disown By fairest fruitage. Somewhere, our human effort of to-day,
                            The faltering outcome of a pure intention, Eternity shall hold as brave assay And true
                            ascension. 0, Universal Soul! The finite range Of earth and time may dwarf our high
                            endeavor, Yet life is victory, through the evolving change Of thy forever.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bristol, Augusta Cooper" TEIform="persName"/> Augusta Cooper
                        Bristol.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fretting" TEIform="index"/>FRETTING</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">FRETTING. Fretting won't pay. To the contrary, it is always
                                    practiced at a loss of time, strength and temper, ending in the greater loss of
                                    happiness. Fretters are much more apt to practice their pernicious habit because of
                                    small matters than great ones. Nay, imaginary troubles are quite as apt to be the
                                    subject of their disquietude as real ones. And so, if they have nothing real to stew
                                    themselves over, they will conjure up something wherewith to make themselves
                                    miserable. We have read an anecdote well calculated to show the folly of people
                                    fretting over their misfortunes. It told of a couple of gardeners, whose pea crops
                                    had failed because of the frost, or some other adverse influence. One of them went
                                    about amongst his neighbors fretting and insisting that he was "the most unlucky
                                    creature in existence." Sometime afterward, on visiting his unfortunate neighbor and
                                    getting a glimpse of his garden, he exclaimed: "What a fine crop of peas you have !
                                    How is this, that you have peas this year and I none? I thought your planting was
                                    all for naught, like my own !" "Precisely so," said the other. "Butwhile you were
                                    fretting I replanted my crop!" Fretting would not be so bad a habit were its
                                    consequences confined to the fretter. But they are not. Fretters are almost certain
                                    to make their families and friends and neighbors unhappy. And so they become social
                                    nuisances, calling loudly for abatement. Remember this, ye fretters, and fret no
                                    more !</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Granite free press" TEIform="index"/>Granite, Free Press.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="264" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our Captain's call" TEIform="index"/>OUR CAPTAIN'S CALL</head><p TEIform="p">Canterbury, N. H. 1. Forward, step forward, 2. Forward, step forward, 3. Forward,
                            step forward, Is our Captain's call: Gospel Zeal renew; Clad in armor bright; Upward, step
                            Upward, step Upward, step Fiercely the battie Who greater love can Grandly the prospect
                            rages, As the foe meets the cross: offer, Than to lay down his life, opens, 'Yon the turmoil
                            and the strife; Turn within For the win Peace and rightupward, Hold the ranks, let no one
                            fall, upward, Loyal hearts, with heav'n in view. upward, Bound for truth, attain the height.
                            the glorious weapon, And our gains ¦ arc more than loss, ning of the kingdom? Tis the
                            Christian's daily strife. righteousness abounding, Fruits of Eternal Life</p></div2>
                    <!-- <pb id="p29"/> <div2 type="section"> <head> <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head> <p>[Advertisements deleted.]<pb id="p30"/> <pb id="p31"/> <pb id="p32"/> </p> </div2> --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>