<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1010" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><date value="18801001" TEIform="date">October 1880</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">217-240</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> Vol. X. No. 10. OCTOBER, 1880. 60 Cents Per Annum. The Shaker MANIFESTO. G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, N. Y.
                        Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT SHAKERS, N. Y. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony:'* ''Go
                        preach the Kingdom of God!" ADDRESS ALL COMMUNICATIONS $> G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1880.</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="217" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Transplanting" TEIform="index"/>TRANSPLANTING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER</byline><p TEIform="p"> Behold the care for the transplanting Prom pots of earth to earthly sod! But what from
                            earthly life to growing Into the spirit of our God ? Who watches here the chills of evening
                            ? Who hides the scorching sun at noon ? None less than Saviours of Mt. Zion, And such the
                            need in Zion's home. First let us bear our earth transplanting, As household plants to
                            natural soil ; The atmosphere of every duty, Where man is placed to daily toil. If men and
                            women, then, who need shield us 1 Shall other hands of earth, as ours, Be left to earn the
                            bread to feed us, . And we make dormant equal powers ? Nay, heaven forbid. The call is
                            equal; Gome up and do each with his might, And earn the blessing of the faithful, The joy
                            and peace of doing right. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Relation of intellect and emotion" TEIform="index"/>RELATION OF INTELLECT AND EMOTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. HAMPTON</byline><p TEIform="p"> In looking around us and into the general structure of the universe, the most palpable and
                            obvious departments we can discover therein are the dual ones of male and female. The origin
                            of these may be traced to the no less palpable principles of wisdom and love, a duality
                            observable in all the dispensations of Divine Providence, and for aught we know to the
                            contrary, a duality constituting the Infinite mind itself. This matter of duality receives
                            amongst mankind the several names of positive and negative, active and passive, male and
                            female, love and wisdom, discreting all things into a constant duality without any
                            exception. Intellect and emotion in man are merely finite manifestations of the dual
                            principles of wisdom and love, transmuted to the sublime offices of reason and religion in
                            man. The first is necessary to develop, define, explain, to illustrate the character as well
                            as necessity of discipline, self-government, church government, organization, order and
                            regulations, necessary to the existence of a self-perpetuating community. The second is
                            necessary to the development of the religious sentiment, together with all the Pentecostal
                            gifts, inspirations, ministrations from the spirit world, proprieties, tongues, healings of
                            disease, together with all sympathy for human suffering, going out of one's self to do good
                            to others. Unless these principles of wisdom and love are equally and normally developed in
                            the individual, his or her efforts to attain to spiritual perfection must necessarily be
                            abortive. <pb n="218" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 218 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. An individual all intellect is a
                            monster who needs regenerating to ever become normal. One who is all emotion is in the same
                            degree abnormal, and needs reconstructing quite as well. The golden mean between these
                            extremes is a well-balanced mind, under the influence of a thoughtful, serene and
                            unostentatious wisdom, and at the same time so thoroughly imbued with love, good-will and
                            sympathy toward others as to develop a high standard of social benevolence to all and
                            without partiality. I often feel a solid concern, that I accordingly labor earnestly to
                            resolve in myself this happy normal medium, in order to become as useful and highly
                            beneficial to society as possible. Intellect relates to all matters within the domain of
                            reason. Emotion relates to all those indescribably grand and important matters within the
                            domain of religion and inspiration, often transcending the bounds of reason, but never
                            necessarily contradicting her suggestions. Intellect enables us to search into all truth
                            which can be discovered by logical research, experiment and analysis. Emotion presents to us
                            the beauty of holiness, the peace of righteousness, love to each other, sympathy and
                            tenderness toward the suffering, the glory and perfect splendor of purity, and often opens
                            up a vista of sublimity and glory far-reaching even into the serenest recesses of heaven
                            itself. And yet intellect and emotion are so perfectly correlated that one is in every way
                            and under all circumstances necessary to the other, in the highest and most harmonious
                            development of which humanity is capable. If one is so far overborne by the other that
                            spontaneity in the direction of either is forestalled or annihilated, the abnormal results
                            of mental and spiritual disaster and sorrow are sure to follow, and persistently continue
                            until the normal equilibrium is restored. I found in my earlier experiences great need to
                            strenuously watch and regulate these powers of intellect and emotion, and cultivate them
                            with regard to something like a consistent balance. I found my emotions sometimes so far in
                            the ascendant that I was in great danger of turning fool on my own hands and going into
                            ecstacies beyond all bounds of consistency or propriety. At other times my intellect would
                            become so positive and persistently concentrated upon some abstruse study or question, that
                            I could not relinquish my grasp of it even in times of religious worship. I remember once of
                            being so persistently beset with a problem in algebra that I could scarcely keep it out of
                            my mind for a moment, even while at religious worship. Hereupon I shut my algebra and did
                            not open it again for more than two years. By this means in similar cases I restored my
                            normal condition of mind and gradually disciplined myself into a condition equally x-emoved
                            from both intellectual and emotional extremes. We must be thoughtful upon this matter of
                            healthy development of mind, or we may have to regret having spent a useless life among the
                            Arctic icebergs of an intellectual North Pole, or in traversing an equatorial Sahara of
                            emotional enthusiasm, neither of which will confer much happiness upon the individual, and
                            still less blessing and benefit to the community. Union Village, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Why do not Shakers vote!" TEIform="index"/>"WHY DO NOT SHAKERS VOTE?"</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p"> [This question having been frequently asked, we requested Elder Evans to send us for
                            publication a concise and pertinent reply. Besides the philosophical reasons he gives below
                            we might happily add, that by refraining to exercise this franchise the societies have been
                            saved from an immense amount of worldly corruption and bitter, political, enduring
                            antagonisms. Simply as a promoter and protector of social peace our absence from engaging in
                            political partisanships and giving expressions thereof by our votes has well paid us.—Ed.]
                            For the same reason that they do not marry, nor fight, nor hold individual private property.
                            They are a church, not connected with any civil government; do not believe in church and
                            state union, not even with the American republic. As citizens <pb n="219" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 219 they are law-abiding, peaceable and loyal to the civil government,
                            which they regard as the best in existence. But even it is not perfect until their Shaker
                            sisters are equally citizens with themselves — until woman is not only a law-abiding but a
                            law-making factor. Our civil government was founed by philosophical free-thinkers,
                            rationalists — skeptics — of all classes, who had grown out of Christendom and were agreed
                            only in disintegrating her, and in declaring independence of theology and all forms of
                            ecclesiasticism. The Shaker order was founded cotemporaneously with the civil government, by
                            New Lights, religious Free-thinkers, Comeouters and Heretics, who had gone into Babylon and
                            were from thence delivered by the American revolution and the American civil government,
                            delivered from a mixture of church and state systems upon which rests the responsibility of
                            all the blood shed upon earth — systems drunk with the blood of the saints and martyrs of
                            Jesus, by holy inquisitions and unholy religious wars. Inasmuch as the Shakers live under a
                            civil government entirely separated from the church, so do they live in a church that
                            provides for soul and body, and is entirely separated from the civil government. Therefore
                            the Shakers do not vote.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beautiful vision" TEIform="index"/>A BEAUTIFUL VISION</head><p TEIform="p">[In a most beautifully-printed volume, entitled " Our Homes and Employments Hereafter,"
                            written by our friend J. M. Peebles, and published by Colby &amp; Rich, Boston, Mass.,
                            we find the following beautiful vision by our beautiful Sister Eunice Bathrick, and have
                            copied it for the interest of our readers. The book purports to tell us " what a hundred
                            spirits, good and evil, say of their dwelling places," and is well worthy the perusal of all
                            interested in the subject of the world to come.—Ed.] I am now in the sere of life, and as my
                            earthly career is drawing to a close, I rejoice to say that invisible agencies have
                            supported me all through these changing years up to the present time. I have felt the
                            companionship of spirits, as though they were tangible to the physical touch; I have seen
                            them as distinctly as I see things with my natural eyes. I have frequently conversed with
                            them audibly, and though I heard no external response, the answer, in some unexplainable
                            way, was intelligently echoed to my interior consciousness. I have been informed of and
                            prophesied of events before their occurrence, and have been turned from the course I was
                            pursuing, where dangers awaited me, by loving, ministering spirits. I have heard angelic
                            voices, have been patted upon the shoulder when in the room by myself; have listened to
                            heavy footsteps, so heavy as to seemingly jar the floor, the ground, and the forest through
                            which I was walking. Listening to the songs of angel hosts, I have committed them to
                            writing. Sitting quietly alone at twilight, I have sung under the inspiration of angels one
                            new song after another, till they numbered scores; and they were joined in aim and purpose
                            like intertwining links in a golden chain. It is impossible for me to find language to
                            describe the landscapes that I have seen in vision; their verdure, their velvety lawns,
                            their crystal streams and musical birds, almost overcame me with a joy and a love for God
                            and His creatures. On some of these green lawns were lofty trees, with delicate vines,
                            climbing over and clinging to the branches, bearing transparent fruit resembling clusters of
                            grapes. Walking on these lawns, among these groves, and in the alcoves, were children
                            dressed in white, with teachers instructing them. The pure and beautiful angels seemed to
                            have no fixed abode, but roamed at will through elysian fields, while the darker spirits
                            seemed confined to given localities; and the atmosphere in which they moved appeared to me
                            hazy and gloomy. There were no green fields, no fragrant flowers, and no dancing fountains
                            to cheer their desolate abode. These were shown to me for lessons of instruction. The places
                            where some good spirits wtere conducted after leaving their bodies appeared to me like the
                            outer court of a magnificent building, with architectural beauty surpassing all earthly
                            workmanship. Their walls <pb n="220" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 220 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. were festooned with
                            vines and flowers, and hung with paintings symbolizing sacred scenes in the Scriptures, and
                            the lives oJ good and pure men and women. At one time I saw in vision public worship among
                            the spirits. The building stood facing the south, with a sloping, undulating plane I should
                            judge a mile in length, at the extremity of which was a dense forest through which murmured
                            a winding" river, with banks fringed with delicate mosses. All of the surroundings tended to
                            promote contemplation and a prayerful mood of mind. The extensive and symmetrical build, ing
                            for worship was of pure white, and, as far as I could see, without the least ornament. It
                            was clearly constructed for worship, and not for the display of pride. I did not enter the
                            structure, but the two doors facing the south stood open as they had been left by the
                            assembled throng. Before approaching so near, and while standing in meditation, I saw the
                            brethren and sisters —¦ angels they were — go forth in the march and the dance. I saw them
                            pass the windows, arrayed in white, transparent robes, as they moved like seraphs to the
                            heavenly music. It seemed to me as though I was at the very gates of the city celestial, the
                            home of the new Jerusalem, and was about to join in the song of the hundred and forty-four
                            thousand. In that heavenly world — for I seemed to be there — I was pained when told by my
                            guardian angel that I must return again to the material world; and now I only desire to stay
                            upon earth that I may do good and help poor mortal souls to rise in the resurrection life,
                            where alone is found peace and true happiness.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manners, morals and personalities" TEIform="index"/>MANNERS, MORALS AND PERSONALITIES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER</byline><p TEIform="p"> Morals grow out of the facts that each individual has a distinct personality, and a sphere
                            of rights, as extensive and as well secured as those of any other personality. Morals are
                            the trunk of the tree; manners the branches, twigs and leaves, extending from and
                            overshadowing the trunk. Bad manners are evidence that there is a flaw in the morals.
                            Whatever is injurious to others is immorality. Whatever acts are disagreeable to the
                            feelings of others, or set aside the necessary little rules of life, are bad manners. Good
                            morals and manners are fulfilled when justice and kindliness prevail. A harsh tone of voice,
                            even in a just cause, is a moral disturbance. Social relationships are nicely balanced. Each
                            stands in his or her own personality, ever sensitive how they are approached. This is right;
                            and that there may be no rigidity, good manners allow in social intercourse a margin both
                            ample and elastic; yet it is well not to go beyond, nor to strain the tension. In the Ten
                            Commandments the Great Lawgiver took notice of the grosser forms of bad manners; the nicer
                            distinctions of moral conduct are summed up in good manners. ' Love of the neighbor is the
                            foundation of true politeness; to increase his or her happiness is angelic morality. The
                            politeness of the natural man or woman is but a thin veneer over a nature common to the
                            savage ; scratch deeply enough and the evidences thereof will be forthcoming. One of the
                            worst forms of bad manners is to live on the labor of others, and to rule over them with an
                            iron hand. Can devils do more than this ? Those who do so are very polite among themselves,
                            and very sensitive of any encroachment upon their sphere of personalities. One of the great
                            lessons of life — an every day one—is: "There are other personalities in existence besides
                            self, which have as good a right to exert their influence on us as we have on them." Those
                            of superior ability and who have power to comprehend others are not thereby entitled to
                            intrude upon others, but the contrary. Even the personalities of animals are recognized :
                            Thou shalt not muzzle the ox," etc. Again: " Six days he may labor, but on the seventh he
                            shall rest." Looking into the great book which creative wisdom and love have written, we
                            find four grand divisions of animated existence. The radiate comes first, seemingly a mere
                            elatinous disk floating with the current, <pb n="221" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 221
                            its personality almost expressionless, yet it lias an individuality. A step onward we come
                            to the mollusk. There we find the oyster and the clam; each has a house of its own, open and
                            shut their doors at will. Entering the order of articulates we find personalities of no mean
                            importance. It swarms with interesting beings. The bee and the ant are there ; teachers of
                            construe tion, of government, of social economy, of community of goods, of industry, of
                            colonization and of devotion to the public good. The most important human problems are
                            instinctively solved by these little creatures. As we enter the order of the vertebrates we
                            find, from the tiny fish of the mountain streamlet to the whales of the ocean, from the
                            humming bird to the eagle, from the unobtrusive mole to the stately yet unassuming elephant,
                            and from these to man, who connects with spiritual beings, who inspire him to good or ill,
                            just as he elects, all have a personality of their own. Even that of the perverse is
                            recognized : " Come let us reason together." Happy day when men and women shall so reason
                            and elect, intuitively decide to rise above the groveling emotions of their lower selfhoods,
                            and claim relationships with angelic personalities. Creative wisdom and love have
                            emphatically determined to stamp every sentient existence with a personality all its own ;
                            and the more elevated the being the more intensified is that personality. It is written:
                            "The invisible things of God are clearly seen and known by the things that are made, even
                            His eternal power and Godhead." Therefore, our Eternal Father and Mother are personalities
                            and the source of them. " Let us make man in the likeness of OUR own personality." Let us
                            hear what the wise men of our day have to say of the spiritual duality of man. Agassiz and
                            Sequard have no superiors in their specialities, and they state; " There is a double set of
                            mental powers in the human organism, or rather that act through the human organism; they are
                            essentially different from each other. The one may be designated our ordinary conscious
                            intelligence ; the other as a superior power associated with our better nature, suggests the
                            right thing at the right time, and solves sometimes suddenly and unexpectedly, even in
                            sleep, our perplexities and problems, acting through us without conscious action of our
                            own." Agassiz suggests that our daily habits, sensual or otherwise, may shut off or
                            facilitate the action of this superior power. Being servants to whatever emotion, fixed
                            thought or floating imagination we yield ourselves to, it will be well to unite only with
                            those that speak of heaven, and breathe of an atmosphere higher and holier than those do
                            which spring spontaneously from our lower selfhoods. We are intrusted with powers of a wider
                            range than is generally supposed; we can create for ourselves and others heaven or its
                            opposite. Also, we can create methods to intensify either. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Liberalism, spirtualism and Shakerism" TEIform="index"/>LIBERALISM, SPIRITUALISM AND
                            SHAKERISM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p"> Liberalism, what, is it ? Victor Hugo would say, Liberalism is Voltaire—is the French
                            Revolution. I might say, Liberalism is Thomas Paine and Victor Hugo, who says, at Voltaire's
                            centennial: " With Voltaire a new cycle begins. The 18th century proposes, the 19th brings
                            to pass. To-day war is indicted, force is violence. If to slay be a crime, to kill
                            multitudes cannot be an extenuating circumstance. The Inquisition was murder by the church,
                            war is murder by the State. Te Deums do not make a deed great, homicide is homicide,
                            bloodshed is bloodshed. In the sight of the Eternal God the character of murder is not
                            changed by putting on its head an emperor's crown." Constantine was great — a great
                            murderer, a fit representative of a Christianity when it (the sun) had become darkened, and
                            of the state (the moon) which had been married to the church, and was turned into blood —
                            into war. Voltaire, the infidel, confronted and confounded the monster — church and state —
                            as a second Jesus, the Prince of Peace; he said, Let us dishonor war. There is no bloody <pb n="222" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 222 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. glory, no, no, it is not well to make
                            corpses. " He that taketh the sword shall perish with the sword," said Jesus the first. "
                            Thou shalt not kill," said Moses. Let us ask counsel of him (Voltaire) whose life was useful
                            to man. It came to an end a hundred years ago. His work is immortal. As Spiritualists, let
                            us ask ourselves if those other mighty thinkers, auxiliaries of glorious Voltaire, Jean
                            Jaques, Diderot, Montesquieu, shall not speak —¦ utter forth— "Stop shedding human
                            blood—enough, priests and despots, enough ! " Let us proclaim the right of man to life, the
                            right of conscience to freedom, the sov ereignty of reason, the sacredness of labor, the
                            blessedness of peace, and inasmuch as darkness issues from the pulpits and thrones, let
                            light shine forth from the tombs — from the spirit world. The vision of John is a map — a
                            chart of the history of the church, from the first to the second appearing of Christ. The
                            primitive Christian church was peace and good will to humanity. The Mosaic law was
                            cooperation. The Pentecostal church was communism, the law was holy and good. It taught
                            abstract, absolute truth respecting physiology, health, property, the land and its products,
                            and also of woman, the relation of the sexes. In the wilderness for forty years, a whole
                            generation, they lived on manna, did not kill, did not eat corpses as food. As a consequence
                            it was declared, as a church dogma, " The Lord your God shall take all sickness away from
                            amongst you." The land was held in common. An article of church faith was, " The land is
                            mine, saith the Lord." The people held it only as tenants, and the most undone man or woman
                            in Judea held an inheritance in the Land of Promise. Another article of faith was the law of
                            nature that pervades all ranks of being, except man — commerce of the sexes for offspring
                            only—and no murders. Thus was the law glorious in those fundamental principles of human
                            existence. Yet, as compared with the Primitive church, it was no longer glorious, by reason
                            of the glory that excelleth in respect to all of these principles. The Last Supper — the
                            Sacrament, typical of the Lord's spiritual body, or church, when Christ should come the
                            second time, to restore spribual Israel, the true Israel, daily bread — shew bread—should be
                            the staff of life of the saints in the kingdom of heaven upon earth. In that kingdom,
                            instead of the God of the Jews —- a bloody God — should be the Christ spirit, making -peace
                            by removing all the causes of war, in the diet, in property and in the sexual relations of
                            the least in the kingdom of heaven, who would still be superior to John, the greatest born
                            of woman under the Mosaic law. As killing animals leads to murder, so does the possession of
                            land and its products, under the law, feed or keep alive selfhood. Therefore, Primitive
                            Christians sold their individuality, private possessions and had all things common, none
                            saying this is mine. Communism was the law of Christianity to preserve health ; a vegetarian
                            diet was a law. And inasmuch as the law of the sexes did not make the comer thereunto
                            perfect, but condemned as sinful the most perfect commerce of the sexes — perfected
                            generation — ceMbacy was proclaimed as the corner stone of the Temple of God in the new
                            creation. A virgin life, common property, peace and the sanctification of labor. He or she
                            who will not work, neither shall he or she eat, and he or she who would be great among you
                            let him or her be your servant. But now the question arises, what have we had under the name
                            of the Christian church for the last 1800 years 1 For an answer let us look to our chart.
                            Turning back to that we see very plainly a spurious article, labeled Christianity, has been
                            foisted upon mankind, just as the Spirit saw and predicted. Rev. 17, verses 1 to 7, as
                            follows: " 1. And there came one of the seven angels which had the seven vials, and talked
                            with me, saying unto me, Come hither ; I will shew unto thee the judgment of the great whore
                            that sitteth upon many waters; " 2. With whom the kings of the earth have committed
                            fornication, and the inhabitants of the earth have been made drunk with the wine of her
                            fornication. " 3. So he carried me away in the spirit into the wilderness; and I saw a woman
                            sit upon a scarlet coloured beast, full of names <pb n="223" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 223 of blasphemy, having seven heads and ten horns. "4. And the woman was arrayed
                            in purple and scarlet colour, and decked with gold and precious stones and pearls, having a
                            golden cup in her hand full of abominations and filthiness of her fornication : " 5. And
                            upon her forehead was a name written mystery ' Babylon the Great' and mother of harlots and
                            abominations of the earth. " 6. And I saw the woman drunken with the blood of the saints,
                            and with the blood of the martyrs of Jesus; and when I saw her I wondered with great
                            admiration. " 7. And the angel said unto me, Wherefore didst thou marvel ? I will tell thee
                            the mystery of the woman, and of the beast that carrieth her, which hath the seven heads and
                            ten horns." If we assume the truth of the vision, are we not compelled to accept just one
                            conclusion, to wit, Christendom is Babylon ? Is not mystery stamped upon all the orthodox
                            creeds? Do they not, one and all, demand belief by authority, not as the result of evidence
                            ? Is not reason blasphemed and tabooed? Faith — blind aquiescence—expected of all? And when
                            the Beast '• was" — when it possessed the civil power — the whore was drunk with the blood
                            of saints and martyrs — reformers, philosophers and rationalists. The Crusaders cost
                            5,000,000 lives — seven distinct expeditions. Lecky says the transubstantiation controversy
                            cost 300,000 or 400,000, the image controversy 50,000, the St. Bartholomew massacre 40,000,
                            Charles 5th 50,000, the Spauisli inquisition 50,000. As Baxter says, Blood, blood, blood, on
                            every page of church history (verse 16). '' The ten hoi*ns which thou sawest upon the beast,
                            these hate the whore, and shall make her desolate and naked, and shall eat her flesh and
                            burn her with fire, for God hath put it into their hearts to fulfill His will and to agree
                            and give their power unto the beasts." Voltaire and his companions, Thomas Paine and
                            Jacques, Jefferson and his followers, produced the American Revolution, severing church and
                            state, being the fruit of the French revolution. Is there any question that the French
                            infidels — horns — hated the Babylon church and state system ? Or that it was the French
                            revolution, in which Thomas Paine was mixed up, that began to break up the kingdom of the
                            beast with seven heads, Catholicism, the Greek church, Calvinism, Lutheranism,
                            Episcopalianism, Methodism, Presbyterianism and the kingdom of the image of the beast,
                            Protestantism? Voltaire caused the torture of witnesses to be abolished in France. Monarchy
                            was overthrown by the revolution, never to recover its former power. Then came the American
                            revolution—independence. Republican principles began to grow, being engrafted in the
                            American Constitution. Already, in the separation of church and state, much progress has
                            been made. Primogeniture has been discontinued. Slavery is abolished. Public lands are given
                            away. Homesteads can be made inalienable, and soon women will be made citizens. This will
                            prepare the way for the beating of swords into ploughshares and spears into pruning hooks,
                            for the abolition of all national wars, and a more perfect separation of church and state
                            than now exists. Ann Lee and her companions founded, by the spirit, the new heavens—a new
                            spiritual order. Voltaire, Thomas Paine and fellow infidels founded, by the spirit, the new
                            earth — a new natural order, wherein shall dwell righteousness. This is the rela tion
                            between liberalism, spiritualism and American Shakerism. The kingdoms of this world will
                            become true republics, and Shaker societies will hold in check the principle of population.
                            MYSTERY WRITTEN ON HER FOREHEAD. The Trinity is a mystery. How we could have a Father and
                            Son where there was no Mother in the family. The omniscience, omnipotence and omnipresence
                            of God are mysteries. Foreknowledge, foreordination and decrees of predestination are grand
                            mysteries. Edwards' theology is a mystery. The justice of God, compelling Him to be an
                            unrelenting tyrant, and to kill His own Son to <pb n="224" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 224 THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. satisfy His infinite sense of right, is infinite nonsense. The physical
                            resurrection is a mystery that cannot be solved by any thing but thou slialt believe.
                            Damning people because you cannot convince them is a very mysterious dispensation. Christian
                            warfare is a mystery to all who read the sayings of Jesus with their unclouded reason in
                            operation. The Inquisition is a mystery beyond human comprehension. Te Deums and Auto de fes
                            are more suggestive of hell than of heaven. In the late expulsion of the Jesuits, when M.
                            Clement was about to affix the red seal of the police on the door of the Jesuit temple,
                            FatherPitau said: " If you do that you will incur the penalty of major excommuni cation.
                            God, in the sacred host, is lying upon the altar. Perversity could not surely be pushed to
                            the extremity of making His Divine Majesty (God) a prisoner ! " When the official did his
                            duty a wail of sorrow and impotent anger went up from deputies, senators, ex-ministers of
                            the empire and the Duke de Broglie. Said one : " Fie upon you, you are about to imprison our
                            God."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sure to win" TEIform="index"/>SURE TO WIN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL ORCUTT</byline><p TEIform="p"> The true crossbearer is sure to win in this life of ours. If you regard the rights of others
                            as well as your own; if you are modest and unassuming; if you are virtuous and truthful, you
                            are sure to win, while others, with equal abilities, may fail. This is where " the race is
                            not to the swift nor the battle to the strong ;" this is what society is socking for, and it
                            is astonishing how much people may win, who possess these qualities. The holy Savior won his
                            bright crown only by personal exertion. Oh ! how worthy of imitation ! "' What has been done
                            can be done again." Only those who battle for the right, the true and the pure, " wear the
                            Christian's crown." A pure life is the greatest victory on earth. " Be wise in time that you
                            may be happy in eternity." Start right, and the battle is half won. A constant warfare and
                            the victory is yqurs. Do not despair at slow progress ; little by little great things have
                            come to pass. Life, and great things are made up of little things, and little things often
                            lead to great results. " Despise not the day of small things." This earth is made up of
                            little particles. The great ocean is composed of little drops of water. " The sunshine of
                            life is made of little beams, that are bright all the time." The little bees, how much honey
                            they gather! Be not discouraged because you are little. A little star shining brightly in a
                            dark night may be the means of saving many a poor sailor from shipwreck ; and little people
                            may do much good if they will try. There is nothing like trying. "Iwill try " has worked
                            wonders. Bear in mind the maxim," where there's a will there's a way." Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Has Jesus any followers?" TEIform="index"/>HAS JESUS ANY FOLLOWERS?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eads, Hervy L." TEIform="persName"/>HERVY L. EADS</byline><p TEIform="p">[reply to jamieson.] " " BY This question is asked with a flourish of trumpets, by one
                            Jamieson, in his closing1 critique of the character and sayings of Jesus Christ. The
                            announcement that the end has come will doubtless give relief to some. I have concluded,
                            however, not to let the matter die without answering his important question that heads this
                            article. I now respond in the affirmative, with as much emphasis as he has in the negative.
                            Fjvery man or woman who takes Jesus Christ for an exemplar-lives His life— brings him or
                            herself into the conditions He prescribes, as far as he or she is able — is emphatically an
                            adherent and follower of Christ. It is, however, thought by our critic to be impossible to
                            follow him and obey His teachings in consequence of their absurd and contradictory"
                            character, and wrong to do so in consequence of their immoral tendency. Besides, he says, "
                            no man can represent all truth, " and he wants the universe for ^his fountain from which to
                            draw his portion. Novv,-he who best repre- <pb n="225" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 225
                            sents the attributes of Deity best represents truth; for God is truth. This, Christ did
                            better than all the universe beside, so far as we have knowledge, which His own biography,
                            if true, fully substantiates. The spiritual truth of the universe may be said to have been
                            focalized in Him; while truths pertaining to mere matter were more or less ignored. In
                            ascertaining that His teachings were absurd and immoral, it would, at least, have been
                            commendable in the asserter to have added this clause: " If I am able to comprehend and
                            understand them." This much modesty would have revealed a deeper vein of thought than is
                            otherwise exhibited in his productions, and would have shown a due respect to minds equal to
                            his own, that might chance to differ from him. To my mind, his articles all show a great
                            want of ability to comprehend the true meaning of the texts and sayings quoted by him. "What
                            seems to him a "perfect muddle," is to others, of equal learning and culture, a harmonious
                            and consistent whole. If I am able to understand our critic, I find many of his assertions
                            without foundation, and some I think, untrue. The assertion that " but few of Christ's
                            teachings were of importance, and these few came from the heathen," he must have known to be
                            groundless, unless he has had access to heathen productions not accessible to the common
                            public. Besides, of the few that are found in heathen works can he be quite sure that they
                            were not interpolations by interested parties from Christ ? Assertion is one thing, proof is
                            another. It seems presumptuous to assert that Christ has no followers, because the critic
                            thinks it impossible. I profess to be one of the followers of Christ, as I understand Him,
                            but not as Jamieson does. It is not his prerogative to dispute my claim until he shall have
                            proven my understanding to be wrong and his right; and this he might find a task not easily
                            performed. "The natural man," says Paul, " receiveth not the things of the spirit of God,
                            for they are foolishness to him ; neither can he know them because they are spiritually
                            discerned." — (1 Cor., chap. 2, 5, 14.) Our critic seems to be of the class here referred
                            to, as he is able to see little else than foolishness in Christ's teachings. He will pardon
                            our classifying him. But in regard to the contradictory character of Jesus' teachings, I
                            fear not to affirm that by comparison and a rational exegesis the contradictory features
                            will mostly, if not all, disappear. Allow me to take one of his most prominent examples, and
                            one of the most difficult to reconcile. Christ teaches us to love all, hate none, honor
                            parents, to do good for evil, even to bless our persecutors and love our enemies. It is
                            thought His commanding or making it a condition of discipleship, and consequent happiness,
                            that the husband and wife, and partial relations, must not only be forsaken but hated, is
                            contravening the direct command t« love all; and hence our critic avers, if we take one
                            position, it is impossible to take the other. I must be excused for taking a different view.
                            That they do not antagonize, and that they are all in support of the pure, sweet, loving and
                            unselfish life which the blessed man taught and practiced during His earthly pilgrimage, I
                            shall proceed to show. It is well known that Christ was a Celibate, Spiritualist and
                            Communist, possessing a heart overflowing with the milk of human kindness, charity and love
                            for humanity ; and who taught that whatever antagonized with these should be hated and
                            forsaken. Now, selfhood and selfish property must exist in the pro-creative and generative
                            world, all of which are at variance with the equal spiritual communism of Christ, and
                            consequently must be forsaken in coming into the Christlife. The husband and wife who may
                            desire to come into Christ's spiritual community would at once perceive that the relation of
                            husband and wife, private property and generation were incompatible with the Christ-life
                            conditions, and must be forsaken. The woman could not very consistently say to her husband :
                            " 1 love you, William ; but the husband of it I despise — that is what has brought on ' all
                            our woes;' and now if you will permit me to hate the husband and allow me to remain your
                            sister in Christ, I will love and respect the brother better and more than ever I did the
                            husband." The husband could consistently <pb n="226" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 226 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            say the same to the wife, and love the sister while hating the wife. Hence it is clear that
                            the wife and husband may be hated, according to the command of Christ, while all mankind are
                            loved. Thus this stumbling paradox is found to be no contradiction at all; and thus it is
                            with all our critic has set before us. He complains, and says Christ " commands us to
                            cultivate poverty in order- to secure bliss," and adds, " let him keep his bliss." I will
                            certainly be enlightened if he will point out a single instance in the history of the world
                            where riches have produced bliss. Riches and bliss are incompatible with each other. I would
                            almost go as far as a certain great telacher who said: " Every rich man is either himself
                            dishonest or the son of dishonest parents;" and dishonesty and bliss cannot occupy the same
                            berth. Solomon's experiment might satisfy any one on this point. He says: " I made me great
                            works, buildedme houses, planted vineyards, made pools of water, got me servants and maidens
                            and greater possessions than all that were before me. Whatsoever mine eyes desired I kept
                            not from them. I withheld not my heart from any joy, etc., and behold all was vanity and
                            vexation of spirit." All men naturally would do the same if they could, and find the same
                            result. Thus we see that there is nothing in riches to satisfy the spirit. Natural riches
                            can satisfy in some measure the natural desires of the animal body ; but it takes spiritual
                            riches to satisfy the immortal or spiritual man and woman. Our critic, after placing Christ
                            below the heathen, tells what He (Christ) would have done had He been equal with some of
                            them. He says if Christ had been sensible, He would not have requested others to follow Him,
                            but, instead, would simply have enjoined on all— " Be thyself." He consoles himself however
                            "thus :" " There is none to do Jesus honor, none whose common sense will permit him to keep
                            His sayings. No one believes on Jesus! None follow Him ! " Now, I would just here beg him to
                            make one or two exceptions, if he pleases. We will admit that we do not follow Him as friend
                            Jamieson understands Him; but we do follow Him as we understand Him. Hence, I here confront
                            him by asserting that there are still some to " do Jesus honor," " whose common sense
                            permits them to keep His sayings," " who believe on Him and follow Him." So, right here, we
                            and our critic are at swords' points. If he sustains himself in the position assumed, he
                            must show that we are not Christ's followers by putting his finger on facts. But before I
                            close, at the risk of being thought invidious, I would beg leave to institute a short
                            comparison between the wisdom of what Christ did and the wisdom of doing what our critic
                            says He should have done. Christ's doctrine carried out in His life, was to love and do good
                            to all ; boundless in forgiving charity unto death, from the prostitute to the thief on the
                            cross. Such love hath no man ever had, and such a life was never before exhibited. But now
                            for the application of our critic's wisdom — " Be thyself ;" Gambler be thyself; drunkard,
                            be thyself; thief, be thyself; master, be thyself; slave, be thyself ; whoremonger, be
                            thyself; prostitute, be thyself — don't listen to Jesus' advice." go and sin no more;"
                            ravisher, be thyself; ravished,be thyself — don't cry, because lie was being himself. Thus
                            we see what a world J. would have — passion let loose with no restraining influence— who
                            would wish to be a denizen thereof ? His doctrine, carried out, would make a world of devils
                            incarnate, instead of saints. But Jesus, the " Blessed Jesus," has followers.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pretissiana: history and prophecy, without hyperbole" TEIform="index"/>PRENTISSIANA:
                            HISTORY AND PROPHECY, WITHOUT HYPERBOLE</head><p TEIform="p">"Fall." — Prostitution of man's most sacred prerogative to gratification purposes. " First
                            Resurrection." — One man and one woman coming together, in pursuance of congeniality's
                            unerring law, making the heaven-appointed use — nothing beyond — of their reproductive
                            powers, imbuing the dear little ones with the affectional and the religious. These are the
                            "New Earth." ' Second Resurrection" — Of the children <pb n="227" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 227 of the new earth, begotten, brought forth and nurtured above common
                            humanity's plane, some will aspire to the purity of the " angels of God in heaven " — will
                            preserve their virginity unmarred. Such are the "New Heavens" — "first fruits unto God and
                            the Lamb." Now, as never before, are minds of the better classes reaching forth, some to the
                            new earth, some for the new heavens. In the Fine Arts Academy in Buffalo, N. Y., "The
                            Captive Soul," a fair damsel in a halo of glory, is reaching up to higer planes of being, an
                            iron clasp around her left wrist is chained to the cragged rock, and holds her in bondage.
                            Could I change places with that fair damsel, I'd burst that rock in flinders.</p></div2><div2 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Relation of food to morals" TEIform="index"/>RELATION OF FOOD TO MORALS</head><p TEIform="p">[We make some telling extracts from a discourse of the Rev. J. F. Clymer. We only wish we
                            could publish the whole discourse.—Ed.] * * * Disobedience to law brings penalties. There is
                            nothing that men need to see more in their efforts at reform than the connection between
                            their sufferings and their disobedience. * * * Science and Revelation both declare that our
                            physical life is in the blood. The physical, mental, and moral natures are so intimately
                            connected that that which affects one affects the others. So that a man's mental and moral
                            nature, as well as his physical, can very largely be determined by his blood. Now, it is a
                            physiological fact that our blood is made out of the food we eat. That which enters the
                            mouth makes blood. By the mysterious processes of digestion and assimilation, our food is
                            transformed into blood ; and the blood passing through the veins and arteries repairs the
                            waste tissues and forms new ones, thus building up our bodies and sustaining life. It
                            follows, then, that our bodies are made of the food we eat. Evidently, then, it was the
                            design of our Creator that the prime object of eating should be the building up of tissues,
                            muscles, bones, and brains. That this may be a pleasure to us, he has associated with eating
                            the delights of appetite. But most of us have so far perverted tho divine order as to make
                            the pleasures of appetite the chief object of eating. " Give us something good to eat," is
                            the great cry of humanity, and the goodness of food is gauged by the sensations of the
                            palate and not by the law of nutrition. Most of us determine the goodness of our food by the
                            amount of sensual delight it gives us between the mouth and the chest; no matter how much
                            damage it may do beyond to the delicate and intricate structure of the stomach and viscera.
                            Hence a vast amount of food enters the mouth that makes bad blood, blood that in itself is
                            corrupt, and carries poisonous particles to every organ in the system, and putting us in
                            splendid condition to be easily provoked to some outbursts of anger, passion, or revenge. My
                            hearers, there is a sure and vital connection between bad blood and bad morals. Blood always
                            tells in morals as well as in muscles. Blood has power throughout the whole realm of life,
                            whether it be in a human body, in society, or in the body of a horse on a race-course. You
                            ask, what kind of food makes bad blood ? I answer, very much of the flesh of animals that
                            forms the staple diet of most of us. Sty-fed pigs and stall-fed oxen are fattened under the
                            most unlawful and unhealthf ul conditions possible; shut up in the dark, cut off from
                            exercise, the fat deposited on their bodies is made up of the waste matter that the life
                            forces of the animal have been unable to expel. This waste fatty matter is useless,
                            unnourishing, and poisonous. Even in the living animal it sometimes becomes so effete, that
                            is, lifeless, that it breeds vermin, such as has been found in pork, which cannot be
                            destroyed by ordinary cooking or by the process of digestion, and hence live and generate in
                            the human body, producing disease and death. * * * The use of large quantities of animal
                            food as a staple article of diet makes the blood gross, coarse, and corrupt, filling the
                            flesh of the body with scrofulous elements, sending poison to every part of the system,
                            causing it to break out in running sores, <pb n="228" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 228 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            saltrheum, tetter, and the like, producing an inordinate appetite, throwing every organ of
                            the body into fractional relations to every other organ. It is a matter of everyday surprise
                            to me that any human being will consent to eat the flesh of pigs. Consider their
                            uncleanness, their selfish, greedy habits, the vast amount of corruption that enters into
                            their bodies, and think when you eat pork all this train of horrid elements enters into your
                            body. And your body thus detoned by a low order of animal flesh, it can have no other effect
                            than to make you take on the disposition and tendencies of the hog. God's bill of fare, in
                            the 11th chapter of Leviticus, excluded from the tables of the Jews the hog, and all water
                            animals except those that had fins and scales. This bill of fare was given to the Jews, not
                            only for the preservation of their health, but as God's great purpose was moral reform, he
                            had an eye single to their moral condition in the matter of their eating. Does any one doubt
                            that the unhealthy, ugly, and vicious elements that make up the flesh of most of the animals
                            we eat, enter our blood, and in that way affect the disposition or carriage of the soul? I
                            am confident if there were less demand for animal food, the quality would be very much
                            better. Animals would not be subject to false and unhealthy generation and false and hasty
                            methods of growth. They would come up more in keeping with the laws of their nature, and
                            come to us with more health and better qualities. As for the hog, if man would not
                            domesticate him, he could not propagate his species. He would become extinct, just like the
                            lion, leopard, and hyena under the march of civilization. As the blessings of civilized life
                            come on us, you notice the carnivorous or flesh-eating animals become extinct. So it seems
                            to me, that with the developments of civilization, there ought to be such moral refine.
                            ments in human beings that they would grow away from their carnivorous tendencies and eat
                            such food as tends to develop the mental and moral faculties, and not the animal
                            propensities. Among animals you find that those that live on the flesh of other animals are
                            the most vicious and destructive, such as the lion, leopard, and hyena. Those animals that
                            live on the grains and the higher order of foods, are the best and most useful, such as the
                            horse and cow If this law obtains among animals, why not among men ? If you want proof of
                            this, study the character and lives of those who live largely on animal food, and you will
                            find them very animal-like in all their relations—¦ restive, impatient, passionate, ugly in
                            their ways, fiery in their disposition, easily provoked, readily put out of humor. And if
                            you could look into their private lives, you would find all their baser qualities having the
                            fullest sway, stopping," it may be, inside the fence of human laws and customs, but seldom
                            considering the claims of a higher and divine law. I charge, then, very many of our
                            household miseries, domestic woes, and connubial wretchedness to unrestrained lusts,
                            begotten in the body by the inordinate use of animal food. We forget, my hearers, that the
                            great law of nature, "Like produces like," is universal. " Every seed after its kind " is
                            the law of all creation. Monkeys and men are not exceptions to this law, notwithstanding
                            Darwin to the contrary. This principle obtains not only in the production of life, but in
                            the processes of its development. If the position about the intimacy of soul and body is
                            true, then, if a man's body is made up chiefly of flesh taken from diseased and stall-fed
                            cows, and his whole physical frame is saturated with the irritating and exciting condiments
                            of what is popularly called good food, the whole bias of his bodily powers will be toward
                            animalism. All the impressions and impulses that the soul receives from such a body are
                            beastly and debasing. Like produces like in the formation of physical tissue out of food, as
                            well as in the generation of stock in the stall. Hence I hold that very much of the
                            wickedness of mankind is the natural expression of physical beastliness, rather than the
                            outflow of innate viciousness. A body made up largely of all manner of nerve-goading,
                            passion-producing, anger-generating elements, such as are found in the gross animal dishes,
                            with their belongings, just as surely drives the soul to sin as a tempest drives a feather
                            before it. <pb n="229" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 229 The kind of food a man eats and
                            the time and manner of his eating it are not merely a question of medicine, but one of the
                            first questions of morals. The effects of food on the passions and feelings are thus
                            described by Prior : " Observe the various operations Of food and drink in several
                            nationsWas ever Tartar fierce and cruel Upon the strength of water gruel? But who shall
                            stand his rage and force When first he rides, then eats his horse ? Salads and eggs and
                            lighter fare Tune the Italian spark's guitar ; And if I take Don Confrere right, Pudding and
                            beef make Britons fight." If, therefore, our meet has something to do with our morals, or if
                            our food in some way affects our faith, it seems to me that many of our efforts at moral
                            reform ought to be preceded by instruction in hygiene. In other words, efforts to make a man
                            genuinely devotional ought to be prefaced by efforts to correct bad dietetic habits. A
                            father, by prayer and precept and flogging, had done his best to reform his boy, whose
                            staple diet was meat and sausage, pie and cake, at his meals, with lunch between. The family
                            physician said to the father, "If you will put a leech back of each of your boy's ears once
                            a week for a month, you will do more to reform him than your preaching and pounding will do
                            in a year." This father asked for the philosophy of this prescription. " Why," said the
                            doctor, " your boy has bad blood and too much of it; he must behave badly or he would
                            burst." «' Then," said the father, " I'll change his diet from beef and pie to hominy and
                            milk." In three months thereafter a better boy for his age could not be found in the
                            neighborhood. In your use of animal food be very particular as to quality and quantity. Lamb
                            and mutton are considered the most healthy by the authorities. Avoid, as you would
                            contagion, the use of pork, unless you raise and feed it yourselves with good grain, and not
                            the refuse of the house or barn, and keep the animals as clean as you do your pet dogs.
                            Never fry your meats with hog's lard, but stew, bake, boil, or broil them. Use hog's lard in
                            no form of cooking. Most of it is reeking with scrofulous elements. Displace it in all your
                            cooking by milk or butter. If you want aid, and not hinder the growth of your soul Godward,
                            and you desire to have pure thoughts and a pure heart and a pure life, see that you make
                            your blood out of pure food, or you will find that your soul will have an enemy within the
                            castle of its body more treacherous and deadly than any of its enemies without. There is
                            another popular article of food which has a vital connection with bodily disorders and bad
                            exhibition of character. Good in proper quantities and in its sphere, when made in the
                            largest and chief articles of diet for every meal, the one kind of food upon which we depend
                            most for building up the waste of our bodies, thus used it indirectly does no great damage.
                            I refer to the ordinary fine-flour bread made out of bolted wheat-meal. The process of
                            bolting or refining takes from the wheat most of the phosphates and nitrates, the elements
                            that are chiefly required for making nerves, muscles, bones, and brains. The phosphates and
                            nitrates being removed by bolting, very little remains in the flour except the carbonates,
                            the heat and fat-producing elements. The use of fine-flour bread as a staple article of food
                            introduces too much heat and fat-producing elements into the system, and where there is too
                            much carbon or heating element, it tends rather to provoke the system to unnatural and
                            abnormal action, and instead of serving as an element to warm the body, its tendency is to
                            burn or consume, heating and irritating all the organs, getting one into that state which is
                            popularly known as " hotblooded." One reason why children fed chiefly on white bread feel
                            hungry nearly all the time, and demand so much food between meals, is found in the fact that
                            their bodies are insufficiently nourished. Their bones and nerves not receiving the nitrates
                            and phosphates they need, are suffering from hunger. When children are fed with food that
                            thoroughly nourishes their whole system, they will seldom desire to eat between meals, and
                            thus retard the process of digestion, laying the foundation for dyspepsia and all its
                            kindred evils. <pb n="230" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 230 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Flour made of white wheat,
                            unbolted, popularly known as Graham flour, contains all the elements necessary for the
                            nourishment of the body. Not every flour called Gra ham flour contains these elements. There
                            is a great deal of bogus stuff in the market, which has brought the genuine article into
                            disrepute, and made many thoughtful people disgusted with every thing in that line. * * * I
                            am confident that the American habit of eating sumptuous and late suppers, whether at our
                            homes or church fairs or festivals, is damaging the physical, mental, and moral health of
                            our nation more than any other one thing of its kind; more damaging because it has the
                            appearance of innocency, and the sanction of our fathers, mothers, and some of our pastors.
                            Furthermore, the habit of eating hurriedly or hastily is preying upon the vital and moral
                            forces of many of us. A meal eaten hastily or nervously, under the pressure of intense
                            mental activity or nervous tension or great weariness, begins its work of nutrition under
                            the greatest possible disadvantage. All our meals should be eaten calmly and deliberately,
                            so as to thoroughly masticate the food, and not impose on the stomach and viscera the
                            legitimate work of the teeth, In the interest of health to soul as well as body, I enter an
                            earnest plea for more time in eating, and especially at noon when most hard-working people
                            take their principal meal. Clerks, business men, and school-teachers, mechanics, laborers,
                            and our children who attend the public schools, need more time at noon to properly dispose
                            of the chief meal of the day. No better investment could be made to secure the best possible
                            physical, intellectual, financial, and moral returns than for all classes of people to take
                            two hours at midday for resting and eating dinner. Selfish greed demands otherwise and makes
                            a show of gain, but the loss is sure to come in due time to all parties concerned. My
                            friends, when will we fastliving, fast-eating, fast-working, and fastdying Americans learn
                            the great lesson that life is a unit ; that the trinity in us, namely, the physical,
                            intellectual, and spiritual, is one life, with different phases of expression, and whatever
                            mars one mars the whole, and whatever builds up one most surely builds up the others ? All
                            our* powers are many members in one body, with an inter-dependence which is eternal. Slight
                            your body, and you smite your soul and enervate the mind. Corrupt the mind, and you detone
                            the body and debase the soul. When will those who profess to be God's children, by the
                            adoption of the Holy Ghost, catch the spirit of his great apostle Paul, who, more than any
                            other sacred writer, maintained the sanctity of the human body, and its subservience to the
                            mind and soul. Hear him : " I beseech you, brethren, by the mercies of God, that ye present
                            your bodies a living sacrifice, holy acceptable unto God, which is your reasonable service,
                            and be not conformed to this world, but be ye transformed by the renewing of your minds,
                            that ye may prove what is that good and acceptable and perfect will of God." I admit the
                            power of the Holy Ghost in the work of regeneration, but is there not something for us to do
                            in keeping our bodies under, "lest we become castaways ? " I do not say, mark it, that all
                            human evils and ills have their primary origin in physical habits, but I do say that the
                            great mass of impulsions from our bodies toward our souls are in the interest of sin. The
                            economy of salvation orders otherwise. By the gospel the body may become the temple of the
                            Holy Ghost. By the law of self-denial, of the New Testament, our bodies with all their fiery
                            elements may be made an inspiration to our souls. * * *</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Poor heathen convert came to ask the missionary" TEIform="index"/>Poor heathen convert came to ask the missionary
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A poor heathen convert came to ask the missionary if he could procure a Bible. " I have not a
                            new one that I can give you," said the missionary; " I have a second-hand one, but it is
                            old." " Oh ! that is nothing ! If the book is old, the word is new."</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Give entertainment to pious thoughts..." TEIform="index"/>Give entertainment to pious thoughts...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Give entertainment to pious thoughts, and hear what they say. Holy thoughts are precious
                            things, and if not angels, they are God's messengers, and in that sense angels sent from
                            God. They come from God and they tend to God.</p></div2><pb n="231" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Letter from Wm. Fishbough" TEIform="index"/>LETTER FROM WM. FISHBOUGH</head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Brooklyn, August 13, 1880" TEIform="index"/>Brooklyn, Aug. 13,1880.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Elder H. L. Eads : Dear Friend — I acknowledge, with thanks, the receipt of your book, "
                                Shaker Theology," which you were so kind as to send me, accompanied with your letter of
                                August 6. Your expression of sympathy with my views as expressed in the article in the
                                R. P. Journal, gives me strength and encouragement. I feel that there is beginning to be
                                a necessity of more union and cooperation between those spiritualists who believe in God
                                and revere Christ and his re ligion. Yet there is one thing for which I am thankful — it
                                is that since the advent of " seducing spirits and doctrines of devils " must come, it
                                comes, with all its force, in these earlier years of the spiritual manifes. tations ;
                                and when it exhausts its direful power, as it will at no distant day, we shall be rid of
                                it forever. There is no element in infidel spiritualism that can give it permanence,
                                though for a time, its specious appeals to the unworthy and selfish propensities of the
                                animal man may lead many astray, and to their own destruction. Meanwhile let us labor
                                and pray, and feel assured that the truth will prevail as surely as God lives. This is
                                about the only thought that has consoled me during these many — many weary years of my
                                life. I have not yet had time to read your book, but I see by its attractive table of
                                contents that I shall read it with pleasure and profit. Again thanking you, I subscribe
                                myself truly and fraternally yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fishbough, William" TEIform="persName"/>Wm. Fishbough</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="E. L. Eads: Dear Friend — Your very valuable and kind gift was received..." TEIform="index"/>E. L. Eads: Dear Friend — Your very valuable and kind gift was received...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Lockport, July 11, 1880" TEIform="index"/>Lockport, July 11, 1880</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Friend — Your very valuable and kind gift was received yesterday. It is not
                                necessary for me to assure you that I shall prize highly for the material evidence it
                                pre sents of your generosity and appreciation of my work, and what is still better, its
                                demonstration of your broad spirit of genuine catholicity and pure religiousness. It is
                                a source of untold satisfaction to know that there are so large a constituency of true
                                minds that wish to see the largest measure of truth and liberty to prevail ; minds that
                                are conscious that liberty violates no truth, and that all truth leads the soul to
                                understand in what liberty consists. Your three aphorisms in your " Harmony of Truth "
                                are a clear, concise statement of a principle running through every department of our
                                natures, and it were folly to con. tradict a statement so self-evident. The simple
                                recognition of this law would make the way clear to a ready comprehension of the ''
                                unity in divinity" and the spirit of indwelling agreement in seeming contrarieties. It
                                is sometimes painful to me to perceive the lack of true charity on the part of those who
                                claim to have reached the solid ground of mental and spiritual liberty. " By their
                                fruits ye shall know them." All of us reflect the measure of our culture and
                                understanding, and whatever else may succeed or fail, a true life is the measure of the
                                possessor's conception of justice and duty. There is no liberty outside of truth, there
                                is no evil outside of error. There can be no clearer definition than the one you give.
                                Obedience to organic law is freedom from pain and bodily sickness. Obedience to the
                                mental and spiritual give us peace of mind and lofty conceptions regarding our moral and
                                spiritual possibilities. These take us out of the realm of petty self-hood, where our
                                desires and aspirations seek the true liberty of all that is human. Stephen Pearl
                                Andrews, years ago,wrote quite extensively regarding the harmony existing in the
                                principles of the various sciences, and said they were but parts or segments of that
                                which included all, and which he defined as the " Unitary Science." The principle was
                                undeniably true, and the failure of the school of specialists to fully appreciate it,
                                make themselves dogmatic in defense of their pet theories. The material school make too
                                much ado over the purely physical, and fail to perceive the true import of the spiritual
                                forces <pb n="232" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 232 THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. of the universe, and especially
                                so, as these forces exist in human nature. We are little without them. The refining,
                                inspiring, and sustaining elements, that are more spiritual than mental, are the potent
                                factors that make us objects of love and respect, and I think the purely materialistic
                                has nothing to offer that can possibly give us hope and courage to build up that liberty
                                and truth for which the world is famishing. The religious elements, like the
                                imponderable forces of nature, will and must manifest themselves, and thus, or
                                therefore, many of those who condemn religion in name, most beautifully illustrate it in
                                practice, while many that are most anxious to exhibit their fealty to it, as well as
                                love for its defense, are the poorest possible imitators of its principles. Your society
                                has done a noble work in the true and pure direction. You have proven the benefits of
                                co-operative association. The possibilities of religious devotion to principle, without
                                a spirit of narrowness to those with whom you differ. Your record as regards the absence
                                of crime, and the perpetuation of virtue, harmony and prosperity is a constant testimony
                                in your favor, and a standing rebuke to popular Christianity, the present forms of human
                                government, and the present injustice of the race to one another. Yours in love,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lynn, George" TEIform="persName"/>George Lynn</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Geo. A. Lomas: Dear Editor. — For some reason unassignable by me, the music..." TEIform="index"/>Geo. A. Lomas: Dear Editor. — For some reason unassignable by me, the music...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Enfield, September 6, 1880" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.,
                                September Qth, 1880</dateline><p TEIform="p">Geo. A. Lomas: Dear Editor. — For some reason unassignable by me, the music in the last
                                issue of the "Manifesto" is defective in its transcription. The four upper staves
                                containing the simple melody or solo — all of which should have been single—are coupled
                                by two braces, which would greatly bewilder both reader and player, though they might
                                puzzle it out. Would you deem it of enough importance to insert an explanatory remark
                                upon the point in the next issue ? If so, by so doing you would greatly oblige your
                                friend and brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>James G. Russell</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Man approved of God" TEIform="index"/>A MAN APPROVED OF GOD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">"." In this age of fearless reason and brilliant intelligence, we dare to descend to
                                learn of the manliness of Him whom we love to call Jesus, Lord and Master. Eeverent
                                theologies carry us so high above the relations of our humanity with that of the
                                beautiful Jesus that they strike the twig so bent —the mind so elevated to grow—with a
                                sense of sacrilege to think of Jesus, not as a God, but as a most manly man. To think of
                                Jesus as a God, there is but little derivation of a possible, practical good; but to
                                know of Jesus as our fellow in childhood and manhood, as one who, though our High
                                Priest, " could be touched," and was made to experience all our human infirmities,
                                temptations and frailties, whom " it behooved not to take upon Him the nature of
                                angels." but simply our same humanity, herein have we the lever to resurrect ourselves
                                as men and women to what we know Jesus to have been and what Jesus is. Tempted and tried
                                in all points as we are, how did Jesus pass the ordeals of the tempted and prove Himself
                                after the trials ? In our trials and temptations by passion and worldly tendency, we
                                learn of the same in Jesus, for He was " tempted in all points, even as we are," and do
                                we succeed as manly as did Jesus ? The excuses we make, and that are made for us by
                                those who would excuse and smpathize as Jesus would not, are ever expressive of an
                                unmanliness not found in the man approved of God. <pb n="233" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEK
                                MANIFESTO. 233 Viewing Jesus as a God instead of a godly man set for our example, we
                                plead that the inequalities of positions prevent the possibilities of similar examples
                                by us. But knowing Jesus as '• a man/' tempted and tried like ourselves, is evidence of
                                the possibility and probability of our being '"approved of God" even as Jesus was. To
                                love Jesus, a most lovable man, and to so love Him as to be ardently anxious to be and
                                to live just like Him, is expressive of a love of God, of goodness, never determined by
                                an idolatrous worship of Jesus as a God. Jesus was a man, at one with God, when acting
                                as God taught Him to live; and we can only be at one with Jesus, having "the Father in
                                us" when acting in life as Jesus taught His disciples should live. Do any doubts arise
                                as to how the man Jesus lived ? None. The little children are easily taught to
                                comprehend His purity, peace, unworldly and heavenly character, and what a pity it is
                                that this childlike simplicity of knowledge of the true essence of Christian life should
                                ever be interrupted and displaced by humanly worldly creeds and false theological
                                dogmas! As was the man, Jesus, "approved of God," so must we be approved as His
                                disciples or followers—by His good works and miracles which we believed He accomplished.
                                Truly it would be acts most approved of God for us to follow, to live just like that
                                goodly, godly man. Truly it would be a miracle to transform our worldly selves into men
                                and women as unworldly as was Jesus. Let us reflect. And now, men and brethren, and
                                particularly the preaching class, let us arraign ourselves before the bar of reason, and
                                as men and women, having the man Jesus set up for our Christian pattern, count ourselves
                                unworthy of the Christian name unless we renounce all worldliness which Jesus renounced
                                " as a man to be approved of God." Let us count ourselves as unworthy of the profession
                                of His fellowship as a man, and know how radically wrong it is for us to preach in His
                                name until and unless the radical characteristics of His goodness as a man shall shine
                                out brilliantly in our chastened, self-denying characters. Jesus was a pure, virgin
                                celibate man. Whosoever is able to receive the saying—the testimony of His
                                example—follow Jesus. Jesus was an unresisting peacemaker, yet a man ! We can be thus
                                like Jesus in our manliness and womanliness. The questions to be determined are, will we
                                be manly and Godly as He was in peace and nonresistance, and are we His Christian
                                followers in this ? Jesus ivas a most unselfish man, never as a Christian holding any
                                thing as His own, selfish property. All that He had or might have had as a selfish man
                                He gave to the poor. In all respects Jesus tvas an unworldly man. Until we can copy
                                these radical, characteristic adornments of Jesus into our lives we cannot be His
                                followers nor receive the approval of God as He did, nor be worthy of the Godly love
                                which these characteristics invariably and forever impart. </p></div3><pb n="234" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our number for October" TEIform="index"/>OUR NUMBER FOR OCTOBER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Will be found brim full of beautiful contributions. Once more will be found the familiar
                                pens of Elders Evans and Eads — two valued veterans of the cause The Manifesto would
                                represent. The " Correspondence," although not directed to this office, is absorbed by
                                us for the benefit of our readers, and will be relished, especially that from the noble
                                Fishbough, the foster father of the inimitable A. J. Davis. The thoughts given us by the
                                sages Fraser and Hampton are well worth reading and remembering, and the vision of
                                Mother Eunice is very truthful and instructive. We challenge the genii of music to
                                present a more beautiful "gate" than the " golden " one we sing this month to our
                                listeners. We ask kindly charity for our personal, editorial briefness this month. Our
                                duties in this line are simply labors of love — our pastime, not employment — and our
                                time has been limited this month by the pressure of other duties. And yet we long since
                                determined there should be no issue of The Manifesto but would contain a digest at
                                least, of our faith and principles, which even the casual reader might " read as he runs
                                " just what many dear friends would know of Shaker life and principles.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Food and religion" TEIform="index"/>FOOD AND RELIGION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Our reverend friend J. F. Clymer continues in the good work of stirring up sensible
                                people to the consideration of vital topics. In the September number of the American
                                Phrenological Journal may be found a most wholesome sermon by him upon the kind of
                                religion our food incites. The theory has long been accepted that the dyspeptic has a
                                most gloomy way of looking at religious devotions, and the terrors of an impossible hell
                                have been most graphically described by those who have made grave-yards of their
                                stomachs by the consumption of murdered, animal innocents. We have much to learn yet,
                                and to practice, physiologically, before we can boast of much real spiritual perfection.
                                We would like to see this sermon and another by the same talented writer — " Who Killed
                                Chief Morris? " — sent broadcast the world over, the first as a lesson upon Christian
                                diet, the second as a most terrible arraignment of the rum-seller. We copy some
                                important extracts from the A. P. Journal.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Another bright light trimmed" TEIform="index"/>ANOTHER BRIGHT LIGHT TRIMMED</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">A beautiful instance of conscientious harmony, or an attempt at it, is illustrated by a
                                Rev. Milne, of Brooklyn, N. Y., who, unable to believe in the monstrous Trinity
                                doctrine, and the unreasonable, untruthful Atonement theory, resigns his pastorate
                                rather than preach such lies. This Congregational minister, we are only sorry to say, is
                                an exception in honesty among a large class of teachers called divines, who are
                                preaching for hire what they cannot believe in reason and which they know cannot be
                                true. For these reasons we look upon the clergy who practice such hypocrisy as did
                                Thomas Paine, as any thing but the servants of God or lovers of their fellow men. When
                                the clergy will only teach what God, through the light of their reasoning <pb n="235" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 235 powers, gives them to say, ungoverned and
                                unbiased by the theological tactics taught and demanded by theological schools and their
                                text-books, then, and not till then, shall we be relieved of the curse of " blind
                                leaders."</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Visit to the Shakers" TEIform="index"/>VISIT TO THE SHAKERS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hale, Albert" TEIform="persName"/>Albert Hale</byline><p TEIform="p">[ visits the Cleveland, 0., Shakers, and thus writes to a local paper his extreme
                                pleasure:] * * * * Left the hack two miles this side of East Cleveland, and walked one
                                mile south, which brought us to one of the Shaker villages, where we spent a week very
                                pleasantly. The opinion we formed of these people last winter was more than confirmed.
                                On further acquaintance we are prepared to say, in the words of Horace Grreeley, in his
                                notes on the Shakers: " With the Shakers, so nick-named, 1 have some personal
                                acquaintance, and I am not ashamed to own that I have been instructed and cheered by
                                them. They have never been fairly appreciated by the world." And further, says this
                                illustrious individual, " Are our relation as men and women so universally pure and
                                exalted that we may rightly despise those who, unable to separate the palpable evil from
                                the latent good, reject both together ? Is exclusive property so beneficent a feature in
                                our social order, as practically exemplified around us, that we may fairly stigmatize
                                those who, not needing its incitements to thrift or industry, see fit to decline them?
                                Mr. Greeley adds: " The peculiarities of Shaker worship I really abandon to the ridicule
                                of the caviler, only wishing that theirs were the only absurdities committed in
                                attempting to honor our Father in Heaven, and that no religious errors more popular and
                                enduring than theirs were worse than simply ridiculous. When I stood among the quiet
                                homes of this unaspiring, unpoetical people, and marked how they have steadily and
                                surely advanced from abject poverty to amplest competence; when I have observed how
                                their patient but never-excessive toil has transformed rugged barrenness into smiling
                                fertility and beauty, how could I refrain from thinking lightly of that dogmatism which
                                asserts the impossibility of inducing men to labor except for their own selfish
                                gratification ? " Further comment in praise of this singular and honest people is
                                unnecessary. I would only add, that during my sojourn among them I received the greatest
                                kindness and most generous hospitality I ever received at the hands of any of my
                                fellows, and I would further state, in reference to the female part of the society, that
                                I can truly say, in their deportment they are indeed models of Christian women, and
                                carry out to the letter the injunction of Peter, 3d chap., 3d and 4th verses. Since we
                                made them a visit last winter the angel of death has visited them, and removed four of
                                their members to the unseen world. Oliver Dewey died while we were there, and was buried
                                Sunday. We attended and witnessed the obsequies. Like every thing they do, the funeral
                                obsequies were conducted in an unimposing way, simply carrying out the example recorded
                                Acts 8th, 2d. After the grave was filled the sisters and children covered the mound with
                                floral wreaths and flowers. * * *</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I like to help people" TEIform="index"/>I LIKE TO HELP PEOPLE</head><p TEIform="p">A woman was walking along the street one windy day, when the rain began to come down. She
                                had an umbrella, but her hands were full of parcels, and it was difficult for her to
                                raise it in that wind. "Let me, ma'am ; let me, please," said a bright-faced boy, taking
                                the umbrella in his hands. The astonished woman looked on with satisfaction, while he
                                managed to raise the rather obstinate umbrella. Then, taking out one of those ever-handy
                                strings which boys carry, he tied all the parcels strongly in one bundle, and politely
                                handed it back to her. " Thank you very much," she said. " You are very polite to do so
                                much for a stranger." " Oh, it is no trouble, ma'am," he said, with a smile; " I like to
                                help people." <pb n="236" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 236 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Both went their way with
                                a happy feeling in the heart, for such little deeds of kindness are like fragrant roses
                                blossoming along the path of life. We all have our chances day by day, and shall one day
                                be asked how we have improved them. Almost any one likes to be helped in any difficulty.
                                Are we all as fond of helping others over the hard places ? If we take the golden rule
                                for our guide we shall not only make a great many people glad they have ever known us,
                                but we shall ourselves be glad in heart.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Foolish bee" TEIform="index"/>THE FOOLISH BEE</head><p TEIform="p">The Brethren's Advocate has this to say about . Last week we spoke in praise of the
                                little bee, commending its good sense and industrious habits, but like people who may
                                have many good qualities and yet have one weak point, the bee has its failings, too. Of
                                course not everbody does wrong in the same way, neither do all bees do as foolishly as
                                did the one we have in the fable. One bright summer morning, according to the story, two
                                bees flew away from the hive in quest of homes. For some time they flitted around among
                                the flowers without finding much to award their search. At last they came to a
                                wide-mouthed bottle half full of honey, which hung from a limb of an old peach tree.
                                Here was a chance. " What is the use," said one, "for us to fly around all day to gather
                                a little honey when we can go down in this bottle, eat all we want and get an abundant
                                supply to carry home to the hive? '' The other was more cautious, and warned his little
                                friend against the danger, but he was too headstrong to listen, and plunged right in and
                                commenced eating like a glutton ; but the wise one flew away, gatheringlittle by little,
                                bit by bit, from the delicate buds and open flowers, spending the day in delightful
                                labor, and at evening on his way home, with all his little limbs could carry, he thought
                                of his friend, and called to see if he was ready to return ; but oh, to his sorrow lie
                                found him " reveling in sweets which he was as unable to leave as to enjoy." It is
                                better to labor patiently and long than with hope of becoming rich in an hour, plunge
                                into that which may prove our ruin.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Short rules for home use" TEIform="index"/>SHORT RULES FOR HOME USE</head><p TEIform="p">The Brethren at Work presents the following: . Put self last. When others are suffering
                                drop a word of sympathy. Tell of your own faults rather than those of others. A place
                                for every thing and every thing in its place. Hide your own little troubles, but watch
                                to help others in theirs. Take hold of the knob and shut every door behind you without
                                slamming it. Never interrupt any conversation, but wait patiently your turn to speak.
                                Look for beauty in every thing, and take a cheerful view of every event. Carefully clean
                                the mud and snow from your boots before entering the house. If from any cause you feel
                                irritable, try the harder to do little pleasant things. * ******* You will not be sorry
                                For being courteous to all ; For doing good to all men; For speaking evil of no one ;
                                For hearing before judging; For thinking before speaking; For holding an angry tongue ;
                                For being kind to the distressed ; For asking pardon for all wrongs ; For being patient
                                toward everybody ; For stopping the ears to a tale-bearer; For disbelieving most of the
                                ill-reports.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There is a warm place in the gospel of Christ for the children..." TEIform="index"/>There is a warm place in the gospel of Christ for the children...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">There is a warm place in the gospel of Christ for the children. In the olden time parents
                                brought their little ones to Jesus, that he might touch them, and He did touch them; but
                                He did more — He took them in His arms and blessed them, while He pressed them near to
                                His heart. Atheism has no God, and it has nothing for children.</p></div3><pb n="237" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Young historians" TEIform="index"/>YOUNG HISTORIANS</head><p TEIform="p"> Fannie.— " Mintie, who was it tliat first discovered the Shakers? I can't think."
                                Mintie.—"It was Mother Ann Lee. She discovered them first at Watervliet, then she
                                discovered them here at Mt. Lebanon, then at Hancock, and then in other places.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Departed this Life</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Russell, Rodney" TEIform="index"/>Rodney Russell</head><p TEIform="p">At North Union, O., September 3, , aged 84 years. Another pioneer gone</p></div4></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We hear of considerable changes and transfers..." TEIform="index"/>We hear of considerable changes and transfers...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We hear of considerable changes and transfers now being made by the Central Ministry in
                                eastern societies, but not having received the information officially, we defer
                                statements.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="All reports to the contrary..." TEIform="index"/>All reports to the contrary...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">All reports to the contrary, we are officially informed, that no appointments have been
                                made in the Enfield and Hancock bishopric, in place of Elder T. Damon, deceased; nor
                                associate sister appointed.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="At Shakers, N. Y., there is a much needed..." TEIform="index"/>At Shakers, N. Y., there is a much needed...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Shakers, N. Y., there is a much needed improvement of the cemetery taking place.
                                Beautiful marble slabs are being placed at the heads of all the graves. Each stone has
                                the full name and age of the individual occupying the grave, with date of death. The
                                stones, with one exception, are of one size, the exception being that of Mother Ann Lee,
                                which is considerably larger, and has inscribed on its surface her name, date and place
                                of birth, also same of death. We are sorry more pains were not taken to have the
                                orthography of the given names engraved correctly; as it is a matter now difficult to
                                correct. There is a feature, however that can be corrected with much improvement — the
                                restoration of the symmetry of the yard. On enlarging the cemetery some years since the
                                enlargement was made on one side only, thus leaving the grave of our founder very far
                                from the center. But it stands improved by what is being done, and to our credit
                                greatly. The neatest, prettiest grave-yard among the Shakers which we have seen is at
                                Union Village, O.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Notices</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="John Ploughman's pictures; or, more of his plain talk, for plain people" TEIform="index"/>John Ploughman's pictures; or, more of his plain talk, for plain people
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline">by <persName reg="Spurgeon, Charles H." TEIform="persName"/>By Charles H. Spurgeon</byline><p TEIform="p">John Ploughman's Pictures; or, More of His Plain Talk, for Plain People, No. 40 Standard
                                Series, Publishers, I. K. Funk &amp; Co., 10 and 12 Dey street, New York. Price 15
                                cents. This is a new book by Spurgeon, after the style of his celebrated "John
                                Ploughman's Talk," which has had immense sales in this country and in England. It is
                                exceedingly humorous and instructive. Each of the thirty-nine short chapters is
                                illustrated by a quaint, apt picture. The humor and homely wisdom of this book should
                                carry it into every household. The above enterprising firm have also issued the
                                following valuable and immensely cheap volumes:</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thoughts of the emperor Marcus Aurelius Antoinus" TEIform="index"/>Thoughts of the emperor Marcus Aurelius Antoinus
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline">Translated by <persName reg="Long, George" TEIform="persName"/>George Long.</byline><p TEIform="p">The Thoughts of the Emperor Marcus Aurelius Antoninus. No. 37 Standard Series. Price 15
                                cents (former price $1.50). •'The noblest product of Paganism,"—N. Y. Tribune. " As a
                                treatise on Ethics it deserves praise less only than the Sermon on the Mount."—John
                                Stuart Mill. " The English reader will find in his (Long's) version the best means of
                                becoming acquainted with the purest and noblest book of antiquity."—Canon Farrar.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Salon of madame Necker, vol. II" TEIform="index"/>The Salon of Madame Necker. Vol. II. </head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="D'Haussonville, Othenin" TEIform="persName"/>Othenin D'Haussonville</byline><p TEIform="p">Translated for the Standard Series by Mary Stuart Smith. No. 38 Standard Series. Price 15
                                cents. Ours is the first publication in America of this very interesting book. The
                                Hermits. By Charles Kings!ey. No. 39 Standard Series. Price 15 cents (former price
                                $1.75). None of the books of Canon Kingsley is more readable or instructive. Another
                                work has just appeared on our Table, which we defer comments upon until our next
                            number.</p></div3></div2><pb n="238" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Golden gate" TEIform="index"/>GOLDEN GATE</head><p TEIform="p">Canaan, N. Y. 1. Lead me lest mine eyes be blinded, And thy way I fail to see; 2. Feed me
                            lest my spirit famish, For the bread and living wine; Guide my trembling, erring footsteps
                            Teach me, and my life forever, Father, home to Mother, shall be thee. thine. CHORUS. Home to
                            thee, Ever thine, Home to thee, Yet Ever time, Still trusting will I wait, Till trusting
                            will I wait, Till ¦#¦' Angels bear me o'er the sea, And ope' the golden gate.</p></div2><pb n="239" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rubber cement" TEIform="index"/>Rubber Cement</head><p TEIform="p">— The following recipe for making cement for shoes is said to be reliable:— Gutta percha,
                                -§• oz.; bi-sulphuret carbon, 2 oz. In a wide-mouth bottle put the two together, and
                                shake occasionally until the gutta percha is dissolved, and it is ready for use.
                                Directions.—Where the patch is to be applied, scrape the boot or shoe until the blacking
                                is off, and the leather is a little rough. On this dust with fine rosin, minutest
                                quantity ; serve the patch the same way. Then spread a little of the cement on both the
                                shoe and the patch, first having shaved the edges of the patch. Apply like court
                                plaster, and smooth with a warm spoon or iron, and the shoe will soon be ready to wear.
                                A few hours will harden the cement. When properly done, the patch will be invisible, and
                                will last as long as the shoe. This cement is water-proof. The gutta percha, shaved to
                                thin slices, is kept in india rubber stofes for the above purpose. Ten cents' worth will
                                do the work of a family for a longtime. The bi-sulphuret of carbon is sold by druggists,
                                and will cost five or ten cents an ounce. The smell, which is offensive, soon passes
                                off.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Warts" TEIform="index"/>Warts</head><p TEIform="p"> — A Correspondent says— '• I had no less than twenty large warts on my hands and several
                                small ones. I applied a common Irish potato, cutting it in two, and applying the juice
                                over each wart two or three times a day. Mine have all disappeared, and I thought the
                                remedy worth publishing."'</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Felons" TEIform="index"/>Felons</head><p TEIform="p"> — It is said that the painful sore finger known as the felon may be effectually cured in
                                three hours, with a poultice of the size of a small bean, made of quick lime slacked
                                with soap, bound on the spot, and renewed every half hour.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Styptic" TEIform="index"/>Styptic</head><p TEIform="p"> — Bleeding from a wound, on man or beast, may be stopped by a mixture of wheat flour and
                                common salt, in equal parts bound on with a cloth. If the bleeding be profuse, use a
                                large quantity, say from one to three pints. It may be left on for hours, or even days
                                if necessary.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Air in bedrooms" TEIform="index"/>The Air in Bedrooms</head><p TEIform="p"> — As to tests, we are glad to see that a scientific lecturer has reminded people that
                                nature gave them their noses to use, and he advises them to employ this picket-guard of
                                the body to see if the air of their bedrooms is right. " When you get up," he says,
                                "leave your bedroom just as it was ; go out into the pure morning air and breathe that
                                till your nose is wide awake, then go back and take a few snuffs of your bedroom air ;
                                if it smells fresh and sweet, like out.door air, you have good ventilation, and have
                                breathed the breath of life all the night." If on the contrary it smells close, musty, "
                                thick," sickening, your nose will have told you what your sense ought to have made clear
                                without the test. Another test.— If you desire a killing proof of the impurity of air
                                that has been once breathed, hang up a canary bird in a cage at the top of a closely
                                curtained bedstead, and if the bed is occupied, the bird will be dead in the
                            morning.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fever and ague" TEIform="index"/>Fever and Ague</head><p TEIform="p">— Take one large onion, cut it in two; take out enough of the heart to admit of a large
                                sized nutmeg and then close the onion together; roast it in the fire till soft, then
                                take out and pound it a little ; put it in one pint of cider brandy, of which take one
                                teaspoonful before each meal.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ears" TEIform="index"/>The Ears</head><p TEIform="p">.— No sharp instrument should ever be used in cleansing out the ears, for they are easily
                                injured. A damp cloth round the end of the finger will do all that is necessary. When
                                children press pebbles, beans, or other substances into the ears it is best to inject
                                warm water with a syringe, and if that does no good consult a doctor; but in no instance
                                should pincers, hooks, etc., be used by the unskilled. The same rules hold good when
                                insects make their way into the canal. Itching is often temporarily relieved by dropping
                                a little warm glycerine into the ear. Boxing children's ears is liable to injure the
                                tympanic membrane and may produce deafness. The same may be said of the use of cold
                                water when allowed to enter the ears. Therefore bathers should plug their ears up with
                                cotton. Strong draughts should also be avoided.</p></div3></div2><pb n="240" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>The Farm and Poultry Yard</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spare the horse" TEIform="index"/>Spare the Horse</head><p TEIform="p">:. O, teamster, spare that horse, How hard he tries to go, There's load enough for two,
                                Don't strike another blow, Give him a helping hand, Or ease the load, I pray, And he
                                your kindness will A thousand-fold repay. How patiently he toils, All through the heat
                                and cold, A faithful servant still, Though wearied, worn, and old. Poor, dumb,
                                unconscious brute! And yet he seems to know, Caressing oft the hand That deals the cruel
                                blow. What an imploring look, And what a knowing eye, And yet without the power To utter
                                e'en a cry. See how he writhes and shakes, While smarting with the pain. Oh, cruel
                                driver, pause ! Don't strike the brute again. Humanity at last Brought to a sense of
                                shame, Will punish those who give Unnecessary pain. Oh, driver, spare that horse, How
                                hard he tries to go ; There's load enough for two, Don't strike another blow.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tonics for fowls" TEIform="index"/>Tonics for Fowls</head><p TEIform="p">.— The best tonic is iron, a few drops of the tincture being mixed with the drinking
                                water, or half a dozen rusty nails being thrown to the bottom of the drinking vessel.
                                This is especially advisable during moulting. Cayenne pepper and asafcetida are good
                                digestive stimulants, and also gentian. Ale is a good stimulant. In using cayenne
                                pepper, be careful to buy a good article, and do not use too much of it at once, so as
                                to disgust the fowls, nor continue the use of it long. Asafoetida, garlic and onions all
                                have a good effect on the lungs and bronchia. Ginger will weaken the digestive organs if
                                used too long. Charcoal (and you can economically use the little bits of charred wood
                                that remain after every wood fire) is a good purifier of the digestive organs, as it
                                absorbs fetid matter. It stimulates digestion. Furnish it in small pieces about the size
                                of grains of corn ; they will swallow it when they need it, particularly if some in a
                                powdered state has been previously added to their soft food to teach them. Sulphur is a
                                very valuable drug to the poulterer, but should be used carefully in the case of young
                                chicks, as many have been reported killed by its use externally, and apparently more
                                often when it is used with lard. The fine powder has often caused blindness by getting
                                into the chick's eyes. The flour of sulphur is often contaminated with oil of vitriol.
                                To get this out wash your sulphur carefully in hot water, which does not dissolve the
                                sulphur. To apply it to small chickens, sprinkle it from a dredging box and keep the
                                chickens out of the wet for the next day. Persian insect powder is safer, however.
                                Chicken Powder.— Four ounces each of copperas, cayenne, sulphur and resin ; powder all
                                and mix ; two spoonsful for each dozen fowls several times weekly. Lime water.— Four
                                ounces of lime and one gallon of water; slack the lime with a little water and pour on
                                the rest. Cover and set aside for three hours, then pour off the clear liquid from the
                                top and use the lime that is left when wanted.— Am. Poultry Yard.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Warm bedding" TEIform="index"/>Warm Bedding</head><p TEIform="p">— If any farmer doubts the efficacy of warm bedding in cool or cold weather for his
                                stock, let him observe one fact. That which he fails to warm by bedding, he loses by the
                                extra amount of food requisite to keep his stock in good condition.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Surplus straw" TEIform="index"/>Surplus Straw</head><p TEIform="p">.— Let the surplus straw be stacked in the yards. If the stock have a picking at this, it
                                will answer well the purpose of noon feeding; and will also keep the animals on the move
                                to their warmth and growth. The straw scattered by such a plan is not wasted.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Composts" TEIform="index"/>Composts</head><p TEIform="p">.— Every gardener and farmer should have a compost heap ; and upon it pile up every sod
                                and rubbish within his reach that would make manure. It will pay.</p></div3></div2><!--
                    <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>