<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0505" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><date value="18750501" TEIform="date">May 1875</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">33-40</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="33" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">Vol. V. No. 5. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY, F. W. EVANS, • ,«---. Sixty Cents Editob. Mt*
                        Lebanon, Col. Co. N. Y.. May 1875. PEB AmnjK</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Materialization" TEIform="index"/>MATERIALIZATION</head><p TEIform="p">Is there any Law, under which Spirits can so clothe themselves, with earth elements, as to be
                            tangible to the senses of mortal men and women ? This is one of the great issues of the last
                            half of the 19th Century — to be tried by the jury of intelligent minds. As a scientific
                            fact, is it not wonderful that so much time and patience should be expended, in deciding
                            whether a certain speaker to an audience of 25 or 30 persons be an inhabitant of this world
                            — or only a visitant from the other ? Hear — 1st — the following testimony of R. D. Owen. 2d
                            — the Late Expose. 3d — Dr. Orcutt's report, after a two weeks' investigation. And finally,
                            take note of the oft-repeated Prophecy that " Large assemblies will yet be addressed by
                            materialized speakers, from the Spirit world."</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Robert Dale Owen and Henry T. Child thought they had a 'fee simple' on spiritualism..." TEIform="index"/>Robert Dale Owen and Henry T. Child thought they had a 'fee simple' on spiritualism...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Robert Dale Owen and Henry T. Child thought they had a "fee simple" on spiritualism and the
                            Katie King "business," but it has slipped through their fingers. That there has been
                            humbugging is doubtlessly true, but it turns out favorable to the mediums, the Holmes ; for
                            Owen and Childs have been humbugged to believe that they had been humbugged. Let them and
                            the public get their lessons out of it and be ready to move on to the next " beat in the
                            bar."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Kingdom of heaven" TEIform="index"/>Kingdom of Heaven</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritualism" TEIform="index"/>SPIRITUALISM</head><p TEIform="p">The following extract gives a good idea of the progress made in the seances Mr. Owen
                            attended: I have seen "Katie" issue from the cabinet more than a hundred times in full form
                            ; passing in her graceful way around the circle and addressing a kind word or two or a " God
                            bless you! " to the friends she knew. She has suffered me to cut from her head a lock of
                            hair: and she has herself cut for me and in my presence a piece of her dress, and also of
                            her veil, the former being apparently fine bishop's lawn, and the latter a bit of lace,
                            either of the finest quality of Honiton, or else of point de Venise, I am not certain which.
                            She has allowed me to touch her hand, her face, her person, and to kiss her on the forehead;
                            she then taking my face in both her hands, and giving me a similar kiss in return, She has
                            handed me from the cabinet aperture a nosegay of red and white roses, wet as with heavy dew,
                            and I found among them a little note, asking my acceptance of them. During a private sitting
                            I gave her a mother-of-pearl cross with a piece of white silk cord attached, together with a
                            small note folded up in which I had written : "I offer you this, dear Annie, because, though
                            it be simple, it is white and pure and beautiful as you are." She took both, did not open
                            the note, suspended the cross from her neck, kissed it, and retreated to the cabinet,
                            closing the door. In a minute or two she returned, with the cross in one hand and the folded
                            note in the other, bent over me and said, in her low, earnest voice and with her charming
                            smile : "White and pure and beautiful like me —is it?" How did she read that note? The
                            cabinet with its door closed, and its apertures covered with black curtains, is, as I have
                            often verified, quite dark. Ever after, when she appeared she wore that cross on her breast,
                            reminding one of the well-known lines in Pope's " Rape of the Lock." I observed that at
                            times when she issued from the cabinet this cross shone as with a phosphorescent luster. She
                            had also given to her, by visitors, a ring, a bracelet, and a locket, which she frequently
                            wore. The most usual gifts, however, were nosegays, and these seemed to give her especial
                            pleasure; she frequently, after smelling them, remarked to me how charmingly fragrant they
                            were. On one occasion I handed to her a hair chain which had been presented to me by a
                            friend since deceased. This she took with her and returned next day with a message from her
                            who had given it to me. I was in the habit after each sitting of carefully examining the
                            cabinet; but neither cross, nor ring, nor bracelet, nor locket, nor chain was ever to be
                            found; minute search, with a light, did not even reveal a rose-leaf. With such or similar
                            phenomena you are doubtless familiar; but I have seen "Katie," on seven or eight different
                            occasions, suspended in full form about two feet from the ground for ten or fifteen seconds.
                            It was within the cabinet, but in full view; and she moved her arms and feet gently, as a
                            swimmer upright in the water might do. I have seen her on five several evenings disappear
                            and reappear before my eyes, and not more than eight or nine feet distant. On one occasion,
                            when I had given her a calla lily, she gradually vanished, holding it in her hand, and
                            fading out from the head down, and the lily remained visible after the hand which held it
                            was gone, the flower, however, finally disappearing also. When she reappeared the lily came
                            back also, at first as a bright spot only, which gradually expanded into the flower. Then "
                            Katie " stepped out from the cabinet, waving to us with all her wonted grace her adieu ere
                            she finally retired for the evening. Thus I have seen a material object as well as a spirit
                            vanish and reappear. One principal objection which the scientific men have made to the
                            examination of spiritualistic phenomena is, that most of the communications received from
                            the spirit-world have been weak, foolish "twaddle," utterly unworthy of the persons from
                            whom they purported to come. This objection is very fairly met by a communication from "
                            Katie " through Dr. Child, reported by Mr. Owen in these words: SPIRIT ADDRESS. My Dear
                            Friends —I should be sorry if you inferred that the way in which I sometimes appear and
                            speak to you and to other friends when I am materialized is a true exponent of my present
                            condition, and that the rude and trifling manner then exhibited is a real reflection of my
                            interior state. It is important you should know that spirits either in or out of the form,
                            as you call it, are to a very great extent subject to the influences of the material
                            elements with which they are clothed; and if I could have you spend a little time with me in
                            an appreciative manner, in my interior home in spirit-land, you would not know me as the
                            same Katie that calls you " stupid " and uses expressions which are often quite repulsive to
                            my inner consciousness. The laws of spiritual manifestation are absolute, and whenever a
                            spirit approaches a medium it must be more or less materialized, first, in order to come
                            into the atmosphere of the earth, and then into that of the medium ; and if it presents
                            itself in form, it is obliged, under a law, to appear as nearly as may be as it was when it
                            passed from the earth. Then a child of earth, though grown to maturity in spirit-life,
                            returns as a child. Deformed persons present their deformities with precision. Spirits
                            retain not only the recollection of the earthly conditions and appearances, but also the
                            power of assuinipg them in spirit-life whenever it is desirable. You will see the importance
                            of this power of maintaining or recurring to the primitive conditions of spirit-life, at
                            least for a time, and until all those to whom a recognition is necessary shall have passed
                            into that state; for this power is retained so as to be easily exercised until after all who
                            are living on the earth at the time a spirit enters this world have also passed on, so that
                            the new born spirit cannot fail to recognize its friends and relations. I am requested to
                            say to you that all spirits, when they return to earth, whether they communicate or not, are
                            absolutely subject to this law. They muxt assume the conditions they had when they left the
                            earthly form, although they may bring to earth many thoughts and ideas, which they have
                            acquired in the interior life ; but even these are somewhat modified by being presented
                            through the necessary conditions which surround them at the time: for instance, scholars
                            from the spirit-land, speaking through mediums who are ignorant of language and the rules of
                            grammar, may be compelled to use the incorrect expressions of the medium. It is a truth that
                            " the spirits of the prophets are subject to the prophets;" and every spiritual
                            communication that has ever been given has been more or less modified by the channel through
                            which it has passed, as well as by the essentially materialistic conditions which spirits
                            may have been compelled to assume when they came into the earth's atmosphere and into
                            rapport with mediums. A notable feature of all spirit-manifestations thus far has been the
                            low character of the spirits engaged. Leaving behind the old methods of theological proof by
                            argument, I believe that sooner or later, God, himself, will manifest his existence in some
                            such way as these spirits do, and so make us sure of it. He can do it, and he certainly
                            will; there is no reason why he should not. There is something impressive in the recent
                            developments of spiritualism, progressing as they do in the midst of the tremendous struggle
                            between infidelity and old Bible theology. Just now when Positivism exalts itself and
                            prepares to condemn all religions which are not susceptible of proof, new facts appear and
                            furnish the proof required. If Dr. Holland had understood the meaning of the spiritualistic
                            phenomena of the present day he would have " spoken with better cheer " when he wrote the
                            following lines: " The old orthodox view of the Bible as a plenarily inspired book, from the
                            first word of Genesis to the last of St. John's Revelations, is already forsaken by more
                            minds than can be counted; and, by necessity, with the relinquishment of this view goes by
                            the board a great mass of theology entirely dependent upon it for existence. The current
                            popular theology cannot possibly be saved without the current and popular view of the Bible.
                            They stand or fall together. • * * * "The facts are, however, that the revolution Is going
                            on independent of the theologians and the religious teachers, and if they are doing any
                            thing about it they are fighting it. The result will probably, and most naturally, be a
                            reign of infidelity, out of which, after weary, wretched years, we shall slowly emerge with
                            our Christianity purged of its extraneous doctrines, and with a new class of religious
                            teachers, who will look back upon the present position as one of gross blindness and fatal
                            fatuity on the part of their predecessors." * * The materializing spirits belong to the
                            generative order. The same class ministered to Swedenborg, the Angel of Spiritualism. That
                            the reaction against the false " exposure " has fairly set in, see a lengthy article on
                            Spiritualism, in Tribune of March 27, by Francis G. Fairfield.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Rev. Mr. Wells, secretary of the Ohio State Y. M. C. A., made the statement..." TEIform="index"/>The Rev. Mr. Wells, secretary of the Ohio State Y. M. C. A., made the statement...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The Rev. Mr. Wells, secretary of the Ohio State Y. M. C. A., made the statement on the
                            evening of the 11th inst., to an audience of several hundred people, that " the time is
                            coming when Christians will love God so intensely that they will put to death even their own
                            children who may be found holding and teaching heretical opinions." Has the doctrine of the
                            " Vicarious Atonement" begun to bear such fruit as this, in these latter days of 1' boasted
                            civilization ?"</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S., L. M. H." TEIform="persName"/>L. M. H. S.</byline></div2><pb n="34" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Letter from Col. Olcott" TEIform="index"/>LETTER FROM COL. OLCOTT</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">To the Editor of the Times: Allyn House, Feb. 19,1875. Sir—You are quite correct
                                    in saying that "the Katie King problem is not solved yet." But certain things are
                                    solved to any reasonable man's satisfaction, viz.: 1. The mediumship of both Nelson
                                    Holmes and his wife. 2. The perjury of the woman, Eliza White, whose sworn statement
                                    under the pseudonym of u Katie King," has gone the rounds of the papers. 3. The
                                    actual appearance, to myself and others, of a male spirit recognized as John King,
                                    and of a female spirit claiming to be and recognized as Katie King. 4. The
                                    exhibition of marvels of "direct writing," the apparent dissolution and
                                    transportation of signet rings and documents. 5. The occurrence of all the Holmes'
                                    phenomena of their public circles in my own apartments, under the most satisfying
                                    test conditions. 6. The ability of the supposed spirits to understand the French,
                                    German, Italian, Spanish, Latin, Greek, Turkish, Georgian and Russian languages. 7.
                                    The writing of communications to myself by both John and Katie King, in the
                                    identical autographs of their notes of last summer to Mr. Owen and other persons. I
                                    cannot begin to tell you the things I saw during the course of my fortnight's
                                    investigation, for the narrative occupies over fifty pages of my forthcoming book;
                                    but I will leave it to you and the public to decide, after seeing my report, whether
                                    this sensational case does not, in a very marked manner, serve as a warning to those
                                    who jump at conclusions before hearing both sides of any question. Perhaps the most
                                    disgusting feature of the affair is that there is ground for a grave suspicion that
                                    the poor creature whose perjuries have been so widely circulated, was moved by the
                                    promise of a large sum by persons connected with the Young Men's Christian
                                    Association to do what she did, ostensibly in the interest of truth and good morals.
                                    If this should be found true, a sudden revulsion may be expected from the present
                                    state of public opinion. Henry S. Olcott.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl">From the <index level1="Hartford weekly times" TEIform="index"/>Hartford (Conn.) Weekly Times,
                                    Feb. 27</bibl></cit></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Olcott, Henry S." TEIform="persName"/></byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eddy seance" TEIform="index"/>Eddy Seance</head><p TEIform="p">The following is the best representation I have met with of this New Phase in Spirit ualism.
                            It may be relied upon as a correct statement. The Orthodox papers are kicking against the
                            pricks in their false exposes of real facts. MATERIALIZATION AN ESTABLISHED FACT —
                            "WONDERFUL PHENOMENA AT THE HOME OF THE EDDY MEDIUMS. We give below an account from a
                            Vermont correspondent, wherein are detailed occurrences which, speaking after the manner of
                            men, " border on the marvelous." The narrative is most unqualifiedly indorsed by the
                            witnesses present at the seance, and is by them offered to the public as evidence of the
                            astounding power now developed at " Spirit Vale: " To the Editor of the Banner of Light: The
                            materialization of spirits at the home of the Eddy Mediums still continues to increase in
                            power, and for the last three weeks the manifestations have made such wonderful progress
                            that I feel it should be known to the world, so that those seeking for light may know what
                            spirits can do. The s6ance held by William Eddy, medium for materialization in the light, on
                            the evening of February 10th, was one of the most wonderful that I have ever witnessed. The
                            power shown by Honto, the Indian squaw, seems beyond belief. I will try and give you a brief
                            description of a part of what transpired during the evening. After William Eddy had been in
                            the cabinet a short time, Honto made her appearance at the cabinet door, bounded out on the
                            platform, dancing for a moment. She then advanced toward Mrs. Cleveland, who sat at the end
                            of the platform, some twelve feet from the cabinet door, and took her hand, shaking it in a
                            friendly manner; together they descended the steps leading from the platform to the floor of
                            the circle room. Advancing close to the company composing the circle, she danced for an
                            instant, then started for the end of the circle room (accompanied by Mrs. Cleveland),
                            passing the lamp and stove on her way to the door — the light reflected from the stove and
                            lamp having no apparent effect upon her. Honto was now forty feet from the cabinet; she
                            opened the door at the end of the circle room, looking out into the hail; she then returned
                            to the circle, and, in passing the stove, drew a materialized shawl apEarently from the side
                            of the stove, threw it over er shoulders and wore it during the evening. Honto was now
                            having a good time with some of the company; she put her arm around Horatio Eddy's neck and
                            kissed him repeatedly; leaving trim she went to the other end of the circle, took the violin
                            from Joseph Rugg, who was at that time playing upon the instrument, and kissed him upon the
                            cheek. Honto, with violin in hand, picked upon the strings a moment, and then laying it down
                            she again started for the end of the circle room. Reaching the door she opened it and passed
                            out into the hall, down the stairs to the sittingroom below (about seventy feet from
                            cabinet), where two of the Eddy family were sitting — Mrs. D. M. Eddy Brown and Miss Alice
                            Eddy. Honto stood in the doorway of the room, facing the light of two ordinary coal-oil
                            lamps, burning brightly at the time. She invited the ladies to come up to the circle room,
                            as she was going to have a good time, speaking in an audible voice to them. They accepted
                            her invitation, and accompanied her to the circle room, where they witnessed what further
                            transpired. Honto now mingled freely with the company; sitting down beside Mr. Waterman she
                            put her arm around his neck and kissed him several times; she visited all in the circle,
                            kissing some, caressing others, till all present had either felt or touched her. She then
                            started for the cabinet, springing over the railing in front of it (about five feet high) at
                            a bound. Stopping in the doorway of the cabinet for an instant, and waving her hand and
                            bowing good-night to all, she disappeared, and was seen no more during the seance. From the
                            time Honto first came out of the cabinet till she left us was some twenty minutes. The next
                            spirit that appeared I recognized as my grandmother. She spoke in an audible voice. Next
                            came an old lady, recognized by her daughter who was present, as Mrs. Carpenter. Next came
                            Mrs. Eaton, one of the spirits frequently controlling the mediums. Next came Mrs. Eddy, the
                            mother of the Eddy mediums; she stood out upon the platform, speaking in a full, distinct
                            voice, telling her children to stand firm for truth, to live good, pure lives, and that the
                            joys which awaited them in the other life would compensate them for all they suffered here.
                            She spoke much more that was beautiful and instructive, making all present feel stronger to
                            battle for truth. The next spirit I recognized as my mother. Next came a sister of Mr.
                            Waterman, whom he recognized ; followed by a lady recognized by Mr. Watson as his sister.
                            The next spirit I recognized as John Nevins, a brother-in-law, who stood out plainly and
                            distinctly. Next came an old gentleman, recognized by Mr. Watson as his father, John Watson.
                            He was succeeded by William Brown, one of the medium's guides, who spoke in an audible
                            voice, so that all present could hear ; he said not one jot or one tittle of the law should
                            pass away till all was fulfilled ; I think it related to what has been promised by the
                            spirits. The spirits who appeared during the stance were clothed in various costumes, some
                            being beautiful, others plain — the Indians showing more taste for display, and their
                            dresses being magnificent. I have given only a part of what transpired. I have written facts
                            which are attested to by those who witnessed the manifestations of which I write, they
                            requesting me to subscribe their names to this statement. Most truly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brown, Edward" TEIform="persName"/>EDWARD BROWN. Mrs. R. Cleveland, Mrs. Watson, Mrs. D. M. Eddy
                            Brown, Miss Alice Eddy, Charles Waterman, Mr. Watson, Horatio Eddy, Joseph Rugg. Chittenden,
                            Vt., Feb. 10th, 1875</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Elder Frederick:" TEIform="index"/>Beloved Elder Frederick :</head><p TEIform="p">Your card and document came yesterday. I kindly thank you for your good wishes. I desire you
                            may be blessed in body, soul and spirit; and that the tribulation, resting on a Gathering
                            Family, may bear good fruit in many souls. Your visit to Vermont was in season to meet R. D.
                            Owen, and to form another strong link in connection with those, outside, who are being
                            prepared for an advance movement. The Spiritual forces seem to be waiting the proper moment
                            to strike conviction — to touch the heart and awaken the conscience. Wise are the Virgins,
                            who have laid in a store for their lamps — who are baptized with the light of the coming
                            degree — who have honestly confessed and put away all violations of Mosaic, as well as of
                            Divine Law. They may rejoice and be exceedingly glad. Happy the Virgins who have thrown away
                            tobacco, drugs, superfine flour, saleratus, and the murdering of animals for food. Men and
                            women, living the Divine Life, need none of those things, nor do they desire them. Leave
                            them to such as seek low enjoyments—whose aspirations reach not above the animal plane.
                            Yourself, Elders, Burden-Bearers, Brethren and Sisters, accept our Love, and pray for us.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Fraser, Shirley, Mass., Jan. 5, '75</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Antipodes" TEIform="index"/>ANTIPODES</head><p TEIform="p">State School, Ascot, Victoria, Australia, ) December 30,1874. J Dear Friend and Brother Evans
                            : At last the Spirit World has opened to me, and a regular visitation occurs, at my house,
                            once in every twenty-four hours. Six different spirits have held communication with us, one
                            of whom says he will abide with me as a regular visitant until the time of my going home.
                            Last week, I had the felicity of receiving a message from Ann Lee, through the Spirit Katy
                            King, who writes through my little daughter Grace. Need I tell you, dear friend, how highly
                            I prize the inestimable privilege accorded me of being put in direct communication with the
                            hosts of Heaven ? I trow not, for your own recorded experience, in your Autobiography, has
                            long ago informed me how precious, how soul-charming and life-giving such experience was to
                            yourself. I can now say -with Simeon of old," Now let thy servant die in peace, for mine
                            eyes have Been thy salvation." Or with Paul, " For me to die is gain," and " to live is
                            Christ." But in reality, there is no more death. It is swallowed up in life, and life is
                            eternal. The Spirits tell me I shall never see America, in my body life, but that is no
                            disappointment to me now, for, being all of one Faith and of one household, we shall,
                            eventually, live together. Let me here greet, fraternally, all the Brethren and Sisters in
                            your happy Mountain Home. I am often with you, in the desire and faith of soul — the
                            foreshadows of the reality, near at hand. Outwardly speaking, I am, at present, alone. This
                            is the season allotted to holidays, and I am in the very middle of a three weeks' vacation,
                            six days of which I have been in the house by myself. My nearest neighbor lives half a mile
                            away. The Spirits, who told me I should never visit you, in the body, speak differently of
                            George. He will be accorded that physical, as well as intellectual and psychical
                            gratification. My three children — by present wife — Peter 21; George, 19 ; and Grace, 10
                            years of age, have all elected to live a virgin life — to keep the body pure and devote it
                            to its highest uses. During the six days I have been living outside of human society, I have
                            realized, somewhat better, the most eventful periods of Moses, Jesus, Mahomet and others, in
                            their times of seclusion from mankind. Solitude is no protection from sin and temptation.
                            The severest temptation awaited Jesus in the wilderness. And I find, in my brief experience,
                            that the greatest safety, and the greatest freedom from temptation lie in actual service —
                            in real work — in doing the will of the Father. A garden, allowed to lie idle, will produce
                            weeds — but one in constant cultivation will yield fruit, to the comfort and profit of the
                            cultivator. Pure and cheerful society — what a blessing to those who have it! And what a
                            deprivation to those who have it not! We read that after the temptation in the wilderness "
                            Angels came and ministered to him." This was not only a seasonable relief, but a 34 Dr.
                            Ckowell says: " The phenomena of Spiritualism will win belief from persons to whom they
                            appeal. The time is near at hand when they will receive their fair share of attention. More
                            important it seems to me to ae to direct attention to the source and nature of ;he
                            intelligence which wields this new power : to show wherein it corresponds to that which
                            always aas been the chosen vehicle of Divine Kevelation: to mark its claims to a hearing on
                            grounds purely religious: and to show, as may easily be done, that t is of God, not of the
                            devil: in strictest accord with previous Revelation as preserved in the Bible, not in
                            antagonism to the Divine utterances in ages past. Man has been crying out long in hope for
                            something which shall satisfy his spiritual cravings. He has outgrown the old faith, and
                            seeks a creed more rational and more comprehensible. If his spiritual nature, as in too many
                            cases, has been starved well nigh to death, he has been dimly conscious all through his
                            blank materialism of a something within that is not satisfied. If the spirit has mercifully
                            been preserved through its trials, its voice is heard in lament over spiritual destitution,
                            and earnest cries for more light. How many in the last two decades have said wearily to
                            themselves, ' This theology is dry, dry as dust. I cannot assimilate it. It does not nourish
                            me. If something better do not come somehow, then religion will soon be dead; and faith will
                            loose its hold upon men.'" <pb n="35" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKERE88. 35 beautiful compensation.
                            Judging from the Law of compensation — the equity of things— I incline to the opinion, that
                            fewer direct Angel visitations would be experienced by persons enjoying the blessing of good
                            and suitable society, than by those deprived of it — even for a season. We might never have
                            had the Book of Revelations, had John been in bodily companionship with the visible Church,
                            all his life. Who knows, that in the yet undeveloped but near future, there will not be
                            craniograms, homograms and mentignxms— just as there are now telegrams and cablegrams ?
                            There is little left to surprise us now, in the way of new discoveries, though there is yet
                            for us, an untouched, untasted infinitude, to be received with thankfulness and joy. Every
                            discovery made, a little wider opens the veil — a little more appreciation of our relation
                            to God, and sub-relation to things about us and to each other as dwellers in higher spheres.
                            We are ascending to God in a double ratio. We are being relieved of the dross that weighs
                            down, and increasing in Angel strength that wings aloft. Earth recedes and Heaven draws
                            near. Before closing this rambling letter, I beg to be kindly remembered to Bro. Peebles. I
                            intend, as soon as my family come home, to go and spend a few days in Melbourne, among the
                            friends and associates of friend Peebles, while in Australia. I seek also to be had in
                            brotherly remembrance by the associated family of Believers at Mount Lebanon. I am, Dear
                            Br., thine truly in eternal relationship.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Finlay, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Finlay</byline></div2><div2 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Few thoughts on diet" TEIform="index"/>A FEW THOUGHTS ON DIET (For the American Shaker and.
                            Shakeress.)</head><p TEIform="p">" To the pure, all things are pure." None are more fond of quoting this saying than gluttons
                            and gross, indiscriminate feeders. Another favorite subject of reference, by the same class
                            of persons, is the Viaion of Peter— Acts 11 —wherein he saw all manner of beasts, fowls and
                            creeping things, all of which he was commanded to eat. Construe this vision literally, into
                            an injunction to use, as daily food, all the articles therein mentioned, and there is
                            nothing alive, so repugnant to our senses, that it may not be eaten, by ourselves, and
                            placed before our friends as a delicacy. Except the vision be bo construed as to warrant
                            serving up the most obnoxious reptiles and vermin, as food, on our tables, it means nothing
                            as regards the regulation of diet — and without seeking for the true and deeper meaning
                            concealed beneath the symbolic creatures of the vision, we will, for the present, lay it
                            aside as having no bearing upon the subject of diet. Of the first quotation, it is worthy of
                            observation that the saying is applicable to one class only — the Pure. The impure —nay,
                            even the half and between sort are excluded. To the Pure, alcohol and aquafortis are alike
                            innoxious, because the pure will put each to its proper use. The foolish, or impure might be
                            tempted to put one or other into the mouth. It is as if we should say, fire-proof materials
                            are in no danger from fire — but it is abundantly evident that all combustible substances
                            must be excluded from the category of things not in danger from fire. The Pure, in body,
                            mind and soul, will seek to clothe themselves with purity, and to promote the purity of the
                            world, by eating and drinking only what tends to purity, and by keeping every thing in its
                            proper place. A pig in a sty may be tolerated, but a pig in a parlor would be abominable.
                            Some there are, and the writer of this article is one of them, who think that a pig in a
                            human stomach is a greater abomination still; and when the pig is no longer considered fit
                            matter for the human stomach, even the pig in the sty had better be put away too, and the
                            pig allowed, as of old, to consociate with the wolf and the bear, away from the haunts of
                            men. Some would even go further, and exclude animal food of every kind from the stomach. Who
                            will judge what is fittest? Is the drunkard, the daily besotted drunkard, the fittest person
                            to judge of purity and health in our beverages? If he be not so, then let me ask who shall
                            judge of what is best and most appropriate for human food? The gourmand — the glutton, the
                            obese-faced, drum-paunched humanity, whose lack-lustre eyes, after a full cramming, show as
                            much intelligence and little more than could be observed in a couple of boiled gooseberries
                            stuck in a pudding! Is this moving hogshead of lard one of " the Pure to whom all things are
                            Pure ? " Shall we appeal to the ordinary experience of humanity, its fair average ? Let it
                            be so, and surely no one claiming to rank among the average will object to the scrutiny of
                            the eye and the nose as to what articles of food are fittest and best for human beings to
                            eat. First, then, animal food as the base or lowest element, beginning with the cannibal —
                            his diet is human flesh — and this we all know, when in a state of decomposition, is the
                            most offensive substance with which we can possibly come in contact through the senses. Let
                            any one that doubts this try the air of a dissecting room, or open a grave, that is three or
                            four weeks filled, and he will be convinced. Here then we find human flesh, the most
                            repulsive considered as food in a state of decomposition — and be it observed all food is
                            decomposed before it leaves the body, which is built up with the products of this
                            decomposition. Second rate in the scale ascending, is the flesh of animals, which in a state
                            of decomposition, is ,not quite so hateful to us as is human flesh. Third rate ascending, is
                            the flesh of fowls and fishes, judged by the same process; and fourth rate higher in the
                            scale of purity, is animalized substances including milk, butter, cheese and eggs. These are
                            all offensive in a state of decomposition, but not so bad as any of the preceding three
                            classes of food. Fifth in the ascending scale, are the roots of plants, such as potatoes,
                            turnips, carrots, etc. Sixth in order, are green and succulent vegetables, as greens,
                            cabbage, spinach, etc. Seventh in order, are the various kinds of grain, which in a
                            decomposed state are cer tainly not agreeable, but tolerable by com parison with the others.
                            Higher we come to pulse, such as peas, beans, lentiles etc. Higher still we come to berries
                            — and highest, best and purest of human food, we come to fruit, and so little is that
                            obnoxious to us that the most fastidious and refined in taste may cut off the decayed half
                            of a peach, and eat the other half of the same fruit; who among you would do the same with a
                            pig or even a sheep? It may here be objected that there is not fruit enough in the world for
                            all — and that even if there were, still it would not agree with all. To these and a host of
                            other objections the writer of this would only say, with the means placed at your disposal,
                            study every day to live according to your best and purest instincts. Do the best and BE the
                            best you possibly can every day ; and you will shortly find that both your means and ability
                            to do better will increase. Do not be discouraged with failures —try again ; and never by
                            any means let the impure or the foolish laugh you out of your purpose to become Pure, for
                            when you are once Pure in heart, you shall See God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Finlay, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Finlay, Victoria, Australia</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, March 12,1875" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, March 12,1875</head><p TEIform="p">John Finlay—My Dear Friend : Your Letter, and Article, for the Shaker and Shakeress, were
                            received on the 9th inst. I was much pleased to hear from you once more, and to learn of
                            your welfare and fortunes. I shall publish most of your Letter, and the Article. Glad the
                            connection with the Spirit World, is formed, with Medium in your own house and family. That
                            you grow in understanding and increase in faith is evident. I would love to meet you, in the
                            body. If that may not be — or if it may be, I rejoice in the hope of meeting you in the land
                            of bouIh. And also that you see the telegram, from you to me, among the possibles. And why
                            not? The Law, under which it can occur, exists — under the Magnetic Law, time and space are
                            ignored. Your views, upon Diet, are in accord with our experience. Your mind is in a
                            profitable labor. It is pleasant to think that your children have consecrated themselves to
                            chastity — the foundational virtue. " In this thou art marvelous before the most high, in
                            thy continence which thou hast had from thy youth up " — were the words of a Spirit to a
                            Sire of old. It is just as true to-day. Abuse of the Stomach leads to abuse of the
                            generative powers and functions — and that corrupts the earth at its foundations. " The
                            foundations of the earth are out of course" — was a true saying. Then came wars and
                            fighting, from the lusts of flesh and spirit. What a work is that, of redemption ! —
                            redemption from all the evils that fleshly man is heir to ! I And what a fearful fact, that
                            Immortals are, without their own agency, or consent, born into existence, saddled by their
                            progenitors, with hereditary vile propensities, wicked passions and pernicious habits 11!
                            How shall that wrong be righted ? A momentous question I! Will it be answered—the problem
                            solved ? Is not the Life and Immortality, of which the Scriptures speak,here referred to?
                            Think of it. The Gospel is a Gift of God to Humanity. It is designed to square accounts
                            between man and God. A day of judgment — the orthodox say — to punish the wicked. Very well,
                            while justice allows the All-Wise—All-Good-Almighty to take vengeance upon the wicked
                            violaters of his Law, will not outraged humanity cry unto that same God for Amnesty — a
                            condoning of all past offenses—on the same ground of justice, right and goodness? " Come and
                            let us reason together, saith the Lord." And come and let us reason together responds
                            humanity.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Healing" TEIform="index"/>HEALING</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Elder Frederick : It is a duty, which I feel incumbent upon me, to give an humble
                            statement of the travail of my soul within a few weeks past. About two years ago, two Shaker
                            Fathers, from the Spirit land, came and showed me these walks and buildings, and this
                            beautiful home with its delightful associations. I was induced, almost immediately, to visit
                            Mount Lebanon. My visit gave me entire satisfaction. I returned to my home. My body was
                            absent, but my spirit was continually with you. Being, all my life, a confirmed invalid, I
                            felt it would be unjust to try to thrust myself upon your Order. My Angel Fathers came
                            again, and gave me a kind and loving invitation to renew my visit. I wrote you in December.
                            You said: " We are willing you should come and try yourself by our Order. We cannot tell how
                            much you need a new creation, both soul and body, until we see you." I came, as you know,
                            and threw myself at your feet, assuring you how grateful I would be if you could be the
                            medium of affording me any aid, spiritually, or physically. Your faith, and. the faith of
                            the family, took hold upon me. I seemed to rise from discouragement and despair. I followed
                            your rules with regard to all hygeian laws. The idea was strong, in my mind, that it would
                            take a long time to eradicate a disease which had, so many years, <pb n="36" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> been
                            fastening itself upon my system, and had so successfully baffled all earthly power.
                            Thursday, the 4th of March, my Angel Fathers made me another visit. They said : " Child,
                            step in, while the waters are troubled." I asked what they meant by " stepping in — and the
                            waters being troubled." They replied : " Water is an emblem of truth, because of its
                            cleansing, healing and purifying effects, and when the mind is wrought upon by spirit
                            ministration, and brought into proper relations and heavenly conditions, and in perfect
                            unison with the heavenly spheres, then the waters are troubled, and the effect of obedience
                            is peace to the soul, and health to the body. " Child, you are now brought into relations
                            and surroundings, mental, physical and spiritual, whereby you may look for a new creation,
                            both of soul and body." It is now nine weeks since I came here. My recovery has been
                            constant and rapid. For thirty years I have not known a well day, nor a night of undisturbed
                            repose. Now I feel well and strong, and sleep in peace, at night, with all the sweetness of
                            an infant. How can I be humble enough, or thankful enough, for all these earthly and
                            heavenly ministrations, which have been the means of delivering me from the earthly Babylon,
                            and introducing me into the Kingdom of Heaven — not ideal — real, tangible and praetieal. My
                            dear Angel Fathers wished me to give their Angel Love to all Believers, throughout the land,
                            and tell them to have faith in Angel ministrations — that Organizations and Communities are
                            being formed, whereby the elements of society, on earth, are being stirred, in conjunction
                            with the Spirit world—that soon, it would not be thought a strange thing for men to converse
                            with Angels, as familiarly as one man converses with another — that soon, the lame, the
                            blind, the diseased would be flocking to the Pentecostal Church, for deliverance from all
                            the ailments of earth — inquiring what they must do to be saved. Angels, as well as men,
                            will rejoice, when they see eye to eye, and discern between the righteous and the wicked —
                            between him who serveth God, and him who serveth him not. Then the little ripples, appearing
                            here and there, upon the waters of truth, shall be a mighty wave, will sweep away all error
                            and false doctrine — and the Kingdom of the Lord will cover the earth, as the waters cover
                            the sea. In thia way, the Millennial Church, on earth, will be caught up to meet the Spirit
                            Spheres, drawing all men unto it, and each individual Avill become a Savior — many Saviors
                            in Mount Zion, each a drop composing the unfathomable ocean of truth — each a grain,
                            constituting the new Heavens and the new Earth — each a living stone, composing the vast
                            Temple — the beautiful structure, which shall go towering into the highest Heavens, with
                            shoutings'of Grace ! Grace 1 unto it.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hubbel, Gilbert" TEIform="persName"/>Gilbert Hubbel. Mount Lebanon, March 10,1875</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Facing the music" TEIform="index"/>FACING THE MUSIC</head><p TEIform="p">There is a music in truth that attracts the multitudes, while it cJiarms the lovers of
                            righteousness. The homely idiom of " facing the music," is replete with metre ; and to the
                            truly honest, is abundant with melodious chords. But, our love of truth too frequently finds
                            illustration, in our delight at seeing others confront the music of truth ; while a
                            noticeable discord is apparent, with a careless use of rhythm, rests, diminuendoea, slurs
                            and trills, when we listen to the music of what we are, and what we ought to be. However
                            mellifluous we claim the undulations of truth to be, we are apt to realize, that the more
                            beauteous melody is evolving, when others, instead of ourselves, are facing the undulations.
                            Truth never appears so inharmonic, as when we face the music, which we ourselves have made.
                            We have large faith in humanity; yet we believe it is easier for any nation to acknowledge
                            all truth, than for any individual to practice it; while we know of some individuals, who
                            are so in earnest to harmonize their lives with truth, that they listen to its particular
                            symphonies, with an interest, which, considering how discordant their organisms, is simply
                            wondrous. The melody of Jesus' life was the result of his facing the music of the heavenly
                            law, which led to the denial of selfishness, and a thorough consecration to godliness. So
                            much for preface. Do we love the music of truth so well, that we are willing to face it,
                            until our theology, thoughts, logic and lives, are in unison with " the song of Moses and
                            the Lamb 1" Let us see what is meet to face this musical arrangement: The song of Moses is
                            illustrative of the work of Moses with his people ; and this was, undoubtedly, a system that
                            promised and resulted in such physical perfection, that after many hundreds of years'
                            deterioration, we are forced to admit, with Parton, that the Jews of to-day are the purest
                            and healthiest six millions of people on the face of the earth! When we recall the catalogue
                            of diseases with whose infliction they suffered when they went out of Egypt; and reflect on
                            the fact, that under the guidance of Moses, this entire catalogue was obliterated, we are at
                            once interested to inquire into the system Moses inaugurated, and to pray for a Moses to
                            lead us Gentiles out of our lazar conditions, even though it be through a forty years'
                            labyrinthian pilgrimage, sustained by a manna or saw-dust pudding diet. Let us have health I
                            How those old Jews longed for their former regime, we can imagine; and how the poor doctors
                            must have railed, when they realized that their base of drug supplies was on the other side
                            of the waters, needs not a vivid imagination to comprehend. All history has not presented a
                            character that has called forth more of our sympathy, than this same Moses, who, aiming at
                            the salvation of his peoples' bodies, was, nevertheless, so terribly abused by them because
                            he would not let them continue in sin and die by wholesale ! A little experience of ours,
                            has intimated to us their sufferings, and their conquests. Before we concluded singing the
                            praises of pork, we faced the music of nine-tenths more bilious fevers and cancerous
                            afflictions than we have suffered since learning to sing better songs. And yet our Moses and
                            Miriam had a serious time with us on that journey. What we did in derogation of pork, we
                            should do with every unphysiological practice, and every unchristian habit; and though it
                            might consign to the dead sea, a thousand gods and gewgaws, that pleased perverted taste and
                            pride of life ; that unnaturally stimulated, narcotized, or falsely embellished our physical
                            beings; yet, if it is not the call of the gospel to us, to face the music of such a good
                            riddance, then I am unhappily deceived. And yet, some one must be willing to suffer abuse,
                            to be underrated, spiritually stoned, or perhaps consigned to oblivion, who will raise the
                            standard of gospel progress, and go ahead! And while some musician sings the songs of
                            physiological reform, which appear discordant and adverse to us, let us sufficiently " agree
                            with our adversary " to ask : While we are trying to overcome the evils of the flesh,—the
                            perverted passions of nature,—are we not feeding and strengthening such evil passions
                            through the alimentary canal, every day of our lives ? Hence, from such a cause, what the
                            effect ? what success 1 " Watchmen, what of the night ? " Had there been no Moses, to lead
                            Israel from their unphysiological habits, there never would have been a Jesus, to sing the
                            song of perfection of body and health of soul. Judaism and Christianity should go hand in
                            hand to-day, for, so far from their being antipodes, as Paul, in his unchristian
                            genuflections to " foolish Galatians " and "carnal Corinthians," would cause to appear, they
                            are the dual affinities that make the perfect Christian ! It is a feature of original
                            Christianity, that appears almost lost to recollection, that before Jesus accepted any as
                            disciples, he would either refer them to " keep the law," or by the powers of health
                            investing him, would cure them. How many millions of miserably sick, whom nature will not
                            own, and until nature does own them, the gospel can only in part accept, if at all, yet
                            making large professions of Christianity ; and ourselves among the number! Until that time
                            shall come, when we can sing " I am not sick," let us ever have an apology ready, for
                            hymning "Iama Christian ! " Brethren, this is facing the music in earnest — is it true music
                            ? How many will agree with me, that the poor grace with which we face " the song of the
                            Lamb," is the direct consequence of our progenitors' inability and unwillingness to face the
                            music of the Song of Moses V We shall leave for our next paper " Christ and Moses j" but it
                            is only proper to consider how beautiful the relations, between the true followers of Moses,
                            and the same of the Lamb would be to day, had each in the past, and did each now, face the
                            musical instructions of their respective heads I The former, in health, would reproduce
                            healthy bodies containing sound minds. The latter would baptize these, with the advancing
                            light and conduct of the heavenly school. "But to-day, a healthy soul cannot be found,
                            because of the want of a befitting tabernacle. What are we to do? "Keep the law;" shun the
                            disastrous consequences of broken physiological law; recreate a new body by the uses of
                            reason, religion and science ; and invite a new soul by the regeneration of a foul stomach.
                            Let us face tlie music of reform, of truth, no matter how much it may be opposed to our
                            tastes, or educations. " Conceived in sin, and born in iniquity," let us not repine, and say
                            there is no use trying. Let us own and face the music ; there is nothing gained by hiding
                            behind the bulwark of professional Christianity. Let us own we are not Christians; but very
                            desirous of being such; and though laboring under the very unfavorable conditioDS of
                            unmosaic organizations, physically and mentally; yet determined to retrieve these
                            misfortunes to the extent of our ability, by obedience to the physiological laws of Moses,
                            and adhesion to the virginal, unselfish characteristics that are ever heard reverberating
                            from the life-song of the Lamb.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. Lomas, Shakers, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Marriage.  Protestant Christianity" TEIform="index"/>Marriage. Protestant Christianity</head><p TEIform="p">"The Significance of the Tilton-Beecher Trial," from which we excerpt the following, touching
                            the two dominant institutions of the country — Christianity and Marriage: These questions
                            will be asked and profoundly considered by the Christian world, and by everybody who has not
                            already settled them adversely to the "only name under heaven" by which it is claimed it is
                            possible to be saved. We entirely agree with Mr. Tracy, attorney for Beecher, that the
                            validity of the Christian scheme is at stake in the Beecher trial. There is another equally
                            important Institution at stake in this trial, and that is the marriage institution, at least
                            from the church standpoint. If such a man as Beecher cannot and does not keep his marriage
                            vows, who can and who does? If the result of two generations of Christian sanctification,
                            salvation and ministerial exaltation, does not prepare a man to live virtuously inside
                            marriage, there must be something wrong in marriage or something wrong in the Christian
                            salvation. EarlviUe Transcript.</p></div2><div2 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bill for hanging and boiling a friar" TEIform="index"/>Bill for Hanging and Boiling a Friar.</head><p TEIform="p">A person writes as follows to the Kentish Observer: " In the present age of religious
                            tolerance and high price of labor, the following may not be uninteresting. It is extracted
                            from an old magazine, and is an authentic copy of a document of the date : 'Account of the
                            hanging and parboiling of Friar Stone, of Canterbury, in 1539. Paid for half a ton of timber
                            to make a pair of gallows for to hang Friar Stone, 2s. 6d.; to a carpenter for making the
                            same gallows, and the dray, Is. 4d.; to a laborer that digged the holes, 3d.; other expenses
                            of setting up the same, and carriage of the timber from Stablegate to the dungeon, Is.; for
                            a hurdle, 6d.; for a load of wood, and for a horse to draw him to the dungeon, 2s. 3d.; paid
                            two men that sat at the kettle and parboiled him, Is.; to three men that carried his
                            quarters to the gates and set them up, Is.; for halters to hang him, and Sandwich cord, and
                            for screws, Is.; for a woman that scoured the kettle, 2d.; to him that did execution, 3s.
                            8d.; total, 14s. 8d.' " </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Character makes the man" TEIform="index"/>Character Makes the Man.—</head><p TEIform="p">The man of character is always the man of iron nerve ; he may be neither a great statesman
                            nor politician; he may be humble in his associations and his aspirations ; but with all
                            these exceptions, if he has character, his heart is right, his integrity is unshaken. He
                            looks on truth with a clear vision, acting in accordance with its glorious dictates; he does
                            not fear nor shun the face of his fellow-man, for his heart is white with integrity, and he
                            looks humbly and trustingly up to the source of truth, and his fellowbeings, in a lowlier
                            sense, look up to him because he is trustworthy, and, in short, has character— good and
                            stable character. Character is the corner stone in individual greatness—the Doric and
                            splendid column in the majestic structure of true and dignified man, who Is at once a
                            subject and a king.</p></div2><pb n="37" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: the baptized Jesus" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: THE BAPTIZED JESUS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">One point, we take as granted, upon which all Believers in Christ's Second Appearing are in
                            accord ; that Je3us was born a Jew ; educated and reared a Jew — the highest type of Judaism
                            — morally and spiritually more progressed than any other of his race and was thus prepared
                            to receive the Divine Messenger sent of God to open a new Bra, by ministering a new Holy
                            Spirit baptism — a baptism of fire. That this Holy Spirit took up its abode with Jesus, and
                            became his spiritual Guide and Inductor into a new Christian dispensation. The question
                            arises in the minds of many, whether the Christ-Spirit, that descended upon him, at his
                            baptism, took entire possession of the man Jesus, so much eo, that thence forward, every act
                            that he did, and word that he spake, were under the full control and direction of that
                            Spirit. The Apostles of Jesus, in their different epistles, to the Churches — to whom we
                            give credence as truthful, and measurably inspired men — make some statements that would
                            seem to justify investigation from honest truth seekers. The Apostle James states a
                            self-evident axiom that " God cannot be tempted to evil, neither tempteth he any man ;" by
                            which we understand it was the human Jesus — not the 'divine Christ that was tempted. In
                            Matthew, we read that after Jesus was baptized, " he was led, of the Spirit, into the
                            wilderness,"— does not say what Spirit — " and was there tempted forty days and nights ;"
                            and that he fasted during that time ; but the Apostle does not specify what the peculiar
                            temptations were, while in the wilderness ; probably he did not know precisely. Then again,
                            " the devil took him up into the holy city, and set him on a pinnacle of the temple," and
                            conversed with him there ; and he (Jesus) told him " It is written, Thou shall not tempt the
                            Lord thy God ;" evidently showing that two spirits or influences were at work to gain the
                            vantage-ground; and for that purpose the devil persevered in his efforts, and again 11 took
                            him into an exceeding high mountain, and showed him all the kingdoms of the world, and the
                            glory thereof." Luke states that this was done in a moment of time, if so, it must have been
                            done in thought, and not by actual sight. Be that as it may, the writer undertakes, this
                            time, to show something of the nature of the temptations. That Satan was very anxious —
                            seeing the superiority of the organism of Jesus, and the force of his intellectual powers,
                            and spiritual attainments — to thwart the design of Providence in regard to him, there need
                            be little doubt; for Satan knew, that if he could not engage his services in his cause,
                            Jesus would be a powerful medium to pull down and destroy his kingdom ; and thus he offered
                            to make Jesus ruler over all those things which ho had showed to him, and tempted him with,
                            if he would worship him. Jesus, although sorely tried, could not be bought; but said " Get
                            thee hence ;" and the devil fled — left him, — and Angels, or the Christ-Spirit returned to
                            him with a renewed baptism, and gave him great spiritual power. Paul said in his epistle to
                            the Hebrews: " We have not an High Priest that cannot be touched with the feelings of our
                            infirmities ;" but he was tempted in all points as we are. May we inquire by what authority
                            the Apostles of Jesus made those assertions 1 Did lie make those statements to them, or to
                            others ? Or did they infer from observation, or write by inspiration concerning it ? If the
                            Apostles had not positive knowledge respecting it, did they not take an unwarrantable
                            position when they asserted that such was the case ? Jesus, himself said, " Be of good cheer
                            ; I have overcome the world." Truth will lose nothing by candid investiga. tion. We cannot
                            conceive that it would be a mark of infidelity to Christ, or of irreverence to the man
                            Jesus, who received the Christ baptism, if we seek to understand, whether, by that baptism,
                            he was instantaneously lifted up above the traditional education of his Jewish fathers, who
                            believed in war, marriage and the private property system, and practiced the same, or
                            whether he was lifted up by degrees, and gradually emancipated; or in other words, whether
                            he did find a degree of travail after his first baptism, and really learned obedience
                            through suffering. If this be so, then we can approach him very nearly, and find succor; for
                            in this also, he is our example, and can be touched with the feelings of our infirmities. We
                            see a wide difference between Belief and Temptation. Belief is the result of evidence
                            presented to the conscious reasoning faculties of the soul. Temptation comes through the
                            lower passional nature in man and in woman. I do not say that Jesus believed in the physical
                            resurrection, in war, marriage, or the private property system after his baptism. I would
                            not be willing even to acknowledge that / have thus believed, since my first baptism into
                            the faith of the Gospel of Christ's Second Appearing. But, the baptism into the old
                            theology, which I first received in Anti-Christ's Kingdom, often beclouded my vision, and
                            was an impediment in my way, and had to be outgrown. I found that impressions imbibed in
                            early life, that had found a lodgment in the soul, would not give place to new ideas without
                            a conflict — an effort. So, reasoning from analogy, I am inclined to believe that if Jesus
                            was really tempted in all points, as men and women are tempted, whom he came to save and
                            redeem, and that the Apostles, who listened to his teachings and promulgated his doctrines,
                            were men of like passions with us, and were liable to misconceive and misunderstand — see
                            and understand in part — then we can find a solution, and reconcile the seeming
                            contradictions which we find in the Scriptural records. Although Jesus was greatly favored
                            by his ancestry in his birth and education under the Essene and Platonic teachers of his
                            time — which enlarged his powers of conception and discrimination, and prepared him to
                            receive the heavenly Dove Spirit — yet we think he was not then fully perfected; but
                            continued to travail and suffer, and learn obedience. Some of the Gnostics, in the early
                            days of Christianity, taught that Christ was a mere man, born of a virgin, and excelled the
                            prophets in virtue. They said the Apostles thus taught; but those who came after them, made
                            a God of Jesus, who was not a God. Neither did those writers make a distinction between the
                            man Jesus, and the ChristSpirit that anointed, or baptized him. From the earliest ages of
                            time, of which we have any record, the great sea of human thought has been in constant
                            agitation concerning God, his attributes and his requirements upon the race. Also, as to the
                            quality, and potency of the Agents employed to execute his will; and how many Gods there
                            are, either created, or self-existent. All this is well, and perhaps very necessary for the
                            exercise of the reasoning powers in men and women; and to create a healthy action, that will
                            mature, and advance them from childhood conditions, and give force of character and strength
                            of mind. So long as it does not engender strife,, and lead to bitter controversy, it is
                            pleasant to exchange thoughts. Through this medium, if truth be our aim, we sometimes drink
                            in new inspirational ideas which give life to the soul.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Duality of Jesus" TEIform="index"/>THE DUALITY OF JESUS</head><p TEIform="p">Considering the great difficulty under which the life and teachings of Jesus have been
                            transmitted to us — written from oral statements made half a century after they had
                            transpired, and how much that was relevant and essential to a perfect understanding of those
                            teachings may have been forgotten in the life of the witness, or lost to the world through
                            their death, and consequently the equivocal character of our own religious education, it may
                            not be strange, that so many who speak or write upon the subject of " New Testament
                            Spiritualism," fall into the error of confounding the medium Jesus, with the controlling
                            spirit Christ. If the fact could be fully comprehended and accepted that Jesus and Christ
                            are two distinct personages speaking and acting at different times through the same
                            organism, what an amount of brain labor would be saved in the vain endeavor to reconcile
                            apparent contradictions and obvious paradoxes. To my understanding of the scriptures, Jesus,
                            per 8e, never claimed to be more than the son of man. and of the seed of David. That he was
                            susceptible to spirit impressions from his childhood, as all great mediums have been, there
                            is little doubt, but he was never Christ until after his baptism by John, when he became
                            clairvoyant and clairaudient, both seeing and hearing the divine spirit that was to possess
                            and control him. During the subsequent forty days, by fasting and prayer, he overcame the
                            evil spirit—which it seems entered him by the same law with the good — was fully developed
                            as a grand healer, with the power to cast out devils or evil spirits, and also became an
                            impressional or trance speaker, for when he appeared among them as a teacher, "they were
                            astonished at his doctrine, for he taught them as one having authority, and not as the
                            Scribes." They evidently understood his mediumship, but had no conception of the magnitude
                            of the controlling spirit. They were looking fora fulfillment of the promised Messiah, but
                            did not expect him through so humble a channel as a poor mechanic, who had been reared in
                            their own country. Peter was the first to whom the divine truth was revealed. " When Jesus
                            came into the coast of Cessarea and Phillippi, he asked his disciples, whom do men say that
                            I the son of man am ?" Please note the significance of the reply : " Some say that thou art
                            John the Baptist, some Elias, and others that thou art one of the prophets." (They were
                            willing to concede him one of these spirits.) " But whom think ye that I am ? " And Simon
                            Peter answered and said unto him, " Thou art the Christ, the Son of the living God." Then
                            Jesus perceived that Peter was clairvoyant and enthusiastically exclaimed, " Blessed art
                            thou, Simon Barjonas, for flesh and blood hath not revealed it unto thee, but my father
                            which is in Heaven, and I say unto thee that thou art Peter, and upon this rock I will build
                            my church and the gates of hell shall not prevail against it." He spoke confidently because
                            he saw that his disciples possessed the elements of mediumship of which Peter was the first
                            fruits, and he felt that through them he should be able to build a spiritual church that no
                            evil influence could subvert, " and he charged them that they should tell no man that he was
                            the Christ." Luke says at the time of his baptism, " Jesus began to be about thirty years of
                            age, being (as was supposed) the son of Joseph," which was doubtless true, since Mary his
                            mother, who should know, called Joseph his father, " Thy father and I have sought thee." So
                            then when he affirms, " I can of myself do nothing," etc., it is Jesus the son of man, but
                            when he prays, " Father glorify thou me with the glory I had with thee before the world," it
                            is Christ the son of the living God. Again when accused of casting out devils, through
                            Beelzebub, the prince of devils, he replies, " Whosoever speaketh a word against the son of
                            man, it shall be forgiven him ; but whosoever speaketh against the Holy Ghost, it shall not
                            be forgiven him in this world nor in the world to come. Could he more clearly express his
                            duality ? Say what you like against the medium, <pb n="38" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 38 8HAKEE A. 1ST I) but
                            don't dare to attack the pure spirit that controls him 1 I have great faith in Bible
                            Spiritualism. The very fact that these phenomena exist to-day, is proof positive to me that
                            they did exist eighteen hundred years ago, and the marvel is, that all Christendom does not
                            perceive the analogy; but Jesus said to his disciples, "I would not have you ignorant,
                            brethren, that this blindness has happened unto the Jews in part, that the Gentiles might be
                            brought in." Is it not thus at the present time? May not this blindness have happened unto
                            the churches in part, that Materialists, Skeptics and Infidels might be brought in ? I am
                            not impatient concerning the churches, since they dare not crucify us—still it might be well
                            for them to consider the"admonition of Gamaliel, a learned doctor of laws, a Pharisee, which
                            was, "Refrain from these men and let them alone, for if this work be of men it will come to
                            naught, but if it be of God, ye cannot overthrow it, lest haply ye be found to light against
                            God."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Saxe, S. K." TEIform="persName"/>S. K. Saxe, Salt Lake City, Utah</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faithfulness" TEIform="index"/>FAITHFULNESS</head><p TEIform="p">S, in all things which, pertain to the life that now is, as well as growth into the divine
                            life, is the Christian's duty. " If, therefore, ye have been unfaithful in the unrighteous
                            mammon, who will commit to your trust the true riches ? " was a sublime saying of Jesus, our
                            Lord and Pattern. Our first parents in Shaker history, strictly enjoined the principle of
                            Prudence, upon their followers, as essential to the Christian life. They taught that as we
                            are dependent upon the Giver of all good, — through the natural elements — for the
                            sustenance of life, therefore, it is a sin to waste, even a particle. They started poor in
                            this world's goods, with neither houses, food, nor clothing, sufficient to make them
                            comfortable. But they were rich in faith and good works. And we, by following their examples
                            of Industry and Prudence, through years of toil, have obtained comfortable homes; but
                            neither wealth, nor luxury connected therewith. It is a truthful remark, that no one would
                            become rich, by honest industry alone. The various speculations which the children of this
                            world engage in, to gain riches, are not tolerated by the teachings of Jesus, nor by the
                            life examples of the first Founders of our institution. One of the Apostles said, "They that
                            will be rich, fall into a snare ; and into many hurtful lusts, which drown men in
                            destruction and perdition." We are also admonished of the near relationship between the
                            spiritual and the temporal; that they are connected as closely as soul and body. A healthy
                            soul cannot exist in a diseased, sickly body ; and while the soul is tenanted in a mortal
                            body, it must hold a strong sympathy with it; and while possessed of physical needs, those
                            needs have a demand upon us. Our temporal possessions, which are gained by industry, and
                            consecrated to the good of all who are striving to upbuild a second Pentecostal Church of
                            Virgin Purity — United Interests — separate from worldly pride, and ambition — greatly
                            enhance our spiritual advancement. In the early days of Believers, when they were scattered
                            upon the mountains, struggling with many privations, they would, after doing a heavy day's
                            work, often travel many miles through storm and cold, to meet, with kindred spirits, at some
                            convenient place, and there renew their vows, and present their offerings unto the Lord. We,
                            of to-day, experience but little of their sufferings and privations; scarcely any, until the
                            recent catastrophe of our Sister Society, at Mt. Lebanon, which was possessed of a
                            comfortable home ; but in a few moments all was swept away by a devastating fire! We feel a
                            deep sympathy with our afflicted brethren and sisters, who through long years of toil and
                            faithfulness, had built up comfortable homes for themselves and others ; so suddenly swept
                            away in the most inclement season of the year 1 An event, which must awaken heart-felt
                            sorrow in all who are cognizant of the facts. Though suffering be our portion, and gloomy
                            the day that hangs over us, with renewed diligence, let us toil on hopefully — humbly and
                            prayerfully.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bullard, Harriet" TEIform="persName"/>Harriet Bullard, Watervliet, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let us apply our hearts unto wisdom" TEIform="index"/>"LET US APPLY OUR HEARTS UNTO WISDOM."</head><p TEIform="p">Prompted by feelings of grateful response, I dip my pen, and would give utterance to the deep
                            emotions of my heart through this medium, that they may be lovingly conveyed by the same
                            white-winged messenger that has borne so many choice and profitable words to me. One has
                            lately spoken of the benefit derived from the experience of others; so would / humbly
                            acknowledge full appreciation of the truthful life-examples, and words of wisdom, given by
                            those who have passed tho devious winding ways — the snares and pitfalls that lie in the
                            path of the youthful traveler. Just here I am reminded of the vision of Theodore, the hermit
                            of Teneriffe. Weary and worn he sat down to rest, and soon fell asleep. An angel appeared at
                            his side, and said, " Lift up thine eyes." There arose before him a mountain. " This," said
                            the angel, "is the Hill of Existence." At its base lay the ever blooming, flowery fields of
                            childhood, thronged with the gay and sportive ; all of whom were under the direct
                            guardianship of innocence. When she yielded the control of those who had outgrown her
                            charge, Reason and Religion were ready, as sure guides, to lead in the upward advance ; but
                            many had, at this period, grown impatient of control, and sought out by and forbidden paths,
                            which led to precipices, caverns, impenetrable thickets, and. dangerous ways, and in these
                            ways were seen groups of pigmies (Habits), who carried with them chains, which they
                            imperceptibly twined around those who trespassed on their ground, until they fell victims to
                            their power. Then there was great lamentation on the part of some, who beheld, in the
                            distance, those who had submitted to guidance, and traveled the straight path, happy,
                            untrammeled and free. Obedience to God's laws impressed upon our being, and a forward
                            advance in the direct line of duty, regardless of the syren's song, or fancy's fitful call
                            in opposite directions, is most assuredly the only means of attaining permanent happiness
                            and continual enjoyment. Many truthful lessons have been given by sages and seers of the
                            past and present, from which those who seek the pearls of wisdom, rather than the
                            destructive charms of wickedness, will draw morals that shall prove beneficial in educating
                            them aright. The greatest gifts of soul and mind are a cultivated conscience, and an
                            enlightened reason. Ah ! here is a great point of weakness with young people who are not
                            acting upon that " grand principle," so beautifully illustrated in a late number of our
                            little paper. In a lukewarm condition of conscience — the supreme judge of our actions —
                            natural tendencies and feelings gain the ascendancy, and the individual too often claims
                            pity, charity and sympathy, for his or her shortcomings, and willful violations of law,
                            order and right, when, in reality, a sharp reproof is needed to arouse the delinquent from
                            abnormal conditions which have arisen from thoughts and feelings averse to purity and truth.
                            " Better is the reproof of a friend than the kiss of an enemy." There is an enemy, strong
                            and subtle, that entwines the human soul like a slimy serpent. It is the filthiness of the
                            flesh. It clings to humanity with the caresses of its polluting influence — clouding, with
                            thick darkness, conscious reason — and stifling beneath the velvety cloak of its fallacious
                            arts, God-given conscience ! Under its control, souls pander to low loves and desires, till
                            they come to the condition of which Auger speaks. " There is a generation that are pure in
                            their own eyes, and yet are not washed from their filthiness." Again " There is a
                            generation, O, how lofty are their eyes ! and their eyelids are lifted up." O that young
                            people might turn the tide of life in the channel of purity, and learn from the wise and the
                            unwise as they journey along, ever remembering that, " From purity of thought, all pleasure
                            springs; And from an humble spirit, all our peace." Self-denial is the key-note to endless
                            harmonies. It strengthens every chord to the " harp of a thousand strings;" while
                            self-indulgence, with its counter action, destroys its sweetest music. We all admire a
                            perfect form, a vigorous intellect, and a pure, genial spirit; these combine to complete the
                            model man or woman. How are they attainable ? Under present imperfect organic conditions —
                            the result of disobedience to moral and physical law through successive generations — a
                            perfected being seems beyond possibility. But shall we broaden the chasm that separates the
                            two extremes, or, by self-denial, retrace lost ground, and keep the grand ideal ever before
                            us — by being self-disciplinarians ? The sooner an individual begins the work the better.
                            The promise of the Spirit is, " They that seek me early shall find me." It is this
                            determinate seeking after truth, in early life, and a practical application of the same in
                            building up character, that results in a strong and beautiful manhood and womanhood. To
                            require the indulgences of old age, while yet in youth, is to sap the roots of the tree of
                            life, whose early growth should give promise of future usefulness. Who languishes in middle
                            age, and seeks to shirk the burdens and responsibilities they should bear ? He or she, who,
                            in early life, sought out self-pleasing ways, and built not on the rock of self-discipline.
                            Now, every breeze that blows seems like a tempest; they cannot breast the billows; but seek
                            some easy place, where they can be shielded by the strong towers of righteousness. Such are
                            not fitted as leaders for the battling hosts who follow after ; neither have they strength
                            to give to those whose right it is to ask. Now ye who journey up the hill of time, Be firm
                            every step you climb •, Keep the straight path, nor ever turn aside, While purity and truth
                            your footsteps guide ; Heed the experience of the wise and true, And blessings to the end
                            shall follow you.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Martha J. Anderson, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Parasites" TEIform="index"/>PARASITES</head><p TEIform="p">We wonder, sometimes, whether the admirers of the idea, that man is as a tree, while woman is
                            best represented as a clinging vine, have sought for the wisdom as well as beauty of the
                            arrangement. To any who have ever attempted to remove from a valuable and thrifty tree, a
                            vine, which seemed bent on taking full possession, the experience must have been suggestive.
                            Tendrils, which once were soft and pliable, have become like rings of steel, and in every
                            direction, are girdling the limbs with such tenacity, that as the tree grows, they almost
                            cut into its marrow, and thus, by preventing the flow of its life juices, are hastening it
                            on to certain destruction. Are they not parasites, or too near akin to them ? Mutually
                            enfeebling each other, instead of blessing — while if the vine could have been, by favoring
                            circumstances, provided with a suitable trellis, where it could have luxuriated in the
                            sunshine and air—the natural life and stimulus of all God's animal and vegetable creation —
                            rich and luscious fruits might have crowned both their lives. " Created upright"— by
                            leaning, and thus losing the individuality she should have retained, she has not only failed
                            to develop her own powers, and those of her supporter, but dwarfed her own strength and
                            womanhood, beyond the ability for present uprightness. She must have time to put on the
                            solid growth, which comes of healthy, harmonious conditions, ere she rises to her true glory
                            and usefulness.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. Webster, Ayer, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tithe offering" TEIform="index"/>TITHE OFFERING</head><p TEIform="p">I wotTLD make a Tithe offering to our little " Monthly" which is again before me. Its pages
                            are well filled with words of wisdom, calculated to give strength, hope and encouragement,
                            to all who are striving to concentrate, in their lives and characters, those principles
                            which will practically benefit them- <pb n="39" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> BHAKERESS. selves, and bring the
                            greatest amount of good to the human race. Through this little messenger, I feel inspiration
                            ; and I bless all who are willing to employ their pens to advocate, and show their devotion
                            to the noble cause of Truth; and through self-denial and holy-living, to uphold its
                            standard, and bear aloft its shining lamp, to light the pathway of those who are seeking a
                            way out of the theological errors of the past. I would welcome all Messengers, who bring, to
                            our understanding, the new truths of the present day, and point us to the living increase of
                            the future, which we honor, and give credence to the true and good, anterior to the present.
                            I realize, that if we would be elevated from earthly conditions, into true spiritual life,
                            it must be accomplished by a growth from the old into the new; to find an abiding with the
                            pure, and an increase in all that is true. I give thanks, that through the providence of
                            God, I was permitted to hear the Gospel call, and was made a willing subject; that I
                            accepted the invitation to come out from the world — forsake the ties and relationship there
                            formed, — and to consecrate myself, body, soul and spirit, as a true Believer in Christ, and
                            live the angel life. As a reward, I have found spiritual fathers and mothers, and brothers
                            and sisters, that I love with that kind of love, which will endure when earthly loves shall
                            have passed away. To them, I am indebted for strength when I was weak; for comfort when
                            afflicted. They have guided, my footsteps, on the heavenly journey, to me, have broken the
                            bread of life, and given of their spiritual treasures. In humility, I will seek to be worthy
                            of such love, by living the true life. This can only be attained by a watchful, prayerful
                            spirit, guarding the avenues of the heart, closely interrogating the motives which lead to
                            action ; and in all the intercourse and relations of life have our influence such as will
                            leave an im press for good, and not evil. In this way, we may return blessing for blessing —
                            love for love — and by obedience, add to our faith every Gospel virtue.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Green, Louisa" TEIform="persName"/>Louisa Green, Canaan, W. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Eldress Antoinette:" TEIform="index"/>Dear Eldress Antoinette:</head><p TEIform="p">It is the commencement of a new era ; and I wish to tender to you my heartfelt thanks for
                                your faithful labors, especially, for helping to keep our little missionary craft
                                afloat, and in sailing order to bear its precious freight over the troubled waters of
                                life amid adverse winds and conflicting elements, to each destined port. I realize that
                                your duties are many, and onerous; and I pray that good Angels may continue to lend
                                their aid, and that those who are still in the form, may be ready and willing to extend
                                a helping hand, in every time of need. "Were I young, and possessed of ability, 1 would
                                not fail to contribute my share for its support. Now that I have felt the scorching
                                summer suns, and the wintry frosts of more than four score years, it is but little that
                                1 can do, except to bless, and pray that the work may prosper and be sustained—that
                                millennial light may shine through our missionary medium — the paper, sent from Mt. Lebanon, 
                                as a white winged dove, to bear good tidings. Had I the strength of a host, I
                                would give it freely to the glorious work. I see that light increases rapidly ; and I
                                sometimes almost wish to be rejuvenated, that 1 might take an active part in the labor
                                which the present day demands ; for I see beautiful fields fast ripening for the sickle,
                                and there will be need of reapers. May God strengthen the hands of those now in the
                                field, and send more laborers, who will be able and willing to do their whole duty, is
                                the prayer of your aged friend and sister in the Gospel of Christ. I would not wish any
                                to act the part of Ahimaaz — run without tidings — or before they are sent; but as a
                                lover of truth, I would ask all of Zion's daughters to not give their minds, too much,
                                to matters of less importance, to the neglect of weighty labors, and duties which lie
                                before us. Let us all guard against inaction, and be willing to sacrifice every selfish
                                motive, and work unreservedly, with unity of purpose in the one great cause of religious
                                freedom. Oneness of action is essential to success, in any cause. While we are emerging
                                from seas of conflicting elements and ideas, which surround us on every side, let us
                                keep in solid phalanx, as much as possible — keep a compact body and always try to
                                preserve the unity of the spirit. Then we shall have great strength, that will enable us
                                to perform the work needful to be done in our day and time. Progression and Conservatism
                                are two contending forces. The former is sometimes exposed to force the wheels, and
                                cause them to roll with too much velocity; while the latter, strives to clog, and hold
                                them back ! If an equilibrium can be reached, and harmony preserved, it will be a
                                desirable blessing. A great responsibility rests upon the progressive portion of the
                                community, and weighty moral obligations must also rest upon their opponents. They, who,
                                from selfish motives, would impede the progress of individuals, or society, commit a
                                great wrong. Then, let us unite in prayer, that "Wisdom may guide the helm, and bear our
                                bark over the dark waters of theological conflicts and errors, into the sea of love, and
                                help us to anchor firmly in truth that never can be shaken. I realize that my stay in
                                time must be short, and I feel grateful to my Gospel friends, for kindly greetings, and
                                for the love which I often receive from them. It shall stimulate and nerve me to more
                                earnest devotion. When I pass on to the other side of the river, I expect to continue
                                the work I have commenced here until perfect victory is attained. Lovingly — yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bathrick, Eunice" TEIform="persName"/>Eunice Bathrick, Ayer, Mass.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dispensation" TEIform="index"/>DISPENSATION:</head><p TEIform="p">Three Dispensations of Spiritual Order Were minus the female, therein ; She, who was given to
                            man for a help-meet, ' Twas said, " led from God unto sin." If woeful transgression was in
                            the beginning, And blighted, our first parents fell — Were driven from Eden,because of thei»
                            sinning— Then earth, echoes back the death knell. Sin begot sorrow, envy and malice, And sin
                            unto murder gave birth ; Cain hated his brother, and vengefully slew him, And there was
                            confusion on earth. Yet many were righteous, for that dispensation, True typical men of
                            their day; As Noah, and Abraham, Lot, Isaac and Jacob, And Enoch, with God, walked their
                            way. Joseph, was cruelly sold into Egypt, But quickly arose to a ruler's estate ; While
                            those who had sold him, with hearts void of pity, Bought then for their children, a slavery
                            great. An inhuman law cast a babe on the water; The son of a Levite was he ; From death he
                            was rescued by king Pharoah's daughter, Thus foiling the royal decree. Time, and events,
                            brought the Lord's visitation; Signs and great wonders appear, Moses, and Aaron took
                            administration, And woman remained in the rear. Israel was groaning beneath heavy burdens,
                            Their God saw them sorely distressed, Ransomed his people from Egyptian bondage, And smitten
                            were those who oppressed. For their deliverance, all Israel shouted, Glorious the Lord and
                            his ways! While Miriam went forth with her timbrels, not jdoubting The Lord's ear would list
                            to her praise. Thus joyful in freedom, the women with timbrels Now danced on the banks of
                            the sea; Signal their victory; but one is more glorious, When by it from sin we are free.
                            Moses, in meekness fulfilled his high calling; Yet once he offended his God; Therefore,
                            ne'er entered the fair land of promise Altho' he beheld it abroad. Moses departing, left
                            Joshua ruling, And Israel was blest in that day; This dynasty ended with spirits ungrateful,
                            All Israel from God turned away. Sad, sad the event; they were sold into bondage. And were
                            by the Gentiles depraved ; When woman arose, and made mighty efforts, 'Till from woeful
                            distress they were saved. Deborah, — prophetess, —judging in Israel, A mother to Israel
                            became,— Sought out a plan — and delivered her children, A type of the Mother we claim.
                            Yearly a feast of the Lord was in Shiloh. And many glad virgins there came ; Joyful in
                            dances, the latter-day virgins, Dance as the prophets proclaim. Thus, passed generations,
                            one after another, With seers both gifted and bold, The Psalmist — prophetic — in sweetest
                            of numbers Of Bride, and of Bridegroom, foretold. Thou wast anointed above all thy fellows,
                            With oil of true gladness and joy; On thy right, stood the Queen, in bright gold of Ophir,
                            And free from the earth's base alloy. Consider, O Daughter! forget thine own people, The
                            house of thy father forsake I And to this injunction the daughter was loyal, All ties with
                            her kindred to break. For greatly the King shall desire thy beauty, He is thy Lord, worship
                            thou him ; Wrought gold, is the robe, of the King's royal daughter, And she is all glorious
                            within! And unto the King —in needle-work raiment — Are virgin companions brought, too — And
                            now in the palace of sacred fruition, "^2 All things are presented anew. Look not to thy
                            fathers, but now to thy children; For princes on earth they shall be; Thou shalt be
                            remembered through all generations And praises be rendered to thee. The Lord our
                            righteousness, she shall be called, As prophets were free to declare ; Judah be saved and
                            Jerusalem dwell safely A ruler of Justice be there. Thus saith the Lord, I will shake every
                            nation The desire of all nations be one ; Also a day, which shall burn as an oven, And then
                            shall arise healing sun. Sing, sing and rejoice, O Daughter of Zionl For I, saith the Lord,
                            dwell with thee 1 And thou art the Branch, in the holy temple And in counsel of Peace thou
                            shalt be. Fear not, O thou mother, embrace thou thy children I Abide till thy quietness
                            come; Fear not thou good nurse, by the wells of salvation My hand shall establish thy home.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Agnew, Hannah A." TEIform="persName"/>Hannah A. Agnew, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thought" TEIform="index"/>A THOUGHT</head><p TEIform="p">If goodness be beauty, 'tis ours to create ; Through pleasure and duty, in Church, or in
                            State Good morals — good manners, — good influence control, Which give to life vigor, and
                            beauty to soul. One talent, first given, we have no excuse, For earth or for heaven, if not
                            put to use. One lone seed, the acorn, brings forth the great Oak; One word fitly spoken will
                            lighten a yoke. The germ for a science, the bud for a flower, Have first small beginnings,
                            and deep hidden power; Tick, tick, and this ticking, time's length march shows ; Think,
                            think, and by thinking, the human mind grows. Life, breath, and all motion have pulsation
                            small; Drops make up the ocean, and atoms earth's ball; And as we contemplate body and soul,
                            We find them but atoms in one perfect whole.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>Mary Whitcher, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Contributors should concentrate thought upon a subject..." TEIform="index"/>Contributors should concentrate thought upon a subject...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Contributors should concentrate thought upon a subject — grasp it — and when the sunshine of
                            revelation shines upon it, write, not using a single duplicate or redundant word.</p></div2><pb n="40" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Returning spring" TEIform="index"/>RETURNING SPRING</head><p TEIform="p">Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. 1. The voice of the returning Spring Bids nature wake and rise ; And put
                            her best new garments on, For she has fresh supplies. a. Then why should we, whose lines
                            have fallen, In such a pleasant place, Be backward in the praise of Him, Or e'er fall short
                            of grace? 3. We've all the eye of man could wish, And fruitful is the land; And greater than
                            Assyrian hosts, The angels round us stand. How wond'rous are the ways of God! How bountiful
                            His hand! We see His love in ev'ry tree, And broadcast o'er the land. "We ought to leap,and
                            shout,and sing, Till all the mountains round, Reverberate the joyful news, To earth's
                            remotest bound. And yet, to many thousands more, We such a home could give; If they would
                            leave a carnal world. And learn in Christ to live.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Consecration" TEIform="index"/>CONSECRATION</head><p TEIform="p">the varied vocations to which those are called, whose labors and interests support the
                            isolated relationships of the natural order,— even in the most legitimate manner, are merely
                            tithe-offering to the Supreme Being, who is Love and Harmony, in their broadest, deepest
                            meaning. All the obligations of that relationship are ever in conflict with the expansion of
                            soul, which reaches upward to God, and outward to humanity — which would enlarge its sphere
                            to a universal brotherhood, for which all private interests must be renounced. As the
                            volcanic fire, that silently, yet persistently, continues its dissolving work beneath the
                            crust of earth steadily gathers force, then bursts forth with resistless power, often
                            producing great changes in the surrounding surface — so we perceive, by glances over
                            history's pages, that the power of Religion has been as a vital fire in the human heart; for
                            a time, quietly operating within, changing, disuniting, and melting the carved images of the
                            mind, the iron bands of creed — then, with accumulated force, breaking through the crust
                            that theological and political organizations have formed over the soul — effecting upheavals
                            and revolutions in the world of thought. Thus change succeeding change, wrought through the
                            suffering witnesses for truth, has ushered in the dawn of the Millennium. The records of the
                            past century acquaint us with the time and events of the organization of a 'new religious
                            system — based on principles of eternal progress, in which God might have a people dwelling
                            in a superior relationship, — wherein ^A^-offering would give place to full consecration of
                            the whole being to His service, for the blessing of humanity, in a life free from all bands
                            that fetter the soul, or cause any compromise with selfish interests. A prophet, of olden
                            time, alluded to a day that should be as the light of seven days; a beautiful illustration
                            of the consummation of the Gospel work, when the " seven seals" shall have been opened, and
                            the " seven thunders" shall have uttered their voices, through progressive mediums of truth.
                            The first thunder— Virgin Purity and Community of Interest — has rolled through the heavens
                            with mighty power! and they, whose consciences and aspirations were quickened for the higher
                            life, cheerfully obeyed its voice, and found the baptism of Christ-Love, through which they
                            were directed to establish a beautiful Consecrated Home — to lay the foundation of the work
                            of human redemption — by, and through a decisive testimony against a carnal life, that was
                            their mission and their toil. Those, first called to that work, have been reaped, by the
                            sickle of Time, to their spirit home ; but they still live; and, united with other
                            spiritually progressed souls of a corresponding order, there seek to inspire those who
                            inherit the fruition of their labors, and to perpetuate with increase, the truths to which
                            their lives were dedicated. Only through consecration and sacrifice has truth been attained,
                            and placed on the altar of service, as a blessing to posterity; and thus may we become the
                            recipients and ministers of increasing degrees, that not only draw closer the reins of
                            self-discipline, but give souls corresponding liberty. Violated law places human beings in
                            bondage to many diseases and abnormal appetites ; at present, a condition almost universal.
                            To understand and remove the causes of these, seems highly important, as an underlying and
                            preceding work of future progress. Do we not need aid from the heavens, to accomplish this 1
                            — the vivid lightnings to awaken slumbering energies, and the voice of a Second Thunder, in
                            testimony against those transgressions of physiological law, to which multitudes are victims
                            ? We are debtors to our predecessors ; and it remains for us, who are in the strength of
                            youth, to reach forward for their ministrations, that we may extend the work which they so
                            nobly began, and make our Consecration a blessing to ourselves, and to others.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/>Catharine Allen, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Curbed be the spirit that would dauntless be..." TEIform="index"/>Curbed be the spirit that would dauntless be...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Curbed be the spirit that would dauntless be, In the fierce strife of crushing out the truth
                            — the light of age, the guiding star of youth — the priceless pearl of life and liberty.
                            Dark would be earth, had truth no victory won ; still dull monotony would beat her round,
                            while spirits wrapt in stoic sense profound, would, like the glacier, coldly spurn the sun.
                            Then shine, O glorious truth ! forever bright; pursue thy course even to the nether sphere,
                            till Superstition's altars disappear, and error quails, and cowers in trembling fear; till
                            love of right displaces rule of wrong, and in thy triumph earth is filled with light. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., Martha" TEIform="persName"/>Martha A.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Richmond, William" TEIform="index"/>William Richmond
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Richmond, William" TEIform="persName">William Richmond</persName>, February 20, 1875, aged
                                65, Union Village, Ohio.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Yarrington, Joseph" TEIform="index"/>Joseph Yarrington
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Yarrington, Joseph" TEIform="persName">Joseph Yarrington</persName>, March 15,1875, aged
                            77.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hawk, Thomas" TEIform="index"/>Thomas Hawk
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Hawk, Thomas" TEIform="persName">Thomas Hawk</persName>, March 20,1875, aged 55.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hayes, Edward" TEIform="index"/>Edward Hayes
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Hayes, Edward" TEIform="persName">Edward Hayes</persName>, February 16, l87o, aged 11.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sherman, Manley" TEIform="index"/>Manley Sherman
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Sherman, Manley" TEIform="persName">Manley Sherman</persName>, February 21, 1875, aged
                            75.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Carter, Eliza" TEIform="index"/>Eliza Carter
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Carter, Eliza" TEIform="persName">Eliza Carter</persName>, February 25,1875, aged 80.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hunter, William" TEIform="index"/>William Hunter
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Hunter, William" TEIform="persName">William Hunter</persName>, March 27,1875, aged 74,
                                Watervliet, N. Y.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Persons, Elizabeth" TEIform="index"/>Elizabeth Persons and Betsey Maynard
                                
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Errata — Elizabeth Persons and Betsey Maynard, in April number, should be Harvard,
                                    Mass.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker music books" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER MUSIC BOOKS</head><p TEIform="p"> For the use of schools among Believers. Contains all the pieces that have appeared in the
                            Shaker and Shakeress and some forty new songs. A beautiful book. Published by Weed, Parsons
                            &amp; Co. Price 40 cents.</p></div2><div2 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">NOVITIATE ELDERS AND ELDRESSES. Elders. Elder F. W. Evans.................. " G. A.
                            Lomaa................. " James Goodwin............. " Simon Mabee................. " Robert
                            Aikin................. A. J. Battles................. Wm. Leonard................ Daniel
                            Frazer ............... Henry CumtninQs............ B.H. Smith.................. J. B.
                            Vance.................. Nehemiah Trull.............. J.S. Prescott................. Isaac
                            Beals............... Jacob Kulp................... John R. Cooper............. Ezra
                            Sherman.............. Stephen Ball.................. Post-office Address. Mt. Lebanon,
                            Columbia county, N. Y. Shakers, Albany county, N. Y........ Sonyea, Livingston county, N.
                            Y..... West Pittsfield, Mass................. Thompsonville, Conn................. South
                            Lee, Mass............... ...... Ayer, Mass............................ Shirley Village,
                            Mass.................. Enfield, N. H.......,.................. Shaker Village, N.
                            H.................. Alfred, Me............................ West Gloucester, Me..........
                            ....... Cleveland (Shakers), O................ Lebanon (Shakers), O.................
                            Pleasant Hill, Ky...................... South Union, Ky............, ........ Preston,
                            Hamilton county, 0...... Dayton (Shakers), 0...............__ Eldresses. Eldress Antoinette
                            Doolittle. " Harriet M. Bullard. " Abigail Crosman. " Caroline Helfrige. u Anna Ervin.
                            Harriet Storer. Nancy Fairbanks. Lucretia Godfrey. Hannah Taylor. Harriet March. Eliza
                            Smith. Hannah Davis. Prudence Sawyer. Susannah Farnham. Betsy Svalding. Sarah Small. Betsy
                            G. Gass. Adaline Wills.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>