<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0506" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><date value="18750601" TEIform="date">June 1875</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">41-48</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="41" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">Vol. V. No. 6. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. F" IsditI^8' Mt- Lebanon Col. Co. N. Y. June
                        1875. Sixty Cents per annum.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trees of life" TEIform="index"/>TREES OF LIFE</head><p TEIform="p">(Rev. 22,1.) " He showed me a pure river of water of life, clear as crystal, proceeding out
                            of the throne of God and of the Lamb." This river was Truth— abstract Truth. On either side
                            of the river, a tree of life, bearing fruit; and " the leaves of the tree, on one side, were
                            for the healing of the nations, and there shall be no more curse." The Natural and Spiritual
                            Orders are here set forth in a vivid and very striking manner. First, the Natural, or
                            Reproductive Order — now under so much curse — is to be healed, and the curse removed. All
                            truth, thereto pertaining, will be in practical operation, creating a millennial state.
                            Over-population, Famine, War, Prostitution of life powers, Physical disease, Poverty, and
                            mental infirmities shall cease to be. Like Moses, the people shall become servants of God.
                            Faithful in all the household of nature, on the earth plane, they will sing the song of
                            Moses — truth, in all things relating to the body. They shall see the God of generation,
                            face to face. Man and Woman, being equal in legislation, will observe the true Sexual laws,
                            protected by Statute, in the New Earth. The Land will be held by government, for the benefit
                            of the people. To live, all must eat, and food can come only from the land. So shall all who
                            eat, labor, and not consume the food of other people. Peace and Plenty will abound — there
                            being no more curse. On the opposite side of the river of Truth — of Life — will be the
                            Spiritual Tree of Life — the Resurrection Order. In this Order are the pure in heart, who
                            see God — the God of celibacy — Christ Spirits. Jesus saw Him and Her. Their life is cut off
                            from the earth. They neither look, nor think, upon the opposite Sex, to desire them in
                            physical reproduction. These see Christ, face to face, and His and Her character is written
                            in their foreheads, and throughout their whole physical system. Like Christ Angels, their
                            sexual relation is purely Spiritual. Their Lord and God give them Light, and they shall
                            reign forever —¦ not over the lusts of the flesh and mind only, but over the generative life
                            itself. Pure Truth, from the Heaven of Heavens — the inner Seventh Sphere — the esse of
                            creation — will flow to them continually. Christ, the Lord God of the holy Prophets, sent
                            his Angel, one of the ancient Prophets, to John, to reveal to him a view of the two Orders,
                            of which, the Prophets and Prophetesses, of all nations, had spoken, under various types and
                            symbols —that Truth would become incarnated upon Earth — the Kingdom of God would come, in
                            which the will of God would be done upon Earth, as in the Christ Heaven. These two Orders
                            will balance each other. Depopulating agencies will be no longer needful. Natural increase,
                            in the Earthly Order will be held in check by the rational faculty, which will deter a human
                            pair,from conferring life, unless that life be a blessing. And the Spiritual Order will
                            balance the reproductive principle, by celibacy. Truth will come, whose right it is to
                            reign. Blessed are they who do his commandments, that they may have right to the tree of
                            Spiritual Life — Life, eternal, as the Throne of God. Was ever more beautiful vision
                            presented to human soul ? A pure river of water of life, flowing down from the Throne of
                            God, through the mouth of all the Prophets and Seers, since the world began, coming into
                            holy souls, who will receive truth, in the love of truth.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unborn poetry" TEIform="index"/>UNBORN POETRY</head><p TEIform="p">There is a river that makes glad the City of our God. Passing over the river is not to die,
                            With outstretched limbs in state to lie. For as a man thinketh so is be, In time or in
                            Eternity. To die is a change that none forego, The Peasant, the King, the friend and foe, go
                            hastening on in weal and woe, to the land of Ghosts, which none may know. Know as we know
                            the things of earth, In manhood, youth, and back to birth. Mystery of mysteries From the
                            beginning! Why do we live, love? Why keep on sinning? Where did we come from ? Whither go
                            we, Men, Women and Children, Bond and free ? To die is not to pass over the river, for still
                            we live — live on forever. But there is a river that never's dry, That none may pass over
                            until they die. Die to the life that reproduces, The race of man without abuses. The end has
                            come, the summer is ended. The harvester, Death, with life is blended. Life — Eternal Life,
                            From the throne of God, The Lamb was the first, the first who trod The banks of that river,
                            The river of God. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Ed.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Protest" TEIform="index"/>A PROTEST</head><p TEIform="p">How are we going to sustain morality enough for a foundation to build the principles of
                            Christianity upon 1 It is now twenty-four years since I first imbibed the principles of a
                            Shaker life. In that time there have been over one hundred children brought into our Society
                            with the expectations of making members, adopting the faith and principles of a Christian
                            life. And to-day, out of that number I count four males and ten females; the balance have
                            turned again to seek Esau's portion. The question arises, What is the cause? The response
                            must be, a greater love for sensuality than for a life of Virgin Purity. And shall the
                            responsibility rest upon the parents for the low state of morals ? A question which can
                            easily be answered by one who has had much deal with children. Jesus said by the Fruit the
                            tree is known. And so it is in the work of generation. Parents, who violate the Order of
                            nature, in a total disregard to times and seasons, in their work of generation, must expect
                            the fruit brought forth will be of a disorderly character—dwarfs, deformed, sensual and may
                            be devilish, to the degree that they have allowed their lower passions to rule and govern
                            them, in the work of generation. Corrupted and abused as those functions are, they are still
                            supported and maintained by professors of Christianity, by legal ceremony under the name of
                            divine institution. Where is the evidence that the nature of the act is purified, or the
                            shame taken away by snch means ? For although the Most Reverend and pious divines may exert
                            all their piety and all their divinity to gospelize it in their sermons — legalize it in
                            their marriage ceremonies — sanctify it by their fervent prayers — they can neither take
                            away the shame of the act nor purify the nature of it. Not long since I heard a woman state,
                            in public assembly, the following. Placing herself between a company of Shakers and a
                            company that were not of our faith, she said : " I have been thinking, since I came here, If
                            Jesus Christ should rise up among us and draw the dividing line, which side he would choose
                            for His followers ? " These friends clad in a plain uniform dress manifest the spirit that
                            actuates them. " The dress /have on is not one of my own choice. I would choose to dress,
                            differently. It was imposed upon me contrary to my feelings. But you know, sisters
                            (addressing those of her own life), the scorn heaped upon any one that dares to be out of
                            fashion is enough to crush a body. This is my first visit. I came yesterday from the City of
                            New York — the Great Babylon, where the ministers are to-day discussing the social question
                            in terms of greatest smoothness and soft words, so as not to offend the delicacy of their
                            hearers. I'll tell you how it is, friends. Many that you see decked in so gay attire are too
                            poor to pay for those dresses, and so they sell their bodies to get what they call Pin
                            money." Then turning to the males, she said : " You men (brothers) make laws against
                            Adultery, and then hire your sisters to break them." This is but a short clause of the words
                            uttered, that seemed like awful truths. And I would that all could have heard them, who are
                            still pleading for carnal gratification on the animal plane. As we live a celibate life —A
                            life of Virgin Purity — as a matter of necessity we draw, from you, material to sustain our
                            institution. And, dear friends, we want something besides animals to be our successors, to
                            hand down to mankind this heavenly gospel treasure that we hold so dear in our hearts — A
                            life Of Virgin Purity. In love.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barrett, Andrew" TEIform="persName"/>Andrew Barrett, Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society removed" TEIform="index"/>SOCIETY REMOVED.</head><p TEIform="p">THETyringham Society of Shakers has removed to the Enfield Society, Connecticut.</p></div2><div2 type="book-notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker music book" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER MUSIC BOOK.</head><p TEIform="p"> Price, 40 cents —may be ordered from Weed, Parsons &amp; Co., 41 Columbia street,
                            Albany, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="42" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Swedish letter" TEIform="index"/>[From a co-worker in the Gospel Workshop.] SWEDISH LETTER</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Frederick: I feel very much indebted to your ability and sacrificing spirit.
                            Pray, accept my humble contribution as a member of a little over two years, drawn on by the
                            spirit of religious communism, that does favor the downfall of aristocratic principles,
                            which comprise all evils. Luxury, the murderer of real happiness — Ignorance, indolence,
                            idleness and slothfulness, as co-operators, predominate. Shaker — Soldier of the crusade of
                            the present century — teach — learn the worldling how to subdue the love of money — Mammon —
                            the seducer of honest men, women and children. Shaker, make them acquainted, first of all,
                            with crusader's discipline — a requirement of male and female, that they may understand that
                            there is a certain standard of intelligence to be obtained by being obedient to Orders,
                            essentially necessary to be maintained — as Elder William Reynolds says — a solid ground to
                            stand on. Some libertines object to it, calling it absolutism. Nature, itself, ia absolute.
                            Time is absolute — therefore, we must have Law — Liberty — God. Often, I ask myself, Where
                            are you ? Among Godly people — or in the serpent's or lion's den? I care nothing for such a
                            bugbear as anathema and outlawry of a narrow-minded Christian professor, a mere pretender,
                            but look upon time as an empty field, wherein nothing good will grow itself. We must, first
                            of all, till and build up, with our own hands and muscles, and whatever we then sow, in that
                            field, we will, with God's aid, then reap. In that field pray — in that field work, and the
                            heavenly blessing will join to labor — and if God be with us, who will be against us 1 O, ye
                            wicked ones 1 tiresome it is to you, through care and labor, to gain your daily bread, that
                            you may live comfortably ! Well, then, meet the evil of the time, with the prudence of the
                            wise. Learn to spare, and you will be rich. Learn to be modest with little, and you will
                            observe abundance. Learn to be saving in housekeeping, with what we earn ourselves, and we
                            will never be in pressing wants. But how ? Is it hard for us to dispense with certain
                            indulgences ? Are we servants to our palates ? slaves to our comforts ? O, if we cannot
                            break such fetters then are we worthy of only slave wages — worthy to sink into poverty and
                            reproach. No one will save us, if we do not want to save ourselves, and we, ourselves, will
                            feel it. Our consciences will tell us that. If we don't deny ourselves, we ignore wisdom —
                            we cannot be Christians. True wisdom is in God — comes from God — leads to God — and rests
                            in God. Wisdom makes friends of God. Where wisdom turns in, there is God. Wisdom and Love
                            have Their Habitation. May they inspire and comfort you. Your Brother, in spirit of sympathy
                            and love.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Audler, Carl G." TEIform="persName"/>Carl O. Audler, South Union, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mediatorial confession" TEIform="index"/>MEDIATORIAL CONFESSION</head><p TEIform="p">" He that covereth his sins shall not prosper, but whoso confesseth and forsaketh his sins
                            shall find mercy." From whom does man seek to cover his sins ? Surely not from Him unto
                            whose eyes " all things are naked and open," but from his fellow mortals. If the private
                            deeds of a person's life will not bear the scrutiny of a righteous man or woman, who lives
                            innocently before God and mankind, how will they come to Him whose presence is a consuming
                            fire to all iniquity — to Him who dwelleth in the light which no man can see nor approach
                            unto, and retain a carnal life within him ? Would not such feel as did the children of
                            Israel when they said to Moses " Let ua not hear again the voice of the Lord our God,
                            neither let us see His great fire any more. Speak thou with us and we will hear, but let not
                            God speak with us lest we die." And the Lord said to Moses " They have spoken well. I will
                            raise them up a Prophet from among their Brethren, and I will put my words in his mouth, and
                            he shall speak unto them all that I shall command him." Accordingly, Jesus testified " The
                            Father gave me a commandment what I should say and what I should speak, and I know that His
                            commandment is life everlasting. Whatsoever I speak, therefore, even as the Father said unto
                            me, so I speak." This faithful witness taught " He that doeth evil hateth the light, neither
                            coineth to the light, lest his deeds should be reproved," or made manifest. This is
                            confirmed by tracing the effect of transgression. There was first a sense of shame or guilt;
                            next a desire to conceal their shame from each other; and third a desire to hide from the
                            light of their superior, which would make manifest or reprove their sin. This is history,
                            not only of the first pair in Eden, but of all their posterity to this day. Hence, when the
                            light and knowledge of " the beginning " (termed the Ancient of Daps because it is the light
                            of the most ancient principles which existed before all things created) is revived and
                            received in the soul, it first reproves or convicts it of sin; and the first step that can
                            be taken to regain union with God is to voluntarily remove the covering by honestly bringing
                            all sin to the light of God in His witnesses (whose works are wrought in and of the light,
                            or they cannot be true witnesses), with a firm resolution to forsake them forever. This
                            destroys the false covering of hypocrisy by which the enemy tries to hide, not only from
                            others -but from ourselves also. For souls to rehearse their evil deeds shamelessly, without
                            desire for repentance, to comrades or confederates is not confession, but only adding
                            darkness to darkness. God has promised to " stain the pride of all flesh;" and what can more
                            effectually accomplish this than "to expose its filthiness and hypocrisy to that light which
                            it stands most in fear of ? This process, so simple that a child is able to comprehend it,
                            is found by experience to affect the chief adversary of the soul as the stone from David's
                            sling affected the proud champion of the enemies of Israel— it lays him low. Therefore,
                            those who have experienced the effect of genuine confession to God in His witnesses, need
                            none of this reasoning. Some, who admit the propriety of confessing sin, object to the
                            presence of living witnesses— confessing to man as they term it. Let such candidly examine
                            their hearts and see if the principal objection does not lie in the cross. If so, the
                            benefit will be in proportion, as it will constitute an equal barrier against subsequent
                            transgression. Moreover, this is strong evidence that the requirement is not of human, but
                            of Divine origin. Let us look a little further into this matter. It appears evident that
                            principles have no power to manifest only as they are embodied in organization. At least,
                            such is their presentation to us. Organization requires superiority of parts, that there may
                            be harmony and concert in action. For without superiority there can be no dependence, and
                            without dependence no government or controlling center of unity and interest. Again,
                            distinct orders of principles require distinct forms of organization for their complete and
                            distinct manifestation. Thus mineral and vegetable organizations are not adapted to
                            principles of intelligent action. In the animal creation inferior to man, none are adapted
                            to manifest reasoning intelligence, and much less religious sentiment and moral
                            responsibility. But man, as representative of the Creator, combines all previous
                            manifestations, and more also. Though many inferior objects of Creation surpass man in the
                            exhibition of particular qualities — as certain animals in strength and fleetness — and the
                            operations of the elements in magnitude and power of effect, yet man is found superior in
                            that he possesses an intelligence which is able to comprehend all and even compel them to
                            servitude— while no other visible object, nor all of them together, can comprehend man nor
                            enslave him. Hence we find in man the highest visible manifestation of Intelligent Deity.
                            Yet man, enslaved by his sensual nature, hating the light which would expose and reprove his
                            sin, and fearing the loss of its pleasures, is far more likely to form of his fallen
                            affections an " Image (or imagination) of the beast," before which to offer up his
                            adorations, than he is to discern the Image and likeness of the God. "For where the true
                            treasure is, there will the heart be also," and " without holiness no man shall see the
                            Lord." It is, therefore, in vain for man to look for God as a Dispenser of forgiveness and
                            salvation from sin, except in His duly accredited messengers or purified Saints, before whom
                            as the Judgment seat of Christ, the covering must be taken off and all things made manifest.
                            The Faithful and True Witness has declared " There is nothing covered that shall not be
                            revealed, neither hid that shall not be known." The covering referred to is hypocrisy, of
                            which he had just cautioned his disciples to beware. "And there is nothing secret which
                            shall not be made manifest." " That which makes manifest is light. He that doeth
                            righteousness cometh to the light, that his deeds may be made manifest that they are wrought
                            in God. He that dwelleth in God, dwelleth in light, and all his works are open, going
                            beforehand to Judgment. For God is Light, and in Him is no darkness at all." Know ye not
                            that the Saints shall judge the world ? "And ye shall sit on twelve thrones, judging the
                            twelve tribes of [spiritual] Israel." It alters not the purpose nor the wisdom of God that
                            the sacred mediatorial office has been usurped by the false Prophet that succeeded the fall
                            of the Primitive Church, and abused by false Christs.who profess to teach in Christ's name
                            but deny him in works. Both characters were foretold and described by the true Witness, and
                            the prediction has been amply verified through many centuries to the present day. But the
                            fact of a counterfeit affirms the existence of the genuine original — and the latter cannot
                            be debased nor its virtue and efficiency diminished by a spurious imitation, however well
                            executed. And however highly esteemed the spurious may be, in the absence of the genuine, it
                            should not deceive those who possess the genuine. It must fall into disrepute and neglect,
                            wherever the genuine prevails.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo" TEIform="persName"/>Alonzo Hollister, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="World" TEIform="index"/>THE WORLD</head><p TEIform="p">" Be of good cheer, for I have overcome the world," was a saying of Jesus, to his disciples.
                            John says, " The lust of the flesh, the lust of the eye and the pride of life are of the
                            icorld." All Christians may overcome the world, in the same way, and by the same spirit, in
                            and by which Jesus overcame it — by the Christ Spirit. " Ye are not of the world, even as I
                            am not of the world, for I have chosen you out of the world; therefore, the world — they
                            that are of the world — hateth you." The hereditary passions and propensities of human
                            beings, are evil treasures which all inherit from ancestry. To overcome them, is to lay up
                            treasures in Heaven, where moth cannot corrupt, nor thieves steal. Generation, and
                            Regeneration, are two distinct principles, which cannot be permanently mixed. One or the
                            other will prevail. No man can serve both, and serve God, to his acceptance. The married man
                            and woman care for the things of this world — how he and she may please wife and husband.
                            The unmarried, for conscience sake, care for the Lord, to be holy, in body, as well aa in
                            spirit. Such live a pure, holy life, for the kingdom of heaven's sake. Let all nominal
                            Christians, who are blending flesh and spirit, examine themselves, and see whether they be
                            in the faith, or no. If the Spirit of Christ be in them, they are not reprobate to the lives
                            of the Apostles, nor to that of Jesus, their Lord and master. And how far will they then be
                            from being Shakers ?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mabee, Simon" TEIform="persName"/>Simon Mabee, Hancock, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Two witnesses" TEIform="index"/>Two witnesses
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Two witnesses—Brothers Thomas Smith and Charles Sizer, of the two Canaan Families, having
                            attended four Seances at the Eddy's, attest the reality of over thirty apparitions from the
                            Spirit world.</p></div2><pb n="43" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Almost a Christian" TEIform="index"/>ALMOST A CHRISTIAN</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Elder Frederick : How sad it is that the pleasures of this world and its fashions should
                            have such a blinding influence, and hold in worse than Adamantine Chains so many souls who
                            otherwise might become bright and shining ornaments, if not substantial pillars in the Zion
                            of God on earth. Below is the substance of a note left with us bv an inquirer, showing how
                            near a person may come to a realization of his duty and yet fail to make the requisite
                            sacrifice to obtain the pearl of great price—the enduring treasure. "As this is the most
                            important step that can be taken in life, I feel that it ought not to be taken without deep
                            consideration. " Earnestly desiring to find truth, yet I have no desire to hastily arrive at
                            conclusions which I may afterward regret, I feel that my knowledge of Shakerism is not large
                            enough to govern me in taking a step which should, when once taken, be life-long in its
                            duration. " I freely admit that the faith of the Shakers has impressed me favorably, and it
                            appears to me to be the only true and just way of solving the great problems that agitate
                            the public mind. All my impressions have been favorable, yet I am undecided. The importance
                            of the step makes me hesitate before I take it. I have no wish to put my hand to the plow
                            and then draw back. " When I look at the importance of the step which involves the giving up
                            of the ambitions and dreams of youth, a separation from the busy world, its many
                            attractions, and a long farewell to friends, I feel more than ever the need of divine
                            assistance to guide me to a right decision. " To substitute, for worldly hopes and
                            ambitions, the quiet and retired life of a Shaker, and to live a life founded upon the
                            highest and most divine part of man's nature, is indeed a noble aim. To carry into every-day
                            life principles so high and lofty as to discard self, must require a strong measure of faith
                            in those who do it. I wish my faith and zeal were equal to it." We trust that young man may
                            not have to grope his way ^through the wilderness of sin, and in twenty or more years find
                            he has been chasing an empty bubble, and regret that he had not had moral courage to break
                            away from the world while he had health, strength and ability to battle for the truth and
                            right. With Love unfeigned we greet you. Unbounded thanks for the pleasurable interview and
                            kind entertainment received during our recent visit to your abode. May the blessing of
                            Heaven be with you all. And may the sad afflictions which have befallen your society be
                            overruled to our ultimate good — as a people — in an increase of wisdom, charity and
                            unflinching devotion to the pure Gospel of Jesus and Ann, Is the Prayer of your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitely, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Whitely, Ayer, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbath of sabbaths" TEIform="index"/>THE SABBATH OF SABBATHS</head><p TEIform="p">The student of Jewish history finds much of interest to attach him to the fact that a power
                            above the selfishness of man was in constant exercise, working for the resurrection of that
                            peculiar people of the Judean period. I say constantly working; for although set times were
                            indicated when the results of this unselfish power should be especially manifested, yet, ere
                            the next anniversary for the manifestation of the same humanitarian spirit arrived, the
                            influence of its predecessor had not become extinct. And although there has been a
                            scattering of the Israelites, and the hands of many nations have been turned against the
                            Jews, yet we find that the influence of their Sabbaths has apparently become an innate
                            principle, so that a Jew has, if able, ever been ready to help a brother Jew. We have, among
                            professedly Christian people, a day intended to correspond with the seventh or Sabbath — the
                            Lord's day. We wonder, realizing how nearly universal is the practice to abstain from
                            physical employment on that day, that the mental powers do not present to the people why
                            this should be called the Lord's day; and whether the constant recurrence of the Sabbath is
                            a reminder of the fact that we should so live on that day as the Lord would have us live
                            every day. Is our Christian Sabbath any thing more, generally speaking, than a cessation
                            from physical employment ? Does it compare with the beauteous unselfishness that illustrated
                            the ancient Jewish Sabbaths ? Let us see. " Six days thou shalt labor and do all thy work,
                            the seventh thou shalt rest," etc.; and the etcetera was loving thy neighbor as thyself, the
                            rich feeding and administering to the wants of the poor — a reminder of the time when there
                            should be no rich nor poor. Six months were had for me and mine, but the seventh was a holy
                            convocation, during which the higher law of love was in such exercise that the estimation of
                            neighbor above self was in excess till the month ended. Again, six years were allotted to
                            the development of self; during which debtor, creditor, master and slave were, with the
                            above exceptions, the rule. But the seventh was the Sabbatical year, when all debts were
                            canceled and all slaves were free; the land was permitted to rest, and the free spontaneous
                            growth thereof belonged to who should gather it. After seven times seven years came the
                            fiftieth — the Sabbath of Sabbaths. Now were all debts forgiven, all slaves were made free,
                            and the land, the source of all wealth, with property of every description — all reverted
                            back to the people at large, and selfishness became severely shocked. In these Christian
                            days do we not need some of these Sabbatical occasions, at least, to fulfill the beautiful
                            law of loving our neighbors equally with ourselves ? And would not we be nearer the
                            millennial times if the Sabbath of Sabbaths had, for several centuries, been in active
                            illustration upon every fiftieth year ? We are aware that there would be much weeping, some
                            wailing and gnashing of teeth, at the prospect and during the exercise of the power of this
                            Sabbath ; and we doubt not the Jews of old suffered all the pangs of crucifixion to self
                            during this year of godly reproof; but are we, after the better law of Jesus has been
                            preached for centuries, not as able to meet it and to submit to its excellent and universal
                            blessings ? Or are we content with taking a step backward, and glad to console ourselves
                            with the idea that such procedures are now impracticable ? Heaven forbid that there was any
                            good thing practiced by the peculiar people of God in ancient times, that Christians can
                            discard with impunity, until we can substitute something in its stead. W'hat have we
                            substituted for the Sabbath of Sabbaths ?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. Lomas, Shakers, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Natural rights vs. governmental usurpation" TEIform="index"/>NATURAL RIGHTS vs. GOVERNMENTAL
                            USURPATION</head><p TEIform="p">In a letter to James Madison, dated Paris, September 6, 1789, Thomas Jefferson says: "The
                            question, whether one generation of men has a right to bind another, seems never to have
                            been started either on this or our side of the water. Yet it is a question of such
                            consequence as not only to merit decision, but a place also among the fundamental principles
                            of every government. The course of reflection in which we are immersed here, on the
                            elementary principles of society, has presented this question to my mind; and that no such
                            obligation can be transmitted, I think, very capable of proof. I set out on this ground,
                            which I suppose to be self evident, that the earth belongs in usufruct totheliving: that the
                            dead have neither powers nor rights over it. The portion occupied by any individual ceases
                            to be his when he himself ceases to be, it reverts to society. If society has formed no
                            rules for the appropriation of its lands In severalty, it will be taken by the first
                            occupant, and these will generally be the wife and children of the decedent. If they have
                            formed rules of appropriation, those rules may give it to the wife and children, or to some
                            one of them, or to the legatee of the deceased So they may give it to his creditor. But the
                            child, the legatee or creditor takes it not by natural right, but by a law of the society of
                            which he is a member, and to which he is subject. Thus, no man can, by natural right, oblige
                            the lands he occupied, or the persons who succeed him in that occupation, to the payment of
                            debts contracted by him. For if he could, he might, during his own life, eat up the usufruct
                            of the lands for several generations to come; and then the lands would belong to the dead,
                            and not to the living, which is the reverse of our principle. * * * " Suppose Louis the XIV,
                            and Louis the XV had contracted debts in the name of the French nation to the amount of ten
                            thousand milliards, and that the whole had been contracted in Holland. The interest on this
                            sum would be five hundred milliards, which is the whole rent-roll or net proceeds of the
                            territory of France. Must the present generation retire from the territory in which nature
                            produces them and cede it to' the Dutch creditors ? No ; they have the same right over the
                            soil on which they were produced as the preceding generations had. They derive their rights
                            not from them, but from nature. They, then, and their soil are, by nature, clear of the
                            debts of their predecessors. To present this in another point of view : suppose Louis XV and
                            his cotemporary generation had said to the money lenders of Holland, 'Give us money that we
                            may eat, drink and be merry in our day ; and on condition that you will demand no interest
                            until the end of thirty years, you shall then forever after receive an annual interest of
                            fifteen per cent.' The money is lent on these conditions, is divided among the people,
                            eaten, drunk and squandered. Would the present generation be obliged to apply the produce of
                            the earth and of their labor to replace their dissipation ? Not at all. * * * " On similar
                            ground it may be proved that no society can make a perpetual constitution, or even a
                            perpetual law. The earth belongs always to the living generation ; they may manage it, then,
                            and what proceeds from it, as they please during their usufruct. They are masters, too, of
                            their own persons, and consequently may govern them as they please. But persons and property
                            make the sum of the objects of government." In a letter to Dr. Gem, Jefferson says: " Buffon
                            gives us a table of twenty-three thousand nine hundred and ninety-four deaths, stating the
                            ages at which they happened. To draw from these the result I have occasion for, I suppose a
                            society in which twenty-three thousand nine hundred and ninety-four persons are born every
                            year, and live to the age stated in Button's table. Then the following inferences may be
                            drawn: Such society will consist, constantly, of six hundred and seventeen thousand seven
                            hundred and three persons, of all ages. Of those living at any one instant of time, one-half
                            will be dead in twenty-four years and eight months. In such a society, ten thousand six
                            hundred and seventy-flve will arrive every year at the age of twenty-one years complete. It
                            will constantly have three hundred and forty-eight thousand four hundred and seventeen
                            persons, of all ages above twenty-one years; and the half of those of twenty-one years and
                            upward living at any one instant of time will be dead in eighteen years and eight months, or
                            say nineteen years. Then the contracts, constitutions and laws of every such society become
                            void in nineteen years from their date." In a letter to John W. Eppes, dated June 24, 1813,
                            Jefferson says: " The earth belongs to the living, not to the dead. The will and power of
                            man expire with his life by nature's law " In a letter to Major John Cartwright, dated June
                            5,1824, Jefferson says : " Can one generation bind another, and all others in succession
                            forever? I think not. The Creator has made the earth for the benefit of the living, not the
                            dead. Bights and powers can only belong to persons, not to things. * * * a generation may
                            bind itself as long as its majority continues in life ; when that has disappeared, another
                            majority is in place, hold all the rights and powers their predecessors once held, and may
                            change their laws and institutions to suit themselves. Nothing, then, is unchangeable but
                            the inherent and inalienable rights of man." Equity.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hudson donation" TEIform="index"/>HUDSON DONATION</head><p TEIform="p">By unanimous vote, the citizens of Hudson have presented a beautiful hand lire engine to the
                            New Lebanon Society of Shakers. Accepting this timely and appropriate present, the brethren
                            and sisters return heartfelt thanks to their friends in Hudson. To the Mt. Lebanon
                            fraternity it will be a standing memento of friendship.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="War is in utter violation of Christianity..." TEIform="index"/>War is in utter violation of Christianity...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">War is in utter violation of Christianity. If war be right, then Christianity is wrong —false
                            — a lie. But if Christianity is true, if reason, conscience, religion, the highest faculties
                            of man are to be trusted, then war is the error, the falsehood, the lie.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Parker, Theodore" TEIform="persName"/>Theodore Parker</byline></div2><pb n="44" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith without works is dead.  Why is it so?" TEIform="index"/>FAITH WITHOUT WORKS IS DEAD.
                            WHY IS IT SO?</head><p TEIform="p">Because they are inseparably connected in principle. All theories, whether scientific or
                            religious, are the seed of their Father, principle, but without the conception of Faith, in
                            "works, to bear, travail and bring forth, they are an abortion. Works, therefore, are the
                            tangible form of the Eternal Mother, as theory is of the Father. Nurturing and fostering
                            come in place. Work is indispensable, therefore, for the life and growth of all things. The
                            Father is not without the Mother, nor the Mother without the Father, in the Lord, for
                            regeneration, any less than in generation. The mere " Declaration of Independence " does not
                            make us free. The striving by works is indispensable, to possessing liberty. Jesus worked
                            and died, on the same principle that a mechanic works for his trade, and the apprentice,
                            must follow the example of his preceptor. So the followers of Christ have the injunction of
                            warfare in self-denial — with the " way that seemeth right unto a man" and " the sin that
                            doth so easily beset us." The objection " If all were to become Shakers what would become of
                            the world ? " is a very shallow one. It comprehends neither Christ nor his mission, " If we
                            do the will we shall know of the doctrine." Christ, thro' the medium, Jesus, fulfilled the
                            law and all righteousness, independent of marriage, his mission was of a higher order, to
                            introduce the resurrection. He did not condemn marriage, neither do the Shakers. But both
                            have declared that marriage is a sphere that is natural, honorable under the law, but below
                            the sphere of Christ and his resurrection. Resurrection is not only a rising and changing,
                            but a moving and travel, and like the Children of Israel, the present subjects of the
                            Resurrection are now on their camping ground. The trumpet sound is beginning to be heard,
                            for a further remove, " to be led — in a way we know not," and expected not — from the
                            physical and moral sickness, disease, misery and crime of Egyptian darkness, toward the land
                            of milk and honey, where the wilderness doth blossom as the rose, with homogeneous vine and
                            fig tree to rest under. Not only so, a language, moral and orthographical, " pure," simple,
                            natural, easy, uncontradicting, and perfectly reliable. And we are strongly impressed that
                            the nearer we approach that desirable land of true liberty, the less we will feel disposed
                            to draft the poor brute and fowl into bondage and service, because the strength of the lust
                            of the flesh in concupiscence, and that of the eye, will be reduced, and the plausible but
                            nefarious lust of the appetite also. When the feminine temperance movement is prosecuted, we
                            believe the "man-child," who is to " rule the nations," will begin to be made manifest. He
                            will no doubt bear the appellation : " The Lord our Righteousness "— prominent features of
                            temperance, truth and soberness. The injunction to be" temperate in all things " is of the
                            Father, and will be carried out by the agency of the mother principle, thro' the medium of
                            works, where tlie mother can be seen and is tangible, and where the voice of the Father in
                            theory or word is audible. Deity is Dual, and from the increasing light, the faith is
                            spreading, to become universal.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barnett, J." TEIform="persName"/>J. Barnett, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Earth cooling" TEIform="index"/>EARTH COOLING</head><p TEIform="p">A new theory is gaining ground, that the earth is to be destroyed by frost, and not by fire;
                            and that the premonitory symptoms of decline are now upon us, in the form of severe winters.
                            There is abundance of evidence to prove that the arctic regions once enjoyed a temperate, if
                            not a tropical climate. The forests in Greenland, which were once in a growing and thriving
                            state, have been destroyed by the decreasing temperature. Two Frenchmen recently explored
                            the island of Spitzbergen; and a singular fact, noticed by them in connection with this
                            island, is the enormous quantity of floating timber which literally covers the waters of the
                            creeks and bays. How came this timber there, unless it grew in that region ? and, if it grew
                            there, these northern regions must once have had a milder climate. Animals requiring a warm
                            climate, also once flourished in high latitudes. A vessel lately from Alaska, brought to San
                            Francisco a cargo of fossil ivory. The adjacent marshes are full of bones and tusks of
                            ancient elephants, many sticking out of the mud like stumps. A member of an Alaska Fur
                            company afBrms that there is ivory enough on the Yucon river to supply the world for a
                            hundred years. Whether this ivory region extends across the North American continent, or is
                            confined to the country between the Pacific and the mountain range., is not yet determined.
                            A volume might be written, to show that the arctic regions once had a warm climate; but
                            perhaps the above is sufficient. I will now inquire what is the cause of this change in the
                            climate ? Professor Agassiz says the glaciers are moving from the hemispheres toward the
                            equator. Will they finally meet, and thus entirely freeze us up. Among the many theories
                            which have been broached, to account for this phenomenon, there is none which appears more
                            reasonable than that which ascribes it to the decreasing power of the rays of the sun. If
                            the sun should give out, say twenty-five per cent more heat than it now does, the effect
                            would be to increase the circulation of the atmosphere, when the heated air within the
                            tropics would rise upward, and flow toward the poles; while the air in high latitudes would
                            rush toward the equator. This would tend to equalize the temperature all over the globe. On
                            the other hand, if Sol should lose two or three degrees of heat, a less circulation of air
                            would be effected; and, although the tropical world would be nearly as warm, the arctic
                            climate would approach nearer the equator. The region where we live has been called a
                            temperate climate ; but it is becoming almost an arctic one. It is in the nature of things,
                            to have one or two cold winters, and then one or two mild ones. In comparing our winters
                            with those of former times, we must compare cold winters with cold ones, and mild wintei-s
                            with mild ones. As the great luminary, the sun, is of such vast dimensions, it will perhaps
                            be two or three hundred thousand years before its light and heat will go entirely out. In
                            philosophizing upon the increasing frigidity of our latitude, would it not be well to take
                            cognizance of the decrease of the earth's internal heat — not lay too much to Sol ? Editor.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Poole, J. B." TEIform="persName"/>J. B. Poole, Hancock, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Respiration and ventilation" TEIform="index"/>RESPIRATION AND VENTILATION</head><p TEIform="p">We need to breathe more pure air, that the venous blood may be properly changed. The purity
                            of the air is affected by every respiration. The quantity of oxygen is diminished, the
                            amount of carbonic acid increased, and a certain amount of watery vapor is expelled from the
                            lungs in the expired air. If we rebreathe air it does not part with its remaining oxygen as
                            freely as when it contained the proper amount of this element, consequently the same changes
                            will not be effected in the lungs. We are familiar with the fact that a taper will not burn
                            where carbonic acid exists in any considerable quantity. Hence the judicious practice of
                            sinking a lighted candle into a well, before descending into it. A man may enter a
                            subterranean passage and feel no inconvenience in breathing, while the dog that follows him
                            falls apparently dead and soon dies, if not speedily removed to pure air. This arises from
                            the fact that the carbonic acid sinks to the bottom of the cave. Birman says the air we
                            breathe should not contain more than three and one-half per cent of carbonic acid. And as
                            air once respired contains eight and a half per cent of carbonic acid, it clearly shows that
                            it is not fitted to be breathed again. Physiologists tell us that from seven to ten cubic
                            feet of air are necessary for a man to breathe each minute. Conditions varying the amount,
                            such as size, age, and habit. The effects of breathing the same air again and again are well
                            illustrated by an incident that occurred in one of our halls of learning. A large audience
                            had assembled to hear a lecture ; soon the lamps burned so dimly that the speaker and
                            audience were nearly enveloped in darkness. The oppression, dizziness, and faintness,
                            experienced by many of the audience, induced them to leave, and in a few minutes after the
                            lamps were observed to rekindle, owing to the exchange of pure air on opening the door. We
                            are familiar with the fate of the Englishmen who were imprisoned in the Black-Hole of
                            Calcutta. A schoolroom, fifteen feet square and eight feet high, contains about 3,600 cubic
                            feet of air. This room will seat thirty pupils, and allowing ten cubic feet of air to each
                            pupil, per minute, all the air in the room will be vitiated in twelve minutes. We exclude
                            the pure air from our sick rooms for fear the patient may take cold, forgetting it is one of
                            Nature's best restorers. We should give more attention, in building, to ventilation, even at
                            the expense of the architectural beauty. We open sewers for matters that offend the sight,
                            or the smell, and contaminate the air. Our food and drink must be free from impurities. We
                            even avoid drinking from a cup that may have been pressed to the lips of a friend. On the
                            other hand, we assemble in crowds and draw into our mouths air loaded with effluvia from the
                            lungs, skin, and clothing, of every individual present — exhalations offensive, to a certain
                            extent, from the most healthy. But, when arising from a living mass of skin and lungs, in
                            all stages of evaporation and disease, prevented by the walls and ceiling from escaping,
                            they are, when thus concentrated, in the highest degree injurious and loathsome.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Conway, William" TEIform="persName"/>William Conway, West Pitts field</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our justification" TEIform="index"/>OUR JUSTIFICATION</head><p TEIform="p">As individuals, what is our standing before God ? Our walks in life, as moral beings, may be
                            circumspect before men. We may, from our youth up, have kept the letter of the law, and yet
                            in our hearts have many concealments which the light of our own consciences condemn, and in
                            the sight of God are not justifiable. We may be morally honest, having been truthful in our
                            language and just in our dealing, yet fail of coming to the standard of a Christian, because
                            of omissions and commissions — hidden sins — which the light of God would condemn, and which
                            hold us in bondage until confessed before a man of God — our witness. "Confess yonr faults,
                            one to another." James, 5 : 16. " If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive
                            us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness." 1st John, 1: 9. With all the
                            ostensible fairness of honesty and justice before men — with all our conscientiousness and
                            correctness in living to the letter of the law, which has thereby given us great external
                            salvation, conferred upon us worldly honor and places us in exalted positions in society, we
                            are but moral beings. Before God, we are dishonest and unjust, until we sacrifice and bring
                            ourselves to that order of life, which truly gives us the Christian character. Our
                            justification is derived only from being true and honest to principles — true to the
                            convictions of our own souls — the light which we have received, personally. Measuring
                            ourselves by other men, making them standards of righteousness for us, will never give us
                            justification. It is but a foolish attempt to throw off responsibility — an acknowledgment
                            of imbecility. As truth alone will ultimately prevail, in its wake justice will follow as a
                            reward for every human act. God alone is true. Our only means of justification are in our
                            sacrifices, accepting the teachings of Jesus in all their sternness, making his life our
                            constant example. Thus we enter the paradise of God, walk the golden streets of the New
                            Jerusalem, enjoy the associations of angels, become like them, shorn of all the grossness of
                            a worldly life, redeemed from its generative order, by a baptism into the Christ spirit of
                            the resurrection Order.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>Abm. Perkins, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><pb n="45" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: time flies swiftly" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: TIME FLIES SWIFTLY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">In the infant and childhood state time often hangs heavily, and parents or guardians are
                            necessitated to devise some means by which to beguile the weary hours. I well remember that
                            when a child, Murray's grammar was placed in my hands, and as I was trying to analyze a
                            sentence contained therein, " Time flies, 0 how swiftly ! " how difficult it was for me to
                            understand its import. Oftentimes, when my mind was filled with expectancy concerning some
                            future event which promised pleasure and amusement, weeks seemed like years, days like
                            months, and hours like weeks. After I had passed one score of years, and the realities of
                            life, its duties and responsibilities began to settle upon me, I often thought of those
                            words, " Time flies swiftly," and felt that they were true. From my present stand, point and
                            experience in life, I look back over the history of half a century and mark the great
                            changes which have been wrought even in our own nation, and it is marvelous to contemplate.
                            Time in its onward march, which to me has quickened its pace year by year, has accomplished
                            great results. Science and Art have been brought to degrees of perfection not then dreamed
                            of. New channels of thought have been opened, which are continually growing broader and
                            deeper. Few are now willing to accept as authority the assertions of any man or woman,
                            without evidence, or to be bound by creedal forms of past centuries. Many who lived in those
                            times when people were simple in their habits of life, and thought it an honor to honestly
                            till the soil and earn their bread by the sweat of their own brows — fathers who had
                            influence over their sons to hold and keep them as help-meets on the farm until they were of
                            lawful age — look back to those days of primitive simplicity, and ask, Was there not as much
                            real enjoyment in life then as now ? When mothers thought it a duty and made it their
                            pleasure to guide their own household, and teach their daughters practical lessons of
                            industry, how to make good unadulterated bread, " to lay their hands to the spindle and take
                            hold of the distaff," instead of the art of flirtation and gossip — they inquire, Was there
                            not as much virtue and integrity then, as at the present time ? Others, again, have felt
                            that the religion of their fathers was narrow, creed-bound, and sectarian — that it shackled
                            the mind and hindered the soul's expansion and growth — and have prayed sincerely that a
                            radical change might be affected, and pledged themselves to accept the agency through which
                            that change might come. But when they feel the great commotion in the elements and see the
                            irre. Hgious tendencies of the present age, the lack of godly reverence, they almost tremble
                            lest the nation should utterly forget God. It will be well for all to remember that the old
                            heavens cannot pass away and be superseded by the new, without noise and confusion. All the
                            good and true of the past will remain, but the false must be removed to make room for more
                            light and truth. We find that Apostolic theology and the doctrines of the primitive Church
                            were, at best, incomplete — for the Apostles themselves testified that they only saw and
                            prophesied in part. Since that time they have been mixed up with creeds and dogmas, and have
                            been diluted by a hireling priesthood, to a degree that has rendered them impotent; and they
                            must be tested by the revealed truth of the present day. A prophet said " The day of the
                            Lord will burn as an oven." Already cremation fires are kindled on the altars of truth, that
                            will consume papal absolutions, old heathen mythologies with their pagodas, and the
                            protestant priesthood will see their hitherto well guarded creeds yield to the fervid heat
                            of the fire of truth. All that is false, whether designedly or ignorantly produced, must
                            have its day of judgment. The dignitaries of what are called Christian Churches have held
                            the consciences of the people with a firm grasp, and swayed the scepter of ecclesiastical
                            power over Christendom, by covering the transgressions and transgressors with a covering not
                            of God's spirit, having hypocrisy for its warp and self-indulgence for its woof, and they
                            have cried " peace, peace," in the ears of all who were willing to listen. Now we see the
                            fruits. Sects have become numerous ; but the power that saves from wrong-doing, from
                            selfishness, sensuality and intemperance, is not found, to any great extent, within their
                            precincts; and we view them as so many dead forms, bodies lying in the streets of
                            Christendom, which, being spiritually defined, is Sodom. The witnesses have given away their
                            strength, and the infidel powers are merry. The priesthood have had their mart, and while
                            many have doubtless been undesigning and sincere in the performance of duty, as a body, they
                            have come in with professional doctors and lawyers for their full share of craft; and under
                            a sanctimonious religious garb have sold their services to the highest bidder. The same
                            Spirit that gave power unto the two witnesses to shut up the heavens — close the doors to
                            the spirit world for a time — has now re opened the doors. The Angel seen by the Revelator
                            John, that descended to earth, lightening it with glory, has come down in the nineteenth
                            century and proclaims with a loud voice " Babylon the great is fallen! " Inasmuch as " she
                            has become the hold of foul spirits, a cage for unclean and hateful birds, and has glorified
                            herself and lived deliciously, so much torment and sorrow are held in reserve, and will be
                            meted out to her." Spiritualism, in its ancient dress, had its place with the prophets of
                            olden time, and did its work adapted to the day in which they lived. And when these prophets
                            were visited by the Christ Spirit they were inspired with the glorious truths of the coming
                            ages — the veil was lifted from their eyes and they stretched forth their hands while under
                            the prophetic powers which attended them, and pointed to the glory to be revealed, when the
                            harvesting angels would be sent to thrust in the sharp sickle to reap the tares and the
                            wheat which had been suffered to grow together until the harvest. They could only point the
                            way as far as their spiritual telescope permitted them to see it. The Spiritualism of
                            to-day, in its present form, is a disintegrating power. It is shaking the foundations of the
                            orthodox Churches, and they do not possess vital force enough to withstand the mighty shocks
                            which they are caused to feel from interior spheres. And the prophets of the present time
                            are warning both priests and people to leave the old theological temples built of stones
                            that have never been tested by the rod of truth, as seen in vision by Herman for they cannot
                            stand as they are now organized. " Time flies swiftly," and the spiritual powers are working
                            mightily. In many classes in society there is a fearful looking toward a tribunal which they
                            feel that they must meet, which to them will be a day of sorrow not joy, darkness and not
                            light, for the reason that they are strongly joined to their idols and they want to be let
                            alone, even if their temple and idols all perish together. Manifold are the thoughts and
                            plans to avert the sequence of the revolutionary tendencies which are at work, and prevent
                            great changes in evangelical councils, in this moving, progressive age. Messengers are sent
                            to distant lands, and oecumenical councils are held, while the ecclesiastical powers of the
                            old and new worlds combine to prevent, if possible, a fatal issue. Now is the time for the
                            true saints of God to utter the prayer of faith, continue in watching, and fast from the
                            indulgence of inferior passions of body and soul. Let the winds of heaven blow, and separate
                            the chaff from the wheat, the false from the true. When some of the debris of hypocritical
                            profession which has been covered up by anti-Christ is cleared away, a vitalizing,
                            quickening spirit of divine life will energize and uplift humanity, and by practical
                            goodness bring them into communion with God. The Angels of Spiritualism that are guiding the
                            cars of progress call upon all to make ready for their coming.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Abstinence" TEIform="index"/>ABSTINENCE</head><p TEIform="p">The Apostle Paul, in his epistle to the Thessalonians, said : "Abstain from all appearance of
                            evil." He also urged the necessity of adding to knowledge, temperance, patience and
                            godliness, and taught that a bishop could not be blameless, unless he became temperate, and
                            that'' aged men " in the Church " should be grave and temperate, and the aged women likewise
                            should not be given to much wine, but teachers of good things." It is a great point to be
                            attained, to be able to act from principle in all things. In eating and drinking, if
                            governed by perverted appetites — either in quality or quantity — instead of the law of use
                            — we cannot be blameless. All sensible people, who have given attention to the subject of
                            dietetics, agree that plain, nutritious food is far more healthful to the human system than
                            that which is highly concentrated ; but the plainest, coarsest food may be indulged in to
                            excess, and tend to gluttony. Over-ea.ting, as well as eating improper food at unseasonable
                            hours, is a National sin. An over-taxed, over-loaded stomach produces torpor, deadens the
                            moral sensibilities, and perverts the mind. Through this medium the feelings, thoughts,
                            words and actions are often forced into wrong channels, and thereby many offenses are given
                            and taken by unkind and misdirected words and acts. It is evident that inordinate indulgence
                            of the appetites, in either eating or drinking, beclouds the mind and retards the soul's
                            progress into the higher life. Stimulating drinks, of whatever kind, have a tendency to
                            produce nervous excitement, for a time, then to leave a feeling of lassitude and depression.
                            All food is more or less stimulating, necessarily so in order to nourish and give vital
                            force and action. Highly-seasoned food, however palatable it may be, is not a necessity ;
                            but whenever indulged in, it engenders disease, which produces suffering, and entails misery
                            upon 45 <pb n="46" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEE the human family — one great cause of the degeneracy, in
                            health and morals, at the present time. The needed reform in this regard will be attained
                            through self-denial only. It is far easier to form correct habits when young than to change
                            erroneous practices, of long standing, in advanced life. Hence, my young friends will bear
                            with me while I exhort them to commence early in life to lay a foundation of good physical
                            health, by Temperance in all things. Thus they may live long in the land, be useful and
                            happy, and acquit themselves honorably, to the satisfaction of mortals and the joy of
                            Angels.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Morse, Rosie" TEIform="persName"/>Bosie Morse, Shirley, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Temperance" TEIform="index"/>TEMPERANCE</head><p TEIform="p">We feel deeply interested in the Temperance cause. We watch its progress as we read the
                            public prints, and pray for its success. We look upon it as the reformatory movement of the
                            present decade, as the abolition of Slavery was the leading movement of the last decade, in
                            which we witnessed the liberation of four millions of the human race from chattel slavery.
                            We rejoice that this foul stain is so far removed from our land of free institutions. It now
                            remains for the plague spot of Intemperance to be blotted out, which is in reality more
                            pernicious in effect, morally considered, than Slavery, inasmuch as it is spread over nearly
                            the whole habitable globe, and the high and low, the rich and poor, fall a prey to this
                            great destroyer, and are held by hands stronger than the chains which held the colored race
                            in servile bondage. Those strong chains held the outward forms, and did much to demoralize;
                            but they did not bind the soul and kill the spiritual aspirations of the heart, like
                            alcoholic drink. Intemperance enslaves and degrades the physical, mental, moral and
                            spiritual powers — spoils the whole — until man and woman, who were formed in the image of
                            God, sink lower in the scale of being than the brute creation. We bless every effort to
                            raise humanity out of such fallen conditions. We bless, in a special manner, the efforts of
                            ¦women in this direction — the praying bands. We believe they are influenced by the Mother
                            Spirit in Deity, and are sustained by supernatural power, and while they keep humble and
                            lowly in spirit their labors will be blest. Those who are called into the Resurrection
                            Order, to follow Christ in word and deed, must learn to be temperate in all things ; to use
                            every blessing as not abusing it, and be careful that we do not, by misuse, turn blessings
                            into curses. We are called to lay the ax of truth at the root of the corrupt tree, which
                            bears many kinds of evil fruit, and by a life of self-denial, crucify and rise above all
                            debasing passions and desires—to be free, not only from alcoholic drinks and tobacco, in
                            every form, but from all lusts of body and mind, that would lead the soul from God, and
                            learn to be pure in heart — live in chastity—free from every evil thought and imagination.
                            If we thus fulfill our calling, we shall rejoice in every thing that will tend to elevate
                            the race and lead to a higher life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Danford, Nancy G." TEIform="persName"/>Nancy G. Danford, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watch the thoughts" TEIform="index"/>WATCH THE THOUGHTS</head><p TEIform="p">The human mind is ever active. Thoughts ebb and now like the tidal waves of the ocean. They
                            need watching, and guarding. If kept in a proper channel, under the control of moral
                            principles — natural and spiritual laws — they produce good fruits ; and are powerful agents
                            to uplift and restore mankind to a normal, healthy condition of soul and body, from which
                            they have departed, through the indulgence of perverted thoughts, which have given birth to
                            unrighteous deeds. Evil thoughts are the parents of evil deeds. Thoughts, like links in a
                            chain, are connected together, either in the false, or the true. It is highly important that
                            young minds, in a special manner, should have proper nutrition, and avoid unhealthy
                            stimulants that would excite the brain, and invert the moral and spiritual faculties of the
                            soul. Natural, physical truth, should coalesce with spiritual divine truth; and form a
                            strong magnet to draw and hold intelligences, and operate in concert together, to progress
                            humanity from one degree of knowledge and goodness to another ; for all truth is of God. I
                            am now in the morning of life, and have yet many years before me in this world, if I should
                            only attain unto Jialf the allotted age of man — three score and ten ; — and I have a desire
                            to address a few thoughts to my young companions in the gospel work, through the Shakeress,
                            and to give expression to feelings of gratitude which well up in my heart, for the many
                            blessings which I am daily enjoying; and for the peace of mind that I find, in walking the
                            path of purity — the highway of holiness. In obedience to truth, as I have been able to
                            comprehend it, I have found food for mind and body; and have drank of living spiritual
                            waters, which have been sweet to my taste — far sweeter than the transient pleasures of
                            earth. The youthful mind — unrestrained — seeks happiness in things that are vain and
                            perishable. It grasps whatever is fairest, and will yield the greatest amount of pleasure,
                            for the time being, without regard to future consequences. Many of the fairest flowers that
                            bloom, wither and fade in a few short hours, and disappear like a phantom, leaving
                            disappointment — regrets — remorse. Since I have turned my mind to take counsel of Wisdom
                            and Prudence, which dwell together, I have found, that in the fear of God, and in works of
                            righteousness, are enduring joys. And, as the mind becomes elevated and purified, and learns
                            to subsist upon substantial food, it loses its relish for the artificial, and for the
                            grosser elements ; and is more and more able to discern the beauty and excellence of a truly
                            spiritual, and consecrated life. Wisdom's path is indeed pleasant to walk in — peaceful and
                            pure. This path I have chosen, aad in it lam joyful — hopeful—and strong. In it I am
                            shielded, in a large degree, from the blighting influences of sin, which bring sorrow and
                            death, to the immortal spirit. My dear young friends and companions in the Gospel, let us
                            renew our pledges of fidelity to true principles, and henceforth, let our lives be hid with
                            Christ, under the covert of Truth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Burger, Martha A." TEIform="persName"/>Martha A. Burger, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reflections" TEIform="index"/>REFLECTIONS</head><p TEIform="p">At the close of an Autumn day, I was led to admire the beauty of the sky, and to gaze upon
                            the azure realms on high, until their opal brightness slowly faded from my view; but the
                            variegated clouds were held within my thoughts as by a holy magnet. I fancied that in the
                            whole wide world, there was nothing that could compare, in beauty, with the sky of evening,
                            as the sun slowly faded in the west. I then turned my thoughts to my Zion home, and
                            reflected upon the glories of the self-conqueror ! And to my mind, I beheld beauties as
                            bright, serene and peaceful, as the golden twilight. I then asked, Are the acts of my life
                            fully controlled by Gospel principle, am I so moulded and fashioned by spiritual power that
                            my whole being is brought into activity under rays of divine light — that the deeds which I
                            perform may appear as stars, twinkling in the light — illuminated with tints of goodness ?
                            Ah! there is toil for me — much labor to perform. While stirred to more fervor by these
                            reflections, I resolve now in the morning of life, to consecrate myself anew, to be fruitful
                            in good works — to keep my heart with all diligence — that it may be a receptacle of love
                            and light; and that I may possess the true adorning which attends the perfection of
                            goodness. Thus, I shall possess the treasures of holiness, the reward of consecration — the
                            wealth that truth will give. The springtime of life, if spent in true devotion, will be
                            fraught with glory and strength. And as years roll on, by continued growth in all that is
                            true and good, beneath celestial rays and Angels' care — I may continue, an indwell er in
                            the temple of God, to go no more out forever.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Staples, Lydia" TEIform="persName"/>Lydia Staples, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Right and wrong" TEIform="index"/>RIGHT AND WRONG</head><p TEIform="p">It is written, " The way of the transgressor is hard," and that " Wisdom's ways are
                            pleasantness and her paths peace." When the mind is rightly directed, it is far easier to do
                            right than to do wrong. Right leads in the straightforward path of life and duty; error
                            leads into the by-ways of sin, and among hedges. Eight dwells, walks and is conversant with
                            her followers, as with companions,; never forsaking them in adversity. She attires them in
                            robes of honor, and crowns them with immortal glory. Wrong tempts and allures her votaries
                            with fair promises of happiness and pleasure, that are never realized. Her greatest
                            pleasures leave a sting behind. Her reward is pain and misery. She clothes her subjects with
                            degradation and shame. The old theory, that it is hard and disagreeable to do right, is
                            false — a device of satan's own planning to deceive and captivate souls and retard their
                            progress. It is true, educated as most children are, pernicious habits are formed in early
                            life; hence many difficulties are experienced by such, in seeking to do right, and effort,
                            self-denial and moral courage are requisite to remove obstacles, which appear formidable ;
                            but a wise, determined energy to do right will bring a recompense — a just reward.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stratton, E. A." TEIform="persName"/>E. A. Stratton, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If we forgive not, can we hope to be forgiven?" TEIform="index"/>IF WE FORGIVE NOT, CAN WE
                            HOPE TO BE FORGIVEN?</head><p TEIform="p">There is no virtue more essential to the Christian character than Forgiveness. It smoothes
                            life's journey, inspires hope in the forgiven, and shows forth nobility of character in the
                            forgiver. The gifted Sterne, discoursing on the excellence of a forgiving spirit, said : "
                            The brave only, know how to forgive ; it is the most refined and generous pitch of virtue
                            that human nature can arrive at. Cowards have done good and kind actions ; but a coward
                            never forgave. It is not in his nature to do it. The power to do it flows from a strength
                            and greatness of soul, conscious of its own force and security, rising above the temptation
                            of resenting every little affront." When Jesus taught His disciples to pray, ''Forgive us
                            our trespasses, as we forgive those who trespass against us," how plainly he exhibited the
                            law of justice as running parallel with mercy. Truth and Love, Righteousness and Peace, are
                            copartners. It is not probable that any human being was ever created so perfect, in every
                            respect, as never to have committed an error — never to have sinned in a degree to fall
                            short of the glory of God, and of the love and confidence of some mortal being. If this be
                            true, then all, in a greater or less degree, have felt the need of the exercise of this
                            beautiful virtue toward them. Those who humble their spirits, and seek forgiveness, will be
                            exalted thereby. It is a sweet boon, when attained, worth the effort. Bitter envy and strife
                            —jealousy and hard feelings — never made any soul noble nor happy. But when we kindly take
                            an erring, repentant brother, or sister, by the hand, breathe the spirit of forgiveness and
                            love, speak words of kindness to them, remembering that " to err is human, to forgive,
                            divine," then we feel the sweet consolation which the Christ Spirit—the Dove of Peace —
                            alone can give.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bullard, Marcia M." TEIform="persName"/>Marcia M. Bullard, Canaan, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For the shaker and shakeress" TEIform="index"/>[For the Shaker and Shakeress.]</head><p TEIform="p">Deak Editors : I was much edified and comforted, while perusing the excellent article on the
                            " Gift of Tongues and the Gift of Healing" in the March number of your valuable paper. I
                            love the cause of truth, and am interested in <pb n="47" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEEES8. its increase;
                            and I would work to promote it, but I find that my best efforts are feeble. I have faith in
                            Spiritual Gifts. Four years ago I attended a Spiritual Convention in St. Paul, Minn. I there
                            met with three young women who were called Mediums. They sang and talked in the Indian
                            tongue, greatly to my satisfaction. I was convinced that they were entirely ignorant of the
                            language, except as they were influenced by other minds. 1 have also been used as an
                            instrument to help the sick and maimed, by laying on of hands, which was effected through
                            faith, and by earnest prayer. For many years I have been seeking for an increase of light
                            and truth. I formerly be lieved that " Christ would come in the literal clouds of heaven,"
                            and set up His kingdom on earth, to reign a thousand years, and my mind was much exercised
                            concerning that event; for I believed the prophetic periods were fulfilled. About that time
                            I obtained the book entitled " Millennial Church." From it I received much light concerning
                            the manner — not the time — of the Second Advent. Instead of looking for Christ to appear
                            personally, in the atmospheric clouds of earth, I turned my eyes to look for a spiritual
                            appearing in a cloud of witnessing Saints — "Clouds of Witnesses to compass us about, and
                            Saviours that would come upon Mt. Zion to judge the Mt. of Esau " — the heavenly would judge
                            the earthly. From that time to the present I have been in unison with Believers (or Shakers)
                            in feeling and in practical life, as far as circumstances would permit. Family ties and
                            temporal conditions have prevented me from walking in close relationship, and now, while I
                            am writing, there are mountains and valleys which divide us; yet I try to commune with you
                            in spirit. I am also trying, in my feeble way, to influence people here in Winona, who
                            believe it is their duty to live in the marriage relation, to regard the law of Nature,
                            which is use, and I think my efforts in this direction have not been entirely fruitless.
                            There is a spiritual song—from which I have derived much comfort — that I understand
                            originated in your Society. With your permission I would be pleased to have it appear in the
                            Shaker and Shakeress : " On the beautiful hills of Truth we will roam, For there the sweet
                            flowers of purity bloom ; We'll gather the immortal fruits that there grow, And drink of the
                            "well-springs of life " that flow; We'll inhale the pure breezes of that healthful clime,
                            And. unite in the strains of music divine. O, there is our home ! when life's conflicts are
                            o'er, We'll join our blest kindred who've passed on before."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Clark, Cornelia L." TEIform="persName"/>Cornelia L. ClarK, Winona, Minn.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Compliance" TEIform="index"/>COMPLIANCE</head><p TEIform="p">The Laws of God are immutable — unchangeable— as the source whence they proceed. Those laws
                            are not only operative upon large bodies of mind and matter, but descend to, and take
                            cognizance of, small objects and atoms. It is said: " Not a sparrow falls to the ground
                            unnoticed." Hence, obedience to the laws, in small, as well as in things of greater moment,
                            is necessary to secure the blessing. All causes, whether great or small, will produce their
                            legitimate effects. King Solomon said: l' Train up a child in the way he (or she) should go,
                            and when he (or she) is old he (or she) will not depart from it "— implying that impressions
                            first stamped upon the mind and memory are not soon erased. If children are taught obedience
                            to that which is right and just, in little things, a foundation of character is laid for
                            after life ; and it is far easier for those who have rendered fealty to parents and
                            guardians, while in a iuvenile state, to regard law and order, when, at more mature age,
                            they engage in the duties of life, in an enlarged sphere of action, whether it be in social
                            relations — governmental, or religious — there are laws pertaining to each, and all. Is
                            there not, therefore, an important duty, which guardians of children and youth are bound to
                            feel in regard to them, which few seem to realize ? Do not the inmates of jails, and prison
                            houses, strongly rebuke the fathers who begot, and the mothers who bore them — then
                            neglected and left them, half cultured — half subdued, if subdued at all — to grow up in
                            self-will, and non-compliance with the desires of their parents or guardians ? As a general
                            rale, children who are allowed to disobey their parents, and disregard the counsel and
                            admonition of friends, do not listen to the voice of conscience in the soul, and are left to
                            be tossed upon the billows of their passional natures, subject to the winds that are created
                            in the haunts of vice ; and often, intoxicating drink, which fevers the brain, and sets on
                            fire the animal, sensual passions, tempts — allures — and draws them into a vortex of vice,
                            from which it is not easy for them to extricate themselves. I am happy, at every
                            recollection, that I was taught the principle of obedience, in early life. My parents placed
                            me under the care and guardianship of Believers, when I was but three years of age. With a
                            firm hand they led me — in wisdom counseled me — and in love, chided me for my faults, and
                            taught me to yield my will and judgment to my superiors, and to those of riper age. In
                            compliance with those instructions, I was shielded from harm, and my young life was peaceful
                            and pleasant. Now, that I have passed beyond the childhood state, reason and conscience call
                            for a continuation of the principle of Obedience. There are physical, moral and spiritual
                            laws, which we must obey, if we would enjoy health and happiness. A departure therefrom,
                            always result in pain and suffering. I have full confidence that the observance of Law —
                            natural and spiritual — will restore Order and harmony, bring souls into union with God, and
                            establish just relations in the human family.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Green, Ellen" TEIform="persName"/>Ellen Green, Canaan, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Consider the lilies" TEIform="index"/>"CONSIDER THE LILIES"</head><p TEIform="p">Slumbering in restful quiet — under the pure white mantle of snow — what miracles of wonder
                            are reposing ! Miracles, scarce less wonderful than that of creation, await only the genial,
                            magnetic rays of the sun, to astonish us with their beauty. First will come the violets, and
                            then, the crocuses and tulips, from their wonderful bulbs. Every one has its own marked
                            characteristic individuality — its own perfect life — to spring forth, to bud, to open and
                            exhale its little wealth of bloom and fragrance, and then retire. So of all Nature's
                            creations, in their simple state, be they bird or beast. They know their time, fulfill their
                            life of freedom, and then retire. And does it seem probable that the wise Creator ever
                            intended that his last and crowning work of completeness should have less of the spirit of
                            spontaneity than inferior things ? Must she, because time was when her charm was in her
                            dependence, ever be doomed to rob herself of the health and stamina — back bone — which her
                            cares — her duties — so urgently demand of her? To every mortal the message comes: "JEach
                            Soul to its Maker." No sponsor can answer for another, before " the great white throne," for
                            " the deeds done in the body," each one must account for himself or herself. To live out our
                            ideal of perfected man, or womanhood, physically, mentally and spiritually, is the call of
                            God to our souls. If indifferent, and supine, on us will come the results — condemnation —
                            for misimproved talents, and unfulfilled uses ; for '' I have called you to freedom," and
                            have given you every needed good that you might " grow as the lily " and obtain all the
                            possibilities of life and being.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. Webster, Harvard, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Talent" TEIform="index"/>TALENT</head><p TEIform="p">A Christian community need, and have a right to, every faculty and talent. And no one who
                            holds membership in such community can, in justice to that community, to his or her self, or
                            to mankind, withhold or bury his or her talents, whether they be few or many. No one,
                            through pride, because he or she does not possess as much as some others, can be justified
                            in withholding what to him or her was committed. " God will require his own with usury/'
                            whether it be little or much. Unless talent be put to use, it is of no avail. Life in this
                            way will be a blank ; and when called upon for a just account of Stewardship, those who have
                            thus lived will receive the sentence " Unprofitable servant." Talent, though small, if well
                            improved, is a blessing. In what better way can we honor God, the Giver of all good gifts,
                            than to be active in duty ? giving with a liberal hand of what we possess, and diligently
                            seeking to add thereto, that we may have more to give ? If we are only able to hand in a cup
                            of water, in a right spirit, we shall not lose the reward of so doing; we shall hear the
                            comforting voice speaking to the conscience, " Inasmuch as ye have done it unto the least of
                            these my brethren, ye have done it unto me."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hall, C. F." TEIform="persName"/>C. F. Hall, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Feeling subordinate to principle" TEIform="index"/>FEELING SUBORDINATE TO PRINCIPLE</head><p TEIform="p">Principle is the foundation of character. It should rule personal feeling, and govern the
                            motions and actions, in the performance of every duty. Small particles of earth form great
                            mountains. Little thoughts and feelings produce actions — deeds — which form and determine
                            character. Though separately considered they may appear small as a grain of sand, yet they
                            are the moulding element of the human mind, and should be of such type as to fit us for the
                            companionship of each other, and for the society of Angels. Scripture teaches that " The
                            tree is known by its fruit." A tree must have roots, else it could not live. Are not
                            principles, which are the basis of character, like the roots of a tree and the external
                            conduct the fruit produced ? It has been said "A good man, out of the treasure of the heart,
                            bringeth forth good things ; and an evil man, out of the evil treasure, bringeth forth evil
                            things." " Out of the abundance of the heart the mouth speaketh." How important that in
                            early life we should study to understand the necessity of bringing our feelings and inner
                            life under discipline. It is as essential to our moral and spiritual development as pure air
                            and wholesome food are requisite for physical growth. If we would be substantial members of
                            society, we must begin in the spring-time of life and build securely upon good principles,
                            regardless of personal feelings which would often lead us to deviate from the right. It
                            would be well for young persons who are commencing life's journey, to consider this subject
                            and give it due weight. They, who in childhood and youth have been blest with the influence
                            of moral and spiritual teachers, should be admonished to bear those instructions in mind as
                            they advance in life, and to bring every feeling into subjection to principle, in "obedience
                            to the law of Christ." This will require vigilance and self-denial, which will give growth
                            to virtue and leave no room for idleness either of body or mind. Thus we shall be able to
                            help bear the burdens of society and show by our works an unselfish devotion to principle
                            and love of God and humanity.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cochrane, Mary M." TEIform="persName"/>Mary M. Cochrane, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cross my choice" TEIform="index"/>THE CROSS MY CHOICE</head><p TEIform="p">The cross of Jesus I'll bear, I'll bind it near to my heart; His yoke voluntarily wear, And
                            in his service take part. I'll yield up my all unto him, And walk in the straight, narrow
                            way That his shining goal I may win, In regions of eternal day. Earth shall not my progress
                            impede, Nor hinder my journey above; I'll hie me on ever with speed, To that land of light
                            and of love, Where Ann and where Jesus have gone. And all ancient Saints onward press'd; And
                            where, 'mid the glorified throng, Our own spirit kindred are blest. O beautiful home that I
                            see ! I fain would take wings, and away From earth and its shadows to thee — To substance
                            that ne'er will decay.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Julia" TEIform="persName"/>Julia Johnson, West Pittsfield, Mass.</byline></div2><pb n="48" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Heavenly goal" TEIform="index"/>HEAVENLY GOAL</head><p TEIform="p">Andante. 1. We are all marching on through the shadows of time To our beautiful, beautiful
                            home! Where amid the green bowers of 2. Oh, gladly we're leaving the lowlands of earth,
                            Where we dwelt 'mid the phantoms that perished; Where the promise of pleasure but 8. We've
                            tasted the bliss of the heavenly state, And have found the rich pearl of salvation ; The
                            pure inspiration of Wisdom and Love, In the sunshine of truth we will roam ; ended in pain,
                            And vain were the hopes that we cherished eternal truth, Is the joy of our virgin relation;
                            We'll sing of the blessings of life that abound For the Oh, cheering the thought! we've
                            obeyed the high call, And have Then upward through trial our watchword will be, In the
                            upright, the faithful and holy; And gather the flowers of vlrtue and peace, As we travel to
                            regions of glory, entered the sphere of progression ; "We'll toil for the treasure of
                            immortal worth, Our only abiding possession. light that is ever increasing; Redemption's the
                            goal we're determined to win, For this will our strife be unceasing.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel increase" TEIform="index"/>GOSPEL INCREASE</head><p TEIform="p">Bright angels are passing through the earth, to and fro, Proclaiming God's Word that all
                            nations must know; Yea, bearing the Law that will bring lasting peace, And establish his
                            kingdom which never will cease — Never will cease to flourish and grow,— Until the whole
                            earth is an Eden below; Never will cease in its growth of love, Till mortals are like unto
                            angels above. 'Tis but by the cross, self-denial and truth, The soul is renewed, and brought
                            back to its youth; And by the deep love which the Saviour possassed, The earth is to bloom,
                            and its fruitage be blessed. Put on your whole strength, O ye earnest and bold 1 The seed
                            must be sown, that its life may unfold; The chosen of God, have his work to perform, Yet, He
                            will protect them from ev'ry wild storm. For thus 'tis decreed, the true laborer shall rise,
                            Though scorned and derided—and covered with lies; No mortals have power to harm or destroy
                            Those who for the truth all their forces employ. Those who come forth to march in the van,
                            By angels are guided in God's holy plan. Courage, brave-hearted, be fearless and true ! The
                            Lord is your strength, and will bring you safe through; Eternally yours, his kingdom of
                            peace, Of which there's to be an abiding increase. Eternally yours — his kingdom of love— *
                            As starry and broad as the blue arch above; Rapturous joy, none but victors can tell, What
                            the anthem contains, which their glad voices swell! None but the heroes who've ended the
                            strife, Are crowned with the laurels of immortal life!</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Julia" TEIform="persName"/>Julia Johnson, Hancock, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be careful what you say" TEIform="index"/>"BE CAREFUL WHAT YOU SAY."</head><p TEIform="p">[Selected.] In speaking of others' faults Pray don't forget your own ; Remember those in
                            house of glass, Seldom should throw a stone. If we have nothing else to do But talk of those
                            who sin, 'Tis better we commence at home, And from that point begin. We have no right to
                            judge a man Until he's fairly tried; Should we not like his company, We know the world is
                            wide. Some may have faults—and who has not? The old as well as young. Perhaps we may, for
                            aught we know, Have fifty to their one. I'll tell you of a better plan; I find it works full
                            well, To try my own defects to cure — Before of others tell. And though I sometimes hope to
                            be No worse than some I know, My own short-comings bid me let The faults of others go. Then
                            let us all when we commence To slander friend or foe, Think of the harm one word may do, To
                            those we little know.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Crown of mother's love" TEIform="index"/>CROWN OF MOTHER'S LOVE</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Shaker and Shakeress: In newspapers, as in houses, are corners. If you have a little
                            corner left—unoccupied — please insert " Crown of Mother's Love " — if you deem it worthy of
                            such a privilege. Receive our best wishes for your prosperity. We, here at White Water, are
                            deeply interested in your welfare. Through your aid our views of Shakerism are being
                            expanded. Shakerism never appeared more beautiful to us, than at the present time. Take all
                            the jewels earth can boast; Its diamonds and its pearls so bright; Search southern sea and
                            northern coast — Bring all their treasures to the light; Collect them — call them all thine
                            own; Display to all the eyes that see, Yet will they not befit the crown Which Mother's Love
                            hath set on me. The jewels in my crown that shine, That sparkle in bright glory there, Shed
                            on my path those rays divine, Which make life beautiful and fair. Thine were from mount and
                            ocean, brought, And won by risk of other's life; With mine own heart's blood, mine I've
                            bought And paid for in the gospel strife. O, glitt'ring crown of Mother's Love, I press thee
                            to my joyful heart What'er befall — where'er I move, Dearer than gold to me thou art. Earth
                            from my sight thy gems remove; They do not shine for one like roe ; For mine's the pearl of
                            heav'nly Love, The sparkling gem of Purity!</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fickeyson, C. A. Emil" TEIform="persName"/>C. A. Emil Fickeyson White Water, February 1,
                        1875.</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A newspaper is, in fact, almost as much the production of one mind as..." TEIform="index"/>A newspaper is, in fact, almost as much the production of one mind as...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A newspaper is, in fact, almost as much the production of one mind as a book, for
                                    though there may be fifty different pens engaged in furnishing the matter which goes
                                    into it, it is the individual tact of the conductor that gives it all consistency,
                                    that blots out all objectionable sentences, and adds the necessary words here and
                                    there to elucidate and give point to what would otherwise be obscure and
                                    meaningless. The editor of the London Times is not by any means a brilliant writer;
                                    there are doubtless many men under him who can excel in writing leaders, reporting
                                    speeches, or doing the miscellaneous work of a daily journal, but probably not one
                                    who could conduct that famous paper with the success he has secured to it. The
                                    proprietors properly appreciate his services, and his salary is equal to that of the
                                    President of the United States.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Investigator" TEIform="index"/>Investigator</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth" TEIform="index"/>Truth</head><p TEIform="p">Just as it is — no more, no less; the words of simple truth — the words of righteousness ! O,
                            who will keep this simple rule — avoid exaggeration ! Who will speak the truth, whatever the
                            occasion!</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>[Obituary]</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Huges, Edward" TEIform="index"/>Edward Huges
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Huges, Edward" TEIform="persName">Edward Huges</persName>, February 16, 1875, aged 11 years.
                                Whitewater, Ohio.'</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sherman, Manley" TEIform="index"/>Manley Sherman
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Sherman, Manley" TEIform="persName">Manley Sherman</persName>, February 21, 1875, aged 75
                                years, Whitewater, Ohio.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Carter, Eliza" TEIform="index"/>Eliza Carter
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Carter, Eliza" TEIform="persName">Eliza Carter</persName>, February 25,1875, aged 80 years,
                                Whitewater, Ohio.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Burns, Mary Ann" TEIform="index"/>Eliza Carter
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Burns, Mary Ann" TEIform="persName">Eliza Carter</persName>, March 31,1875, aged 53 years,
                                Shirley, Mass.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>