<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2807" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">28</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><date value="18980701" TEIform="date">July 1898</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">97-112</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="28" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
 1898.
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF  THE
 church,
OK
"United   Society   of  Believers"
t treats of the Rise and Progress of the
with large type  and  on excellent paper.   Society,  together with  the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
It contains  130 pages and has                                              Price   50 cts.
ILL USTRA TIONS                              THE  ALTRUIST^
of the Shakers and their          Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
The  work  gives  quite an extended ac-   live and work together, and hold all their
property  in  common,   all  the  men   and
count of  the  Several SOCIETIES, their   women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
organization and general management.         their   majority vote.     50 cents  a year;
Price   50 cts.         specimen copy free.    Address A. Long'                   ley, 1719 Franklin Ave, St. Louis, Mo.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF   THE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
AND
SHAKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the United   Society  of   Believers  in   Christ's
Second Appearing.    Illustrated.
By Giles B. Avert.
Price,  15 cts.
JULY,
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MA iVlFESTO.
Mr. George Kennan, whose book, Siberia
and the Exile System, created such an impression in this country a few years ago and resulted in very consideiably modifying the
rigors of Russia's treatment of Siberian prisoners, is now writing a Story of the War,
which appears in weekly installments in The
Outlook.   Mr. Kennan is First Vice-President
of the Red Cross Society, and is especially interested in the humanitarian side of the war,
but almost equally so in ifs pictuiesque incidents, and in the underlying social conditions
which have produced the war.   So far his letters have been written from Key West, to
which place he went as the special correspondent of The Outlook.   It is understood
that Mr.Kennan will enter Cuba at the very
first opportunity, and will continue from that
island the letters which are attracting such
wide attention.   They appear exclusively in
The Outlook.   ($3 a year.   The Outlook Co.,
287 Fourth Avenue, New York.)
"Inside figures" are always interesting, and
the following are eeiU.inly some striking
ones about The Ladies' Home .'auniat.    During'
1897,    8,1K5,113 copies of this ii.aj-.ii/.ine were
printed and so thoroughly sold that the latter
year issues are entirely out of print.   It consumes 3,454,362 pounds of paper in a year, and
absorbs 30,902 pounds of ink.   It runs 28 presses.
The advertising columns contained ig4'.i8,325
worth of advertising during the last year.
The editors received 9290 manuscripts and less
than one per cent were accepted.   The magazine employs 22 staff editors.   24,(i48 letters
have been received and answered in the year
by the editors of the correspondence columns.
The Journal has over 15,000 active, working
agents on the road getting subscriptions.   It
has educated 442 girls free of charge under its
free educational plan.   In a single day it has
received as high as 18.000 subscriptions.   300,
000 copies of the Journal  are sold  each month
on the news stand alone425,000 people subscribe for it by the year.
"Torpedoes and Torpedo Boats" is the subject of the leading paper in the June number
of Fkanic Leslie's Popular Monthly.   B. B.
Croffut tells the history and progress of these
little engines of destruction, anil describes
their manufacture, cost and manipulation.
The article would be interesting at any time,
and is particularly so just now.   It is liberally
illustrated with views of short and long torpedoes, the principal torpedo boats of this and
other countries, and interiors of a torpedo
factory.   Another timely article is one on The
Naval Militia, by Charles Sydney Clark, which
describes the work and duties of this excellent auxiliary arm of our navy.   The  illustrations include portraits and groups, and views
of some of the vessels manned by the naval
militia.   The Working of a Modern Mine, by
James Harold Thompson, tells of the life of
the miners at work, and is well illustrated.
The aiticle on Andrew .Jackson   this month id
by Old Hickory's grandson, Colonel Andrew
Jackson, and gives some recollections of the
general's home life.    A pretty piece of music
is contributed by John Philip Sousa, the
March King, the words to which were written
by Hunter MacCulloch.   The Disciples of
Christ are described by Rev. S. T. Willis, with
main good pictures.   Henry Clay Colver l.;i.->
an interesting account of the lesources of
Seattle, Wash., which is illustrated with views
of the principal buildings and points of interest.   A new pen is apparently devoted to the
department known as "The Leslie Portfolio,"
for the matter is much more attractive than
before.   There are numerous other good
things, including several short stories, the department lor boys and girls, etc.
The Anti-Infidel Library, edited by H. L.
Hastings now sends us More Bkioks kkojl
the Babel ok Till': IIicheu Cuitk s.    All
Christians and would-be Christians most
heartily commend the woik, which is a strong
tide heavenward.   47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass.
We extend our congratulations to the Scientific American, on having brought out in its
Special Navy Supplement a work which was
sorely needed by the general public.   We
have already learned to associate ourconteir.
porary with naval matters and its illustrations
of our new ships as they have appeared from
time to time have always been handsome and
the descriptive matter reliable and complete.
The Special Navy Supplement is an extremely
handsome edition, carefully and clearly written, richly illustrated, and well calculated to
make the people of America thoroughly acquainted with the country's first line of defence.   We think one of the best features of
the work is the table which is printed beneath
the illustration of each ship, giving the chief
details of her size, speed, guns and armor.   If
fuller information is desired, it is found on the
same or the adjoining page.   It seems to us
that in handling an extensive subject like this
the object should be to give the essential inforniation and avoid useless and confusingelaboration.   This the Scientific American has
succeeded in doing with very inarkt success,
and the instant popularity which the Navy
Supplement has achieved is not surprising.
The number opens with a very readable
historical sketch of the upbuilding of the New
Navy, which is followed with an article explaining by the aid of diagrams the difference
between the various types of warships.   At
least one, and in some cases several, of each
type of warship is illustrated, so that, when
the number has been read through, the reader
will have a very complete knowledge of the
strength and numbers of our new Navy,   The
illustrations are particularly finewood engravings predominatingand the last page
contains complete tables of the ships, auxiliary cruisers, torpedo boats and guns.   Special
mention should be made of the very artistic    '--><pb n="97" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritual highway" TEIform="index"/>THE SPIRITUAL HIGHWAY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder Henry C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">ON our journey through this life, beset as it is with so many allurements, it is well to bear
                            in mind that there is a highway in which the Lord's people may walk,a state of righteousness
                            into which they may enter, and a Kingdom of God in which they can own an inheritance. In
                            some things we may claim to be in advance of those who have gone on before us, but we may
                            feel amply compensated if by watchfulness and prayer we may attain to the gospel interest
                            that was so fully set forth by the apostle who prayed that he might be able "to present
                            every man perfect in Christ Jesus." With what zeal he toiled, day and night, to impart a
                            knowledge of the testimony of the Christ. Hear what he says of the persecutions that he
                            suffered while preaching the Christian faith, "Thrice was I beaten with rods, once was I
                            stoned, thrice I suffered shipwreck, a night and a day have I been in the sea. Ii^ perils by
                            robbers, in perils by my own countrymen, in perils in the wilderness and in perils among
                            false brethren. In weariness and painfulness, in watchings, in hunger and in thirst."2 Cor.
                            xi., 25. In this we have the record of a minister of the Christ, who dared to do the work to
                            which he was called, and to become crucified to the world. May the people of God in this
                            day, be no less faithful and no less zealous to work for the cause of righteousness. The
                            Apostle had no confusion in his mind when ijie informed the church that he would like to
                            present every one perfect in Christ. He had been acquainted with the history of mankind for
                            several thousands of years. He had learned that in the beginning God had made <pb n="98" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 98 THE MANIFESTO. man upright;had made him after his own image and likeness,
                            and had bestowed on him a fulness of divine gifts. He had learned that God had walked and
                            talked with man, face to face, as one friend converseth with another. He was now learning
                            that man had neglected to keep the laws of God, and had put righteousness far from his soul,
                            and in some cases had become desperately wicked. Some of the best witnesses thought that the
                            evil spirit was in the ascendency and in their confessions had said,"There is none that
                            doeth good, no, not one." It must have been a low state of society when men could defraud
                            each other, could rob and even destroy the lives of their fellow-men and then reach the
                            place in history, where b}' doing these things, they could believe they were engaged in
                            God's service. But the earth is the Lord's and the fulness thereof, and this day of wars and
                            slaughter must come to an end. The God of Love and Peace would rule the earth. The Prophets
                            began to assure the people of a better day when nations should learn war no more; when the
                            knowledge of God should cover the land as the waters cover the sea. That a day should come
                            when the testimony of truth should burn as an oven, and all the proud, yea and all that do
                            wickedly should be consumed as stubble. The Apostle had lived to see that day and had heard
                            the testimony of the Christ, to repent and make strait paths for hunself and for the Lori's
                            people in which they could walk with safety. A day in which every knee should bow and every
                            tongue confess after their baptism into the Holy Spirit and fire, that essential
                            ministration bf the Christ's Kingdom. He had lived to see the day when all unrighteousness
                            would be consumed as stubble and men would grow unto the measure of the stature of the
                            fulness of the Christ. Then comes the mystery that men have thrown around the gospel work.
                            Making public profession that they could not understand it themselves, and were quite well
                            assured that others could not understand it. By the side of this they have built up a creed
                            and then multiplied to themselves forms and ceremonies till the truth is almost wholly
                            obscured from sight. That which Jesus had taught was soon lost from view and in place of his
                            spiritual mission the church accepted all the worldly relations that had occupied the mind
                            of man. They chose darkness rather than light and from this darkness grew the distorted
                            views of a future life. Whatever may be said by speculative minds upon the subject of"
                            present or future happiness, an unerring guide has been given that we may not miss the prize
                            and this privilege is awarded to the pure in heart, to those who by an honest confession are
                            made able to deny themselves of all ungodliness and every worldly lust. It is for them to
                            put off the old man with his deeds and put on the Lord, Jesus Christ. "For every knee shall
                            bow" before the spirit of the Christ, "and every tongue confess" to the light that comes to
                            them from God. This forms the discipline of the gospel work for every man. It is to be the
                            rule of his whole life. He is to become a new creature in his <pb n="99" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 99 general deportment. To speak a new language of which the angels of God need
                            not be ashamed. To 1)3 preseuted perfect in Christ Jesus we must be cleansed from all
                            unrighteousness. This must include the whole of life ; the manner in which we eat and drink,
                            the language we speak, the raiment we wear, and no less the spiritual foundation upon which
                            we build. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith" TEIform="index"/>FAITH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, Jessie" TEIform="persName"/>By Jessie Evans. </byline><p TEIform="p">FAITH is distinctly a gift of God to the soul. The natural mind knows nothing of the
                            spiritual insight which is "the substance of things hoped for, the evidence of things not
                            seen;" "the natural man receiveth not the things of the Spirit of God: for they are
                            foolishness unto him ; neither can he know them, because they are spiritually discerned."
                            The mind which grasps only material evidence and believes only what the senses convey to it,
                            can not lay claim to the possession of this essentially immaterial virtue. Faith is
                            far-sighted. It sees the victory beyond the battle, harvest beyond seed-time, calm after
                            storm, plenty after famine, glory after conquest, answer during prayer and fulfillment in
                            promise. Faith is never discouraged, never cast down. Faith breathes optimism. Present
                            conditions, while anything but gratifying are viewed, not as a permanent evil, but as a
                            means leading by its bitter, its serious lessons to an all-glorious end. The exceeding
                            whiteness of soul alluded to by the inspired Revelator was that "which came out of great
                            tribulation"not untried virtue. Faith is a strong gift, which succumbs to no opposite
                            element. "Change and decay in all around" we see, human affections rise and fall, fortune's
                            smiles and frowns alternate ; and while at times we are permitted to feel that every wind is
                            in our favor, at others we experience the reverses which make us wary. Faith comes from the
                            heavens to our relief, as an unfailing spring in a deserta deep abiding trust that our God
                            is an arm that is "not shortened," an eye that never slumbers, and an omnipresence that
                            takes cognizance of every parching wind of earth that sweeps over us. Like charity, faith
                            "hopeth all things, endureth all things" and "never faileth." Jesus's life was a glorious
                            reign of the Christ faith. The record of his divine ministry shows the extremes of human
                            expression. He was both reticent and aggressive, taciturn and eloquent, persuasive and
                            compulsive, simple yet mysteriousbut all proceeded from the spirit power which was an
                            unobstructed emanation from God to him, and which may be as freely transmitted to us through
                            Christ as mediator. The faith manifested by Jesus, the faith which buoyed his soul even
                            through the death agonies of Gethsemane, <pb n="100" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 100 THE MANIFESTO. may be
                            ours. How dark, how hopeless is a life unlighted by the sunshine of faith! The eye of the
                            human sees the heavy burden, the weary nerves sink under the pressure of its iron hand, but
                            the eye of faith catches sight of the "everlasting arm," which is underneath, always between
                            us and the tri.nl and tho the burden must still be borne, with Christ we whisper, "My yoke
                            is easy and my burden light," since the Almighty is with me. "Without faith it is impossible
                            to please God," for this is the avenue through which he speaks to his earth children. With
                            what glorious faith is the Lord's Prayer freighted !"for thine is the kingdom and the power
                            and the glory forever!" Faith such as that which sustained our holy Savior, if sown in the
                            human family, tho only as grains of "mustard seed," would revolutionize all the affairs of
                            men. The "mountain" is "cast into the sea" at the command of faith ; if we still struggle
                            with the mountain we have no faith, since Christ's words never have been proved false. But
                            carnal reasoning has crept insidiously into our religious circles and its sinister influence
                            clouds the vision. Faith does not stand before the bar of human argument. We should at all
                            times be able to give a reason for the hope that is within us, yet who can "by searching
                            find out God?" Faith is the breath of the eternal, hence can not be defined by the finite.
                            Can a child tell why he reposes implicit faith in the mother love that is his wing of
                            safety, whatever betide ? Neither are we able by any force of logic to impart to another the
                            history of our heaven-born faith. "Deep calleth unto deep," and through spiritual media
                            alone does faith find expression. It is "as if a man should cast seed into the ground and
                            should sleep and rise night and day, and the seed should spring up and grow, he knoweth not
                            how." A writer has left this beautiful allusion to the subject; "With constant faith
                            surpassing doubt I stand and watch the tide go out, That 'twill come back I say to you I do
                            not know, and yet I do. At eventide I see the day Put night on guard and go away, Will
                            morning come the mist to woo? I do not know and yet I do. I see the sere that autumns bring,
                            Will verdure come witli waking spring? My faitli alone can answer true I do not know and yet
                            I do. We see our loved ones droop and die, Hath heaven a brighter life on high? Is death the
                            vale that leads thereto? I do not know and yet I do." <pb n="101" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFES TO.
                            101 "The faith once delivered to the saints" has been entrusted to our keeping tiie faith of
                            the martyrs who have died for it, the faith of the holy who have lived for it. It behooves
                            us to stand fast to its behests like men and women of God. The good old gospel ship has not
                            lost one of its timbers. Its crew, few or many, are all "-free volunteers," the deserter
                            shuns the working force. Passengers leave at all ports; but officers and men are at the post
                            of duty until the voyage is ended. Our spiritual "stars and stripes" float aloft unharmed by
                            a century's cannonading from the enemy. Faitha living faith borne out in practical
                            righteousnessgives us hourly impulse toward freedom and victory, and doubt dies in its
                            presence. God is God, "the same yesterday, to-day and forever," and our faith is anchored
                            there. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Visit of our brother, Dr. J. M. Peebles" TEIform="index"/>VISIT OF OUR BROTHER, DR. J. M.
                            PEEBLES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catherine" TEIform="persName"/>By Catherine Allen.</byline><p TEIform="p"> the "Banner of Light" we learned that our esteemed friend and brother of long acquaintance
                            was again to cross the continent, leaving his home in San Diego, California for regions near
                            our home, his object that of attending the fiftieth anniversary of the advent of Modern
                            Spiritualism held in Rochester, N. Y. For a long time he has kept his connection with us
                            only through correspondence, but responding to an invitation from the North family to again
                            visit us in person, he gave a most cordial reply and on April 11, we had the pleasure of
                            receiving him in our home. Since our last meeting, time had whitened his locks, but in his
                            erect form and energetic manner we noted not failure, but rather an increase of vigor, which
                            at the age of seventy-seven gave promise of verifying the teachings of one of his books
                            entitled, "How to Live a Century and Grow Old Gracefully." It may interest many to know by
                            what means and to what degree, Doctor Peebles holds the relationship of Brother to our
                            Order. About thirty years since, when attending a convention of Reformers in New York City,
                            at which Elder Frederic W. Evans was present, he felt strongly imprest to acknowledge the
                            latter as a spiritual Father. Moved by this feeling, after the meeting he sought
                            introduction to Elder Frederic, and expressing a desire for a further interview was invited
                            to the hotel where he made known the leadings of the spirit and took the initiatory step by
                            freely opening his mind. He thus practically acknowledged the principle of mediation as
                            establisht in our Church, believing that it would prove to him a protection from the
                            influences of unregenerate spirits and a means of quickening the receptive faculties to a
                            fuller influx from celestial realms. THROUGH <pb n="102" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 102 THE MANIFES TO. Being
                            a spiritual spiritist and deeply religions, he placed no undue value on the chaff of merely
                            phenomenal manifestations, but sought the living truth that would touch the inuer life and
                            elevate to that high plane to which Jesus referred when he said ;"If I h.i lifted up I will
                            draw all men unto me." To be ministered to by "Christ angels" and through conquest of the
                            earthly life within, to hold permanent relationship with spirits in aid out of the body who
                            had thus entered th." resum ction life, was his expressed desire at the time of his first
                            meeting with Elder Frederic. Subsequently he visited Mt. Lebanon, which he has ever since
                            consideied his spiritual center,the home of his soul. In his recent visit he immediately put
                            himself at our service, and the first evening the Church family met with us for an informal
                            meeting where we heard much of interest, connected with his travels and experiences with
                            people and places. He seemed alive with the Spirit and desired that chairs be . set aside
                            while we entered into the march, but the room being rather small for so large a company,
                            this was deferred till another occasion. As a physician of long experience, and one who has
                            studied man as a triune bung, body, soul and spirit we felt confidence in his advice
                            concerning the treatment of disease. Without denying that matter is matter and that evil is
                            evil, he accepts and teaches what to us seerm the central truth and vital principle of the
                            many Christian Science and Mental Healing theories, that God, goodness, truth and health are
                            positive in nature, evil and disease negative conditions, that all creative and renewing
                            forces work from within outward. He believes that medicines (from the vegetable kingdom) may
                            sometimes be helpful on the same principle that different qualities of food may supply
                            certain deficiencies, intelligent observance of physiological law is always necessary, but
                            most potent of all healing properties is that influx from the divine creative Source, made
                            possible to those who cultivate the receptive faculties to this end. The second evening, the
                            four families of the Society assembled at the Church family to hear a discourse upon things
                            of this world and that which is to come. Rich in instruction and inspirational power were
                            the two hours of our assembling there. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers and shaker spiritualism" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKERS AND SHAKER
                            SPIRITUALISM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/>By Dr. J. M. Peebles.</byline><p TEIform="p">[The following sketch from the pen of Dr.
                            Peebles, is taken from " The Light of Truth" of May 7, 1898.] 
                            Tho several times encircling the globe, I have never seennever found a Christian. I have
                            found Methodists, Baptists, Presbyterians, Mormons, Seventh-Day Adventistsselling, cheating,
                            persecuting, marrying, robbing, fighting and even killing <pb n="103" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 103 each other on gory battlefields, and all "In his name." But not a Christian,
                            a real genuine, spiritually-minded Christian, did I see. I saw and heard of those professing
                            Christianity, but professing and possessing are very different things. Those professi ng
                            were just as scheming, worldly and wicked as those they condemned for not having a creed
                            fashioned after their own. In fact, they were earthy and fully in line with John Milton's
                            Mythic Demons. On a sunny spring day, I was dropt down from the carriage into the midst of
                            several families or societies of Christiansand what a change! what quietness! what peace!
                            Altho advocating for many years that heaven was only a condition, I was now half inclined to
                            say"It is a placeand I have found it." Tho the Shakers have existed in America for a hundred
                            years or more, the masses do not seem to fully understand their teachings or the heavenly
                            lives that they live. The Shaker socialism is largely a pattern of an Essenean or Nazarenean
                            communism of Apostolic times. They are a spiritual people. They do not profess perfection,
                            but they are seeking to attain the highest and the purest. I know of no locality where there
                            is so much freedom, real soul freedom, as in Shaker communities, and by freedom I mean
                            liberty, the sweet liberty to do right to come into order and live the better, higher life.
                            These Communities are not as numerously peopled as they were many years ago. This was
                            prophesied by their seers and visionists, and it was further prophesied that ere the close
                            of this century there would begin a great ingathering of ripened souls. The Shakers are a
                            progressive people. They seek the new improvements in machinery, in culinary affairs and
                            also in literature. They will not fight. During the Civil War, in Kentucky, both armies, the
                            North and the South, marcht through and over their farms and they fed both armies from their
                            barns, their storehouses and their tables. They believe in arbitration for the settlement of
                            difficulties. The Shakers have made a practical exemplification of woman suffrage, of
                            woman's equality with man, for a hundred years. In their families the government is held and
                            equally administered by both male and female, the two halves of one circle. Many, very many
                            whom I know would be infinitely better off, physically, mentally, morally and spiritually if
                            they were to gather into these beautiful Shaker homes. Here they would find tender,
                            sympathizing brothers and sisters. Here they would find music, libraries to read, gardens to
                            be cultivated, fields to be tilled, and associations at once refining, loving and
                            spiritualizing. Of course they would not find perfectionperfection does not abound upon this
                            earth. There is but one absolute perfection in the universe, and that is Godbut there is no
                            place where the perfect life is so readily and philosophically attained as in a Shaker
                            community. The above description of what I saw, or heard or know of the Shakers, especially
                            at Mt. Lebanon, is true, and the truth as I see it I will fearlessly speak and fearlessly
                            write, and that, too, if I offend every acquaintance, forfeit every friendship, part with
                            every friend and lose every earthly possession. This is my motto: "Peace peace if possible,
                            but the truth at all hazards and at all prices." Indianapolis, Ind.</p></div2><div2 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ceeley, Sally" TEIform="index"/>In Memory of our Sister, SALLY
                            CEELEY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>By Elder Abraham Perkins.</byline><p TEIform="p">"/"^ OD i8 good to Israel, to such as are of a clean heart;"and such VU~ was the character of
                            Sister Sally. For seventy years I have been acquainted with her life and know whereof I
                            speak. Of her genuine good- <pb n="104" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 104 THE MANIFESTO. ness, her kindness of
                            heart, her gentleness of spirit, her humility and selfsacrifice, I have seen and known much.
                            With a God-fearing spirit she abounded, ever bearing testimony against every form of evil,
                            tho it cost her suffering, and tho in a degree, it severed friendships she would gladly
                            hold; and yet, with that testimony she exercised care and gentleness, to avoid giving
                            wounds; and knowing such effect it grieved her and reconciliation and pardon would
                            invariably be sought. In the order of the anointed priesthood, a strong faith was early
                            planted in her soul and it was with the greatest care and interest, spiritually vital, that
                            she sought to understand the gift at the altar and the will of those who ministered thereat,
                            so firmly did she believe this to be the means of God for salvation. Indeed there was no
                            rest for her, until she could feel her soul nnvailed before the light resting there, and
                            through that mediatorial order she received blessing. Persistent as was Jacob who would not
                            suffer the angel to go until he blest him, so our Sister wrestled for that spirit and life
                            which crowns her conqueror. Very soon after my admission to fellowship in our Christian
                            church, I met with the dear Sister and learning that from early childhood she had been
                            educated among this people, how pure and innocent must be her life, I thought,how unknown to
                            her must be the sius of this world ; how faultless must she be before God! I ventured to
                            make some such remark to her. Her reply gave me a surprise; it showed me her convictions. 1
                            perceived she had been with Christ wrho had revealed to her the knowledge of her humanity
                            and an acquaintance with the human heart. Protected as she had been, she discovered in
                            herself a world to overcome. At that early day of my gospel privilege, I was but a tyro;
                            ignorant, comparatively, of the vastness of the Christian work before me and of the weakness
                            of humanity, therefore I was unable fully to comprehend her meaning. Since then, I have had
                            experiences which have enlightened my soul and given me knowledge of the lesson she set
                            before me. I have been in constant attendance at a school which has given me many profitable
                            lessons, given me a key to my own heart and actual knowledge of the work of God unto
                            salvation, clearly delineating the branches of knowledge pursued by our departed Sister
                            early in childhood which, I believe, has given her an honorable and coveted graduation,
                            fitting her for the society of the just made and making perfect and for a home and an
                            alliance with angels. She has left for us a bright example of righteousness worthy our
                            emulation which should stimulate others to "go and do likewise." East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To climb the golden ladder..." TEIform="index"/>To climb the golden ladder...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">To climb the golden ladder, which doth lead to God above ; I must have my strength made
                            great, by feeding on God's tove.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="McGinnis, W. C." TEIform="persName"/>W. C. McGinnis.</byline></div2><pb n="105" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cause and effect" TEIform="index"/>CAUSE AND EFFECT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>By Hamilton DeGraw.</byline><p TEIform="p">IN comprehending and illustrating this Divine law, we are entering a realm which has been
                            considered too sacred for man. if we are to judge by the methods of procedure by which he
                            has dealt with the mome'itous questions pertaining to his life and destiny. But to deny that
                            there is a realm forbidden him to explore is only proclaiming a truth known to illuminated
                            minds of all ages. He has been debarred only by his inability to understand the facts
                            pertaining to those questions, which will be removed as he develops his capacity for their
                            comprehension. The laws both of heredity and climatic influences are as operative with
                            nations and races as with individual entities; they being some of the prominent causes which
                            have produced the diversified lines of thought manifest in the different races. The effects
                            produced are largely shown in their religious beliefs and with that hold upon the intellect
                            and conscience which makes the efforts to turn the current of national thought into a
                            foreign channel an almost hopeless task. In the efforts to Christianize the old religious
                            beliefs of India which date back long anterior to the foundation of our religious cycle, and
                            rejecting the causes by which they were produced and ignoring the universal truth which
                            underlies the foundation of all religious beliefs, and trying to place them upon false
                            premises has produced the effects which are apparent at the present time. Assertions that
                            they do not sympathize with modern thought and are holding back the car of progress that to
                            outward appearances is moving forward with increasing speed is not satisfactory, for while
                            accepting the belief of all religious systems in the universal destiny of the race, may they
                            not find acceptable reasons for rejecting that which to those who are looking into the
                            interior life is moving on a line which unless changed will culminate in results as
                            disastrous as those which overthrew the nations of antiquity. "All is not gold that glitters
                            nor wealth that shines," and in our own country the efforts made to alleviate the
                            unfortunates in life's battle by1 building asylums where they can find relief, and places of
                            refuge where the criminally inclined can be incarcerated and society protected from their
                            depredations is without doubt prompted by feelings of kindness; but it is only dealing with
                            the effects as they are made apparent and neglecting the causes which are productive of such
                            discordant results. When through gigantic combinations of wealth the necessities of life can
                            be advanced in price beyond the limit which the laws of trade demand, and the rights of the
                            people rejected to the extent that millions can be placed to the credit of the combination
                            as witness the recent coal combine, where is the limit to be placed and how will those
                            poverty producing forces be brought under the control of the higher law of love to our
                            fellow man ? By donating <pb n="106" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 106 THE MANIFESTO. a few thousand to the
                            founding of asylums or to prosecute those unfortunates goaded to desperation by want they
                            may think to quiet their conscience and be represented before the world as her benefactors.
                            But "the blood of thy brother crieth unto me from the ground" is the voice of the divine
                            Spirit and never before has it been with such distinctness as at the present time. We are
                            not sounding the note of an alarmist who believes that the efforts which are being made for
                            improvement are futile to stem the revolutionary tendencies but whether the transition from
                            the convulsive period of the present to the more perfect one of the coming'time shall be
                            through a peaceful educational development of an understanding and acceptance of the Divine
                            law which says that, while one being created in the image of the Father suffers hunger or
                            cold, or has not the means placed within its reach that it can use for its material and
                            spiritual improvement society has a great preparatory work to do and is on dangerous ground
                            until it is accomplisht. Or will it be as has been the changes of the past through clashing
                            of interests culminating in the arbitrament of war? The pilot that is to direct human life
                            out of the almost interminable labyrinth into which it has plunged largely through ignorance
                            of the laws governing its own life, is the Divine law which says that every effect is the
                            result of a corresponding cause which clears away the mystification that has to the external
                            mind clouded the truth and in the form of creeds and senseless ceremonies made it difficult
                            to understand, when "the wayfarer tho a fool need not err" in his comprehension if presented
                            unmasked. Geology tells us that the present forms of life retain faint traces of markings by
                            which they can be traced back to the more primitive forms from whence they came and placed
                            in their true order by the divine law of evolution as it has operated in the material world.
                            So in the realm of the spiritual the forms of thought which are the effects of a past
                            barbaric age have left their impress upon the present, but which is passing away through the
                            ability of the soul to more perfectly understand the truth enabling it to discriminate
                            between the forces that are only transitory in their operation and those that are eternal.
                            While in the darkness of night we hope for and have confidence in the coming of morning; so
                            in the present blindness, measures that at best are only temporary in their operation will
                            give place to that knowledge which will go to the foundation of the social structure,
                            placing the temple that will be reared on a basis that is enduring, proving the truth of the
                            words of the Divine Teacher, "for whatsoever a man soweth, that shall he also reap."
                            Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True repentance is turning from evil to good..." TEIform="index"/>True repentance is turning from evil to good...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">True repentance is turning from evil to good ; from self to God. Tears without turning will
                            never be owned for repentance.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. P.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He walks with God..." TEIform="index"/>He walks with God...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">He walks with God who walks with man aright.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><pb n="107" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. JULY, 1898. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is publisht by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all communications
                            to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. TERMS. One copy one year, postage paid.
                            .50 A cross in the margin will show that your subscription has closed. Remittances for
                            subscription by Money Order should be on the Post Office at Concord, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">May. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Rain. 1897. 56.74 2.25 in. 1898. 56.
                                3.875 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 80 above 0. Lowest " " " " 40 " " Number of rainy
                                days " " 10 " " clear " " " 8 " " cloudy" " " 13 June, 1898. May has been profuse in
                                blossoms. Fruit trees of all kinds; shrubs, vines, plants and even the mosses have been
                                clad with all the variegated tints that produce beauty and impart aroma to give pleasure
                                to the artistic mind and to suffuse the appreciative senses. If fruits are produced in
                                proportion to the profusion of blossoms we can not reasonably say that we are scantily
                                supplied withfrugiverous aliment. The month has been superabundantly suffused with rain
                                and overshadowed with clouds, so that very little planting has been done either on the
                                farm or in the garden. Upon the whole, the spring months have been quite backward. We
                                have had but eight clear days in May. About the 8th of June we shall have the presence
                                of our Ministry with us for a few days to arrange the program for the summer and then
                                away they will be gone most of the ensuing year. We are infoimed that the Alfred
                                Ministry will be with us some time this week. It is quite an interval since we were
                                privileged to enjoy their company. They will be very welcome. Some repairs are being
                                made for home accommodations, and our tenants. Turn and turn and overturn are the
                                necessajy requisitions demanded if we keep abreast of this progressive age, even if we
                                abstain from battering the fortifications of Spain. We have a paramount duty to keep at
                                bay those discordant passions that make enemies of nations and that produce discord
                                among members of the same family, and as a religious body to maintain the principle and
                                the practice of unsullied peace and harmony that ultimately will result in the Great
                                Millennium, which is the anticipated outcome of the Chiistian Dispensation, when swords
                                shall be beaten into ploughshares and spears into pruning hooks; when cannons, guns,
                                bayonets and pistols, shall be turned into implements of peaceful industry; when war
                                vessels shall be used for commercial purposes only, and nations shall neither learn nor
                                practice war any more. Even so, angels and men speed the day! It is a time of general
                                health in our family, and so far as I know of the Society. May this blessing continue
                                with us, and may we truly feel; <pb n="108" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 108 THE MANIFESTO. 'Angels e'er
                                are near us. watching o'er our way, We may hear their voices mi;l the toil of day, We
                                may know their presence, giving strength and cheer; Weary not, worry notangels e'er are
                                near." Calvin G. Heed. North Family. June, 1898. June, lovely June, with its sunshine
                                and showers gives us of its beauties in the springing forth of fruits and flowers. The
                                Brethren, engaged in the necessary sowing and planting have watcht with careful and
                                anxious eye for the growth of vegetation. Fear, many times, has taken possession of the
                                sower lest frequent rains might destroy the tender plants. Eldress Anna White and Sister
                                Ann Offcrd spent a few days in the vicinity of Boston. Much interest was shown by the
                                fiiends there through the investigation of Shakerism, also the subject of Arbitration
                                was discussed bringing up both sides of the question. The Sigters distributed many
                                tracts entitled "War Positively Unchristian." On their return home they stopt at
                                Enfield, Conn. The meeting of gospel kindred strengthens the bond of love and friendship
                                which only the true disciple of Christ can realize and appreciate. The article in the
                                Ladies' Home Journal, "A Wonderful Little World of People," has awakened many minds to
                                the knowledge that in this beautiful world there is a people who are living in it, but
                                who are not one with it, that pleasure and enjoyment does not necessarily consist in
                                outward or external amusement. The fruits of the Spirit are love, joy, peace and
                                everlasting life. Sarah .1. Burger. South Family. June, 1898. A new season has dawned, a
                                summer of beauty and action lies before us, the resurrection of life in its fullness.
                                Old things are passing away, behold all things are becoming new. With the aid of paint,
                                energy and perseverance a newness of life is being printed on our home, external and
                                internal, and we wonder "If our home is so beautiful here, What must be our final home !
                                If things that perish, so lovely appeur, What must it be in the world to come!" We have
                                at present a promise of a fruitful harvest; if a profusion of blossoms is a forerunner
                                of such glad tidings no one need want for the fruitage of the vineyard. Just now we are
                                anticipating a delegation from the East. They will compose our Maine company and be our
                                Maine stay while with us. Decoration day was pleasingly observed by members of Second
                                family with a party from our family who spent a few hours among the graves of many who
                                "died on earth but live in heaven." Songs appropriate to the occasion were sung,
                                readings recitations and dialogs were spoken in harmony with the observance of the day.
                                The graves were richly strewn with flowers of the season. Kind thoughts of the departed
                                were exprest as the floral offerings were carefully deposited in memory of the absent
                                ones, and we thought of our dearest friend and Sister, Lydia Dole whose spirit is happy
                                above and ofttimes visits us during the active hours of the day and holds sweet
                                communion with us while we travel through dreamland. The far-famed Shaker chairs of Mt.
                                Lebanon are in constant demand from all points of the compass. They are recommended for
                                their beauty, perfection and comfort. Should any one care For a good Shaker chair At Mt.
                                Lebanon, N. Y. let them call, We have them just right Cherry color and white And can
                                suit both the great and the small. Genevieve DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1898. Theke has been evolved from out of the struggle between ths cold of spring
                                and summer's warmth a royal diadem of <pb n="109" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 109 roses.
                                Lovely June is now triumphantly enthroned as the leader and director of the forces which
                                will, when the shades of autumn deepen, bring to us the consummation of garners well
                                supplied, we hope, with the products which a bountiful season has placed at our
                                disposal. The diary notes from the travels of the early missionaries who visited the
                                West in the early years of the century are interesting. They went forward with their
                                life in their hands, ready to lay it down at the call of duty. Of such souls are
                                constituted the hero martyrs who by their example have made it honorable to be counted
                                with those who are willing to suffer for the truth. Those who were receivers of that
                                divine light, as well as the mediums through which it was given, know that its
                                promulgation was fraught with dangers that the ordinary mortal would not have braved
                                unless inspired by a zeal and consecration that could make the words of the divine
                                Teacher applicable: 1 "'Greater love hath no man than this that a man lay down his life
                                for his friends." We have realized of late more than usual the conscious presence of
                                those dear friends who have past beyond the limits of the shadows that to a greater or
                                less extent enshroud our earth life. In our seasons of devotion they have especially
                                manifested their presence to admonish and to comfort those who yet have the battle of
                                life to fight. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1898. June, the ideal month of sunshine and beautj is with us once more, and we are
                                enjoying its many virtues, realizing that it will leave us all too soon, and imagining a
                                day in the distant future when we may enjoy preserved June sunshine, taken from the
                                abundance of that month for use during the cold winter. Since our last call at the Home
                                Circle nature has been busily at work. The trees have budded and blossomed in all their
                                varied beauty, and have now cast aside their holiday attire, and are hard at wTork
                                forming the fruits for a harvest by and by. . A step from the artificial brings is to
                                the useful, in the plant kingdom, and reminds us of the stores of hay gathered last
                                summer by the wise people of Hancock. After wintering the stock from the supply and
                                losing between sixty and seventy tons by fire, this spring there has been prest, one
                                hundred ninety-five tons, and one hundred tons still remain. Last week six car loads
                                were sent from our depot to New York. The price paid however, is too low to give
                                satisfaction and the remainder will be kept until brighter days and higher prices
                                appear. Some of our buildings are renewing their youth, at least in appearance, by fresh
                                paint. The Ministry's shop is just completed and is greatly improved. Other buildings
                                are to share the same treatment. The new barn is finisht with the exception of the
                                covering of the roof with tin shingles. The familiar couplet, "There's never a day so
                                cloudy but a little sun appears" might be reversed t &gt; suit the present occasion with
                                us. for that there's never a day so sunny but a little cloud appears is proved true by
                                the departure of our loved Ministry to-morrow for Mt. Lebanon. But having resolved to be
                                unselfish, we will congratulate our friends over the mountain for the presence of souls
                                so true. As we are writing the door opens and we are introduced to friends from Maine,
                                Eldress Harriet Goodwin, Elders William Dumont and Henry Green, who are making a very
                                short call at our home, for like golden opportunities we hardly realize their presence
                                when we find they have left us, having delivered, however, messages of courage and good
                                cheer. Fidelia Estabrook.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1898. The daring, heroic deed of Lieut. Richmond Hobson and his associates in
                                sinking the Merrimac in the Santiago harbor to <pb n="110" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 110 THE MANIFESTO.
                                bar in the Spanish fleet, not only adds another mark of merit to American naval history,
                                but tells in clarion tones of strict discipline and self-surrender to duty's call
                                requiring a whole life in service. !N"o less is required of the followers of Christ,
                                called to battle the evils that war against the bulwarks of truth and virtue,a divine
                                engagement, prohibiting conquests by all things that bear the stamp of unchristliness.
                                "Grain by grain the treasure's won, Step by step the race is run, Then be patient, toil
                                away, Gain a little every day." To idly wait for an occasion to do some great deed which
                                idle dreaming may cast upon the glass of transitory imagination, and let pass the many
                                little acts, of fellowhelpfulness each day presents, denotes a slipshod state of
                                morality, a treasure well rusted with sordid selfishness. The fruits of our faith are
                                the acts done, by intellect prompted, and only absolute mastery of self and strong faith
                                in the possibility to gain the aspired-for attitude of spirituality can make chastity's
                                fortress impregnable and her treasures such as bless humanity. Idleness is inconsistent
                                with a Christian life and sweet musings of no inspiring virtue, are the cobwebs of
                                spiritual disease, which if not removed from the life will ultimately deface the whole
                                superstructure of character and active goodness. An inspection of our orchards revealed
                                trees heavily laden with blossoms, foretell ing an abundance of fruit, no unseen foe
                                appearing. Our three strawberry beds, set out and managed by Sisters, Isabella Eussell
                                and Lizzie Curtis, also promise a large crop of our favorite berry. Iron pipe,
                                comprising nine pieces and weighing nearly seven tons, has been pur chased to replace
                                the old wood pipe which has done good service for over half a century at our saw-mill,
                                where over thirty thousand shingles have been sawed this spring by one of our young
                                Brethren. With love to all, we would live out the inspiration of Emerson's grand
                                thought: "And each shall care for the other, And each to each shall bend; To the poor, a
                                noble brother, To the good, an equal friend." George H. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1898. Faith and industry are beautifully combined in the ideal Christian.character.
                                This dual element of success challenges the world for a greater. Our farmers are
                                particularly active at this season, and the home bulletin gives full scope to their
                                reports. One and a half acres of early potatoes, and ten of later variety are already
                                planted. Ensilage corn covering twenty acres has put in an appearance three inches tall,
                                it seems to realize that three large silos, each of 100 ton capacity, are to be well
                                stockt in the fall. Field corn covers three acres. The farmer prophets notify "all whom
                                it may concern" of an ample hay crop D. V. adding the toothsome message that green peas
                                will be ready for consumption before the end of the month. Asparagus and radishes have
                                already been consumptive, but we diagnosed the case successfully. All fruit trees
                                promise well, and we have put in large orders. Caterpillars form an opposing army, but
                                some skirmishing has been done in this direction. "We have met the enemy and they are
                                ours." The crow instinct is strong at this season, but few damages are recorded as yet.
                                Small fruits promise well, cultivated blackberries and raspberries are welcome
                                strangers. Three severe thunder-storms, with almost cyclonic wind, came this way on the
                                9th but without destruction. The pastures so green at this date afford ample diet for
                                the cattle, and as grateful response thirty-two fine cows produce ninety-five gallons of
                                milk per day. This enables us to sell on an average perhaps one hundred pounds of butter
                                per week. <pb n="111" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFES Tt K 111 Love to Zion and her interests,
                                spiritual and material, being the loom which centers all the threads of daily devotion,
                                our web can bear the scrutiny of the keen or the curious. Jessie Evtms.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoossee, Florida" TEIform="index"/> Narcoossee, Fla.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1898. Fbuit trees and vegetables of all kinds from middle to southern Florida are
                                suffering very much for the want of rain. The Managers of the great St. Cloud Sugar
                                Plantation were at our home last week and exprest a deep feeling of interest about their
                                sugar-cane. They said unless there came rain and that soon, their crop would be an
                                entire failure. If such be the case it will be a bad stroke to Osceola Co. They exprest
                                a very satisfactory feeling as to the looks of our cane, pine-apples and Irish potatoes,
                                all telling the worth of irrigation. For over a month our wind' mill and tank have been
                                in constant use. Our young Believers three in number, have attended to this part of the
                                program while we old settlers have been making three miles more of fence to protect us
                                from the herds of marauding cattle that are now covering the plains of Florida, let
                                loose by their owners in search of pasturage and water in hopes of sustaining life
                                through this terrible drought. Every part of Florida that has not a fence to protect the
                                farmer is free plunder. Our tomato crop, which is the largest we have ever planted, is
                                just beginning to ripen, and judging from present prospects we shall have some to sell
                                and many to can. Corn crop all through the state is a failure and this tells on the poor
                                farmer 75 cents a bushel. Sister Annie Lane is just now putting in part of her time in
                                poultry-raisingthus far it is a success. The old hen hatches tiie chickens and after two
                                days Sister Annie takes them to the Brooder to do the rest. This certainly makes the
                                labor in raising a flock of chickens far less. All information in regard to raising
                                chickens by Brooders can be had from Brother Francis Pennybaker of Pleasant Hill, Mercer
                                Co., Ky. To those who make this a business it is worth their time to look into the
                                matter, for in this way we have not lost a chicken, while with us and with others, it
                                was common at times to lose a third of the brood. A word to the wise is sufficient. Corn
                                and rye ensilage is beginning to be used in Florida and farmers are experimenting as to
                                its worth in the dairy line. Could the dairy business be well regulated in Florida it
                                would improve the advantages of living very much. The whole drift has bten for beef
                                cattle and but very little attention given to the dairy. Life means learning to abhor
                                the false and love the true. Every day teaches us lessors in our new home, and can we
                                only reject the errors and hold to the true we shall finally succeed. Andrew
                            Ilarrett.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, Ohio.</head><p TEIform="p">June, Ib98. Season follows season, and we know it has been declaied by the word oi' Cod
                                that "seed-time and harvest shall not fail." We have many blessings to record in the
                                past and present. The month of June is now with us, and nature manifests herself in
                                beauty which delights the eye and the thoughts. Bright prospects of bountiful harvests
                                make us particularly thankful. Our meadows say that there will be a large crop of hay,
                                wheat is looking well, raspberries and strawberries are in fine condition. In fact we
                                expect a generous crop of all kinds of fruit this year, for which we have great reason
                                to thank God. We have been blest by a visit from our Ministry of Union Village, between
                                the 4th and 7th inst. During church service on the Sabbath we were addrest by Elder
                                Joseph, and by Elder Oliver C. Hampton. The words that were spoken came from experience,
                                and we believe much good will result. Our Brother James McBvide is very <pb n="112" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 112 THE MANIFESTO. feeble, otherwise the health of our Society is good.
                                As our prospects seem bright in all temporal things, let us ever be mindful of the
                                goodness of God and his mercies, and seek to realize our spiritual ideals in the life
                                that is and that which is to come. John Westwood.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Which is the better way?" TEIform="index"/>WHICH IS THE BETTER WAY?</head><p TEIform="p">How many of us when we come into collision with another think that he also may be hurt? A
                            little boy bumpt his head against the wall, and ran to his mother crying to be kissed. She
                            said: "What a bad wall to hurt poor Willie! Go hit the wall!" Another day he bumpt his head
                            against a playmate, and at once struck him to punish the injury. Another child, with a wiser
                            mother, hurt himself, and after the spot had been duly kist, the mother said: "But who will
                            kiss the poor chair? You hit the chair when you tumbled against it." When he fell against
                            his little brother, and they both got hurt, he remembered the lesson, and said: "Kiss Harry,
                            too." Which is the better way, and which child will be more likely to grow up kind and
                            considerate in all the relations of life?</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>OUR EXCHANGES.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes and queries" TEIform="index"/>Notes and queries
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Notes and queries is a Monthly Magazine of History, Folk Lore, Mathematics, Mysticism,
                                Art, Science, etc. Publisht by C. S. &amp; L. M. Gould, Manchester, N. H. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian" TEIform="index"/>The
                                Christian
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The
                                Christian is an Illustrated Monthly, Eeligious, Temperance, Family Paper, comprising
                                four, 4page papers. Edited by H. L. Hastings, Boston, Mass. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our dumb animals" TEIform="index"/>Our Dumb Animals
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Our Dumb Animals is publisht
                                in the interest of "The Massachusetts Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals."
                                It is under the editorial management of George T. Angell, Boston, Mass. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of hygeio-therapy and anti-vaccination" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of
                                Hygeio-Therapy and Anti-Vaccination
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of
                                Hygeio-Therapy and Anti-Vaccination, edited by Dr. T. V. Gifford of Kokomo, Ind.
                                "Devoted to a correct method of living and a scientific and successful system of
                                treating the sick without the use of drugs."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="As soon as a hermetically sealed fruit can is opened..." TEIform="index"/>
                            As soon as a hermetically sealed fruit can is opened...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> soon as a hermetically sealed fruit can is opened pour out all the fruit, as the acid on the
                            tin and the acid of the atmosphere, will generate a poison.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Edwards, Rebecca" TEIform="index"/>Rebecca Edwards
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Rebecca Edwards, at South Union, Ky. April 11, 1898. Age 79 years 1 mo. and 25 days.
                                Sister Rebecca entered the Society forty- nine years ago, and has been an interested
                                laborer in the vineyard of the Lord, giving her talents unreservedly to his service. J.
                                C. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ceeley, Sally" TEIform="index"/>Sally Ceeley
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Sally Ceeley, at East Canterbury, N. H. June 4, 1898. Age 92 years 5 mo. and 5 days.
                                A ripened sheaf is gathered into the "harvest home." J. E.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Conklin, Angeline Alvira" TEIform="index"/>Eldress Angeline Alvira
                                Conklin
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Eldress Angeline Alvira
                                Conklin, at Shakers, N. Y. June 4, 1898. Age 72 years 4 mo. and 10 days. She has been
                                among Believers since childhood, has filled all places of care and trust in the family.
                                Faithfully, honestly and conscientiously she has proved her faith by her works. "No
                                greater love and consecration can any soul show, than to willingly lay down his life for
                                the cause." This she has done. In her we lose a mother, counselor and friend. I. A.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truair, Jerusha" TEIform="index"/>Jerusha Truair
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> 
                                Jerusha Truair, at Shakers N. Y. June 6, 1898. Age 81 years 7 mo. and 27 days. She had
                                been with Believers for sixtysix years, first with the Society at Sodus, with whom she
                                removed to Groveland, thence to Shakers, N. Y. She has been an honest, industrious,
                                faithful soul, and has lived a long life of usefulness. E. E. W.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
and characteristic cover, upon which is represented the Oregon on its way to join the
fleet, as well as the colored map of Cuba and
the West Indies which accompanies each
number.   This work is publisht by Munn & Co.
361 Broadway, Sew York, at 25 cents.   For sale
at all news stands.
In our advertising columns will be found an
announcement of Ex Senator John J. Ingiills'
fortncouiing book, entitle 1  America's Wxh
for Humanity.   Canvassing agents will find
in it a book of remarkable interest, s;nd certainly of extraordinary salability.   The history of the war is told in picture and story,
and in a way that always characterizes the
brilliant pen of Senator Ingalls.    In narrating
the incidents of this war he find.-* grand scone
for his superb descriptive and analytical powers.   The theme is worth\- of the author, and
the author is worthy of the theme.   It is published by N. D. Thompson Publishing Co., of
St Louis, Mo.   It will be a monumental work
that will not only be everywhere read, but it
will be a monument to bis genius that will
outlive in history his brilliant senatorial career.   The subscription book trade and the
canvassing agent are fortunate in the fact
that an author of such rare ability has been
enlisted in its interest.
The Journal of tiygi io Therapy, The
Science of Life; The Sick Man's Vision ; The
Fashion of Mourning Veils at Funerals; The
Slaughter of Birds; A ntiVaccination; Christian Living; Tlv Science of Phrenology.    Dr.
T. V. Gifford & Co., Kokomo, Ind.
Rear-Admiral Dewey greets us in portraiture from the cover of The Phrenological
Journal June No., and within is a timely
character sketch of the Hero of Manila, by J.
A. Fowler.   Fighting Physiognomy; An Analysis of Four Prominent Presidents of the United States;   In English and American Men and
Women of Note, D. T. Elliot presents very interesting sketches, with poi traits of Mr. T.
MeKinnon Wood, the late Rev. Geo. Muller,
Mrs. Clarence Burns, and Mr John T. Miller.
Phrenology and Religion; The Amateur
Phrenological Club; The Healing Art in the
Twentieth Century; Child Culture, etc.   Fowl3i- and Wells Co., 27 P^ast 21st St., New York.
WANTED
By Old "Established
HouseHigh Grade
Man or Woman, of good Church standing
to act as Manager here and do office work
and correspondence at their home. Business already built up and established here.
Salary $900. Enclose self-addressed
stamped envelope for our terms to A. P.
T. Elder, General Manager, 189 Michigan
Avenue, Chicago, 111., First Floor.
"THE LIGHT OF  THE WORLD
OR OUR SAVIOR IN ART"
Cost over $100,000 to publish. Contains nearly 200 full-page engravings of our Savior, hy
the Great Msi fteiv. Hi.- not a life of Christ,
bur an exhibit of all the ;.-reat Masters' ideals
of the Christ. No otlici- book like it ever published. Agents aie ti-k.ng lioni three to
twenty orders tlail\ . The nook is so beautiful that when people see it they want it. Published less -than a \ ear and ;:hv;i<i\ in it-twenty-fifth edition, some e.iitions con.-i.-ting of
18,500 books. The pre.^es are running day
anU night to till orders. (It has never been
sold iu this territory.) A peril-al of the pictures of this book is'like taking a tour an.ong
the great art galhnes of Europe. Tin-Hermititge, Prauo, L'liizi, Pitti, Louvre, Vatican,
National of Lou ion, National of Berlin, Belvidere and other celebrsited European ait
galleries, have oil placed tl.e.r rarest and
greiite.-t treasures at oui- di-po.-al that they
might be reproduced for this superb work.
'FIRST GLANCK AT THE PICTURES
BROUGHT TEA US TO MY EYES," says one.
'Cleared $150 first week's work with the
book," says another. Many m-n and women
Inlying arid paying for homes f roi. theiv success with this gres^t work. Also man or
woman, of good church standing, can secure
position of manager here to do office woik
and corresponding witli agents in thi.-s territory. Address for full particulars A. P. T.
Elder, Puolisher, IS!) Michigan Avc, Chicago,
111 , First Floor.
AGENTS WANTED
in Every County to Supply
the Great Popular Damand for
AMERICA'S WAR FOR
Compiled and Written by
SENATOR  JOHN   J.   INGALLS
Of Kansas.
The most brilliantly written, most profusely and artistically illustrated, and
most intensely popular book on the subject of the war with Spain.    Nearly
200 Superb Illustrations from Photograph
taken specially for this great work.
Agents are making $50 to 8100 a week
selling it.    A veritable bonanza for live
canvassers.    Apply for description, terms
and territory at once to
N. D. Thompson Publishing Co.
ST. LOUIS, MO.,or NEW YORK CITY
HUMANITY
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
Royal makes the food pure,
wholesome and delicious.
50   YEARS'
EXPERIENCE
k   Trade Marks
Designs
Copyrights &c.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain our opinion free whether an
invention is probably patentable. Communications strictly confidential. Handbook on Patents
sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice, without charge, in the
Scientific American.
A handsomely illustrated weekly. Largest circulation of any scientific journal. Terms, $3 a
year; four months, $1.  Sold by all newsdealers.
MUNN & Co.361Broadwav New York
Branch Office, 625 F St., Washington, D. C.
HOW TO MAKE MONEY!
If you are out of employment and want
a position paying you from $50 to $100
monthly clear above expenses by working
regularly, or, if you want to increase your
present income from $200 to $500 yearly,
by working at odd times write the GLOBE
CO. 723 Chestnut St. Phila., Pa. stating
age, whether married or single, last or
present employment, and you can learn
how to make more money easier and
faster than you ever made before in your
life.
AUTHOEISED   EULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   0OMMUNITY.
Tlie religious basis of the Obdek must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
SHARER HAMAMELIS
(WITCHHAZEL,)
.A. remedy for Cu.ts, Burns, Scalds,
Headaohe,rSore Throat and all
cases of external inflammation
Taken internally for JBowel
Complaint, Bleeding of tlie
Lungs or IBo^vels, and for 
all aches and pains.
For use externally, bathe the parts and
lay on a cloth wet with the Extract,    Internally, take one half teaspoonful three
times a day.    Use hot or cold.
Ask your druggist for it or send your
order to Arthtjb Bruce.
East Canterbury, N. H.
ROYAL BAKING POWDER CO., NEW YORK.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>