<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0906" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><date value="18790601" TEIform="date">June 1879</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">121-144</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> JUNE, 1879. MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) G. A. LOMAS, Editor. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT
                        HARVARD, MASS. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony:" ''Go preach the Kingdom of God!" ADDRESS ALL
                        COMMtTNTCATIOKS TO " The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1879. Vol. IX. j No. 6. j 60 Cents
                        Per Annum. The Shaker</p>
                        --><pb id="p2" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Advertisements" TEIform="index"/>[Advertisements]</head><p TEIform="p">[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><pb id="p4" TEIform="pb"/></p></div2><pb n="121" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home that we have found" TEIform="index"/>THE HOME THAT WE HAVE FOUND</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>CECELIA DEVYR</byline><p TEIform="p"> Glittering nature wakes to greet us, At the dawning of the day; Blossoms, birds, and
                            fragrant breezes, All " Good morning " seem to say. And the dreams that filled our slumbers
                            Whether sorrowful or bright, Melt away like mists of morning, In the glorious living light.
                            Then we meet and bless each other, With a feeling deep and true. Mingled with oar thanks to
                            Heaven, For a life so sweet and new. Then, I think of hearts that suffer In the world's
                            distracted state ; How the morning breaks upon them, But to show their bitter fate. Quickly
                            from that dismal picture, Turns my spirit in deep pain ; Praying that the powers immortal,
                            Will not ever strive in vain. For, amid earth's boundless beauty Nations dwell beneath a
                            pall! Having with a grim precision, " Things adapted to the Fall." Who shall rend the vail
                            of darkness ? Who shall break the clouds of sin ? God must shake the old Creation, That His
                            truth its place may win. So the burden of my spirit, I consign unto the Lord ; And in
                            gathering to His children, Feel his blessing and reward. Thus the day with all its labor,
                            Rolls so swiftly to its close ; And its shadows long and quiet, Bring the heart a deep
                            repose. When the royal robe of evening, Is exchanged for mantled grey— When the silver stars
                            like spirits, Come so softly o'er our way ; When the wind that rocks the maple, Sings the
                            robin to its sleep, And unnumbered sounds are blended In a concert grand and deep, Then our
                            thoughts, like lambs, are gath ered To our hearts, as to a fold, And we try to count the
                            treasures, That can never all be told. There are words of precious counsel, Acts of
                            kindness, love and care ; Thoughtful eyes that looked a blessing, Smiles of joy and peace
                            are there. And perhaps, " Good night " was spoken, And its gentle tones we hear Like an
                            angel voice above us, As the realm of sleep we near. For in silence, or in music, In the
                            shadow, or the light, Nothing but the hearts that love us, Ever truly says,.' Good night,"
                            Scenes of loveliness surround us, Heaven and earth with gifts abound, Yet the faithful
                            hearts that love us, Form the home that we have found. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mission of Jesus" TEIform="index"/>THE MISSION OF JESUS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p"> Is God less able now to manifest His power than in Apostolic days ? Or is not His power a
                            necessity now as then? Tutelary deities — semi-gods — some partly civilized, others in a
                            limited degree spiritualized, ruled in the unprogressed ages of heathenism, and Judaism, and
                            were adapted to the conditions of idol-worshipping, warring, polygamous nations and peoples
                            of olden time. Mediumistic gods still hold a place between the Infinite and finite, and are
                            directors or guiding stars pointing the way and giving light, as we journey up the hills of
                            truth and spiritual progression. In the days of Jesus and his Apostles, the Ministerial
                            Order under the <pb n="122" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 122 THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. Mosaic law, and the spirit
                            agencies that were employed in that dispensation, were superseded by higher laws and more
                            progressed spiritual agencies. And the prophets who were directed and inspired to build
                            temples and dedicate them in the name oJ G-od, and consecrate them to His service, and were
                            ancient Israel's glory, * strength and diadems ceased to be glorious by reason of the
                            greater glory and brightness that attended the Christ visitation through Jesus and his
                            devoted followers. The converts to a new, living faith required new gifts and ministrations
                            ; and new fountains of inspiration were opened unto them, and through the doors of the inner
                            spiritual temple of God—which the outward temple symbolized—came a higher order of
                            ministering angels and spirits, requiring greater sacrifices and more self-denial. But they
                            came not to destroy the law nor to weaken its force; they, by increased spirituality and
                            vitality added strength to the outgoing epoch, and opened new channels of thought which
                            stimulated to greater action in broader fields and higher spheres. A new baptism was added.
                            Water baptism, as an outward body purifier, was necessary to be retained and practiced; but
                            the soul baptism of fire and the Holy Spirit, to quicken the conscience, give repentance and
                            burn up the lusts of the world and purify the heart, was the all needed ministration which
                            Jesus received and dispensed to his disciples; and with the aid of the heavenly soul
                            baptism, Jesus was inspired to give the beautiful, comforting promise, " Lo, I am with you,
                            even unto the end.'* He was the first baptized Jew; the first whom the Christ spirit
                            anointed, of many brethren, who, by obedience to the divine teacher, also became sons of
                            God, and lights to the world— saviours in their day and time. The time was fulfilled, and
                            the spirit pressed for an entrance into the mundane sphere, peopled with sentient beings,
                            that by the co-operation of mortal agency, souls might be uplifted from low degraded
                            conditions to higher life and holier loves. Jesus was the chosen mediator of a " New
                            Covenant," and he felt his mission and was earnest to act well the part and do the work that
                            was given him to do. He knew there was a baptism for him such as mortal man had not hitherto
                            received ; and in his soulstruggles he said, " How am I straitened until it be
                            accomplished." He could not administer the sacred fire baptism, until his own soul had
                            passed the fiery ordeal, and with all the powers of his being he sought it, and like the
                            hart that pants for the water brooks, rested not till he found it. How many of the professed
                            followers of Jesus in our own time enter into the same struggles and yearn in spirit for the
                            soul-cleansing baptism as did the first anointed, our glorified exemplar, and like Him
                            receive it as God's alessing? He loved not his own life, Dhysical ease and self-indulgence,
                            but preferred to drink the bitter cup of Dain, persecution and suffering, rather than to
                            receive earthly glory, its pleasures or wealth, at the expense of principle. His life was
                            pre-eminently beautiful, for the inner feelings of his leart were out-wrought by noble deeds
                            of charity and love. He pitied the <pb n="123" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 123 erring,
                            sympathized with the oppressed and was merciful to the poor, lame, halt and blind, and
                            served them. He was a humanitarian friend, a marked benefactor of our race ! Such names (or
                            characters) cannot be erased from memory nor the pages of history, but will outlive the
                            centuries as they roll, and shine with increased luster, and be objects of praise and
                            admiration, bnt not of adoration.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Are the Shakers dying out?" TEIform="index"/>ARE THE SHAKERS DYING OUT?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p"> There has lately been an article going the rounds of the press, entitled "Shakers dying
                            out," written, perhaps, pursuant to the wish that an institution so antagonistic to the
                            elements of a worldly life, as the practical application of the principles of true
                            Christianity to the routine of daily life must be, might die out. " Do Shakers die ? "
                            Certainly ; they, as common participants in the effects of universal laws, operating alike
                            upon savage and civilian, sinner and saint, do " shuffle off the mortal coil " when the
                            spirit has no further use for it. Shakers may never be classed with those few hypersophists
                            and religious fanatics, [who never contemplate the experience of physical death! Nor may
                            they be classed with those who are to be equally disappointed by the re-manifestation upon
                            earth of the man Jesus Christ, to inaugurate a resurrection of the physical bodies of those
                            who believe in his mission on earth as the Saviour of Man. But, doubtless, the subject
                            assumes a more communistic type, and the question is, " Are Shaker Communities dying out ? "
                            A fear among conservatives, perhaps, of the success of Communism has agitated this hue and
                            cry, " Shakers dying out." Shaker organizations, as communes, are simply the result of its
                            principles; they do not constitute Shakerism, but consist of families, numbering variously,
                            from ten to one hundred and fifty. Several of these families in proximity are, in common
                            parlance, denominated a society. But some writers call each family or society a commune.
                            These institutions, to some extent, have now been in successfnl operation about 100 years ;
                            and, occasionally, within the past seventy-five or eighty years, there has been a
                            dissolution of some families and societies that were unfavorably located, and circumstances,
                            for the time, did not favor their prosperous continuance. In some cases, new ones were
                            instituted in their stead, in others, not. Sometimes families broken up have numbered fifty
                            or upwards, and the societies more than one hundred souls, and were possessed of many
                            hundreds, even thousands of acres of land, with fine substantial buildings, mills and
                            machinery. Four well organized societies have been broken up or removed during this period.
                            One of them from Wabash, Indiana, because of unhealthy climate, and the vicissitudes of war.
                            One removed from Sodus Bay, N. Y., on account of infringement upon society's possessions and
                            advantages by the anticipated construction of a ship canal, and accompanying enterprises of
                            gigantic magnitude. One removed from Gorham, Maine, while in the full tide of growing
                            prosperity, on account of lack of wood and timber; this proved to be an injudicious move.
                            One broke up and removed from Tyringham, Mass., on account of its unfavorable location for
                            sustaining a society of much magnitude. All these, but the last named, were broken up more
                            than fifty years ago. In reference to numbers, Shaker societies, like all religious bodies,
                            have had, from time to time, their ebbs and flows ; as have the tides of human conditions in
                            civil, social, political and governmental evolutions throughout the world ; and the question
                            of increase or decrease in members, depends largely upon the conditions of outside society.
                            When a wave of spirit life flows upon humanity, producing conviction for sin, and a desire
                            for purer, higher life, then will there be a harvest into the Christ Order— the Shaker phase
                            of progress. And it were useless to attempt to disguise the fact that, to substantially
                            sustain the organizations of families now instituted, more genuine ability and dignity of
                            manhood and womanhood, <pb n="124" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 124 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. more talent
                            consecrated to the upbuilding of Christ's Kingdom, are especially necessary. If the crowning
                            subject for consideration is the question, " Is Shakerism dying out ? " That is, are the
                            principles which constitute its religious status waning? We reply: There has never been a
                            period since its advent, as an institution, when the spread of its wing of power was so
                            wide, nor the height of its soar so lofty, as at the present time ! Never, in the period of
                            its history, has the light of Shaker testimony shone so eff'ulgently, its rays been so
                            peering,-nor the edge of its spiritual sword so deeply incisive upon all manner of public
                            and private evils existing in human society, as at the present day ! But the special mission
                            of Shakerism, which is simply unadulterated Christianity, is not to minister to the sowing
                            dispensation of humanity, but to the harvest of the world into the " Kingdom of Heaven."
                            And, when God's high providential institution for all material existence, mineral, vegetable
                            and animal, is annihilated, then, and then only, will or can, Shakerism die out! This
                            institution of providence consists in a spring time of germination, summer of growth and
                            development, and an autumn of harvest, and appropriation to higher uses. Humanity's harvest
                            from the worldly generative plane, even its most normal and perfect capacity, as well as its
                            abnormal state, must as truly take place in the progress of human evolution, as ever was the
                            earth harvested of its crops of grass, grains, forests and minerals. And the garnering of
                            humanity's soul life into the heavenly state, as subjects of a higher existence than the
                            earthly order can boast of, is Shakerism's labor of love! It is an instructive and
                            interesting fact of human history that, in all the phases of human evolution, whether from
                            barbarism into civilization, or, in its civilizing governmental progress and developments
                            from autocracy and absolute monarchy to limited monarchy on to republicanism; and, in the
                            social relations, from male lordship and polygamy, up to monogamy and female suffrage ; in
                            the religious histDry of human progress, from fetichism of savage life, on through the
                            phases of idolatry, up to ascetic supererogation, priestly domination, national creedism,
                            established and sustained by the sword ; and yet up to freedom of conscience, the liberty of
                            the human will, and the wide swoop of eagle liberty in free religion, ever and anon there
                            hath arisen the cry that the new departure, the new organization "is dying out! " But as
                            universally hath this cry ever been the direct result of the climax of development; the
                            death-throes of the perishing phases of progress, being outgrown, preceding an impending
                            manifestation of still higher and better conditions. In the governmental history of our
                            United States, her struggles through difficulties to attain unto higher nights of true
                            political » wisdom, how often has the vandal cry, the failure of a republican government,
                            been moaning over our fair American land, and even booming over the wide Atlantic to be
                            echoed and re-echoed upon European shores to natter the pride of kings! In the modern
                            struggles of the French nation for freedom from monarchy, how often hath the traitor's cry
                            of " death to the infant republic " been the tocsin of alarm to greater vigor to sustain the
                            onward march of pro gress. The present epoch of the world's history is decidedly
                            revolutionary, not only politically, but socially and religiously. All religious beliefs are
                            feeling humanity's change of blood ; the pulses are beating to purer heart-throbs, and
                            though institutions of human origin may and will perish in the strife, those God-originated
                            plans for human progress will not only survive the shock of deso lation's wand, but will
                            strengthen their roots by the fanning gales which writhe their branches, bowing them, for
                            the moment, to the blast, only to rise again to renewed life and beauty. If Shakerism is an
                            institution of human policy, it is so very contradictory to human nature, as to introduce a
                            house divided against itself ; therefore, cannot stand, and the sooner it falls to the
                            ground the better. If, on the contrary, it is the prestige of Divine love to humanity, and a
                            human evolution growing into existence as an unavoidable round in the ladder of human
                            progress, <pb n="125" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 125 and prophetically declared by thei
                            intuitive desire of humanity, manifest in all ages, among all nations, even with the wildest
                            and most ignorant, causing a class of each nation to live as ascetics, a virgin life, and
                            unto whom the balance of the nation look, as Oracles and Counsellors, which is a historical
                            fact, then, as one of God's Providential Institutions for human weal, and redemption from
                            sin, we behold its foundations sure, its building rising as a temple for the indwelling of
                            the Divine Aura, and the waters of its life fountains of saving power are flowing forth to
                            prepare an ocean for souls who choose to swim—the waters of Ezekiel's Vision! And, once
                            launched upon its waves, there will no longer be power to wade upon the earthly soil of
                            generation, and the consequent reproduction of human ills. Shakerism is not " dying otit,""
                            nor preparing to die ; and, were every vestige of its present trophies of earthly gains, or
                            the entire numbers who profess its faith, to be swept from the earth at once, the mental and
                            spiritual light and truth in vigorous operation, would, phcenix-like, suddenly raise it
                            again into immortal glory, prosperity and renown. Shakerism never can '' die out! " Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Testimony of Abigail Cook" TEIform="index"/>TESTIMONY OF ABIGAIL COOK</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Editor Manifesto : In taking up the book entitled " Testimonies concerning the Character of
                            Mother Ann Lee," and perusing some of the writings of those ancient Believers (Shakers), who
                            were so well acquainted with Mother Ann and her colaborers, among others was the testimony
                            of sister,Abigail Cook, from which I make a few extracts for our interesting little " Shaker
                            Manifesto/' as it will doubtless be new to many of its readers. " In the fall of 1780 (says
                            sister Abigail), we heard of Mother Ann and the/people who followed her; but did not believe
                            they were of God ; my feelings, more especially, were quite biased against them. My
                            husband's distress of mind became so great, that one day, while on his knees crying
                            fervently to God to direct him in the right way, he suddenly broke out in very loud
                            acclamations, which were succeeded by a violent shaking of the body, at which I was greatly
                            alarmed. He then testified that the people we had heard of were the people of God, and that
                            they were in the right way. This was a striking evidence tome, for I believed he was
                            operated upon by the power of God. " Soon after this, some who had embraced the new religion
                            came into Partridgefield, and we visited them, and found them to be very upright and godly
                            in their conversation and deportment, and all their teachings agreed with the precepts of
                            Christ and his apostles. My feelings of nature strove hard to stifle my conviction, and
                            induce me to try, if possible, to turn some other way, for this way was excessively crossing
                            to my vain hopes of carnal enjoyments, being then only in the eighteenth year of my age. But
                            their testimony was too clear for me to gainsay. In short, we both confessed our sins and
                            set out, once for all, to obey the testimony of the gospel. This was in February, 1781. "
                            About the beginning of March we visited Mother Ann and the Elders at Watervliet. The love
                            and kindness I there saw in them, both among themselves and toward those who visited them,
                            was truly beyond any thing of the kind I ever saw before. Many people were there from
                            different places, and their house was but small, and in order to accommodate all who came,
                            they gave up their own beds and slept on the floor themselves, with but very little to lie
                            on, or to cover them. This affected my feelings very much. In all their words and actions
                            they displayed pure godliness and innocence. They taught us to confess and forsake sin, to
                            live upright and pure, and to be honest and just in all things. * * * My husband continued
                            strong in the faith until he departed this life, at Hancock, in 1788. " Mother Ann was very
                            modest and chaste in her deportment. I visited her and the Elders often at different
                            places—at Ashfield, Harvard, Hancock and New Lebanon, and always found them very exemplary
                            and godly in all things. * * * "Mother was always faithful to teach <pb n="126" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/>
                            126 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. prudence and economy, as well as other virtues. I have many times
                            seen her, after the people have been eating, go and gather up the fragments, pick the bones,
                            and make her meal of these, and say, ' It is good, it is the blessing of God, and should not
                            be lost." * * Mother often taught us to love one another. She would say to those that were
                            married, ' You ought to love one another in the Lord.' To the man, ' Be kind to your wife ;'
                            and to the woman,' Be subject and obey your husband in the Lord ; it is according to the
                            doctrine of the apostles.' She taught children to obey their parents, and parents to teach
                            their children godliness, and bring them up in the fear of the Lord. I never saw the least
                            failing in Mother. She was temperate in all things." D. A.. Buckingham. Shakers, N. 7.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Contentment" TEIform="index"/>CONTENTMENT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/>CATHARINE ALLEN</byline><p TEIform="p"> Why murmur, though the talent's small That God hath given thee ? Or why repine ? It is the
                            lesser lights, that make the larger stars appear So brilliantly to shine. 'Tis God who made
                            them all, The large ones and the small ; Arid gave to each an orbit and a space to fill, And
                            steadily through rolling years they keep their course, Performing each its'partsin His
                            creative will. 'Tis thus I'll run the race that God hath marked for me, Content and thankful
                            be, To do with patient heart and willing hands, The little things which he requires of me.
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Labor" TEIform="index"/>LABOR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Byrdsall, Charlotte" TEIform="persName"/>CHARLOTTE BYRDSALL</byline><p TEIform="p"> " Labor is rest from the sorrows that greet us, Rest from world syrens that prompt unto
                            ill." Cultivated powers are wealth to the mind and soul. " Be true to thyself." Let nothing
                            stand in the way of the growth of thy spirit. The principle of labor underlies health and
                            happiness in the present life, and lays the foundation of joys beyond the tomb. We possess
                            the life germs of many noble qualities, which without action on our part would remain
                            useless. Hence, active labor is requisite to develop those seed germs , from honest labor we
                            gain capital. It embodies wealth, in material, scientific and spiritual things. Active labor
                            should be stamped upon every thing. There is something higher and nobler to live and toil
                            for than selfish ends and purposes. Consecrated labor is the highest mark that can be placed
                            upon our Zion home. God's laws, when rightly carried into effect, would equalize labor
                            according to strength and ability to perform. Human governments would mould that law into im
                            perfect statutes according to false and un-. just ideas of caste and capital ; and as a
                            result—not a success—we have a demoralized population. The laborer knows he has been forced
                            into want and idleness by corporate wealth and financial power, and that the aim of the
                            money-holders is to subject all products of labor to their control—so much for so much—a
                            lessening process, until wages fail, and labor seems fruitless; then he rebels, and finally
                            prefers to tramp and beg rather than be forced to work for a small pittance from unjust
                            employers. We need a new era of industrial life. In the centuries past the world has been
                            governed by ideas and theories more than by practical works. Aristocracy has claimed the
                            right to rule the laboring classes—to apportion wages—so that those in the lower walks of
                            life should subserve the interests of those in princely ranks, or in affluence, at the
                            expense of their own interests. Thus, individuals have exalted themselves, and degraded
                            labor and the laboring classes. The needed New Era, is to " level the hills and exalt the
                            valleys." In other words, to equalize capital and labor. Let there be a system of right
                            living brought forth, and the Scripture injunction be enforced, " He that will not work
                            neither shall he eat."' Then there will be more right thinking, and right action. Seed sown
                            in the unseen soi of the heart will germinate, blossom and <pb n="127" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKES
                            MANIFESTO. 127 bring forth fruit according to its kind in individuals. States or Nations.
                            How noble is the thought of elevated labor ! The throbbing heart of the toiling millions of
                            earth's children, with trusting hope, and uplifted eyes, are looking for the dawn of a
                            brighter day. They feel the injustice of their position, and abhor the system which gives
                            power to the few to accumulate immense wealth at the expense of the many. Nations are
                            restive under the oppressive labor system. While the moneyed power, with a firm grasp, holds
                            the balance in their hands, justice will cry in vain. In many respects the laboring classes
                            enjoy life and taste its sweets, where those of the higher classes do not. Their rest, when
                            the curtains of night close around them, is balmy and sweet. They have earned it and they
                            enjoy it. Labor and its proper uses should be the theme of life. The universe teems with
                            life and labor. Humanity should be a universal brother and sisterhood, and afford a
                            comfortable home for each and all. As the old Egyptian builders toiled patiently and
                            perseveringly for centuries, over their vast pyramids, so must humanity in the present age
                            toil on, till they see the fruition of their hopes and desires ; when right shall prevail
                            and there shall no longer exist the master nor the slave; when all shall be brethren, and
                            love shall be the cementing bond between Nations and individuals; when justice and equality
                            shall take the place of oppression and false rule, and true principle shall triumph in
                            righteousness.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible revision" TEIform="index"/>BIBLE REVISION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Basting, Louis" TEIform="persName"/>LOUIS BASTING</byline><p TEIform="p"> A commission, composed of learned European and American divines, has been engaged for some
                            time past in the work of revising the Bible, and it is intimated that their labors will be
                            completed during the course of the present year. The results of this critical inquiry is
                            looked forward to with the greatest of interest and hope, as well as with fear and anxiety,
                            and some high dignitaries of Orthodoxy have gone so far as to already protest against the
                            publication and general distribution of the new version. Now it can only be commendable to
                            revise the text of works of standard authority, to eliminate their errors, and to lessen
                            their ambiguity ; but however correctly the principle may be applied in regard to
                            productions of the human mind, can it be possible that it should ever be exercised to
                            rectify the Word of God? That must necessarily remain unalterable forever, or else we must
                            change our conception of the Almighty. But how are we to account for this paradoxical
                            proceeding of re-editing the sacred Word of God ? Orthodox creed-makers find themselves in a
                            dilemma, which permits of no alternative but to decide upon these two propositions ; either
                            the Bible is the Word of God or it is not. The Catholic and Protestant churches, ever since
                            their establishment, have declared in the most positive and unequivocal manner, that the
                            Scriptures are the solemnly revealed will of the Deity, and that upon their acceptance or
                            rejection depended the eternal welfare, or the endless misery of man. But can that really be
                            the direct Word of God, the disbelief of which is said to be fraught with such fearful
                            consequences when professed believers differ so widely in the interpretation of it ? Is it
                            rational to suppose that God would speak in ambiguous and doubtful phrases when every thing
                            depended upon their being correctly understood ? And even admitting for the moment the
                            original inspiration, that would soon lose its value, except it continued to inspire
                            succeeding translators and copyists ; and more than inspiration would be necessary to
                            protect the Scriptures from willful interpolations and designing fabrications, which are
                            well known to have taken place in many instances. Incorrect translation has led to some
                            ludicrous results. The statue of Moses, to quote a case in point, which is one of the
                            sublimest creations of Michael Angelo's genius, is adorned with two horns, which fact has
                            greatly puzzled art critics and other inquirers, till it has lately been discovered that the
                            Vulgate, which was the version he consulted, has it that when Moses came down from the
                            mount, after his inter- <pb n="128" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 128 THE SHAKES MANIFESTO. view with the Lord,
                            he wore two horns ; King James' Bible has the more probable account that " his face shone."
                            But it is a far more serious matter when even orthodox commentators admit such a passage as
                            I John V 7, to be spurious. Being aware of the many gross imperfections adhering to the
                            Scriptures, the • rational mind cannot but regard the claim to accept them as God's
                            infallible word as absurd and derogatory of Divine Wisdom and Majesty. Yet the necessity for
                            their complete rejection does by no means appear, for they do contain, along with much
                            chaff, the choicest jewels of truth, the highest incentives to virtue and morality. But the
                            Truth of God is not confined to the Hebrew Scriptures ; the Golden Rule was preached in
                            China 500 years before the advent of Jesus of Nazareth, and long prior even to that period a
                            system of the most exalted purity was taught and practiced in ancient India. Christ is the
                            Light "which lighteth every man who cometh into the world ; " it needs no Romish priest nor
                            Protestant divine to hold the candle. That system, that subordinated scriptural ethics to
                            human dogmas, is slowly falling. It is falling by its own hand ; for having asserted
                            infallibility, modern science and spirtualism have demonstrated its fallibility. Silently a
                            peaceful revolution goes on ; slowly the foundation walls of superstition are
                            disintegrating. Who will regret it 1 But let us have the new Bible ! Mt. Lebanon, N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cross no. 1" TEIform="index"/>THE CROSS NO. 1</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p"> It is sufficiently evident to every one conversant with the history of Christianity that the
                            cross to which it was the custom in ancient times to attach criminals for the purpose of
                            putting them to death by slow torture, has become emblematic of that religion. Jesus himself
                            suffered death upon it, hence a system of theology has been devised, having the cross with
                            its victim as the central idea, the idea being that Divine Justice required the death of
                            this victim to expiate the sins of every individual of the human family. Volume after volume
                            has been written to illustrate this idea. Such a cross has been made the standard of armies
                            arrayed against each other on the battle field. It has been held, in'miniature, before the
                            eyes of the dying to remind them that by this alone could their spirits hope for happiness
                            in the world they were about to enter. And the living have been assured, with all the
                            earnestness and power of which human eloquence is capable, that their title to life, present
                            or future, is made certain only by this cross as a seal. It cannot be denied that this has
                            been the prevalent idea in Christendom for centuries. It has assumed the rank of the only
                            orthodoxy. This orthodoxy, it is true, has shown features varying to some extent, according
                            as it has exhibited a Catholic or Protestant front, but essentially it is one and the same
                            everywhere. Such being the case, it seems natural for those who adhere to this as the
                            fundamental thought, in the doctrine of the cross, to regard it as established too strongly
                            for successful opposition, and to deny that those who reject it are really Christians. The
                            doctrine of the cross is evidently the pivotal doctrine of Christianity, but what is that
                            essential thing on which hinges a person's Christian character? This is a question of no
                            other teaching than that of Jesus Christ himself. Whether this is rational and worthy of the
                            Infinite Father, the G-od of love whom Jesus preached, must be determined by every one who
                            thoroughly examines the doctrine. It would seem that that which has been so long and so
                            generally accepted as the true view might be regarded as settled. And yet it is not so. It
                            is not in human nature of the present day, whatever it may have been in the past, to be
                            satisfied with many of the practices or modes of thought of former ages. The old ideas of
                            civil government, of class society, of the relations of the sexes, of the connection between
                            capital and labor, must and will be discussed. So with every thing in science or religion
                            that has been or is presented to the human mind for its acceptance as truth. Not that there
                            is not at the present time liability to error as heretofore, yet the tend- <pb n="129" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 129 ency of the general thought is to accept that which
                            savors of kindness, benevolence, and of universal love, rather than the opposite, and to
                            regard this alone as worthy of the rational mind.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Young people among Shakers" TEIform="index"/>YOUNG PEOPLE AMONG SHAKERS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline><p TEIform="p">(From the Brooklyn Eagle.) <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"Would the morals of a girl of sixteen be corrupted by putting her in the care of
                                    Shakers? By answering the above in your column of ' Questions Answered,'' you would
                                    confer a great favor upon one in great trouble. B." " B" should not confound the
                                    Shakers with any other religious or socialistic order, as has frequently been done.
                                    The Shakers, or Believers, are followers of Ann Lee, and are celibates, believing in
                                    the second appearance of the Christ Spirit upon this earth. They are divided into
                                    three orders, the Novitiate order receiving strangers who are inquirers into the
                                    religious elements of the Shaker faith. Elder Frederick W. Evans occupies the
                                    position of first Elder in the Novitiate order of the society in this country, and
                                    his address is Mt. Lebanon, Columbia county, New York. The morals of the best of
                                    people would be improved by association with the Shakers, who practice all the
                                    virtues, and void as sins many habits which the world's people look upon
                                    approvingly. They are intellectual celibates, live simply and have agriculture as
                                    the base of their industry, though most of them unite with it one or more
                                    avocations. In practical life they are peaceful, exquisitely neat, pure hearted and
                                    sincere. The word of a Shaker in a business transaction is, to use a trade parlance,
                                    as good as a bond. The Shakers nearly always decline to take children, though there
                                    are some in all societies, and for these they have good schools, and each child is
                                    taught a trade as it grows up. Unless a young person goes there from a strong
                                    personal desire, it is hardly likely that he or she will stay, for the life is
                                    strictly ascetic, and a romantic sentimentalist or an idler would find little in
                                    common with the good men and women of this order."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Brooklyn eagle" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit> Comments.—We decline taking girls under ten, and boys under twelve years of age.
                            These we want of good parentage, having been well-governed and cared for, and of good moral
                            or religious character, and expect them to be secured to us until of age. Boys educated
                            among us learn to turn their hands to all kinds of business. During our recent visit in
                            Brooklyn I felt as one of old, " The Lord hath much people in this city." Hope when he comes
                            to his own, his own will receive him. It is seldom that we see so much valuable information,
                            or so many ideas condensed into one short article as are contained in the above from the
                            Brooklyn Eagle, by Laura Holloway, one of its editors.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Renouncing the world" TEIform="index"/>RENOUNCING THE WORLD</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">To renounce the world in one way is the most commendable act of a man's life; to
                                    renounce it in another way is a very dangerous thing, if not a positively injurious
                                    one. The old English question asked of a candidate for baptism inquires whether he
                                    is ready to " renounce the devil and all his works, the vain pomp and glory of the
                                    wicked world, with all the covetous desires of the same." Such things as these, the
                                    Christian must renounce before he can be a Christian at all. There can be no
                                    half-way business about it. Compromise with the downright wickedness of the world is
                                    fatal to the godly life. A partial surrender gives up the whole. There is, however,
                                    another and very prevalent idea of the renunciation of the world, wbich is
                                    materially different from the abandonment of the thoughtless or deliberate acts of
                                    the unrighteous children of this life. It is something more than abandonment, it is
                                    separation. Taking a Pilate's wash-bowl, many persons purify their hands, and then
                                    declare that they have nothing further to do with sin. To them, the text " Come out
                                    from among them, and be ye separate," means not only the abandonment of sin, but the
                                    desertion of sinners. In the endeavor to keep themselves pure, they give up efforts
                                    for the reclamation of those who are stained with guilt. They build convent <pb n="130" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 130 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. walls, and immure themselves within
                                    their dim recesses. In order to remove the possibility of relapsing into evil ways,
                                    they seek to banish the possibility of temptation. If they are never tempted they
                                    never fall. Persons of this way of thinking are by no means Fconfined to the Koman
                                    Catholic Church. The monastic tendency exists where monasticism is unknown. The
                                    desire to make an object of one's self, or to do some startling thing, is universal.
                                    " If I could get dead drunk, and lie in the gutter, with my pockets turned inside
                                    out, I think I should be satisfied," says one. " If I could be known, the world
                                    over, as a marvel of purity, I could rest content," says another, The world is full
                                    of people who, like the little "girl in the nursery rhyme, are very, very good when
                                    they are good, but '' horrid " when they are bad. Of course it is more pleasant to
                                    be a model of excellence than a model of vice ; and so, in their zeal to renounce
                                    the world, men swing on hooks, or climb St. Simeon Stylites' pillar, :or vow to read
                                    no book but the Bible, according to their several religious faiths. It is the same
                                    world they all seek to abandon, though their methods vary. It is the secret plaudit
                                    of their own hearts that they value even more than the world's astonishment or
                                    reverence. Each of them deliberately makes up his mind, like the boy in the juvenile
                                    story, to become a " blighted being." After all, it is Christian work that approves
                                    the believer. Positive virtue is a very different thing from negative innocence. The
                                    Christian organization is the church militant, not the church contemplative . One
                                    man's duty is not another's ; but certainly few persons are so isolated, by nature
                                    or by circumstance, as to be exempt from all other duties than that of self-culture.
                                    The Son of Man came to seek and to save that which was lost. His followers can
                                    hardly excuse themselves for abandoning efforts in the same direction. The fear of
                                    falling, the delights of spiritual piety, or the benefits of religious culture, are
                                    not valid reasons for abandoning the world to its fate. The New Testament lays a
                                    great deal of stress upon Christian endeavor, but says very little about the
                                    cultivation of a mystical spirituality unconnected with active effort in such fields
                                    as seem to lie around each individual. It is the laborer who is worthv of his hire.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="S. S. times" TEIform="index"/>S. S. Times.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Farewell, vain world" TEIform="index"/>FAREWELL, VAIN WORLD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Garphie, George H." TEIform="persName"/>GEORGE H, GARPHIE</byline><p TEIform="p"> Farewell, vain world of strife, With thy delusive snares ; For endless joys of life I leave
                            thy pains and cares. Farewell, vain world once more,O, world of many sins ; My hopes now
                            higher soar, My faith in Christ begins. Once, though a haven bright, With all thy pleasures
                            wild ; I was captive in thy might, Thou leadst me as a child. Brighter now the dawn appearsI
                            see a light afar; Inspiration bids me cheer To the Golden Gates ajar. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cure for slander" TEIform="index"/>A CURE FOR SLANDER</head><p TEIform="p">The following very homely but singularly instructive lesson is by Philip Neri: A lady
                            presented herself one day to him, accusing herself of being given to slander. " Do you
                            frequently fall into this fault?" inquired Neri. " Yes, father, very often," replied the
                            penitent. " My dear child," said Neri, "your fault is great, but the mercy of God is still
                            greater; for your penance do as follows: Go to the nearest market, purchase a chicken just
                            killed and still covered with feathers ; you will then walk to a certain distance, plucking
                            the bird as you go along; your walk finished, you will return to me." Great was the
                            astonishment of the lady in receiving so strange a penance ; but silencing all human
                            reasoning, she replied : "I will obe}7, father; I will obey." Accordingly she repaired to
                            the market, bought the fowl, and set out on her journey,*pluckijug it as she went along, as
                            she had been ordered. In a short time she returned, anxious to tell of her exactness in
                            accomplishing her penance, and desirous to receive some explanation of one so singular. <pb n="131" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 131 " Ah ! " said Neri, " you have been very
                            faithful to the first part of my orders ; now to the second part and you will be cured.
                            Retrace your steps; pass through all the places you have already traversed, and gather up,
                            one by one, all the feathers you have scattered." " But, father," exclaimed the poor woman,
                            "that is impossible. I cast the feathers carelessly on every side ; the wind carried them in
                            different directions ; how can I now recover them ? " " Well, my child," replied Neri, " so
                            it is with your words of slander — like the feathers which the wind has scattered, they have
                            been wafted in many directions — call them back now if you can. Go and sin no more." History
                            does not tell if the lady was converted; but we have the lesson, and all should profit by
                            it.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Only" TEIform="index"/>ONLY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p"> Only an acorn that fell by the wayside— Only a tiny seed hidden from sight— Only a crystal
                            drop lost in the flowing tide, Only a star, gleaming out in the night. Lo ! the great oak a
                            broad shelter is weaving; Many fair blossoms shed sweetest perfume ; Bosom of ocean are
                            mingled drops heaving; Myriad planets the dark sky illume. Thus be our life into purpose
                            expanding— Small in beginning, yet good in intent— Noble and useful, and truthful in
                            standing, Spreading in blessing as days are well spent. Scattering here the rich, and the
                            precious seeds ; Wild wastes shall blossom, and deserts shall smile; Meeting the lonely and
                            desolate spirit needs, Reaping a harvest of pleasure the while. Better to swell the bright
                            billows of gladness, Though we have only a little to give ; Rather than drain the last dregs
                            of life's Only for love let us labor and live. If but a lesser orb in the vast galaxy, Still
                            shall our glory be made -to appear, Ever with steady light, so may our shining be, God marks
                            the orbit of each circling sphere. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Specimen letter" TEIform="index"/>A SPECIMEN LETTER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., T. C." TEIform="persName"/>"T. C. W.</byline><p TEIform="p">The interest in Shakerism is continually increasing and spreading. The following letter
                                is a specimen of what we are continually receiving. We append the answer :</p><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sir—Having become deeply interested in the Shakers" TEIform="index"/>Sir—Having become deeply interested in the Shakers
                                </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Quebec, March 26, 1879" TEIform="index"/>Quebec, 26th, March, 1879.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Frederick W. Evans, Mt., Lebanon : " Sir—Having become deeply interested in the
                                    Shakers, both regarding their life and doctrine, and desiring to know more, I would
                                    like to obtain a simple plain statement of such, and knowing no other method, write
                                    you for it. " Yours sincerely," </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Quebec, Treasury Department" TEIform="persName"/>Address Treasury Dep't,
                                Quebec</byline></div4></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="T. C. W.—Respected Friend : You say you 'have become deeply interested in Shakers.'..." TEIform="index"/>T. C. W.—Respected Friend : You say you 'have become deeply interested in Shakers.'...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, April 2, 1879" TEIform="index"/>Mount Lebanon, April 2, 1879</dateline><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans.</byline><p TEIform="p">T. C. W.—Respected Friend : You say you " have become deeply interested in Shakers." That
                                makes me deeply interested in you. I would be pleased to learn how and why you are
                                interested. Are you a ^Spiritualist ? A person may be a Spiritualist and not be a
                                Shaker. But he or she could not be a Shaker and not be a Spiritualist. Perhaps you are a
                                Socialist, and a friend of communism and co-operation — would readj ust capital and
                                labor. Or you may be a Woman's Rights' man, thinking that woman has a right to be, and
                                to be a law maker. Again, it may be that living in a public building, you are aware
                                that, in Europe, 1,200,000 of male Christians, servants of the Prince of Peace, are
                                organized into destructive machines for depopulating the earth. Physiology has,
                                perchance, occupied your observing and investigating powers, and you desire to search
                                out and remove the causes of human misery, in the form of sickness and disease.
                                Epidemics, fevers, plagues, dyspepsia, and even common colds. Or how can I tell but the
                                subject of usury may cause you sleepless nights, and that you think it one of the grand
                                procuring causes of human wars ? for how could nations fight without money 1 And who
                                would loan money to governments without interest ? Or how would rulers obtain soldiers,
                                    <pb n="132" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. were there no poor, homeless, landless
                                people ? and would any of these exist without usury? If, with Thomas Jefferson, you
                                think the land belongs to man only in usufruct, then the monopoly of land is an evil,
                                co-existing with usury, and you desire to have it removed. Doctor-craft, Priestcraft,
                                Lawyercraft and Warcraft, indicate a separation between man and the land upon which he
                                ought to cultivate his vine and fig tree. Blessed are the meek—men who are not sick and
                                do not fight—they shall inherit the earth. And blessed are those who hunger after
                                wisdom, which is a right use of knowledge. Those having said their say, know when to
                                "stop, as will your unfashionable Shaker friend, </p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers dying out" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERS DYING OUT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, Oliver" TEIform="persName"/>Oliver Prentiss.</byline><p TEIform="p">Editor Shaker Manifesto : In 1779, a powerful magnetic current, from the spirit world,
                                swept over the New England States and the eastern part of the State of New York, waking
                                up the religious element in the honest yeomanry, preparing them to receive the Gospel of
                                the Kingdom. Mother Ann Lee had, through heart-searching, vein-trying ordeals, been
                                previously prepared, and sent from England, to administer the initiatives of that
                                Gospel—the Gospel of the Kingdom of Heaven. Then was the Kingdom of Heaven "like unto a
                                net cast into the sea "— Virginity and Community were the initiatives. The work of
                                gathering the believers into Community Order was assigned to Joseph Meacham and Lucy
                                Wright, then called Father Joseph and Mother Lucy — Like Moses, Father Joseph received,
                                and gave to the people, a code, for the preservation of order in the House of God. He
                                said he knew those statutes and ordinances were " the gift of God." The people were
                                gathered—the doors were closed. Some nine years later, another wave from the Spirit
                                World so awakened outsiders, that the doors were opened and many gathered " as doves to
                                the windows." And still the Kingdom of Heaven was " like unto a net cast into the sea."
                                In process of years, the better material outside became so absorbed in commerce,
                                politics and speculation, that the Kingdom of Heaven became "like unto a certain king
                                that made a marriage for his son." For near half a century, the few that have been
                                gathered in were, with rare exceptions and the children of those exceptions, from the
                                distinct classes referred to in Luke xiv. 21, 22, 23. Let this, with consequent neglect
                                of, and departures from, the Code Joseph, account for the apparent "depletion" of
                                Shakers. As offset to what is truly lamentable, Shakers have been cutting loose from
                                ancient snubbing posts, and catching up with the increase of the age. Mental expansion
                                has been a cardinal principle—many habits in meats, drinks and other objectionables, not
                                cognizable by the initiatives aforesaid, have been left behind. With the increase of
                                facilities for communication and transit, the world correspondingly moves—and Shakers
                                move. And now, the signs of the times fully sustain' the Spiritual Telegraph
                                communications, that a strong wave, a magnetic current from a powerful host in the
                                Spirit World, is moving the better class of minds,, outside of Shakerdom, preparatory to
                                the progression of the New Earth and the New Heaven, so long existing in prophecy only.
                                Mighty men and ^women of power, unknown to fame, will be called to the front,, and the
                                car of human progress will be shoved ahead, irrespective of grade, by unseen
                                locomotives. The Tabernacle of human progress will be rejuvenated upon the basis of the
                                Pioneers,. Father Joseph and Mother Lucy, taking in the additional foundation stones of
                                progressive truth—physiology, hygiene, spiritualism, etc., etc. We will say, and speak
                                advisedly, that of all achieved by the practical self-denial and faithful cross-bearing
                                of Mother Ann, Mother Lucy, Father Joseph, their compeers and devoted successors, never
                                a particle will be lost to humanity. They were simply devoted Pioneers. They acted well
                                their part. In the name of God and humanity, we will act ourd.—Amen.</p></div3><pb n="133" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Acceptable donation" TEIform="index"/>ACCEPTABLE DONATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M., H." TEIform="persName"/> h. m.</byline><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Ohio, Cincinnati, May 9, 1879. " TEIform="index"/>Cincinnati, O., May 9,1879</dateline><p TEIform="p">Elder diaries Olapp : Dear Friend: Inclosed please find a money order, payable at
                                Lebanon, for $10, which I hope you will accept as a contribution to your valuable paper,
                                the " Manifesto." I have time to write only a few hurried lines, to-day, and must
                                content myself by express ing my wish that your good people will meet with all the
                                success they could desire ; you are doing a noble work, and setting the world a shining
                                example ; you have my best wishes for your prosperity in every sense of the word. Truly
                                your friend,</p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The above order for the amount was duly forwarded to this office" TEIform="index"/>The above order for the amount was duly forwarded to this office
                            </head><p TEIform="p">[The above order for the amount was duly forwarded to this office, together with the
                                letter of our kind friend. We have taken the liberty to print the letter and would like
                                to have given the donor's name. Our thanks, fragrant with soul-gratitude, accompany him
                                everywhere. One hundred and twenty such friends would print and circulate 3,500 copies
                                of the Shaker Manifesto twelve times a year ! Who bids for a niche in the building it is
                                erecting ? Ed. S. M.]</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName TEIform="persName">M., S.</persName>Ed. S. M.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind and Esteemed Friend, Elder F. W. Evans: Very naturally, on my return to Brooklyn..." TEIform="index"/>Kind and Esteemed Friend, Elder F. W. Evans: Very naturally, on my return to Brooklyn...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Brooklyn, May 29, 1879" TEIform="index"/>Brooklyn, May 29, 1879</dateline><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M., H. E." TEIform="persName"/>H. E. M.</byline><p TEIform="p">Kind and Esteemed Friend, Elder F. W. Evans: Very naturally, on my return to Brooklyn, my
                                thoughts took leave of me and returned to Mt. Lebanon, or else I left them there and did
                                not miss them until it was necessary to collect myself together for practical work ; and
                                the first was to speedily fulfill the promise to return the paper which I failed to make
                                legal according to the laws of our unruly world. With how much satisfaction I returned,
                                I can hardly explain to you. The visit had but one fault—it was all too short. I found
                                on my first visit, that the dear friends then commenced, unconsciously, to weave about
                                me a sort of net-work of love and kindness, from which I could, perhaps, have extricated
                                myself if I had tried, but I had no inclination that way. This time I found the net more
                                tightly drawn, and I came away surrounded with the sweet, quiet influence from a home
                                where peace and happiness reign supremely, and a love that passeth all earthly
                                understanding. I talk of Mt. Lebanon, I think about it, and all the time with a feeling
                                of wonder that such a place can exist on earth, and with gratitude inexpressible that I
                                am privileged to have a child of mine under its Heavenly influence. Oh, yes, Elder
                                Frederick, I know I am worldly, but I am not wanting in appreciation, and I give you all
                                my hand with a hearty God Speed. As soon as I get back to the world, I am more fully
                                convinced how lacking I am in the many essentials that go to make a Shaker. However,
                                there is notelling what, might be done under some circumstances. A constant dropping of
                                water will wear away a rock, and the influence at Mt. Lebanon is a continual well-spring
                                of goodness and purity, and I have brought away a great deal, I trust I shall never part
                                with. There is much I would like to write you about, and many questions I would ask for
                                information, but I know I have already trespassed too long on your valuable time ; and I
                                should fail to make myself as interesting even, as that man in Walla Walla, Washington
                                territory, with his Indians out west, for I would be the only one benefited. If I send
                                all the messages that come from my heart to my pen, when I think of my boy, you would
                                only say, " Oh, you mothers, will you never learn sense ? " So I swallow down a great
                                longing, love and tenderness for him, with only a request that you inform him of my safe
                                arrival home, and that I am well. I return earnest thanks to you all, for your generous
                                hospitality. Within my own home, I never found more loving kindness. With the best
                                wishes for you all, I am always your sincere friend.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder F. W. Evans : Dear Brother—Recently I saw a few extracts clipped from the New York Sun..." TEIform="index"/>Elder F. W. Evans : Dear Brother—Recently I saw a few extracts clipped from the New York Sun...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Kansas, Miami County, Amo P.O., May 2, 1879. " TEIform="index"/>Amo P. 0., Miami Co.,
                                Kansas, May 2, 1879. </dateline><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., H. M." TEIform="persName"/> H. M. C.</byline><p TEIform="p">Elder F. W. Evans : Dear Brother—Recently I saw a few extracts clipped from the New York
                                Sun, sent by you to a friend of mine. It is indeed truly wonderful, this fact of
                                spiritual ma- <pb n="134" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 134 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. terialization ; and
                                taking place among your holy people I must indeed give it credence. How triumphant the
                                thought that the immortality of the human soul is scientifically demonstrated ! The
                                great scientists of different nationalities are investigating this phenomenon, and some
                                of them profess to have proven beyond a doubt the intercommunion between the two worlds,
                                the spiritual and material. The skeptical mind demands evidence that appeals to the
                                senses, and it is now given. Mediums are being developed everywhere, and this phase of
                                form manifestations is the most startling a,nd convincing. To one with a mind organized
                                like my own, evidence of this kind is a great boon. My mental combination is one of
                                intense skepticism as well as deep spirituality. From the earliest age I was given to
                                metaphysical reasoning, and was constantly reaching after the unfathomable. I frequently
                                got beyond my depth. Painful doubts of humanity preserving its identity were constantly
                                obtruding upon my mind, and I sought for evidence among the writings of the learned and
                                erudite, as well as made personal appeals to the reason of those who were older and more
                                experienced than myself. I read many works on theology, and especially sought for that
                                form of literature which was occult and mysterious. Every work on magnetism and
                                clairvoyance I" came across, I read with avidity. Plow I worshipped the grand and
                                beautiful in nature ! The world was one mighty poem to my inner senses, and I loved to
                                look abroad and dwell with my own communings. At times a simple flower would fill my
                                soul with ecstacy, but when I gazed upon the sublime and grand, I felt like prostrating
                                myself before an Infinite Being in the attitude and spirit of worship. Why such
                                unutterable longings of the human soul, and this tendency to worship a Supreme Power, if
                                there is no corresponding answer to its yearnings ? I would reason thus. There is
                                certainly a spiritual state of being, or we would have no comprehension of the
                                spiritual. It is innate and not taught wholly. All tribes and nations believe in it, and
                                worship some power, showing that it is intuitive. Can it be wondered at that I take a
                                deep interest in these spiritual phenomena ? I keep posted by reading spiritualistic
                                journals. I am constantly looking for irrefragable evidence. There is much that is
                                deceptive and unreliable. We have to use the fine sieve of reason. Now when I heard
                                recently that this phenomenon was known and practiced among the "Shakers, my soul leaped
                                for joy. I have long taken an abiding interest in the order of Shakers, and were I
                                untrammeled I should certainly unite with them. I am a Shaker in principle, I can truly
                                say. How I have longed for a holy retreat, away from the follies and fashions of the
                                world or world's people. There is too much that is jarring and inconsistent with a holy
                                life. Too much excitement and greed of the world's goods do I daily see. War, war, all
                                the time somewhere upon the face of the globe. Strife of all kinds, not only nationally
                                but individually. In every family, domestic grief more or less. No unity, but great
                                divergence. You are a blessed people. Would you, dear brothers, grant me as a boon, a
                                spiritual message from one of your materialized spirits? I would like a test; but then
                                it is the spiritual message I crave. This shall be sacred with me, and not given
                                publicity. This is an earnest appeal. I shall ever be grateful, should you grant it.
                                Pardon me for writing so much at length. Have you any work descriptive of American
                                communities in general? Yours fraternally, P. S. Pardon if I have requested too much and
                                attribute it to a sincere desire for the Truth and Spirituality.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritual wealth and pauperism" TEIform="index"/>SPIRITUAL WEALTH AND PAUPERISM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. MYRICK</byline><p TEIform="p">As in material, so in the spiritual ; what we sow, we shall reap. The quantity and quality
                            depend on industry and cultivation. Our first and chief seeking should be " the kingdom of
                            heaven." But is there not danger that the things which should be added (the external) engage
                            our first attention ? thus causing spiritual pauperism 1 <pb n="135" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 135 We need the gifts of heaven, the food of angels — something to administer to
                            souls, both in and out of the body. Mother Ann said, " though we are poor, yet we are able
                            to make many rich "—rich in all that creates heaven, and makes that heaven a part of earth's
                            experience. Should we always be mendicants, begging the hard-earned treasures of those who
                            store all night to regain the spiritual gift they felt they had lost by sleep ; and who,
                            when worn down by excessive labor of soul and body, prayed for divine aid, instead of
                            yielding to exhausted nature t Who would not rather, realize the greater blessing of giving,
                            than to beg from door to door, " give us of your oil " (light) and spiritual riches ? Is it
                            becoming those who claim to be the children of light, to seek light from those just emerging
                            from nature's darkness, and the superstition of tradition? instead of being " ministering
                            spirits" from that city whose light cannot be hid ? Will we have a sentimental, or a soul
                            re. ligion ? The dead sea of formality, or the fount of inspiration ? We can quench the
                            spirit or feed it if we will. Something more than salvation is required to satisfy the
                            aspiration of the living soul ; (Lot's wife was saved — preserved !) it wants growth,
                            progress, the result of hungering, thirsting, and partaking of inspirations from the
                            spiritual heavens. Social purity, moral integrity, benevolence, and peace, all beautiful in
                            themselves, may be possessed, and yet lack that essential,spiritual gift and life which
                            quickens, inspires, and elevates the soul to live above the world, and follow him who
                            promised " treasures in heaven." The Jews had Abraham for their father, Moses for their
                            lawgiver, and prophets not a few. The Christians claim Jesus for their saviour, and
                            propitiator. The believers in the second advent of Christ have their pattern saints to fall
                            back upon, to praise and adore. Reverence, honor, and a due regard for precept and examples
                            of the heroic pioneers in the world's advancement are tributes no grateful heart can, or
                            should, withhold. But there is great need to guard against the insidious error of idolatry
                            of the person, and their final authority. What is needed and should be most desired is the
                            spirit which animated their lives, and inspired their words. Active, positive, not passive,
                            good (for nothing), dependent saints, supported by a rich ancestry. The great want is men
                            and women of God, the God of to-day, living and guided by the word of God as revealed to-day
                            ; asking not if it agrees with former authorities, but content if it agrees with the living
                            present, imperfect though it may be. Now, as in other days, who that is faithful to reason,
                            conscience, heart, and soul, will through them receive inspiration (direct or through
                            mediums) as his guide through all his pilgrimage, possessing and diffusing the true riches.
                            While the faithless, the slothful, and the despondent will have no covering to disguise
                            their needless poverty. The disparity is between Industry and Indolence. The world rests
                            not, with a careless ease On the wisdom of the past From Moses, and Plato, and Socrates, It
                            is onward, advancing fast. And the words of Jesus, and John, and Paul, Stand out from the
                            lettered page, And the living present claims them all, In the spirit that moves the age.
                            Great, earnest souls, by the truth made free, No longer in blindness bow ; And the good time
                            coming—the yet to be— Is embraced in the good time now. He who lives by his own industry has
                            wealth. He who lives on other men's labors is a pauper, a beggar, whether in rags or
                            ruffles.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Parable: has it an application?" TEIform="index"/>A PARABLE: HAS IT AN APPLICATION ?</head><p TEIform="p">Among the trees that clothe the earth, there grew one more beautiful, yielding more perfect
                            fruit than any before. Said this tree : " I have the most perfect symmetry, the most
                            beautiful foliage, and bear the best fruit of any extant. Am I not perfect ? Thus will I
                            remain — preserved just as I am ; my fruit shall not fall, neither <pb n="136" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/>
                            136 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. shall any leaf change, I challenge the law of evolution, that
                            cannot augment nor improve perfection." So ignoring the laws of life, circulation ceases ;
                            the leaves and fruit being the record only of life and growth. The same elements which added
                            growth to life, in the absence of life (which comes of evolution), effect dissolution. Who
                            that would work with God must work through His laws, the laws of evolution, progress; not
                            stationary, but active, living, moving, gathering and diffusing. " He liveth longeth who can
                            tell most true things truly done each day."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Response to philanthropist" TEIform="index"/>RESPONSE TO PHILANTHROPIST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Parry, Charles" TEIform="persName"/>CHARLES PARRY</byline><p TEIform="p">n May No. Shaker Manifesto. The angel voice in corraled lines, High-toned, by heaven sent,
                            Unfolds the wealth of spirit mines. Explored by souls, on glory bent. Was it not ever willed
                            to be, That sense of balmy, fragrant breath, Should lead us on to taste, and see The life
                            that triumphs over death ? 'Tis yours to know, the Spirit lives Above the reach of earthly
                            woe— Yours, " the mission " that He gives To cheer the way the prophets go. Our human needs,
                            e'er want expressed Through human hearts are bid to flow, On them that love to be caressed,
                            'Neath folds of drapery, white as snow. Then let me pray, that wings divine May speed thee
                            on thy peaceful strain, Mid harvest-fields, erect a shrine, To bless the scattered sheaves
                            of grain. Oh ! spirit pure in human form, From living fountains leading, With thee I'd stand
                            above the storm, To reach the heart that's bleeding. The dreary path of ages old, Below,
                            beneath oppression, Calls loud for feet all shod with gold, For Truth, not mere profession.
                            Bemis Heights, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The manifestations of spirit power is..." TEIform="index"/>The manifestations of spirit power is...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wellington" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Wellington</byline><p TEIform="p">says: "The manifestations of spirit power is, to my knowledge, such that every thing in the
                            entire body of the Shakers may change in a single hour, and quicken them into an activity
                            and force which they cannot resist, and would have no wish to."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Assist each other" TEIform="index"/>ASSIST EACH OTHER</head><p TEIform="p">Lend a hand to one another In the daily toils of life : When we meet a weaker brother, Let us
                            help him in the strife. There is none so rich but may In his turn be forced to borrow, And
                            the poor man's lot to-day May become our own to-morrow. Lend a hand to one another When
                            malicious tongues have thrown Dark suspicion on your brother, Be not prompt to cast a stone.
                            There is none so good but may Bun adrift in shame and sorrow, And the best of men to-day,
                            May become the worst to-morrow. Lend a hand to one another In the race for honor's crown ;
                            Should it fall upon your brother, Let not envy tear it down. Lend a hand to all, I say, In
                            their sunshine and their sorrow, And the prize we've lost to-day May become our own
                            to-morrow.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cure for intemperance" TEIform="index"/>A CURE FOR INTEMPERANCE</head><p TEIform="p">Many inebriates are lost who might be saved by loving hearts. Grosvenor, the Shaker
                            philanthropist, under the banner, " Love conquers all things," moves upon the enemy's works.
                            It seems that forty years ago he began to plead with profane swearers, and when he had
                            secured their attention, begged them in turn to plead with others, which always proves the
                            surest means of self-cure. Finding this personal appeal successful, he resolved to try it
                            upon the victim of strong drink. His plan is this. Meeting a man under the influence of
                            drink he greets him with brotherly kindness, and waits a reply. Whatever the man may speak
                            about, Mr. Grosvenor joins in his thought, and talks on with sincere and affectionate
                            earnestness. Having thus secured the man's interest and confidence, he then speaks to him
                            most solemnly of the sin of intemperance, and induces him, if possible, to promise
                            abstinence. He helps the poor fellow home, and visiting him frequently for a few days, helps
                            him to rouse his will, and then sets him at work helping others. <pb n="137" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. 13.7 His remarkable success in the cure of drunkards confirms liis opinion
                            that in this spirit of fraternal love, and by this method many drunkards may besaved.
                            Reformers should make a note of it. Wendell Phillips thinks that if those who are interested
                            on behalf of drunkards would give Mr. Grosvenor's method " the fair play of an experiment,"
                            it would be a fortunate thing for unfortunate men. Several of the leaders among the Shakers,
                            for example, Elders Evans, Avery and Blinn, warmly indorse Mr. Grosvenor's aims and methods.
                            — Boston Paper.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reflections" TEIform="index"/>REFLECTIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, J. G." TEIform="persName"/>J. G. RUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p"> Time, thou art fleeting, seasons come and go, While change is stamped on all things here
                            below ; The buoyant hours of childhood soon are And earth receives her rightful claim at
                            last. But what of time allotted to us here, For usefulness within this mundane sphere? Year
                            follows year in quick succession round, Springtime and harvest with their own abound ; But
                            mortal, thou, who hast a living soul, And over which usurps supreme control,— Does history's
                            pages give a record true, Of well-spent hours? and canst thou here review The fading past,
                            and find no misspent hours That might have wove for thee a wreath of flowers. Hadst thou
                            been diligent to well improve Each moment, passing in its checkless groove ? Methinks I hear
                            the sad, responsive wail, Of fleeting time, I read my verdict—fail! Some golden moment
                            numbered in the past, Before my vision like a meteor cast, Reminds me of neglected act or
                            care, Which haunts my waking moments everywhere. Some sunny spot in life made darkly dim,
                            Some cup of sorrow swelling to its brim, Some debt of gratitude yet left unpaid, Thorugh
                            negligence or want of kindly aid. O may this sad reflection be to me A lesson learned and
                            fixed indelibly Upon the mind, henceforth my heart to move, Each golden moment wisely to
                            improve. Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakerism vs. atonement" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERISM VS. ATONEMENT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Shakerism, to its credit, takes a very bold, yet consistent position, in that it places
                                no reliance on the blood of Jesus, nor any other, for the benefit of its adherents. That
                                which is commonly kuown as the doctrine of Atonement, is nowhere found in the vocabulary
                                of Shaker theology; thus is Shakerism very distinct from almost every other sect
                                professing the Christian name. Shakerism demands confession of sins committed and an
                                accompanying repentance which is best illustrated by a renunciation of the sinful ivays
                                confessed, acknowledged to be wrong, or conduct wanting in Christian progression. To the
                                Shakers, the well-known theory of the Atonement is not only unscriptural according to
                                Jesus, whose coming was " to give to every one according as their lives shall be," but
                                the teaching is contrary to that common-sense religion of logic represented by cause and
                                effect. Very many otherwise noble and religious people, anxiously hope to be relieved
                                here, and 'particularly hereafter, from reaping the consequences of unwise sowing. To
                                whose ears this promise has reached, it has reached them only to be broken to their
                                hope. "The faith that was in Jesus," makes every one of similar faith responsible for
                                his or her deeds, and to go and sin no more, is an imperative demand of Christian
                                discipleship, remember this. There is no royal road, even among the Shakers, whereby we
                                may escape the just reward of our doings. There is no position so exalted in the Church
                                of Christ, as tends to excuse any one <pb n="138" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 138 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                                from reaping just what he or she sows —all hopes to the contrary are useless; all wishes
                                or prayers in anticipation of escape worse than useless. G-od is no respecter of
                                persons, yet he is a regarder of characters, and takes cognizance of good and bad
                                thoughts and intentions. So soundly, solidly and immovably, is genuine Christianity
                                resting upon godly reason and common-sense religion, that it lays judgment to the line
                                of our conduct, and righteousness to the plummet of its believers' lives—that it "
                                sweeps away all refuge of lies " wrought by the false theology of the so-called
                                Atonement. The doctrine of cause mid effect—of reaping the results of sowing—of being
                                rewarded according as our works shall declare our due, is the " Thus saith the Lord :
                                Behold, I lay ye ZlON FOR A FOUNDATION, A STONE, A TRIED STONE, A SURE FOUNDATION, and
                                he that believeth " needs not be alarmed ! Let every rational religionist look the truth
                                squarely in the face, sow as they would reap, live as they would be willing to die, in
                                anticipation of life's rewards, and accepting Jesus as our exampler, our Saviour,
                                inasmuch as we follow his life, and being saved as he was, look upon the evasions taught
                                by the doctrine of the atonement as a snare, as "a covenant with death, and an agreement
                                with hell," unequaled for mischief by any thing in the annals of religious belief. The
                                life of each individual shall have its accompanying reward. ^r A lecturer, who has
                                recently visited the Societies, remarked " that there was a vital force in the Shaker
                                Society that was full of promise for the future."</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love of God" TEIform="index"/>LOVE OF GOD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">NOTES. There is too commonly made a remark by some who would seem to be religious, that
                                they " love God." It is Avell for us to remind every one, that the seal of Christian
                                discipleship depends on the love which one disciple bears another—"by this shall it be
                                known, etc." There is in scripture the following passage, which, from many appearances,
                                will be new to a great many conceited individuals: "If any say, I love God, and hates
                                his brother, he is a liar!" And this commandment have we from him: "He who loveth God,
                                loves his brother also." Who hath ears to hear this, govern your actions- accordingly,
                                and so love God. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Majority" TEIform="index"/>THE MAJORITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Our friend and companion, Philip Smith, of Shakers, N. Y., sometimes preaches short, but
                                pithy sermons, amid his financial duties as a trustee. Recently, he happened where
                                certain fashionable gew-gaws of a wedding or else were being prepared, and was accosted
                                by the man-milliner or other, with, " You Shakers don't believe in such things, but I am
                                glad the majority have decided against you ! " "That's so," said Philip, " I believe the
                                Good Book does mention the way decided upon by the majority, and also what became of
                                them eventually ! "'</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plain talks" TEIform="index"/>PLAIN TALKS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We again present to the public still another edition of these practical hints upon
                                religious Communism. It has been pronounced by the leading <pb n="139" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                SHAKER MANIFESTO. 139 Bishops in Society, uneqnaled in perspicuity, for i giving in a
                                plain, unvarnished manner, the aim, object and principles of the Shakers. We would call
                                upon Shaker Societies to use it as a Tract, during the coming season of open churches
                                and large congregations. It will preach wherever presented, and in places where you
                                could not preach. There are many who hunger for the knowledge it contains; send it to
                                such, as it is furnished at cost. Single copies, six cents. Per hundred, $5.00. Address
                                The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N. Y.</p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We present in this number of the Manifesto some valuable..." TEIform="index"/>We present in this number of the Manifesto some valuable...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We present in this number of the Manifesto some valuable material for thought. The
                                contributed articles are from noble pens, guided by those living noble lives. The "
                                Correspondence " department will give an insight into what some have been pleased to
                                term " monastic lives" among the Shakers. It also reveals some peculiarly religious
                                features now stirring up pretty extensively in the world. Don't fail to read 0.
                                Prentiss' letter; nor the one from our valued Cincinnati friend. The music will do good
                                to the heart of every one thirsting to do and live better—all can learn and sing it. The
                                " Kind toords to us" though small, mean a great deal and are so appreciated. Wishing
                                love and good will to all, we send the Manifesto to the four winds to light often times,
                                we hope, on some hearts whom it can cheer to live better and for Grod, instead of for
                                the pleasures of the flesh in selfishness.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Do us the favor" TEIform="index"/>DO US THE FAVOR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Friends, to circulate the copy of the Manifesto falling into your handsSend for specimen
                                copies to be sent to friends. Five cents might do five dollars' worth of good, by thus
                                sending to some needy one—needing the influences of spirituality imparted by the
                                Manifesto—a copy of our little paper. We work only for the good of the people ; that
                                they may be better. We wish we could give all for the people's good, without any return
                                payment, but we cannot. We give our time, strength, and the best ability we have,
                                without asking payment, other than that of a good conscience doing our duty. Therefore,
                                good friends, help us to sustain the physical fabric of the Manifesto, even by the
                                pittances of single subscriptions; and "you shall in no wise lose your reward."</p></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>KIND WORDS TO US</head><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Manifesto is a power in the world..." TEIform="index"/>The Manifesto is a power in the world...
                                </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Washington" TEIform="index"/>Wash.</dateline><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Correspondent" TEIform="persName"/>Cor.</byline><p TEIform="p">"The Manifesto is a power in the world, more than you realize it to be." </p></div4><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The March no. of the Manifesto..." TEIform="index"/>The March no. of the Manifesto...
                                </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline><p TEIform="p">"The March No. of the Manifesto was very good, but the May No. very much better."</p></div4><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The May no. looks nice, reads well; but..." TEIform="index"/>The May no. looks nice, reads well; but...
                                </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. Myrick</byline><p TEIform="p">The May No. looks nice, reads well; but should every word not be squared to my
                                    notion, I will not complain. When its every word suits everybody, it will be time to
                                    stop its publication. Go ahead.</p></div4><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakerism, as read through the Manifesto..." TEIform="index"/>Shakerism, as read through the Manifesto...
                                </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Colt, Judge" TEIform="persName"/>Judge Colt</byline><p TEIform="p">" Shakerism, as read through the Manifesto, is having a grand and powerful effect in
                                    the world ; and should, in nowise, be slighted by any one."Pittsfield, Mass.</p></div4><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ed. Manifesto. Sisters Eliza Sharp, Betsey Crosman" TEIform="index"/>Ed. Manifesto. Sisters Eliza Sharp, Betsey Crosman
                                </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. Avery</byline><p TEIform="p">"Ed. Manifesto.—Sisters Eliza Sharp, Betsey Crosman, Sarah Bates, Olive Brown,
                                    Angelic Vedder, and Rachel Sampson, of this place, send love, and blessings on you
                                    for faithful labors on the Manifesto."</p><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</dateline></div4></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We will send copies of this number of the Manifesto to..." TEIform="index"/>We will send copies of this number of the Manifesto to...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We will send copies of this number of the Manifesto to any parties who send us one
                                two-cent stamp for each copy desired.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M., B." TEIform="persName"/>Ed. B. M. </byline></div3></div2><pb n="140" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Short sermon" TEIform="index"/>A SHORT SERMON</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cary, Alice" TEIform="persName"/>Alice Cary</byline><p TEIform="p">One and all who hear my lay, This much I have to say : Each day, and every day, Do what
                                is right— Right things in great and small ; Then, though the sky should fall, Sun, moon,
                                and stars, and all, You shall have light. This further would I say : Be tempted as you
                                may, Each day, and every day, Speak what is true— True things in great and small, Then,
                                though the sky should fall, Sun, moon, and stars, and all, Heaven would show through.
                                Figs, as you see and know, Do not of thistles grow ; And though the blossoms blow While
                                on the tree. Grapes never, never yet On limbs of thorns were set; So, if you good would
                                get, Good you must be. Life's journey through and through Speak what is just and true,
                                Do what is right to do, To one and all. At work, and when you play, Each day and every
                                day, Then peace shall gild your way, Though the sky fall.'</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Please, sir, don't step there" TEIform="index"/>Please, Sir, Don't Step There</head><p TEIform="p">A layer of snow was spread over the icy streets, and pedestrians, shod with India rubber,
                                walked carefully toward the village •church on a cold Sabbath morning in February.
                                Walking somewhat hastily churchward for I was late, I noticed a bright looking little
                                lad standing upon the pavement, with his cap in his hand and his eyes fixed upon one
                                spot on the sidewalk. As I approached him he looked up to me, and, pointing to the
                                place, said: " Please, sir, don't step there. I slipped there and fell down." I thanked
                                the philanthropic little fellow, and passed round the dangerous spot. " Don't step there
                                " was the theme of my meditations during the remainder of the walk. A thousand times
                                since has the clear voice of that kind-hearted child rung in my ear, reminding me of my
                                duty to those around me, and urging me to repeat it whenever it promises to be useful. "
                                Please, sir, don't step there."</p></div3><div3 type="science" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Singular experiment" TEIform="index"/>A Singular Experiment</head><p TEIform="p">Our sight is not always to be depended upon ; and a very odd experiment, illustrative of
                                the fact, may be performed by any one in possession of two hands and a sheet of paper.
                                Take the paper — stiff writing-paper will answer best — and roll it so as to form a tube
                                about an inch in diameter. Apply the tube to the right eye, and look steadily through it
                                at any convenient object ; at the same time keep the left eye open. Now, place the left
                                hand, with the palm toward you and the fingers pointing upward, by the side of the paper
                                tube and near its lower end. The strange sight will be seen of a hole — a clearly
                                defined hole — through the palm of the left hand. The illusion is a strange one, and a
                                good example of the things we are liable to have played us by our two-eyed vision.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Don't grumble" TEIform="index"/>Don't Grumble</head><p TEIform="p">It is as bad to be with a grumbler as to be out on a rainy day. The one dampens our
                                clothing, the other our spirits. But a bright, sunny-faced man or woman cheers us like a
                                ray of sunlight coming into a dark room. Fretting is hateful and tiresome. Cheerfulness,
                                lovely and winsome. We all have our trials and troubles, why should we impose them upon
                                others. There is virtue in suffering patiently and cheerfully. When troubles come, shut
                                your month firmly, look up, take in a long breath and go forward.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be and continue poor, young man, while others around you grow rich by fraud ..." TEIform="index"/>Be and continue poor, young man, while others around you grow rich by fraud...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Be and continue poor, young man, while others around you grow rich by fraud and
                                disloyalty; be without a place or power while others beg their way upward; bear the pain
                                of disappointed hopes while others gain the accomplishment of theirs by flattery ;
                                forego the gracious pressure of the hand, for which others cringe and crawl. Wrap
                                yourself in your own virtue, and seek a friend and your own daily bread.</p></div3></div2><pb n="141" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If we had but a day" TEIform="index"/>IF WE HAD BUT A DAY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dickenson, Mary Lowe; Reed, C. G." TEIform="persName"/>Mary Lowe Dickenson C. G. Reed</byline><p TEIform="p">1. We should fill the hour with the sweetest things, If we had but a day; 2. We should guide
                            our wayward or wearied wills, By celestial light; 3. We should waste no moment in weak
                            regret Ii the day were but one; We should drink alone at the purest springs, In our upward
                            way. We should keep our eyes on the heavenly hills If they lay in sight. But secure the
                            treasure our souls would bless Ere the set of sun. We should loye with a life-time's love in
                            an hour, If the hours were few, Wo should trample our pride and our discontent, All beneath
                            our feet, We should bo from our selfishness wholly free, Live to work or pray, We should
                            rest not for dreams, but for fresher power, To be and do. We should take whatsoever a good
                            God sent, With trust complete. And to be what the Father would have us be, Thro' out the
                            day.</p></div2><pb n="142" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Table</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Light and shadows of spiritualism" TEIform="index"/>Lights and Shadows of Spiritualism</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Home, D. D." TEIform="persName"/>D. D. Home</byline><p TEIform="p">Published by The BeligioPhilosophical Go., Chicago, 111. We have waited long and
                                patiently for this work. D. D. Home is acknowledged as second to no one spiritualist
                                (unless we may except Bros. A. J Davis and J. M. Peebles), in honesty of mediumship, and
                                in anxiety that the truths of Spiritualism may be eliminated from, and exalted far above
                                the villainous chaff of the mere sensational phenomena, which have assumed so
                                extravagant a position under the garb of Spiritualism's name. Bro. Home has done true
                                spiritualism a great favor by introducing to the world these " Lights and Shadows." He
                                will receive the condemDation of the dishonest in the ranks of Spiritualism, even as
                                Davis, Peebles, and their honest ilk deserve the censure of deceivers ; but such censure
                                is extorted praise. Get the book; see what is true of Spiritualism ; see also, its '*
                                Shadows," and avoid them. Price $1.50, postage free.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Announcement" TEIform="index"/>ANNOUNCEMENT</head><p TEIform="p">Ere these lines are read, there will be considerably advanced in printer's hands, a Book
                                of Sermons by Elder H. L. Eads, Bishop of South Union, Ky. To those who know of the
                                keen, clear, logical tendency of Elder Eads' theological writings, we need say nothing.
                                To those who would read lessons learned and taught, by one who was almost born a'Shaker,
                                and who has, through three-score years of faithful service in the cause of Shakerism,
                                demonstrated in life the truths he teaches, we advise a careful reading of this Book of
                                Sermons. The publishers, we make responsible for a fine portrait of Elder Eads,
                                disclaiming asw« would the introduction of any thing that had even the appearance of
                                vanity. The book will be of large type, clear print, and executed in the best manner by
                                Weed, Parsons ;gt Co., Albany, N. Y., and for sale only by the author, and The Shaker
                                Manifesto, Shakers, N. Y. Price $1.00</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>TRANSITIONS</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rogers, Olive" TEIform="index"/>Olive Rogers</head><p TEIform="p">At West Pittsfield, Mass., April 23, , 85 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall, Rachael" TEIform="index"/>Rachael Hall</head><p TEIform="p">At White Water, 0., April 6, aged 75 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bunnell, Timothy" TEIform="index"/>Timothy Bunnell</head><p TEIform="p">At Union Village, O., May 12, l, aged 84 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Patterson, Louisa Jane" TEIform="index"/>Louisa Jane Patterson</head><p TEIform="p">At Shirley, Mass., April 22, , aged 19 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Persons, Hattie Augusta" TEIform="index"/>Hattie Augusta Persons</head><p TEIform="p">Also, May 15, aged 17 years.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Received" TEIform="index"/>RECEIVED</head><p TEIform="p"> April 22, from Benjamin Gates, $68.00. May 16, from James Goodwin, $5.00. May 19, from
                                Galen Richmond, $20.00.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For a crushed foot" TEIform="index"/>For a Crushed Foot</head><p TEIform="p">Take a tablespoonful of honey, one of camphor, and one of wheat flour; mix well and bind
                                on.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="UIcered teeth" TEIform="index"/>Ulcered Teeth</head><p TEIform="p">Toast a piece of bread, then soak it in laudanum, camphor and cayenne pepper, and bind it
                                on the face. It gives immediate relief.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Injury by freezing" TEIform="index"/>Injury by Freezing</head><p TEIform="p">To cure frosted flesh, rub on the part balsam copaiba. This I have used for years, and it
                                always cures. Its effect is wonderful. A ten-cent box is sufficient to convince of its
                                virtue.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inverted toe-nails" TEIform="index"/>Inverted Toe-Nails</head><p TEIform="p">Take of saltpetre, burnt alum, and loaf sugar equal parts, rubbed fine and sifted through
                                thin muslin ; then bind some of it on the toe, and repeat as long as needed. It is a
                                certain cure if persevered in for two weeks. Put lint under the nail and cut it
                            square.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Red ants" TEIform="index"/>Red Ants</head><p TEIform="p">We have tried various things, and nothing seems to answer so well as a common white chalk
                                circle, placing the articles which they infest inside — such as the sugar bowl, sugar
                                barrel, etc. It is no less singular and simple than it is true, that not a single ant
                                will cross the line.</p></div3><pb n="143" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Remedy for felons" TEIform="index"/>Remedy for Felons</head><p TEIform="p">Rags wet with tincture of lobelia, bound on and kept constantly wet. Another good cure is
                                as follows : Take the yolk of one egg, an equal quantity of strained honey, one
                                teaspoonful of spirits of camphor, and one teaspoonful of spirits of turpentine, freshly
                                drawn. Mix well and thicken with flour to the consistency of thin paste. Spread it upon
                                the sore thinly, and cold. It takes hold with astonishing power, and rapidly draws
                                matters to a crisis. Everybody ought to know it.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Make your own syrups" TEIform="index"/>Make Your Own Syrups</head><p TEIform="p">To make a gallon of syrup of beautiful whiteness and crystal-like transparency, such as
                                is known in our markets as silver drips, or rock candy drips, there are required eight
                                pounds of refined sugar, such as is known by its various names and grades of A or B or
                                extra C, and costing from 10 to 12 1-2 cents per lb., according to locality and distance
                                from the sugar refinery. To this quantity should be added three pints of boiling water,
                                and the whole subjected to slow boiling for a period of fifteen or twenty minutes, after
                                which the solution, while warm, should be strained through a fabric of moderately close
                                texture. This will produce a gallon of syrup, at much less cost than the price demanded
                                in market for the grades of syrup named. For a light yellow or golden syrup, the same
                                quantity of light brown sugar may be employed, and so on through the lower grades of
                                sugar and syrup ; but no grade of sugar can be found which will produce so worthless an
                                article as the Cuba molasses generally offered in our markets.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Revival" TEIform="index"/>REVIVAL</head><p TEIform="p">There has been a great revival in Wales. In the moonlight nights of the past few weeks scenes
                            were enacted rivaling those of Martha's Vineyard. At Rhondu Valley young men tore off their
                            studs and gilt watch chains and cast them to the earth ; girls tore their earrings from
                            their ears and flowers from their skirts, and scattered them to the wind, while the preacher
                            exhorted in the Welsh tongue until vast crowds arose from the kneeling posture of
                            humiliation in which they had been listening, and executed a wild, uncouth dance, until they
                            fell exhausted on the earth.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Agricultural</head><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A New Jersey paper says that ninety years ago it was regarded as a settled point that corn..." TEIform="index"/>A New Jersey paper says that ninety years ago it was regarded as a settled point that corn...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A New Jersey paper says that ninety years ago it was regarded as a settled point that
                                corn in drills gave a larger product than in hills, but that now, after much discussion,
                                it remains unsettled. The remark would not be made by any one who had informed himself
                                on the subject. We have thoroughly tested this question by measuring the results and
                                find almost uniformly an increase of 25 to 30 per cent with drill corn over hills,
                                provided the proper distance is given for the plants. It would be easy to obtain a
                                diminished amount from the drills if too thinly planted ; or ears of an inferior quality
                                if too thick. John Johnston informs us that after long experience he arrives at results
                                precisely similar to those we have mentioned.—Country Gentleman .</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sweet cord as stock-feed" TEIform="index"/>Sweet Corn as Stock-feed</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Talcott, Jonathan" TEIform="persName"/>Jonathan Talcott</byline><p TEIform="p">the well-known farmer of Rome, N. Y., reports to the American Cultivator this very
                                satisfactory experience with sweet corn as stock-feed : " During the past two seasons I
                                have had an acre or more to cut up when suitable for roasting'ears, besides what I have
                                fed in its green state direct to the cows, and I think it is the best feed that I have
                                ever used for feeding dairy-cows or fattening animals. In either case it seems a food
                                nearly perfect. The ears furnish material for fattening or milk, as the farmer wishes,
                                and the stalks, if cut when green and well cured, will be eaten very clean, and serve
                                all the purposes of hay, especially for working oxen; and while they are so supplied
                                they feel the effects of good feeding as readily as on any feed 1 have ever given to
                                working oxen. I find, while so fed, oxen will lay on flesh veiy fast if not required for
                                daily labor on the farm. Let every farmer try a piece of sweet corn for 1879, and note
                                the success, being careful to secure the fodder, with the ears on, in fine condition,
                                and keep it bright and sweet till fed out."</p></div3></div2><pb n="144" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Socialism" TEIform="index"/>SOCIALISM</head><p TEIform="p">Professor Henry Fawcett, in a lecture at the University of Cambridge, England, expressed the
                            conviction that repressive measures are powerless to stay the progress of Socialism. On the
                            contrary, they would stimulate its development. This had been shown in England, where laws
                            to prevent combinations of workingmen had driven them into forming secret societies. He said
                            nothing could be more unfair nor unreasonable than to associate the Socialists of Germany
                            and other countries with the crimes of a few fanatics. The principles of Socialism in
                            various forms had been advocated by the wisest and best of men from the earliest times. The
                            social life of the early Christians was organized on communistic principles. " All that
                            believed were together, and had all things common, and sold their possessions and goods, and
                            parted them to all men, as every man had need." The fundamental principle of Socialism was
                            that men should not be permitted to appropriate to their sole use all that they are able to
                            acquire, but that a portion of what they possess should be devoted to the relief of the
                            necessitous.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Character more than reputation" TEIform="index"/>CHARACTER MORE THAN REPUTATION</head><p TEIform="p">Keep straight ahead. The curve line may be the line of beauty, but it is better to be able to
                            walk a crack than describe a circle. The man who can walk in a straight line may be all
                            right, but he who can only walk in a cycloid curve is assuredly all wrong. This injunction
                            concerning your physical peregrination applies as well to your spiritual itineracy. Are you
                            slandered ? Keep straight on in your course and let backbiting die the death of neglect.
                            What is the use of lying awake nights brooding over the remarks of some false friend, that
                            runs through your brain like lightning ? What is the use of getting into a worry and fret
                            over gossip that has been set afloat to your disadvantage by some meddlesome busybody who
                            has more time than character ? The thing cannot possibly injure you, unless indeed you take
                            notice of it, and in combating it give it standing and character. If what is said about you
                            is true, set yourself right; if it is false, let it pass for what it is worth. If a bee
                            sting you, would you go to the hive to destroy it ? Would not a thousand come upon you ? It
                            is wisdom to say little respecting the injuries you have received. We are generally losers
                            in the end if we stop to refute all the backbiting and gossipping we may hear by the way.
                            They are annoying, it is true ; but not dangerous, so long as we do not stop to expostulate
                            and scold. Our characters are formed and sustained by ourselves, by our own actions and
                            purposes, and not by others. Value what you know of yourself more than what others may think
                            of you. Character is more than reputation, and the approval of your own honest conscience is
                            a thousand fold more valuable than the commendation of a community. But you can have both.
                            Live for God's approval and your own proper commendation, and that of your friends will
                            urely follow.—Christian at Work.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What comfort can a serious Christian take in a faith that..." TEIform="index"/>What comfort can a serious Christian take in a faith that...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">What comfort can a serious Christian take in a faith that falls short of righteousness and
                            redemption ? Would it not make a man's or woman's heart ache to think, " I am a believer,
                            but yet have no faitli that reacheth to sanctification and holy living, and redemption from
                            sin ? All my faith [eaves me a sinner all my days ; to my dying hour there is no mastery to
                            be had, no etting victory over sin ; it will prevail over me as long as I live." What! must
                            we never be cleansed ? Must this crooked leart and perverse will always remain ? Vlust I be
                            a sinner and a believer ? A sinner, and call myself a child of God 1 How can these things
                            hang together </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Selfishness" TEIform="index"/>Selfishness</head><p TEIform="p">There is no bar to thorough and wide culture so insuperably fatal as selfishness, nor any
                            external disadvantage so contracting to the intellect as pride and ;ontracted affections. It
                            is possible to be full in sympathy, in one place as well as in another, with all that is
                            human, and with all that is noble; and there are few more honorable ambitions than to put
                            your whole strength, with a willing and a cheerful mind, nto the work and the opportunities
                            of goodwill which lie near you.</p></div2><!--
                     <pb id="p29"/>
                     <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>