<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2501" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">25</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18950101" TEIform="date">January 1895</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="25" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                        <pb id="p1"/>
                    
                    <p>JANUARY. THE MANIFESTO PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. VOL.XXV. " Cast thy bread upon the waters ; for thou shalt
                        find it after, many days." Eccl. XI: i. East Canterbury, N. H. 1895.</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    <pb n="1" id="p3"/>
                    <div2 type="none"
                        <p>THE MANIFESTO PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. VOL. XXV. 'Seek te first the kingdom of god and his
                            righteousness."—Matt, vi., 33. East Canterbury, N. H., 1895.</p>
                    </div2>
                    <pb n="2" id="p4"/>
                    --><pb n="3" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="History of South Union, Kentucky, no. 15" TEIform="index"/>HISTORY OF SOUTH UNION, KY. NO.
                            15.</head><p TEIform="p">AUG. 27, 1862. During the time of the war in 1862 the Believers of South Union are obliged to
                            go to Bowling Green, a distance of fifteen miles, to reach a Post Office. Not less than 500
                            Cavalry pass through our Village to-day, and we supply them with bread and fruit. The whole
                            country is in a state of anarchy and no one feels safe. Robbers enter the dwellings of both
                            rich and poor and take all they can find, by force. Sept. 14. 800 Federal Cavalry and 300
                            Infantry pass through the Village. Some 40,000 Confederates have entered the state, and
                            reached Cave City. It is dangerous to be far from home either night or day. The slaves are
                            beginning to think that they are men. Some are waiting in patience for "Massa Lincoln" to
                            set them free; others who are impatient run away to places of anticipated security. If any
                            are re-taken their masters whip them severely and then drive them before their horses like
                            cattle. There is but little value placed on human life. Oct. 25. The buying and selling of
                            human beings still continues. This morning, three stout black men, having their hands tied
                            behind them and being lashed together, are driven like cattle through our streets. Let us
                            read this,—"Whatsoever measure you mete to others, shall be meted to you again." The Union
                            soldiers are seen nearly every day as they pass through the country, and the Confederates
                            are seen quite as often. Of course they are all Christians and belong to the Christian
                            churches, but are anxious to put each other beyond the breathing point. JANUARY <pb n="4" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 4 THE MANIFESTO. Nov. 4. Five regiments of Union Cavalry pass through the
                            Village. The road as far as one can see is filled with soldiers. When they enter our Village
                            the men and horses are covered with a cloud of dust. All :ire encamped by midnight. "We
                            endeavored, but in vain, to have the army stop in the woods but tiny threw down the fences
                            and all the men, horses and wagons entered our pastures. In a short time nearly 4000 camp
                            fires are lighted, and although the spectacle is beautifully grand, the pleasure is somewhat
                            diminished as we know that they are tearing down our fences and burning our valuable white
                            oak rails. A subsequent estimate of their destructive fires is not less than 20,000 rails.
                            In this company were 5000 men and some 6000 horses. They were all unier the command of Col.
                            Kennett. He is a very kind man, but quite impossible for him to prevent his men, at times,
                            from helping themselves as opportunity offered. Pickets are sent out to guard every road,
                            leading into the place, to prevent any disturbance or alarm. All night long these men sit,
                            patiently, on their horses, keeping guard over the people and their property. By their
                            pilfering we lose the honey of several bee-hives, a few potatoes, some baskets, buckets and
                            some other things. The thieving was charged to the teamsters, but they did not incline to
                            admit it. Nov. 5. The morning opens beautifully clear, and the army leaves the place. The
                            Brethren are soon on the grounds to extinguish all the fires and to care for the property
                            generally. We soon learn that the sold:ers have emptied three barns of all the provender.
                            They gave a voucher on the government for $378.00 but said they were unauthorized to account
                            for the rails that were burned. For those we subsequently received $75.00. The
                            camping-ground is a scene of wraste and desolation. They left three horses th it were unfit
                            for service, also a lot of corn and forage scattered about the grounds. Some of this the
                            Brethren save and also re-build the fences. The great Sahara desert could not afflict one
                            more, on the same area, than do our dusty roads. We have had but very little rain for three
                            months, and with so much travel, the powdered clay on the roads, in some places is not less
                            than three inches deep. When the Cavalry pass or a flurry of wind sweeps over it, the dust
                            goes up in clouds, and even the buildings are indistinctly seen. Some sick soldiers are left
                            in our charge, almost every day. The officers generally eat and lodge in the Trustees'
                            Office and kindly settle all their bills. Nov. 10. A regiment of Cavalry pass on to
                            Russellville, and in the p. m. a company of 2000 are seen marching along the highway. The
                            solid footfall of tramp, tramp, tramp, at the sound of the fife and drum, is a remarkable
                            sight, especially when we consider the errand on which they are sent. <pb n="5" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE MANIFESTO. 5 As soon as this company is gone, another of 250 come from the west and
                            c.unp on our grounds. They c:vll for 100 lbs. of meat and 100 lbs. of bread, which is soon
                            provided for them. In the night another company of Cavalry come along and demand supper for
                            the men and forage for the horses. These men, although they are Union soldiers, are
                            obtrusive and unreasonable. War does not refine the mind. We must either comply with their
                            demands or suffer for not complying. Nov. 13. We receive a letter from PUasr.nt Hill; the
                            first word from that Society since the Confederate invasion of the blue g;ass region. The
                            Brethren and Sisters have come off vastly better than we could have expected. Indeed, the
                            Lord has protected them in their home. They lost a few horses and wagons by the ''impress"
                            process and when the large army of 20,000 passed through their Village they were obliged to
                            cook night and day for nearly a week, but otherwise were uninjured. They are respected by
                            both the Union and Confederate armies, and their religious scruples recognized. Returning to
                            South Union we make record of the considerate care that is exercised by Major Kennedy who
                            came with two other officers and put up at the Office for the night. They left some 300 men
                            and horses at quite a distance from the Village, although they could easily have reached
                            South Union. They thought we had been too much imposed upon already by the large number of
                            soldiers that have camped upon our grounds. (To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Merry Christmas to all" TEIform="index"/>MERRY CHRISTMAS TO ALL</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Goepper, Anna B." TEIform="persName"/>Anna B. Goepper</byline><p TEIform="p">HAVING been solicited to contribute something toward our monthly messenger we accept the
                            present opportunity. Welcome glad Christinas! Though the years are passing all too swiftly,
                            we forget our sighing to greet thee once more, and wish all a very merry Christmas. We
                            should all improve the spring-time of youth, while all nature.is alive within us, before the
                            chilling frosts of remorseless time have sprinkled our brows with silver, and before old
                            Father Time has mown low the flowers that grow along our pathway. We really feel anxious to
                            say something encouraging and cheerful. Shadows often darken our pathway at noon when the
                            sun should be shining but remember the clouds that overshadow will soon change to the bright
                            silver lining. Some of our friends may prove false, but life is too brief to waste it in
                            grieving and repining. Let us look upward and onward when adversity threatens and friends
                            turn away, neglectful of their duty to God and their <pb n="6" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 6 THE MANIFESTO.
                            fellow-man. Look upward; there is still a work for each of us to do. Sometimes in an hour
                            when our hope in her castle lies crushed, our faith should then make us to see the cloud's
                            silver lining. Rough and uneven our life's journey may seem, and the goal though ever
                            distant, yet it is never all lost, and sometime we shall know why the clouds concealed their
                            bright lining. Then again some love to go about to gossip here and gossip there,
                            manufacturing evil and untruthful reports. A pure-minded person is very often open to
                            misconstruction by one of meaner thoughts and motives, and to my style of thinking a proper
                            way of dealing with such an one is, when you find yourself in contact with him, and your
                            actions open to his hurtful innuendoes, to get as speedily as possible from his vicinity,
                            and dismiss all thought of him with the trenchant little phrase, "Shamed be he that evil
                            thinks." But upon the whole we are a peaceable and progressive family and we have devoted,
                            genuiue, gospel, loving Brethren and Sisters whom we would be truly sorry to part with, and
                            trust they may be spared to us many years. During the Ministry's eight week's visit to the
                            East, Elder Oliver presided over our family; and what a beautiful ministration and heavenly
                            influence he carried about with him! He fulfilled the scripture which says ;—"Do unto others
                            as you would have others do unto you." We regretted the time came so soon to part with him,
                            yet welcomed our absent friends back again gladly. "Bless parents, brothers, sisters dear,
                            Bless all I love both far and near; Bless all thy children great and small, I pray thee,
                            Father of us all." Union Village, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York, December 1894" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Dec. 8, 1894</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Henry:—"And still another!" you will say, so soon after receiving the other
                                package of a few days since. We never know what the Spirit has in store for us. The
                                enclosed is fresh from the mint and knowing your mind upon certain things, I thought,
                                "this plea for the turkeys will just please Elder Henry, and as it is the time of year
                                when the poor creatures are particularly noticed, he may be only too glad to put it in
                                the Jan. number of The Manifesto, so I will catch the train and send it be- fore it is
                                too late." "Shakerism is a new phase of human existence. In the first cycle (just
                                closing,) 'Thou shalt not generate,' was the great command. In the second cycle (just
                                opening,)'Thou shalt not kill,' will be the next great command." So prophesied our good
                                father, Elder Frederic; he who put in the first <pb n="7" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 7
                                wedge and gave the first blow that opened a new and startling revelation to the
                                pork-eating—beef-lovers of the Shaker Community. All honor to the great prophet! Through
                                his ministrations others have been, and are inspired to utter the same truths and they
                                bring forth the same practical results. In the days to come, I hope it will be as sinful
                                to raise and sell for slaughter as it is now sinful (to some) to slaughter, simply for
                                the purpose of appeasing a depiaved appetite. "How can we reason but from what we know,"
                                and we know that Believers in general are in the rear guard when they in the face of
                                reason aud common sense, saying nothing of conscience, will, in this age of evolution,
                                dip their hands in blood and deck their tables with dead carcasses. Think you the eagle
                                souls who soar aloft for light in the outer firmament would accept the truths of the
                                first cycle, if they were forced to depart from the truths of the second in order to
                                obtain the first? He that is faithful in that which is least will be faithful in greater
                                things. Our Ministry are at their central home, and we think of keeping them here until
                                the cold season is over. Dear Eldress Harriet we are happy to state is steadily gaining
                                ground from her recent indisposition, and we all mean to be with her on the ascending
                                scale. A joyful Christmas to all our dear friends at Canterbury and Enfield, may old and
                                young be made happy recipients of all the blessings of the church militant below and
                                receive a continuation of divine light and truth from the Church above—in the Spirit
                                world. Elder Henry, we are thankful for your excellent words and mean to hold oui selves
                                in that manner to accept the increasing truth, though it come like a trumpet's blast
                                with no "uncertain sound." Your Sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna White</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York, December 9, 1894" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Dec. 9, 1894</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Henry.—I herewith enclose check for our due on The Manifesto for 1895, and
                                also that of the Canaan family. We have sent a few subscribers but I have not an
                                accurate account of them. [An assessment check was received from Elder John B. Vance the
                                day following. Both payments were received with many thanks. Ed.] The trumpet has been
                                sounding long and loud for sometime, for a forward movement in practical righteousness.
                                When shall we pull up our stakes and move forward in the increasing work of God. Has not
                                the woe (sorrow) come upon us that Jesus predicted would come when all men should speak
                                well of us. The testimony against the flesh, borne so fearlessly by Mother Ann and the
                                founders of our Order, was accepted by no men in Mother's day, and how could they speak
                                well of her, or those who lived the life she taught. Did it not bring persecution and
                                suffering upon them and also prosperity? The world at that time would neither live nor
                                acknowledge the truth of her <pb n="8" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 8 THE MANIFESTO. testimony. But now,
                                all the better and progressive cla-ses acknowledge, even though they do not live it, the
                                truth of our foundation principles. Every righteous public man or woman, in and out of
                                the so-called Christian churches, bears testimony against the corruptions that sue in
                                the world through lust. Now if we, as followers of Christ in the second appearing, would
                                hold our place in the galaxy of bright stars in the spiritual heavens, and be as guiding
                                lights to a progressing world, we must tJce new steps in advance. Can we rest at ease on
                                the testimony of the founders of our Order, and have the Order grow ? Experience and
                                observation say, Nay! But unless we move forward with increased testimony against the
                                Man of Sin, we shall not be able to hold our own, or maintain the testimony of the past.
                                Shall we not move forward in the increased light of the Sun of Righteousness that is
                                shiuing so gloriously, raise the standard higher, and bring our lives practically in
                                accord therewith, and thus inaugurate a new era of spiritual prosperity. I mailed you a
                                letter yesterday from Eldress Anna it contains the keynote of the coming testimony. If
                                ice do not sound it, we can not suppress it, for it will be sounded long and strong. May
                                The Manifesto be the trumpet to sound fearlessly, the incoming t°stimony that shall be
                                as a two-edged sword, that will cut evil within as well as without. It is proposed that
                                if a company go down to Florida to start a new organization, that flesh meats be
                                entirely excluded. I propose that those who want to go, shall commence now and practice
                                at least five years at home; by that time, I prophesy, that is, if we as a people start
                                now, in that new life we shall reach a spiritual baptism that will instill new life into
                                the waste places, and we be prepared to minister to the needs of a growing people that
                                are coming up; and the hireling problem be solved to our entire satisfaction. In kindest
                                love,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Offord</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plea for the turkeys" TEIform="index"/>A PLEA FOR THE TURKEYS</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Vineo, Cora C." TEIform="persName"/>Cora C. Vineo</byline><p TEIform="p">I saw them first when with their mother, they Took scratching lessons, peeped a turkey song,
                            And wandered in the grass that turned to hay When summer sun grew hot and days were long.
                            Again I saw them in their youthful prime After the molting days had swiftly passed, And
                            thought how dextrously old Father Time Had worked, to make their feathers grow so fast. But
                            months passed on, the festal time drew near, The turkeys grew in strength and size and
                            weight; <pb n="9" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. \ But, oh, alas! I felt a sudden fear, And pity
                            smote me as I mourned their fate. I saw the gory execution block, And sharpened ax that told
                            of days gone by When man against his kind with cruel shock Condemned them by the guillotine
                            to die. But justice seemed to call for deeds of shame In those fell days when anarchy ran
                            wild, And truth and liberty bore all the blame, When slaughter made the worst foes
                            reconciled. But in the death of these poor innocents Not even justice could approve the
                            waste, And mercy shocked, forsook the murderous tents Where men raised blood-stained hands
                            and killed for taste. And when I saw the dread dissecting knife Wielded by hands that nurse
                            the infant race, And not content with simply taking life, They mutilate the corpse,—oh, foul
                            disgrace! Aud then before the market-place in rows I saw the naked victims cold and pale,
                            And seemed to hear them say in dying throes, "Come cannibals, our bodies are for sale." My
                            heart sank in me, for in dream I saw Children and lords and ladies (?) sit and jest, Yea,
                            even judges of the moral law, And sport about the part they fancied best. Oh pitiless \ we
                            send the Holy Book And missionaries where the heathen roam, But in our folly blindly
                            overlook The unconverted heathen here at home. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bryant centennial commemoration" TEIform="index"/>BRYANT CENTENNIAL COMMEMORATION</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Martha J. Anderson</byline><p TEIform="p">THE centennial birthday of William Cullen Bryant was commemorated by the "Self-Improvement
                            Society" of the North family of Shakers at Mt. Lebanon in their last weekly meeting. There
                            was a nicely formed circle of twenty members; a large bouquet of the last flowers of summer
                            was placed on a circular stand in the centre and added brightness and cheerfulness to the
                            well-lighted room. After an appropriate song, with organ accompaniment, Catherine Allen, the
                            sister president, made a few fitting re<pb n="10" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 10 THE MANIFESTO. marks
                            concerning the "Poet of Nature;" dwelling on the simplicity and uprightness of his character
                            as a man, and of his loyalty as a citizen of the Republic, deeming it worthy of our notice
                            as a religious organization to pay homage to so worthy and so noble a character. The
                            following sonnet was written in the centre of a large sheet of white paper, artistically
                            embellished with birds, and encircled with beautiful Ampdopsis leaves, rich in color and
                            varied as the hues of autumn :</p><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="William Cullen Bryant—born November 3, 1794" TEIform="index"/>WILLIAM CULLEN BRYANT.—BORN
                                NOVEMBER 3, 1794</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Martha J. Anderson</byline><p TEIform="p">A century's close dims not thy glorious fame, Thou loyal son of brave New England sires,
                                Who at their hearth-stones kindled freedom's fires And won by valorous deeds an honored
                                name. A noble lineage holds thee in claim; Thy soul was cradled 'neath these forest
                                spires Where "God's First Temples" wakened high desires, And inspiration fanned Faith's
                                sacred flame. Thy dream of youth in "Thanatopsis" given Into thy closing days its beauty
                                wrought, And gave thee access to a loftier heaven Than is by creed or cringing error
                                brought. All honor to thy blessed memory, Long live the praise of thy sweet minstrelsy.
                                A most interesting biographical sketch was compiled and read by Lydia Staples. Then
                                followed an original character sketch.</p></div3><div3 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="William Cullen Bryant" TEIform="index"/>WILLIAM CULLEN BRYANT</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/>Lucy S. Bowers</byline><p TEIform="p">Just one hundred years ago a beautiful soul was born into the world, whose spark of
                                divine intelligence glowred and burned and increased till its light has illuminated the
                                hearts of men even to the farthermost isles of the sea, and is destined to shine through
                                unnumbered generations. This soul has become familiar to us in the person of William
                                Cullen Bryant, the poet of Nature whom, though we have not seen in physical form, we
                                have learned to love and admire tenderly and sincerely through that which he has given
                                to us in his melodious and inspiring verses, which sparkle like beautiful gems upon the
                                pages of English literature. They are right who declare that Nature has never had a more
                                devout and appreciative worshipper than William Cullen Bryant. "The beautiful trees
                                wThen covered with green foliage, or crowued with the golden pomp of autumn, or glassed
                                in the ice of winter, as they stand root clasped in root, and branch embracing branch
                                like a band of brothers were his instructors; the sweet sisterhood of floweis gleaming
                                like drops of sky and sunbeam and rainbow were the pets of his passionate love; the
                                warbling birds, the lakes, the streams, green fields and forests were his favorites. The
                                rocks are the altars on which he offered his songs." The mountain is a footstool which
                                    <pb n="11" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 11 touches the throne of God and he often knelt
                                there. Truly what loftier hemes could man's mind employ for the uplifting of his soul
                                toward the Supreme? In what holier realm could he wander? among what grander ob- jects
                                could he search for Divine wisdom than among these precious things of Infinite creation
                                and careful keeping. "Whatsoever things are lovely, true, pure and of good report, think
                                on these things." By obeying this injunction, Bryant rose into and lived in the sphere
                                and element of true holiness and everlasting love. Bryant was born at Cuininington,
                                November 3, 1794. He was descended on both sides from families winch came in the
                                Mayflower. His father was a physician and also a poet. Among the best books written by
                                the best authors the child found pleasant opportunity for the cultivation of talents
                                which he exhibited at a very early age. It is told that when sixteen months old, he knew
                                all the letters of the alphabet, and when three years old, he attended the district
                                school. By the time he was ten years of age he had written verses for declamation in
                                school which were printtd in a local paper. At thirteen he wrote a satire at the expense
                                of Jefferson, entitled "The Embargo," wiiich was printed in book form, and was so
                                successful as to require a second edition. In the year 1817 he reached national fame by
                                the publication in the North American Review of his poem entitled "Thanatopsis," this
                                poem had been written in 1811 when he was but 17 years old and proved to te not only the
                                finest that had yet been produced on this continent, but one of the most remarkable ever
                                produced at such an early age. So that even before he took up literature by which to
                                earn a living, his fame as a writer was well established. There could have been no time
                                in his life for idleness, for at the age of sixteen he was a student at William's
                                college, where he soon became well versed in both ancient and modern languages, after
                                which he was admitted to the bar and practiced law ten years. As time advanced he became
                                known as a poet, journalist and orator; he edited the New York Evening Post for nearly
                                fifty years, made memorable addresses and was a correspondent and traveler, making six
                                trips to Europe and visiting Egypt and Syria. In the year 1821 he married Francis
                                Fairchild, who died in 1866, leaving two children. Among his great literary works are
                                one hundred original poems. He translated the "Iliad" and "Odeysey," wrote many
                                newspaper editorials, and "Letters to a Traveler," "Letters from the East," "Orations
                                and Addresses ;" edited "Picturesque America," "Library of Poetry and Song," and a
                                "School History of the United States." His most famous poems are "The Embargo,"
                                "Thanatopsis," "Forest Hymn," "Land of Dreams," "Waiting at the Gate," "Robert of
                                Lincoln," "To a Water-fowl," "Death of the Flowers," "The Flood of Years," "Among the
                                Trees," and the "Od.e to Washington," which is said to be his last poem, <pb n="12" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 12 THE MANIFESTO. It is not necessary to point out at any length the
                                merits of a poet whose productions are a world wide delight; his poems are distinguished
                                by their perfect finish and exquisite style, their elevated tone, their dignity of
                                sentiment and their lovely pictures of American scenery. He was true to nature, and
                                nature's simplicity and purity were most charmingly reflected in his sweet verses. From
                                such poetry we learn how much we owe those poets whose genius is under the control of
                                moral feelings; who make the imagination and the sense of beauty ministering servants at
                                the altar of the highest good and the highest truth. Among his honors he was enrolled as
                                one of the alumni of William's college, his seventieth birthday was celebrated by the
                                Century Club and on the day that began his eighty-first year lie received the "Bryant
                                Vase." It was not until age had whitened his locks that Bryant's struggle with poverty
                                ceased. We are told that his life was a constant succession of trials, yet through it
                                all he maintained the simplicity and sweetness of manner which were his distinguishing
                                characteristics. His life was free from frailties which mar those of the average man. In
                                his habits he was physiological and abstemious, spending one hour every day in bathing
                                and gymnastic exercises and walking out in all kinds of weather, as a reward he never
                                experienced sickness up to his dying day at which time at the age of eighty- four years
                                June 12, 1878, he was stricken with heat while making an address at the unveiling of a
                                statue to Mazzini at Central Park. When the "Post" became a paying property he purchased
                                a country home at Roslyn, L. I., and named it Cedarmere. There he lived and died and
                                there his body rests in the quiet village church-yard. In due time a monument will be
                                erected to his name in Central Park as a tribute to his genius; it will express the
                                universal admiration of a loving and appreciative people. On the monument, which is to
                                be of pure Italian marble, will be carved the name of the poet and underneath it will be
                                the word "Thanatopsis," the title of his greatest poem. Let me quote a few of his own
                                gentle words and my sketch is finished. "I was always," he says, "from my earliest years
                                a delighted observer of external nature—the splendors of the winter day-break over the
                                wide wastes of snow seen from my windows, the glories of the autumnal woods, the gloomy
                                approaches of the thunder-storm and its departure amid sunshine and rainbows, the return
                                of spring with its flowers, and the first snow-fall of winter, though I rarely heard
                                such things spoken of I cherished them in my secret mind." Bryant must have left the
                                world better than he found it, for who can help growing better when associated with good
                                and pure-minded men and women. SONG. "Trees, swaying trees, waves, whispering waves, Ye
                                tell of the glory of God to me. The beautiful prints of His fingers of love, I find on
                                the land and the sea." <pb n="13" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 13 Recitations from the
                                poet's productions,—"To a Water-fowl." By Julia M. Lincoln. "God's First Temples;" By
                                Grace H. Bowers. "TLanatopsis." Read by Eldress Anna White.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bryant" TEIform="index"/>BRYANT</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Burger, Sarah J." TEIform="persName"/>Sarah J. Burger</byline><p TEIform="p">Long hushed the voice that tuned the hymns of praise; Folded the hands that touched the
                                lyre of song; The heart that hurned with inspiration strong Beats now to rhythm of
                                immortal lays. His was the giant's strength of earlier days, He shared the joys and
                                sorrows of life's throng, And, battling bravely 'gainst the tide of wrong He strove to
                                lead mankind in perfect ways. Across his sunset gleamed the bars of gold, And purple
                                fringed was every changing cloud That wove for him the royal, kindly shroud, That
                                wrapped his noble form within its fold. A garland fair all nature for him weaves While
                                tribute true his memory receives. "October." Recitation by Jennie Vinneo. "November."
                                Mabel E. Lane. "Death of the Flowers." May Rullhausen. "Old Man's Funeral." Ameia Bell.
                                "Land of Dreams." Read by Annie R. Stephens.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Poet and prophet" TEIform="index"/>POET AND PROPHET</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Vinneo, Cora C." TEIform="persName"/>Cora C. Vinneo</byline><p TEIform="p">Oh mighty prophet—soul of love and song: Thou rapt interpreter of truth divine, What
                                other heart could echo songs like thine? Thy words struck vengeance, for their might was
                                strong Against oppression in its court of wrong. Like wintry starlight o'er the groves
                                of pine. Thine eyes beheld the light of freedom shine O'er ranks of slavery's
                                sin-beclouded throng. And when thy magic fingers touched the keys Of Time's great organ,
                                lo, the concert chord Struck the true note to life's grand symphonies, And rolled the
                                finished anthem to the Lord. And with thy knees upon Faith's altar stair Thy gentle soul
                                communed with God through prayer. SONG. O Prophets and immortal Sages Who have passed to
                                spheres above, Left for us on fiery pages Eecords of your priceless love. The members
                                then read shoi-t selections from Bryant's poems. Cecelia DeVere delivered the closing
                                address; the impromptu utterance was eulogistic in a high degree to poet, journalist and
                                patriot and was a star set in his diadem of worth. The interest was unabated to the
                                close of the meeting which continued one hour and a half. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div3></div2><pb n="14" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Incoming year" TEIform="index"/>THE INCOMING YEAR</head><p TEIform="p">WITH the opening of the new "year, come new resolves, new hopes and new aspirations. New
                            interests will attract our attention and new zeal will be awakened for the peace and
                            prosperity of our gospel home. We are astonished at the velocity with which time flies from
                            us and it is seemingly the journey only of a few days since we were reading "The Shaker" as
                            our little paper was designated in its infancy. When Vol. I—No. 1 in 1871 sent out its
                            introductory note, and informed its anticipated readers that it would "be devoted to the
                            cause of religious truths ; devoid of speculative theories of a theological nature," the
                            active workers of that date had but a faint idea of the duties they were preparing to take.
                            Elder Giles B. Avery was probably the most active mind in establishing out first and only
                            periodical publication that has been presented to the public as an official work. The first
                            number of "The Shaker" was sent into the world with anxious hopes and a prayerful desire for
                            the blessing of God to accompany it on its mission of brotherly love. From that date to the
                            close of the present volume there never has been a broken record through a course of
                            twenty-four years. Like everything that has a place in the Providence of God there has been
                            some changes in the title of our little monthly and also some changes in the general
                            arrangement of the paper. For three years it was known as "The Shaker" and was published in
                            a quarto form of eight pages under the Editorial management of Br. G. A. Lomas, of
                            Watervliet, N. Y. In the publishing of "The Shaker" we soon saw the necessity of changing
                            our system of musical characters, which at best was quite imperfect and at the above date
                            were written without the staff, and the small letters of the alphabet represented the notes.
                            It was soon found necessary to adopt the same form that was in general use. To some who had
                            grown familiar with the "sight music" as the letters were termed, this change was like a
                            backward move of many years, and from their hearts the "black heads" had no word of welcome,
                            and it was not till we had reached the twelfth number of the first volume that "The Shaker"
                            was able to publish its first piece of music. Many months then passed along before the
                            Editor could see his way clear to present another piece of music. This time he selected
                            "Faith's Vision," and it needed a deep faith and a clear vision to see far enough into the
                            future to be assured that the "black notes" were the right ones to use. As these characters
                            with but few exceptions, whether in the spaces or on the lines were quite alike, <pb n="15" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 15 they were called "hide and seek" notes as the singers would
                            be obliged to depend largely upon guess work, and it was thought that few only would be able
                            to sing the music by note. As no more music found its way into the columns of "The Shaker"
                            till it had reached the 7th number of Vol. II., there was sufficient time for all to become
                            better acquainted with the innovation and even for many to appreciate the proposed change.
                            From that date to the present, with but few exceptions, the music has found a welcome place
                            in every issue. In 1873 the 1st number of Vol. III. came out under the title of "Shaker and
                            Shakeress" and was edited by Elder F. AV. Evans of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. It carried this name
                            for three years, when it was again placed under the charge of Br. G. A. Lomas, and returned
                            to its original title "The Shaker." During all these years the printing of the paper was
                            done in the office of Weed and Parsons of Albany, N. Y. whose reputation for excellent work
                            was well established. In 1877—78 "The Shaker" was printed in the office of J. H. Pearsons of
                            Concord, N. H. In 1878 the publication took the name of "The Shaker Manifesto" and the form
                            was changed to an octavo of twenty-eight pages. The compositors were now the Sisters of our
                            own home in Canterbury, while the printing continued to be done by the firm in Concord. In
                            January 1879 "The Shaker Manifesto" returned to the office of Weed and Parsons, and remained
                            in that place till January 1882 when the editorial management was accepted at Canterbury, N.
                            H. and the Sister compositors after a respite of three years might again be found busy in
                            the setting of types, which has continued uninterrupted till the present date. From 1882
                            till 1887 the types weie arranged into pages and taken to the office of Sleeper and Evans in
                            Concord, N. H. to be printed. In January 1883 the title was again changed, and this time to
                            the simple form of "The Manifesto." In 1887 we made arrangements to have the business all
                            transferred to our village, and accordingly fitted up the printing office with necessary
                            machinery, and when "The Manifesto" was ready for the mail, at the close of the month, we
                            were much pleased with our own success. Since the above date we have moved quietly along
                            with only such changes as became necessary for its general improvement. The success of our
                            little paper has been largely through the kind efforts of our beloved Brethren and Sisters,
                            who have liberally contributed to its columns and also contributed generously to the expense
                            of its publication.</p></div2><pb n="16" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Center of light" TEIform="index"/>CENTER OF LIGHT</head><p TEIform="p">uBlessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God"—Matt, v., 8. Enfieild, N. H. The pure
                            in heart shall see God; Shall know of his goodness and share in his mercies, Be filled to a
                            ful-ness, with his boundless love. Their light shall shine as the sun; Its bright rays of
                            glad-ness, Shall banish all sadness, And un to its cen-ter all souls yet shall come.</p></div2><pb n="17" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manifesto. January, 1895. Office of publication" TEIform="index"/>THE MANIFESTO. JANUARY,
                            1895. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION</head><p TEIform="p">The Manifesto is published by the "United Society of Believees" on the first of each month,
                            and is the only work issued regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain
                            and simple statement of the religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of
                            righteousness. Ail communications should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury,
                            Mer. Co., N. H. .75 .40 One copy per year, postage paid " " six months, " "</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. November. Thermometer. Bain. Snow. 1893. 31.2 % in. 3
                                in. 1S;)4. 34. 2&gt;4 " 20 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 58 above 0 L .west " " "
                                " 10 " " Number of rainy days " " 4 " " snowy " " " 11 " " clear " " " 10 " " cloudy " "
                                " 5 C. O. Reed. Center Family. Dec. 1894. We wish to extend to you the Compliments of
                                the Holiday season, almost upon us, wishing the Editor and helpers of The Manifesto much
                                success the coming year in spreading the light of our Church organization. We need
                                helpers to build up and sustain what has been bequeathed us by earnest, faithful and
                                noble souls who gave their all for the cause, not to be squandered, but added thereunto.
                                We have been attacked here at Lebanon, at least some of the people, with the Florida
                                fever; whether or no we shall convalesce before spring, remains to be seen. We learn
                                that our Canterbury friends are prospering in their re-organized condition. This is a
                                day of changes, and if all of ours shall conduce to paramount growth, it will be a cause
                                for thankfulness and gratitude. We are housed for tlie season; ail the crops having been
                                stored in pretty good condition. Brethren are engaged in making medicine for the cure of
                                bodies made sick by wrong living, either through ignorance or willfulness, or both; but
                                no matter which, the medicine is needed just the same. Health of our Society pretty
                                good.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rayson, Timothy" TEIform="persName"/>Timothy Rayson</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. Dec. 1894. Thanksgiving ha's come and gone; that is, the external
                                manifestation of the day, but the time can never pass by when we are not able to render
                                thanksgiving. On Thursday, the 29th of November, we attended a meeting for the special
                                review of the blessings vouchsafed to us the past year. The service was opened by
                                reading the 145th Psalm, and our minds were turned to the contemplation of the thanks-
                                giving that it is our duty to render daily. We have blessed seasons of spiritual com-
                                munion in our weekly Society meetings, for which our hearts respond in gratitude. May we
                                always maintain an interest in these seasons for devotion lor they are the perennial
                                springs from which flow the ministrations that enable the Zion traveler to bear aloft
                                the banner; on this depends his success. The hot air engine for water pumping, has so
                                far proved successful, forcing the water up to the reservoir without any difficulty.
                                Plenty of fresh water is a necessary article in any civilized community, and to be
                                deprived of it, is more than an inconvenience. TERMS. <pb n="18" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 18 THE
                                MANIFESTO. The cycle of the second year has passed | since our advent here; and like the
                                tread , of marshaled hosts, the years come and j go, carrying with them the record of
                                both j the meritorious deeds and those that are | not so worthy. One fact we have
                                discovered—that we carry our individuality with us; there is no escape; and when we
                                arrive at that condition where we stand on Mt. Zion with the perfect overcomers, it must
                                be through the same process, whether our home is in the tropics or in the ice-bound
                                regions of the frigid zone. By the time these Notes appear, the advent of the New Year
                                will have been sounded. May it be one filled with joy to our blessed Gospel relation;
                                may the special blessing of our heavenly Father and Mother rest upon those who are the
                                standard-bearers of the higher life and though they walk in tribulation yet will not
                                lower the standard but proclaim the testimony of Everlasting Life, that all who run, may
                                read.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>Hamilton DeGraw</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Second family" TEIform="index"/>Second Family</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1894. The New Year will soon be ushered in. How quickly the moments pass away when
                                hands and mind are employed in well-doing. It seems but a short time since we began
                                "Notes" for 1894. How the seasons come and go! So it is with humanity. As one steps off
                                the stage another steps on. In consideration of this should it not urge us to well
                                improve our day and time not know, ing how soon the reaper will call us home. The light
                                patches of snow here and there, declare the commencing reign of winter, but if we have
                                stored in provisions for the occasion, we shall be numbered with the wise virgins. Our
                                creamery that we started last spring is proving a success, and a decided improvement on
                                the old system. The only trouble is to keep supply equal to demand# We hail all our
                                gospel kindred with kindly greetings. The aged in Zion our fathers and mothers, those in
                                full vigor of manhood and womanhood, the youth and children. We wish you one and all a
                                happy New Year. May the blessings of God and an innumerable company of angels be with us
                                all the coming year.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anstatt, Isaac" TEIform="persName"/>Isaac Anstatt</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1894. To the mandates of time the seasons have rendered Perfect obedience, the
                                autumn has gone, The cold breath of winter now forward hath ventured Silenced the notes
                                of the forest-bird's song. The fields are all bare, trees stripped of their verdure,
                                Save here and there stands a lone evergreen, The rivulets yield to the dictates of
                                Mature, Their murmurs are hushed by an ice-bound chain. Winter has come to stay. Its
                                first monition caught us rather unprepared, but the snow was light and soon left. So we
                                came out all right with nothing harmed. Old zero, after several approaches, came upon us
                                the morning of the 5th inst. but we had taken his hints and were well prepared, so there
                                was no mischief done. At present writing we are having splendid weather, Fifteen
                                carpenters keep the air resonant with their hammers making lively work with shingles and
                                clapboards, the painters following on with paint and brush. Appearances now are that we
                                shall soon have a barn. We assembled Thanksgiving day and with grateful hearts, and
                                united prayers, gave thanks for the blessing of health in our Society, and that the
                                fates dealt so lightly with us in our recent loss by fire. The spirit of care and
                                watchfulness was ministered to us, that we may be spared a repetition of our sad
                                experience. We closed Thanksgiving in the tangible manner of reducing three fat turkeys
                                to skeletons. Our dear Eldress Maria Foster is suffering from an attack of tonsilitis.
                                We hope the worst is over and she will soon be in health again. Time has hurried us on
                                to the month of kindly greetings and good wishes. With <pb n="19" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                MANIFESTO. 19 sincere and true hearts we wish all and every one an enjoyable Christmas
                                and a happy New Year.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bullard, Marcia M." TEIform="persName"/>Marcia M. Bullard</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1894. We stand on the threshold of the New Year. Let us review the twelve months
                                just passed away. One moment, one hour, one day at a time, they have gone, just as the
                                coming year will go. The past year was made up of thousands of little items, and thus
                                will the sum of our whole life be made up. We can not go back to repair aught that was
                                amiss; to improve opportunities neglected; to correct injuries done. But knowing wherein
                                we have failed, we may in the future shun that which was wrong in the past. Every honest
                                heart must admit that the highest satisfaction and joy has come from duty well done, of
                                burdens patiently borne, of temptations to evil resisted, of opportunities of doin;jj
                                good gladly embraced. There are many who would, if they could, recall the selfish
                                feeling of which they have been faulty, the unkind word, the ungenerous act. All that we
                                can do to atone for the past is to avoid committing errors in future, and make the New
                                Year one of happiness and joy. So let us begin with the determination to look to God for
                                our strength and our guidance determined to persevere to the end of the race and lend a
                                helping hand to all within our reach. The corrupting habit of using slang words and
                                expressions is demoralizing. It destroys refinement, self-respect, respect for others,
                                and does injury to the gospel cause. Those "who name the name of Christ" should
                                carefully watch against this evil. Such are some of the "idle words," against which we
                                are warned in the forcible language of Scripture. A spirit of purity and Christian love
                                pervades each number of The Manifesto, and none, we think, can carefully read it without
                                being better for the p Tusal. It tells how to make life pure, peaceful and pleasant. An
                                invaluable journal and one which we trust, will find many t &gt; re id, to ponder
                                anJ give heed to its wise suggestions. ******* Celery, onions and turnips, chopped and
                                mixed with bran, oats, meat and mitk and fed hut, make an excellent morning ration for
                                liL-ns. Buckwheat or wheat and apples at noon; corn and cabbage ;it niglit. In setting
                                hens it is important to provide dry earth or some substitute in the bottom of the nest.
                                While the hen leaves the nest, dirt or sod will retain the heat under the eggs. Food
                                should be placed where the hen may supply her need without absenting herself too long
                                from the eggs.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1894. A happy New Year to all our gospel friends! News is scarce this month and
                                items "few and far between." We have commenced the manufacture of eight hundred Eclipse
                                Corn Planters; the iron work is delivered to us all finished and ready to be arranged
                                into the complete machine. The hard wood frames and the seed hoppers are made from our
                                own lumber and by our own people. There are twentyfour nails, forty screws, and about
                                twentyfive bolts to be placed in each machine. Some of the screws have to be adjusted
                                very carefully, which requires a precision on the part of those who do this portion of
                                the work. We are quite fortunate in having this employment during the win- ter season,
                                as it is quite a help in a financial way, although we do not consider the remuneration
                                we receive is any more than adequate. Many of the old maple trees that have so long
                                stood guard over the street that passes through our village, have at last yielded to the
                                "woodman's ax," because of decay and broken limbs. <pb n="20" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 20 THE
                                MANIFESTO. We are pleased with the decision of the Central Ministry in regard to the use
                                of the organ in our worship. The more beautiful our praise, the more acceptable in God's
                                sight. Let us use it as not abusing it. Mascoma Lake is solidly frozen and covered with
                                snow: this shows to us that winter has begun in earnest.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kirkley, G. H." TEIform="persName"/>G. H. Kirkley</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Alfred, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1894. My vessel is tilled with love, My heart with affection o'eiflows, With mercy
                                that comes from above Anr\ blessing the Gospel bestows. O Charity, best of all gifts,
                                Never failing in casting out fear. Good friends, in the Spirit, I wish you A cheerful
                                and happy Xew Year. As the New Year dawns upon us, what are our plans and promises? Have
                                we resolved to be more fully consecrated and wholly devoted to the service of God? If
                                so, let us hold steadfast to the good resolve all through the year. If we love God, we
                                shall love our fellow creatures, and charity will abound in our hearts. I feel there is
                                no better way to show our gratitude to God for the many blessings and mercies bestowed
                                upon us in the past year, than by living just such lives as He would have us to live
                                during the year that has just begun. To this end may we all strive. Winter seems to have
                                set in, in good earnest. Our teams for a week past have been hauling cord wood. The
                                abundant apple crop brings extra labor with it, as they have to be handled over several
                                times. Those that would not do to sell or keep, we have made into preserves'. We have
                                2(30 two-quart jars filled with apple, which will be ready for use another year, should
                                the apple crop be small. To gospel kindred far and near, we give our love and blessing
                                as a New Year's gift.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Casey, Fannie" TEIform="persName"/>Fannie Casey</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South Union, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>South Union, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 29, 1894. Thanksgiving day at South Union. The air is clear and calm, and the sky
                                looks serenely blue. It is one of those mornings long to be remembered. We are in good
                                trim for a holiday. The sheds are filled with well-seasoned stove wood, and the corn is
                                all husked and cribbed, and the vegetables and tubers are safely stored away for winter
                                use. Although the summer and fall had been unusually dry, our wells gave an abundant
                                supply of good, fresh water, and the springs and creeks boiled up and meandered over
                                their gravelly beds with as musical an air as if there had been a fresh shower every
                                other day, so we might well exclaim with the Psalmist of old Palestine, "Give thanks
                                unto the Lord, for his mercy endureth forever." In the midst of our reverie, the big
                                bell peals out its silvery tones to summon us to Service. Our worship consisted of
                                singing and prayer, and an address by one of the Brethren which was befitting the
                                occasion. We rendered praise and thanksgiving, bearing in remembrance the devout and
                                valiant hearted Brethren and Sisters who established a Society in this place that we
                                might enjoy the benefits of a Communal home. When the hour of twelve came, there were
                                just iifty of us who sat down to that Thanksgiving dinner. The viands on that table were
                                both rich and savory; the big bronzed turkeys being distributed about, showed most
                                prominently to the eye, but your humble scribe is a lover of other good things which did
                                not materialize, in the line of cranberries and baked beans.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Carr, James" TEIform="persName"/>James Carr</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="White Water, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>White Water, O.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1894. We are having rain at present after an exceedingly long drought. We have had
                                some rains lately, but not sufficient to revive the spring. I suppose four-fifths of the
                                wells in our country here are dry. We had a hundred-foot-well, drove, which has about
                                fifteen feet of water in it, which will furnish us all the water we <pb n="21" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 21 need, and will be no doubt a never failing supply.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bear, H. B." TEIform="persName"/>H. B. Bear</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North family" TEIform="index"/>North Family</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1894. I am writing a few Notes for The Manifesto, trusting they will be acceptable.
                                What a beautiful little book it is. We all look forward to its coming with a great deal
                                of pleasure. You can hear on all sides, "Has The Manifesto come yet?" we are all so
                                eager to receive it. We have had a bountiful crop this year, excepting corn which
                                yielded only a little more than half a crop on account of the drought; still we are not
                                complaining, as God our Father, will amply provide for us all. At the Center family,
                                they have just completed drilling an old well near the cow-barn. After working at it for
                                several days and drilling down over one hundred feet, they at last struck water. They
                                intend to put in a new wind-mill as a much needed necessity, for they were compelled to
                                drive their cows to the creek for water. We send our love to all in our Zion homes. What
                                beautiful words those are. O.ir Zion homes. Not for one, but for all. We wish you a
                                merry Christmas and a hiippy New Year.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dixon, Charles E." TEIform="persName"/>Charles R. Dixon</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury, N. H</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1894. It is a beautiful thought, a happy realization, that we still live for a good
                                purpose,—that of making ourselves and others better agents in the strife to help make
                                the earth a paradise, hoping and praying and best of all doing, which is the only source
                                of life, whether good or evil. He who does not work, does not act, is dead; yea, worse
                                than dead. He is an incumbrance, forever in the way of others who have an interest in
                                life and would work to secure its blessing. The idler is a drone, subsisting upon the
                                labors of others, continually impeding progress. He is a pest, a poison to society
                                associated for mutual profit and usefulness, and a gossiper, leaving garbage to burden
                                others to take care of. It would give me great pleasure to pre~ sent Notes for the New
                                Year that would be to our friends a thanksgiving feast. Winter has opened with an
                                uncommonly low temperature of weather, with the springs of water exceedingly low,
                                threatening a famine unless blest with rain. The earth lies bare of snow, a condition
                                especially worrisome to the farmer as he plans how to be able to accomplish his duties
                                of the winter with any degree of ease. We hope ever to be remembered and blest with
                                needful supplies sufficient for the comfort of life. To our many friends we tender the
                                compliments of the season, with congratulations for the many blessings vouchsafed
                                temporally and spiritually, abounding in love, peace and happiness. Abraham Perkins. The
                                variety of corn used for ensilage was tie Early Sanford sweet corn. This is not a
                                wrinkled corn, but seems like a cross between a variety of sweet and the common yellow
                                corn. This may or may not be the case. The ears are not large, but remarkably well
                                filled with good sized kernels. It was used as green corn and pronounced very sweet and
                                tender. It proved not only a rank grower, but also a prolific yielder, 437 bushels being
                                harvested from the 5 acres designed for ensilage. The stalks were not so large as those
                                of some southern varieties, but this difference was overcome by their height and the
                                luxuriant growth of leaves well down to the ground. The amount of seed per acre was 16
                                quarts. Of this piece 2}., acres were old land, having been used for fodder corn for a
                                series of years. The remainder was newly stocked and well covered with a stout growth of
                                clover. The whole piece was manured at the rate of 15 loads per acre and plowed under.
                                The planting was done with an Eclipse Planter in drills S}.i feet apart, the kernels
                                being 3 or 4 inches apart in the drills. At the time of planting commercial fer<pb n="22" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 21 THE MANIFESTO. tilizer was applied at the rate of 200 lbs. per
                                acre. On the old land the seed was planted too deep and most of it rotted This was
                                replanted two weeks later, this time in hills 2 feet apart and the rows 3 feet. At the
                                time of cutting there was no perceptible difference between the fodder on this part and
                                that on the new land but the yield of matured ears was J^ less. Another experience with
                                this corn may be of interest. Thinking to supply our cows with green fodder in the late
                                summer as the pastures became dry we planted % acre in drills 3 feet apart on land used
                                the previous year for potatoes and at that time dressed with 20 loads of manure. Tliis
                                piece matured very early and from it were gathered 76 bushels of ears of very fine corn.
                                We are using some of this corn as cobmeal for our milch cows and like it very much. The
                                rest of the crop has been sold for seed. We are unable to supply the demand.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bruce, Arthur" TEIform="persName"/>Arthur Bruce</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="White pansy" TEIform="index"/>THE WHITE PANSY</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Hopkins, Albert C." TEIform="persName"/>Albert C. Hopkins</byline><p TEIform="p">"In the name of our God, we will set up our banner." This is the promise of the Psalmist and
                            the promise of Christendom. How are we keeping it? What is "our banner?" What is it
                            literally, and what does it represent? It is now generally understood to be the banner of
                            the cross, and to represent the salvation of humanity through Christianity. It must be
                            acknowledged, however, that now, and for several hundred years, the cross represents and has
                            represented, to a considerable part of the human family, aggression, persecution and war.
                            Even to a large part of the Christian world, it represents, by reason of its association,
                            the intolerance of the Inquisition. This being true and it being further true that in its
                            original significance it represents punishment and ignominious death, it is therefore open
                            to grave doubt that it is the best banner under which to advance the universal fellowship of
                            the human family and unity the world. Obviously, the banner under which to rally all true
                            Christians and all true followers of every faith, is one that will fully and conspicuously
                            represent the character of the true Messiah, the gentleness and love that are his
                            predominant characteristics, and that shall be relieved of any associations that will, in
                            any degreee, mar that full signiiicance. Manifestly, the cross can not now do this. Even
                            more manifestly, the white pansy can and will. The pansy or heart1 sease, is the one full
                            and true floral representation of thought, which is the meaning of its common name. It is
                            the gentlest and most loving of flowers, and represents the largest and truest fellowship of
                            any flower of the world, uniting in itself, by its loving fellowship and adaptation, all the
                            characteristics and colors of all flowers. While it is, therefore, as its name in- directly
                            implies, the all-flower, it is well known that white, the color of pure light, is the
                            all-color, and thus the white pansy is the most conspicuously fit symbol of pure, loving and
                            peaceful thoughts, of perfect beauty and complete union, in the world. The floral world is,
                            by common consent, the truest expression of the beauty, gentleness and love of God, and the
                            white pansy is, plainly, the true leader of the floral world, in that it most truly and
                            largely represents these ideals. Put this white, blue-eyed pansy in the centre of a fair
                            blue field that represents a peaceful sky, and you have the true banner of the true Messiah
                            of the earth, the brightest and most helpful emblem of the love, the gentle thought and life
                            that still, forever, save the world. This gives us the flower as the emblem, with the motto:
                            Passionate Purity, Full Fellowship and Perfect Peace, and in a blue field, the full banner
                            of the All-loving unity of human life. Canton, South Dakota.</p></div2><pb n="23" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sincerity" TEIform="index"/>SINCERITY</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Rullhausen, Belle" TEIform="persName"/>Belle Rullhausen</byline><p TEIform="p">"Be sincere, though your sincerity should cost you your life."-----Asiatic Proverb. Among the
                            numerous wise sayings, that have come to us from the Orient, there can not be many that
                            contain more good advice in so few words than the foregoing. When we analyze the word
                            sincerity with reference to its spiritual meaning, we find it to be a combination of truth
                            and uprightness the two foundation principles of a Christian life; it would be as consistent
                            to erect a house upon sand as to try to build up a Christ-like character without these
                            essential qualities. When we review the lives of some of the ancient teachers and
                            philosophers, we are forced to exclaim, how deep was that sincerity which held them to their
                            convictions of right, even in the face of death. It is recorded of Mohammed that sincerity
                            was one of his marked characteristics, and nothing could induce him to abandon an exalted
                            principle which he had once embraced. As an illustration of his devotedness to a principle
                            or to a God-directed mission, let us recall his words to those who endeavored to dissuade
                            him from promulgating his faith among the people; he said; "It is a faith approved by God,
                            and he has appointed me to be its apostle; if the world should put the sun in my right hand
                            and the moon in my left, and give me the whole earth, I could not disobey the commands of
                            God;" neither could he be led aside from his convictions, but in sincerity of soul he rose
                            above physical and adverse circumstances and accepted death as preferable to disobedience.
                            While we realize that sincerity is an important and beautiful quality, yet we know that it
                            is as often found among the ignorant as well as the spiritually enlightened, and unless it
                            is coupled with the wisdom and light of God, it often impedes progressive thought and
                            development. Many through great sincerity, blindly fellow after and cling tenaciously to
                            false doctrines, in preference to thnt which is purer and better and in every respect more
                            desirable. We are told in the Scriptures that in doctrine we should show "uncorruptness,
                            gravity and sincerity;" hence we clearly see, that it is well to seek the wisdom that
                            discerns the false from the true, that we may never uphold a cause that is not worthy of the
                            purest and most sincere devotions of our souls. As individuals awake into a deeper love for
                            the Divine, their lives will become more sincere, deceit and hypocrisy will find no place,
                            and their constant motto will be, "Be sincere though your sincerity should cost you your
                            life." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The time for making good resolutions..." TEIform="index"/>The time for making good resolutions...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">,,The time for making good resolutions for the new year is already past; but the time for
                            keeping good resolutions is still open. It is only as the influence of new year's
                            resolutions is operative on the remainder of the year that there is any special gain from
                            such resolutions." "Pkejudice may be considered as a continual false medium of viewing
                            things, for prejudiced persons not only never speak well, but also never think well of those
                            whom they dislike, and the whole character and conduct is considered with an eye to that
                            particular thing which offends them." "Every man is a tamer of wild-beasts, and these wild
                            beasts are his passions. To draw their teeth and claws, to muzzle and tame them, to turn
                            them into servants and domestic animals, fuming, perhaps, but submissive—in this consists
                            personal education."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ferries, Elizabeth" TEIform="index"/>Elizabeth Ferries
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Ferries, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName">Elizabeth Ferries</persName>, at South family, Mt.
                                Lebanon, N. Y. July 27, 1894. Age 67 yrs. and 5 mo.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Carpenter, Catharine" TEIform="index"/>Catharine Carpenter
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Carpenter, Catharine" TEIform="persName">Catharine Carpenter</persName>, at White Water, O.
                                Nov. 19, 1894. Age 75 yrs. 8 mo. and 1 days.</p></div3></div2><pb n="24" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                THE PHRENOLOGICAL JOURNAL AND SCIENCE of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">THE PHRENOLOGICAL JOURNAL AND SCIENCE of Health for December contain.-, a variety of
                                excellent features. The frontispiece allows thirty-six intelligent faces, comprising the
                                graduating eUus of the Phrenological Institute for 1894. Character studies of Archbishop
                                Corrigan and Dr. O. W. Holmes, by Dr. Edgar C. Beall, with fine portraits will attract
                                attention among Catholics and admirers of the deceased poet. Prof. Sizer continues his
                                interesting series, How to Study Strangers; and Mrs. Wells reviews the life of a
                                phrenological philanthropist. The bx-illiant lecture by Prof. J. S. Van Cleve upon
                                musicians and poets is concluded with fascinating sketches of Whittier, Cowper, Byron,
                                Burns, Holmes and James Whitconib Kiley. Much instructive and etertaining matter will
                                also be found in the reports of the closing addresses of the Institute faculty. The
                                department of Child Culture and Hygiene are exceptionally good, and the editor devotes
                                several pages to Clairvoyance and four "graduates" of the Elmira Reformatory. Price, 15
                                cents, $1. 50 a year. Address The Fowler &amp; Wells Co., 27 East 21st St., New
                                York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of hygeio-therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy. December. Contents. Foundation Principles;
                                Vegetarianism; Anti-Vaccination; Pasteur and Hydrophobia; Editorial; The Pride of the
                                Companj¦¦; The Temperature of the Body; Health Schools; etc., etc, Dr 1. V. Clifford and
                                Co. Kokomo, Ind. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Theatre" TEIform="index"/>The Theatre
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Theatre,—is a harmless little pamphlet of some eighty-live pages.
                                We do not wish you to go into the theatre, but rather to go through this book in careful
                                consideration, and possibly you may gain some new points of information. It is published
                                by H. L. Hastings, 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass. The writer of this little work is
                                evidently fully persuaded in the mission he has taken upon himself and enters it with a
                                zeal that is highly commendable. Believing that the theatre is prejudicial to the life
                                interests of the Christian and exerts a baneful influence over the minds of all classes,
                                lie not only comes forward with a personal protest, but brings with him a formidable
                                array of witnesses who through actual experience or from observation believe that the
                                play houses and theatres are no less than "the gates of hell." The author next enters
                                the churches and handles the Christians without gloves. This gate way to heaven has its
                                church "guild" and pool tables, and billiard tables, and fancy dress balls with
                                theatricals and bacchanalian songs, all brought in to obtain a little money with which
                                to convict the poor heathen. Send for "The Theatre" and ascertain the position you
                                occupy for the good of humanity. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dictionary of United States' history" TEIform="index"/>Dictionary of United States' History
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Jameson, J. Franklin" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Dictionary of United States' History by .). Franklin
                                Jameson, Ph. D. Illustrated with nearly 300 portraits, and published by the Pu- ritan
                                Publishing Co. This beautiful volume of nearly 700 pages need only to be seen to he
                                appreciated. It goes out from the Publishers as a valuable work for the student, in that
                                its many departments are so fully tilled with essential information especially for those
                                who are devoted to historical studies. The type is large and clear, the paper of
                                excellent quality and the binding is substantial. An attractive feature of the Book is
                                the large number of portraits to be found on its pages. It also makes a very
                                companionable book as ready reference can be had with so large an amount of the history
                                of the United States. —The quaint little women of Kate Greenaway are to be seen in a
                                magazine for the first time since their creation. Miss Greenaway has heretofore always
                                drawn them in color and for book publication. Now, however, she is at work, upon a
                                special series of her curious tots for The Ladies' Home Journal, and in that periodical
                                they will alternate with a new series of Palmer Cox's funny "Brownies." THE COLUMBIA
                                DESK CALENDER. Fok ten years the desk calendar issued by the Pope Manufacturing Company
                                has held a unique place among business helpers. Each daily leaf during that time has
                                taught its quiet lesson of the value of better roads and outdoor exercise, and
                                especially the benefits of bicycling. The calendar for 1895, which is just issued, is
                                even brighter than its predecessors in appearance, as clever artists have added dainty
                                silhouette and sketch to the usual wise and witty contributions that have heretofore
                                given this popular calendar its charm. It can be had for five 2-cent stamps from the
                                Pope Manufacturing Company, Hartford, Conn., or from any Columbia bicycle agency.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="You will find as you look back upon your life that..." TEIform="index"/>
                                You will find as you look back upon your life that...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"You will find as you look back upon your life that the moments that stand out, the
                                moments when you have really lived, are the moments when you have done something in a
                                spirit of love. As memory scans the past, above and beyond all the transitory pleasures
                                of life, there leap forward those supreme hours when you have been enabled to do
                                unnoticed kindnesses to those l-ound about you, things too trifling to speak of, which
                                you feel have entered into your eternal life."</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind words produce their own image in men's souls, and a beautiful image it is" TEIform="index"/>
                                Kind words produce their own image in men's souls, and a beautiful image it is
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Kind words produce their own image in men's souls, and a beautiful image it is.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pascal" TEIform="persName"/>Pascal.</byline></div3></div2><!-- 
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>