<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2509" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">25</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><date value="18950901" TEIform="date">September 1895</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">195-218</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="25" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
SEPTEMBER.
THE
MANIFESTO
PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES.
VOL. XXV
'' Cast thy bread tjpoh the waters ; for thou shalt find it after many days."
Eccl. XI.-1.
East Canterbury, N. H.
1895.
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
Til E MA NIFE S TO.
CONTEXTS.
Yiitue, Our Stronghold.
Scenes & McmOl i '-,
Kid m- J >hn Lyon,
Keliaiue,
Democracy,
Peace,
Lett-er,John \Vhitel"y,
Miinhoo.l,               ......
Judging,     - - - - -Faith,       -......
Mysterious 1'rovi ience,
I\Iu>ie,A hiding Hope,      Notes A bout Home,
Sanitary,         .......
Life's Mission,
We Arc Building,
He was an F. litor,
A   Railroa ier'o Prayer,
Life,         Books & Papers,         ....
' Good reliable ti
our    Choice    si
Nursery Stock m
Trees, Roses Sin
Li dies ii ake thi  bn.-n a me
cess,
able,
ences
ter, '.
tita
en, to sell
nl Hardy
eli fs Fruit
ibs.au.i Ornt'.-";- a sue Easy work, ],1 ...-astint, light and profitCuti.it Fkej;. A piJy i.toncr, v,itb icffi, ail'1 secure choice of t"rritorv.
serymfii   and   Seecl
NT. Y.
AGENTS
Salary of commission to <jood men.
Funt sellinc/ Imported Specialties.
Stock failing: to live replaced free,
 WMWM
Also Pure Seed Potato Stock our Leader
"Lincoln," (480 bu, per acre past season
Address  R. D. LUTGHFORD &  GO.,
iVCJOEtS ERYMEW.
(Letters jrromptly answered.)   ROCHESTER, "H. Y.
THE DIVINE APPLATUS,
A.
FORCE IN HISTORY.     ,
Price, 10 cts*
CA\ I ORTATN A PATENT? Fora
prompt answer and an honest opinion, write to
niUNN tfc CO., wholisive hnd nearly fifty years'
experience in the patent business. Communications strictly confidential. A II andbook of Information concerning: Pntenls and how to obtain them seTit free. Also a catalogue of mechanical and scientific books pent free.
Patents taken tlironch Mimn & Co. receive
special notice in the Scifii'tilic Amevionii, and
thus are trouslit widely before the public without cost to the inventor. This splendid paper,
issued weekly, elesantly illustrated, has by far the
largest circulation of any scientific work in the
world.   S3 a year.   Sample copies sent free.
Building Edition.monthly, $2.50 a year. Single
copies, 'in cents. Kvery unrulier contains beautiful piates, in colors, ami pl'otopnipl's of new
houses, with plans, enabling builders to show the
latest designs and secure contracts.   Address
MiJiNN & CO.. New York. ;iiil BeoidwAT.
Everybody knows "Paul Itevere's Riile,'"!
but what else did lie ever do? The "Die!
tionary of United States History'" tells.:
This standard reference book is iirrantrei'
alphabetically, and contains short, crisp,
eon<;ise,h:comprelionsive information. >.boutj
;every event in American history, andi
about the man who made the events. Jt
{tells at a glance what "would take hours of!
research in other books. It fills a place in
bookdom that was wholly vacant before it
came. It is needed in every home am!
library, by writers, teacher.-, preachers,;
|and laymen. Our author, J. Franklin
'.Jameson,'Ph. D., Professor of History of
'Brown University, formerly of Johns Hopkins University...
AfMMWI can make more sales with less talk
AtfiflHiM and less walking with this book
;ihan with anything else they ever sold. It
.appeals to everybody. It is' hf.ndsome, eir
itertaining- and useful. It is good for every
niernber of the familyuseful alike to
Ischoolhoy and grandpa. Write for circuilars and terms to
Puritan Publishing Co.,
!                   36BrpmfieldSt.,   BoatoD, Mass
The'ordinary pot is Sometimes hot"to
lift, as, well-as always heavy, and sometimes the liquor splashes. You can not
tell exactly when, it will start, for the tipping must vary with the quantity in the
pot. Sometimes it is%ard to avoid getting too much and "pouring over;" sometimes it is hard to get enough. Is it/not
delightful to be delivered from all this?
See "acZ?;." on another page.
WANTED
! >.",
IT
] S
l'.l
id i
-il.'l
2(14
2 5
I 11
: 1.5
2i(j
217
Zl'--><pb n="195" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Virtue, our stronghold" TEIform="index"/>VIRTUE, OUR STRONGHOLD.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>By Martha J. Anderson.</byline><p TEIform="p">BRAVE conquerors, for so you are who war against your own affections, and the huge army of
                            the world's desires."Shakespeare. Is there conquest more glorious, or hope more exulting
                            than that which springs from consciousness of having triumphed over the weaknesses,
                            infirmities and affections of the merely animal man and woman? Human nature in the
                            ascendency still pleads for inferior enjoyment, and keeps the soul under the bondage of
                            sense on the plane of selfishness and illusion; the inspiration to climb is thwarted by the
                            impulse that draws back to gross elements ; and humanity vainly lift their hands in mute
                            appeal for help, as they struggle to be free from the ancestral slough and slime of
                            animalism. In the progress of material things we seem to have reached the pinnacle of
                            greatness; in intellectual development, art, science and literature, there has been
                            wonderful achievements. These may glorify a nation in the eyes of the world, as they did
                            Greece and Rome, but what of their prestige? They fell a prey to the corruption of vice,
                            which insidiously wormed its way through their high state of civilization, until it fell
                            like a building in decay. When the moral sense slumbers, and mankind turn their greatest
                            gifts to minister to selfish enjoyment, and their highest ideals are subverted to
                            sensualism, then retrogression takes the place of progression, and the people perish for
                            lack of wisdom and moral stamina. He who lives to serve the body, fails to derive the
                            pleasure he seeks. Hedonism is extolled in our time as it was in the days of Aristippus for,
                            like the pleasure-loving Greeks, modern society, represented by an affluent aristocracy and
                            plutocracy, welcomes all that panders to gross self-interest, nor cares to be schooled in
                            virtue and heroic self-denial. Inordinate desire for that which stirs and stimulates the
                            emotional centers of the being, yields SEMPTEMBER, <pb n="196" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 196 THE MANIFESTO.
                            as a final harvest of seed-sowing to the carnal life, the fruit of sin, which is death to
                            the spiritual nature. "For she that liveth in pleasure is dead while she liveth." The whole
                            tendency of our present high style of living is rapid development in passional desire. The
                            constraint of conventionalism is not the restraint of absolute virtue; and it often occurs
                            that the greatest moral lepers are the lionized leaders in social circles, because of claims
                            to wealth, learning or high ancestral lineage. Behold how many wrecks of human lives, of
                            blasted hopes, and sudden changes of fortune ; and what a mockery of human happiness is
                            presented in the sexual and marital relations of life! The helots of Sparta were not under
                            greater servitude physically, than is man spiritually when under the bondage of the flesh,
                            whose insinuations disarm reason and transform love to lust; in its perversion many sink
                            themselves below the brute creation. The results of unrestricted sensualism are visible
                            among all classes of society; "the sins of the fathers (and the errors of the mothers) are
                            visited upon their children even unto the third and fourth geneiation." Erotic impulses are
                            stamped upon the offspring of those who obey not the law of God written in their being; and
                            how often parents fondly imagine that their children are innocent, when they are indulging
                            in secret ruinous vices, destroying physical health and mental vigor. There is wisdom in
                            well-timed advice and watchful care on the part of those assuming the responsibilities of
                            parentage. Who are filling to such an alarming extent our prisons, insane, idiotic and
                            cataleptic asylums? mainly those in whose veins flows the virus of inherited or acquired
                            pollution, which takes away the power of will and moral resistance. The pabulum and essence
                            of life's accretive forces may be heaven directed for the strengthening of every virtue, or
                            hell inflamed for the production of every vice. All sin and error have their beginnings in
                            that mysterious tree of life whose branches ramify through all our nature, and whose sap
                            flows through every fibre of our being ; and while man is governed by the impulses that
                            minister to his lower nature, he poisons the streams of existence and brings untold misery
                            on future generations. Many wrongs and discords in families, societies and nations are
                            directly traceable to the influence of the untamed passions of human nature, resulting in
                            brute force"Whence come wars and fightings among you? come they not hence, even of your
                            lusts that war in your members ?" "First pure, then peaceable," is the law of the spiritual
                            life; hence there can be no harmonious action among human beings, associated either for the
                            administration of civil law and justice, for social benefit or for mutual helpfulness,
                            unless morality is the basis of their operations; for self-ism is the root of the deadly
                            upas tree that yields the baneful fruits of disintegration and disorganization. <pb n="197" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 197 "Neither the natural, the animal, nor the human can give
                            hope to man; but when with weary and blood-stained feet he climbs up to the Divine, he
                            begins to learn the story of life and the secret of power." While humanity relegate love to
                            the sensuous passion we shall have no higher estimate of its expression than that which
                            flows through animal desire, physical magnetism, sex atti action and the manifestations of
                            endearment and affection that essentially pertain to the expression of natural impulse ; but
                            are often repulsive and disgusting to those who feel and realize that thought exchange and
                            divine soul touch, need no gushing or external demonstration of attachment or appreciation
                            of relationship. We communicate what we possess, and carry with us the aura of our spiritual
                            conditions and states, to bless or to blight those who come in our atmosphere. Living to
                            express the highest and best that we are capable of attaining unto, brings the greatest
                            degree of unalloyed pleasure. Love that is the result of the harmonious blending of mental
                            and spiritual endowments, is expressed in ethical culture and co-operative labor on the high
                            plane of universal interest and devotion, not alone to the offspring of earthly desire, but
                            to all mankind. "All souls are mine saith the Lord." And the more God-like we become the
                            broader will be the sphere of our affections, and the more extended the exercise of our
                            capabilities in doing good. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scenes and memories" TEIform="index"/>SCENES AND MEMORIES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>By Oliver C. Hampton.</byline><p TEIform="p">ON the first day of January of the year 1805 John Meacham, Benjamin S. Youngs and Issachar
                            Bates set out on a journey to Kentucky and Ohio. They were members of the Shaker Church at
                            New Lebanon, N. Y. Their object and mission was to visit the subjects of a very remarkabl
                            revival of religion then prevalent in Kentucky and several adjacent states. This revival had
                            continued without abatement for about four years, and perhaps the history of the world is
                            unabl to produce a more wonderful spiritual awakening. The Brethren came out to ascertain
                            whether these revivalists were ready to embrace the faith and doctrine of the Shakers. As
                            the revival had spent much of its former force and many had already fallen back into the
                            dreary formalities of religion; with little divine power, and none at all in comparison to
                            what they had so lately experienced, they were to a great extent disappointed. A large
                            number of them, among whom were several able divines, had already separated themselvs from,
                            and severed their connection with, the Presbyterian church and had banded themselvs together
                            in what they calld a New-Light movement; a kind of "Go as you please" or as the spirit
                            dictated policy and plan, without any visibl leadership. They were stil unsatisfied and many
                            of them embraced the faith, doctrines and discipline promulgated by the Shaker missionaries.
                                <pb n="198" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 198 THE MANIFESTO. A nucleus of these formd themselvs into a kind
                            of spiritual fraternity at Union Village, without any systematic arrangement or regular
                            Church organization, but under the direction and spiritual care of those Shaker
                            missionaries. This condition lasted some years, the members of this embryotic Church living
                            in their own private families as many as were married, and receiving many young and
                            unmarried persons who, though not related, had embraced the faith. Malcolm Worley, Matthew
                            Houston, John Dunlavy, Richard McNemar, David Spinning, Stephen Spinning, Jacob Holloway,
                            Amos Valentine, and James Smith with th.4r wives, and a vast number more of the revivalists
                            and others embraced the doctrine and faith of the Shakers, so that in a few years the Church
                            at Union Village numb 3rd between six and seven hundred members. Union Village, O.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder John Lyon, first paper" TEIform="index"/>ELDER JOHN LYON. First Paper.</head><p TEIform="p">A few incidents in the early life of Elder John Lyon, confind particularly to his entrance
                            into, and progress in the work of "Christ's Second Appearing1'' and to the various
                            communications of divine light, thru supernatural agency, beginning at early childhood. I
                            WAS born October, 1780, in the town of Shrewsbury, County of Worcester and State of Mass. My
                            parents receivd faith in the testimony of Christ's Second Appearing, and in March, 1785,
                            they embraced the gospel of self-denial, having a family of four children, two boys and two
                            girls. I was the second child and about four years and five months old. Nothing very
                            remarkabl took place at this time, only that as I had been educated thus far in childish
                            vanity, when this change came I felt it severely. As soon as my parents renounct the
                            principls of the world they began to teach me the simpl manners and language of Believers.
                            Altho I was so young, yet when I was required to lay aside my sirs and misters, and uze the
                            simpl yea and nay, it became very difficult to express it. I must now refer to an experience
                            I had about six months before my parents determind to obey their faith. In the latter part
                            of the summer of 1784, a man by the name of Jonathan Wood calld at my father's house, whom I
                            afterward learnd was a Believer, or what sum peple calld, a Shaker, tho at that time there
                            was no special difference of dress or of any outward appearance from peple generally to
                            attract my attention. Br. Jonathan asked my mother for a drink of water; to obtain this she
                            went to the spring, and while she was gone an unaccountabl impression filld my mind. Such
                            luv and affection toward the man came upon me as I never felt for any person, my parents not
                            excepted. <pb n="199" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 199 My mother soon returnd with the water and
                            Jonathan seemed much refresht. Conversation ensued in which my mother became uncommonly
                            anxious and earnest, and a warm argument followd. I saw that it was with ease that the man
                            would confound her in every objection which she brought forward, altho she had an extensiv
                            resource to the Scriptures, for support on her side. He made use of her weapons as wel as of
                            other Scriptures to corroborate the truth of his statement and to cast all her objections
                            into the shade. This pleased my childish mind to see her so easily defeated, altho she was
                            my own dear Mother. From early date to the present time I hav rememberd, not only the
                            Scripture texts which they uzed in their arguments, but hav retaind the feeling which was at
                            that time imprest upon me. It has remaind with me even thru all my hours of temptation and
                            trial. When anything has been brought forward either in my own mind or from any other
                            source, against the testimony of Believers, I always accepted it as my privilege to defend
                            it. Since I came to years of understanding it has been my impression, that at that time sum
                            good work was wrought in me by the Spirit, tho I was too young to know much about religion.
                            From 1785 to 1795 there was no circumstance worthy of note. I often felt peculiar spiritual
                            impz'essions, of which I could hav but very litl understanding, and I also took great
                            satisfaction in listening to the testimonies and meditating on the words, even if I did not
                            fully understand them. In June, 1795, being then in the fifteenth year of my age, I
                            experienced a remarkabl spirit manifestation which, I consider, was on account of the
                            situation I was in, and the state of my rnind at that time. It was soon after sum families
                            had joined the faith, and before order had been establisht, and but litl protection offerd
                            for the young. Some were drawing back to perdition or returning to their former standing in
                            the world. I was now brought under very severe temptation, and shown the glowing pleasures
                            of the world in their many beautiful shapes, which I as often repudiated, tho not without
                            meditating upon and arguing the points presented. It is one of these scenes of temptation
                            which I am about to relate. (To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reliance" TEIform="index"/>RELIANCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Staples, Lydia" TEIform="persName"/>By Lydia Staples.</byline><p TEIform="p">As lifts the lily's snowy cup To drink the dews of heaven, So turns the chalice of my heart
                            For luv as freely given. <pb n="200" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 200 THE MANIFESTO. Let fall into my soul 0
                            Lord Refining grace and power, That every motiv be to Thee A holy fragrant flower. And every
                            thought be at Thy feet Like pearly petals shed, And every impulse of my life To holiness be
                            wed. And when the harvest time of life Brings its reward, the best I'll lay upon thine altar
                            Lord Oh be my offering blest. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Democracy" TEIform="index"/>DEMOCRACY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catherine" TEIform="persName"/>By Catherine Allen.</byline><p TEIform="p">IN what does it consist? A true democracy rests upon the pr.ncipls of absolute, inherent
                            sovereignty of the peple which givs to each citizen the fullest political and religious
                            freedom compatibl with the good order of society and is therefore opposed to any laws or
                            system of government which would favor the growth of an aristocracy or class privileges in
                            any shape. It was evidently the design of the fathers of the Revolution to establish such a
                            government, and had their successors been inspird by the same burning luv of liberty and
                            true self-sacrificing devotion to principl, to-day the peple of the United States would be
                            in much fuller enjoyment of their inalienabl rights, most important among which is that of
                            each person to the undivided product of his labor. The fact that society is so constructed
                            as to make this impossibl at the present time, confronts us on every hand, and is alarmingly
                            apparent in the rapidity with which enormous monopolies ar aggregating the welth of the
                            cuntry, creating an ever widening gulf between the welth producers, who must constantly
                            struggle with poverty, and the consumers, who riot in unearned luxuries, thus bringing about
                            those class distinctions which ar consequent principally to the subjugation of labor to
                            capital, and which ar really more injurious to the interests of democracy than was chattel
                            slavery in the days of its supremacy; because the system of wage slavery in our cuntry now
                            extends itself to every branch of industry, and givs opportunity for much larger
                            proportionate monopoly on the part of the non-producers. It is crippling the energies and
                            stultifying the higher faculties of the most valuabl portion of society, and is utterly
                            destructiv to the enjoyment of those rights and liberties for which the heroes of the
                            Revolution gave their <pb n="201" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 201 blood. It is a black cloud
                            which dai'kens our social and political horizon. An impending crisis awaits us, and unless
                            sum degree of justice is speedily insured to the peple, revolution is inevitabl. Under a
                            true democracy neither the millionaire nor the pauper wil exist. As its central idea is a
                            government of, for, and by the peple, the necessary changes to bring this about ar:
                            First:Universal and equal rights of suffrage without regard to sex, race, or creed.
                            /Second:Control of political power by the peple thru direct and secret ballot in all
                            elections and on every subject of importance. Third:Entire separation of civil from
                            ecclesiastical power. Church property not to be exempt from taxation. No sectarian schools
                            or other institutions to be supported by public funds. All laws for "Christian morality," as
                            such to be abrogated, and our entire political system to be administerd on a purely secular
                            basis. Fourth:The land of the United States must becum the inheritance of her citizens.
                            Revocations must be made of all existing grants of corporations or individuals in this
                            cuntry or in foreign nations. Fifth:A system of taxation which shal rest exclusively upon
                            the natural welth of the cuntry and its unearnd increment, thus leaving untaxt everything
                            which is the product of human toil. Sixth:The free exchange of equivalent values between
                            persons, states and nations, by the producing persons and organizations. Seventh:The total
                            abolition of usury, and, as present help, a tax upon all large incomes and inheritances.
                            Eighth:A legal tender of sufficient amount to leave uncrippled all the business of the
                            cuntry internal and international. This of necessity must be bi-metalic until a larger
                            proportion of our public educators ar convinct that paper may be made equally reliable as a
                            medium of exchange. Ninth:Education for minors compulsory, and opportunities for the higher
                            branches of learning made equal to all. Industrial education included in all scools from the
                            Kindergarten to the University. Tenth:The possession and management by the government of all
                            large systems of transportation and communication. Local advantages as street cars,
                            water-works and lights should be controlled by municipalities ; never by private
                            corporations. Eleventh:Inventors should be liberally rewarded by the government, and the
                            benefit of new inventions left free for all, as the present system often givs opportunity
                            for large and unjust monopolies, and frequently leaves the real inventors unrequited.
                            Twelfth:The administration of justice and legal advice without charge, equally free to all.
                            To bring about these changes, society must be thoroughly reconstructed. <pb n="202" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 202 THE MANIFESTO. How? Let the peple learn that the Great Ruler of all, is Father and
                            Mother, and then frame all earthly institutions in conformity to this grand central truth.
                            Then, monopoly and injustice of every guii?e wil be as undesirabl as impossibl, in a peple
                            whose diviner sentiments, awakened by the breezes astir from a higher world, and liberated
                            from the dwarfing, degrading systems of competition wil express themselvs iu the practical
                            recognition of Universal Brotherhood. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peace" TEIform="index"/>PEACE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vinneo, Cora C." TEIform="persName"/>By Cora C. Vinneo.</byline><p TEIform="p">Long time ago when life was fresh and new, God sent His waters over all its face And spoke
                            His vengeance from the storm cloud's place. But when the sunlight pierced the darkness thru,
                            His dove of peace o'er hills of billows flew To find sum emblem of His wondrous grace, Sum
                            living thing that helpless man might trace, The promise of His luv and mercy too. So o'er
                            the waves that make our spirits clean, Flies sum dear bird to find a verdant spot, Sum
                            resting place where bitter strivings cease. Oh may it reach a quiet isle serene, Where sin,
                            and care, and trial enter not, And bring from thence the olive branch of peace. Mt. Lebanon,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Elder Henry:--I have been thinking..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Beloved Elder Henry:--I have been thinking...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Shirley, July 1895" TEIform="index"/>Shirley, Mass. July, 1895.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Henry :I hav been thinking that it was time you should hav something to say
                                about Shirley. Well, it may be best to say by way of beginning, that the Post Office
                                authorities hav taken the "Village" off our address, so that it is now plain Shirley,
                                Mass. Then I would say that when you next cum to see us, you will find one of the
                                prettiest new Stations you hav seen in a long while; and when the grounds about it are
                                completed, it wil be a very attractiv spot, toward which, and our lovely home, it would
                                please us much to see many honest, earnest souls drawn by the luv of gospel truth and
                                purity. Next I would say, that I think you might look over a great deal of "The <pb n="203" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 203 World's" literature and not find anything
                                better to read than }tou wil find on the clipping enclosed calld"Seed Thoughts," which I
                                would be glad to see in The Manifesto. The writer had the privilege of calling at
                                Alfred, Me. recently, while on a business trip, and was much pleased with the fresh look
                                of their newly painted buildings, but much more with the smiling, cheerful looking faces
                                met, and with the great abundance of beutiful work the owners of those cheery faces had
                                wrought. Then the thought of how many other faces would smile to cum into possession of
                                only a sample of them, for the pieces seemed innumerable. Hope the result may be
                                profitabl and cause much more smiling. Now to cum back to Shirley. Our garden crops are
                                looking very fine. The hay crop is better than we feared it might be earlier in the
                                season. We hav had rather a wet time to get it in but hav succeeded fairly wel, and hav
                                finished haying with the exception of the meadows. Rye crop, thin. Barley and oats,
                                good. Fruit, of which we usually hav considerabl, very scarce indeed,but we ar seeking
                                after the fruits of the Spirit, and with hope and trust in the goodness of our Heavenly
                                Father and Mother,G-od, we expect to take sum comfort as we journey along. I close with
                                kindly greetings to all the readers of our Monthly and more especially those who ar
                                striving to live the truths it teaches. Yours very truly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitely, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Whiteley.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manhood" TEIform="index"/>MANHOOD.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sevester, Edwin P." TEIform="persName"/>By Edwin P. Sevester.</byline><p TEIform="p">" When I was a child, I spake as a child, I thought as a child, I understood as a child, but
                            when I became a man I put away childish things."* 1 Cor. xiii., 11. TTTHAT is manhood? Does
                            it merely consist in being of mature age? V V There are youths who are really men, acting
                            manly; and there are men who never seem to grow away from their boyhood. If I understand it
                            rightly, to be true men, we must lay aside all that is childish and the follies of youth,
                            growing into manliness, rising into our higher and nobler nature; more earnestly and soberly
                            developing and expanding all our faculties; fulfilling conscientiously our duty, however
                            irksome these duties may be. Let us combine the innocence, purity and simplicity of youth
                            with the firmness, earnestness, steadfastness of a man, ennobling our character and
                            developing our spiritual nature, knowing we not only live for thisbut also for another, a
                            higher, better, world. Let us be lifted up out of the animal nature, and grow into a true
                            and noble manhood, a man in every sense of the word; a man who can not be ^swayed by every
                            wind that blows, who <pb n="204" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 204 THE MANIFESTO. stands like a rock, against
                            temptation and adversity. My young friends, cultivate reason, judgment, intelligence and
                            religious sentiments which will ennoble our affections, distinguish us from all other
                            creatures and lead us to become perfect in the fullness of the stature of Christ. If we
                            indulge in passion, restraining not our appetites but gratify our inclinations and evil
                            propensities, we are placing ourselves on a level with the brute creation, that have no
                            reason to govern ihem. Live for a high and noble purpose; strive to reach a broader, a truer
                            manhood. To build a noble manhood, a pure foundation, purity of soul, purity of character is
                            an indispensable requisite. Man is endowed with so many faculties, morally and spiritually,
                            that giving his spiritual nature the control over the lower and animal life, enables him to
                            commune with angels, drawing holy influences around him and receiving Divine inspirations.
                            Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Judging" TEIform="index"/>JUDGING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>By Alonzo G. Hollister.</byline><p TEIform="p">T is written "Judge not, that ye be not judged," which is equivalent to saying "Condemn not
                            another's sincerity, that your own may not be condemned." This text is often quoted, as
                            though it were intended to absolutely forbid any one judging another. Of course this would
                            forbid all comparisons, and annul all impressions of right and wrong as applied to the
                            conduct of another. It would forbid all estimates of character, nor allow us to distinguish
                            between sound and unsound principls, wholesum and unwholesum associates, good and bad
                            exampls. The clause immediately following, limits the expression and shows that such was not
                            the meaning intended. "For with what judgment ye judge, ye shal be judged, and with what
                            measure ye mete, it shal be measured to you." In what judgment ye judge, he says, indicating
                            different manners of judgment. On another occasion, Jesus said, Judge not according to
                            appearance, but judge righteous judgment. Again, "You judge according to the flesh." Here ar
                            two manners recognized, one righteous, the other according to appearance, or according to
                            the flesh. Mother Ann when reproving the latter, said "Creatures see and judge, according to
                            the spirit they ar of." A righteous judgment, must necessarily be true, and do gord, marking
                            a clear separation between good and evil. "Why, even of yourselvs, judge ye not what is
                            right ?" A judgment according to appearance, or according to the flesh, as between two
                            parties, one or both being jealous of the other, without clearly comprehending the motiv,
                            situation, or facts, is liabl to be false, unkind and unjust, and even malicious, and adds
                            to evils already existing. It is frequent- <pb n="205" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 205 ly the
                            offspring of hatred or revenge, and exerts a mischievous and malign influence, as abundantly
                            demonstrated in political feuds. Krino, to judge, is defined in the lexicons, "To winnow,
                            sift, to separate, distinguish, award, rule, divide, determine, decide, sentence, condemn,
                            accuse, blame." The gospel of the world harvest, is the gospel of judgment, to separate
                            creatures from their sins. Its subjects sit upon thrones, judging themselvs and the world in
                            themselvs first. "And judgment was given them," not taken away from them, and they reigned
                            with Christ. ' 'Ye shal sit upon twelve thrones, judging the twelve tribes of Israel." "Know
                            ye not the saints shal judge the world?" Know ye not that we shal judge messengers? How can
                            we know truth from falsehood, wolves from sheep, if we may not judge? But to keep the spirit
                            of the precept, we must judge kindly and righteously, according to the truth, without
                            partiality, and without envy or prejudice. Seeing as God sees, who condemns the sin and
                            saves the creature that wishes to be separated from sinjudging in the spirit and judgment
                            which we wish to hav exercised toward us. If we ar not wiling to be known and judged in a
                            righteous judgment, before a purified human tribunal, it bespeaks a heart unwilling to be
                            separated from its idols. Such must find a change of heart, or be alienated from the
                            righteous who ar traveling in a precisely opposite direction, by casting out the evil and
                            becoming purified. Milk is for babes, solid food for the perfect, those having perceptions
                            habitually exercised for a discrimination of both good and evil. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith" TEIform="index"/>FAITH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/>By Lucy S. Bowers.</byline><p TEIform="p">Faith is a white robed angel pure and bright Who lends to human hearts her holy wings To rise
                            from earthly unto heavenly things. Fear perishes, doubts vanish in her light As morning
                            melts the shadows of the nightStrong grows the will when faith her full strength brings; The
                            spirit gives to God its offerings, And strives each day with fervent love of right.
                            Interpreter of truth's unwritten word ; Diviner of the mysteries of life, "Who gives the
                            evidence of things unheard, The substance of true hope through every strife. Transformer of
                            the mind! sweet joy abides When to the soul's glad victory she guides. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="206" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mysterious providence" TEIform="index"/>MYSTERIOUS PROVIDENCE.</head><p TEIform="p">THERE ar many peple who consider it a mysterious dispensation of Providence that a person is
                            taken out of the world. It makes no difference whether tins takes place in infancy, at adult
                            age, or in the decline of life. In whatever form denth may be brought about, it is entered
                            on the list as specially directed by some overruling influence. On the other hand, another
                            class ar equally as sanguine in thinking that it is a mysterious Providence that keeps the
                            peple in this world, while they ar so persistent in running the "broad way" and doing all
                            they can to encourage the neglect of all law that has reference to the preservation of life.
                            Saints and sinners ar equally determined in holding their places on the sick list, altho it
                            is said that sickness and sin move along, generally, hand in hand, even the saints ar liable
                            to become more or less contaminated. Was Moses correct in writing God's word, or was it one
                            of his mistakes that is recorded in Exodus xv., 26. "If thou wilt diligently hearken to the
                            voice of the Lord thy God, and wilt do that which is right in his sight, and wilt giv ear to
                            his commandments, and keep all his statutes, I wil put none of these diseases upon thee,
                            which I hav brought upon the Egyptians, for I am the Lord that healeth thee." Either that
                            special verse in Exodus is sadly in error or the many existing nations, the Jews included,
                            hav departed disastrously from the Mosaic Law. If the keeping of the Law would take away all
                            diseases, when Moses made the proclamation, the keeping of the Law wil do equally as much
                            to-day. Reformers ar often found running on special lines, and while one class demand a
                            reform in one or more things, they shock the nerves of another class of reformers by their
                            careless neglect of duties which may be of paramount importance. The temperance man
                            denounces the drinking of all alcoholic beverages as a sin against both God and man, and yet
                            he at the same time is indulging freely in the intoxicating and filthy habit of chewing and
                            smoking sum poisonous tobacco. Such reformers while poisoning the atmosphere with noxious
                            fumes and forcing others to breathe it, should think, at least, twice before they ask in
                            prayer for God's Kingdom to cum upon the earth. In this unreasonablness of man with man he
                            incorporates all the bad practices into his life and then justifies them by his religion.
                            Should any of these prove <pb n="207" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 207 ruinous or destroy
                            either soul or body, then it is placed, at once, among the ways of a mysterious Providence.
                            Even the time honored but much neglected Mosaic Law which the Christian says is the word of
                            God, would make a decided improvement in the lives of peple generally, if it was faithfully
                            regarded. No farmer would manage the raising of his stock on anything short of the best
                            knowledge that could be obtaind, nor would he attribute sickness or death to a mysterious
                            dispensation of Providence, when he knew the ruin could be traced to the neglect of those in
                            charge of the stock. It seems quite certain that the nations hav all gone astray and run
                            after not only the rum and tobacco, with a zeal that would hav been commendabl in a better
                            cause, but after nearly everything that would destroy helth and even life. So simple an
                            affair as eating and drinking is placed before us for consideration, and there is, no doubt,
                            but that the class who eat with little or no thought of the articls of food or of its proper
                            mastication may bring on a train of ills that the liver and stomach hav not the power to
                            resist. Dr. Alcott in his excellent work on the *'Laws of Health," says; "One of the worst
                            domestic poisons with which I am acquainted is saleratus. All alkalies ar poisonous in
                            greater or less degree. Some may dout whether saleratus is as poisonous as medical men
                            represent it to be, but they need not. Dr. Ives says,'It is a narcotic, and what is a
                            narcotic but poison?' " But the enemy to helth lurks in many a by way, and, the improper
                            care of exercise, and no less of ventilation may hav as much to do with the disease of the
                            body, as does the food we eat. A large class, however, may march along with their flags
                            flying, as they think of their many victories over these old enemies, while on a closer
                            inspection they may find themselvs the slaves of more modern poisons, as they cum in the
                            insidious form of morphine or chloral. The British Medical Journal says, that ninety nine in
                            one hundred of these sleeping doses ar worse than useless, even for any purpose of relief
                            worthy of that name. But while the good old doctor Alcott has gone on to the "Better Land,"
                            and has escaped the more subtle foe that has surreptitiously enterd the household, he has
                            informd us that for no less than forty years he wanderd "in the wilderness of pills and
                            powders,'' and that his salvation from this dark abode, must hav been from the influx of
                            light, or as sum would term it, a wonderful, mysterious Providence. <pb n="208" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/>
                            208 THE MANIFESTO. At the present time, "Helth finds a new menace in the rapid increase and
                            in the use of pjwerful drugs, especially, salicylic and boracic acids in the preservation of
                            food. It is used in cider, fruits, vegetables and preserves." Dr. Alcott after enumerating
                            several articles that ar unsuitabl to enter the stomach, remarks that "soda is not much
                            better than saleratus, and whether neutralized or unneutralized should be avoided." As the
                            helth of the body is considered to be one of the greatest blessings that has been vouchsafed
                            to man, too much care can not be exercised in selecting that food which is most condusiv to
                            helth and consequently to happiness. All animals and the human included, arvery tenacious of
                            life, and it is surprising what excesses and what reckless deviations may be made and yet
                            life is not destroyd. As more thought is given to this subject and the laws of helth ar more
                            carefully studied, new revelations wil be brought into the light, and that knowledge obtaind
                            which wil assure each one that his life is in his own hands, and that the works of a
                            mysterious Providence are equally in all the wonderful, creative acts that we see abuv and
                            around us. Let us remember the Creator and so live that God may remove from us all disease,
                            agreeably to the promise.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Blinn.</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> who are sending The Manifesto to Mrs. Blankenburg, " Christophen, " Burzynski, " J. Collins,
                            " Carroll, all of Milwaukee, Wis., are informed that they are not taken from the Post
                            Office. (D^An article sent for publication should bear the name of the writer. An article
                            that is received without a name comes from Mr. Nobody.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="They choose unwisely..." TEIform="index"/>They choose unwisely...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">They choose unwisely, who seek intellectual development, at the expense of those kindly
                            offices of sympathy and love whose neglect impoverishes and shrivels the soul.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, C." TEIform="persName"/>C. Allen.</byline></div2><pb n="209" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Abiding hope" TEIform="index"/>ABIDING HOPE.</head><p TEIform="p">"We have tasted the good word of God, and the powers of the world to come." Heb. vi., 5. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y. 1. I have thought of the fair land of promise, 2. I feel their pure influence
                            of blessing, Of the unclouded light glowing there, Their music comes oft to my ear, Of
                            purified souls, their homes pearly white, And Peace flying o'er the deep flowing stream, And
                            the beautiful robes that they wear. Has left her sweet gifts with me here. <pb n="210" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 210 THE MANIFESTO. ABIDING HOPE. Chorus. By the bright shining river I'm
                            waiting, Ever trustingly waiting to go; When the good Angel carries me over, That hoped for,
                            I fully shall know. 3 I walk 'mong the lilies of virtue, And roses of love pave my way; I
                            hold in my hand rich treasures of life, Tet a little while only, I stay. 4 For spiritual
                            truth is my striving, And substance abiding and real; For freedom from sin and lurements of
                            earth, And the true resurrection to feel. 5 'Tis true, what I've sown I shall harvest,
                            Unmerited joys are not mine; But dread holds me not, with courage I hope For life that is
                            wholly divine.</p></div2><pb n="211" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. SEPTEMBER, 1895. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the
                            "United Society of Believers1' on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All
                            communications should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. .75
                            .40 One copy per ye;ir, postage paid " " six months, " "</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. July. Thermometer. Raw. 1894. 72 13 1.4 in. 1895.
                                67.32 4.75 in. Highest Temp, during this mo. 90 above 0 Lowest " " " " 44 " " Number of
                                rainy days " " 9 " " clear " " " 8 " " cloudy " " " 14 C. G. need. Aug. 1895. We fear we
                                are late for even our little say for this month; but the days whirl by so rapidly, that
                                our would be correspondent, pressed with orders for work did not realize that "time's
                                up," until the usual day for sending was past. In early life we were often counseled to
                                "Take Time by the forelock," but in these days of swift travel if we can catch a glimpss
                                of his queue as he vanishes from sight we are fortunate. The one thing worthy of
                                notewhich perhaps others have mentionedis the severest hailstorm of July 13, known in
                                this locality for sixty years. The ground looked more like April than July, and in some
                                places the hailstones were drifted several inches deep, and did not melt until the next
                                day, the thermometer falling from 08 deg to 48 deg. in twenty minutes. Still in
                                comparison to other sections of the country the storm was tempered to us. Leaves which
                                presented a large surface such as beans, squash, corn and melons, also the ripening
                                blackberries and raspberries suffered the most, but had the hailstones been large as
                                well as numerous, there would have been no harvest of anything grown or growing. So in
                                this as in every misfortune there might have been a worse, and we will bless the "powers
                                that be," and count the blessings that are ours, instead of cumbering ourselves with
                                discontent over those which we imagine are denied us. Amelia J. Calver. Center Family.
                                Aug. 1895. We have nothing unusual to report at this time; the crops already gathered
                                are very good, especially cherries, which yielded a large crop, but owing to unfavorable
                                weather, rotted on the trees badly consequently we did not realize so much as last year
                                on them, pears are very abundant the trees being loaded. The weather is warm and dry
                                although we have had many showers during the summer. The spiritual atmosphere seems
                                quite as dry as the physical; scarcely any inquiry as to our faith or principles. People
                                are more interested in our contemplated move to Florida than in anything we have done or
                                said in years gone by. Our Pittsfield friends do not like the idea of our leaving these
                                spendid homes here on the hill-side for such a warm climate as Florida. Well we are not
                                gone yet and no one can tell when the trumpet may sound for TERMS. 2H <pb n="212" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 212 THE MANIFESTO. us to do as did the children of Israel, pull up stakes
                                and move on, Are we ready? If the hand of the Lord be in the movement then it seems
                                wisdom to go wherever His spirit may lead; there alone is safety and protection. Can we
                                sing with the immortal P. P. Bliss, I know not what awits me, Uo;l kindly veils my eyes,
                                Anil o'er each step of my onward way He makes new scenes to rise; And every joy He sends
                                me comes A sweet and glad surprise, Where'er he leads I'll follow, My trust in Him
                                repose, . And every hour in perfect peace I'll sing, He knows, He knows. Timothy Ray
                                son. South. Family. Aug. 1895. "They that trust in the Lord shall be aw Mt. Zion, which
                                can not be removed but abideth forever. As the mountains are round about Jerusalem, so
                                the Lord is round about his people from henceforth even forever."-Psalms cxxv., 1, 2.
                                Great and many have been the blessings of the present year. Our fruit and vegetable
                                gardens are yielding beyond our anticipation. The mountains have furnished a liberal
                                growth of blueberries which we delighted to harvest, and sunny days found us securing
                                the luscious fruit which is ever healthful and refreshing. Fruit trees of the peach,
                                plum, pear and cherry varieties were planted during the past season and old ones shorn
                                of their unprofitable members causing a rejuvenating element to dwell in the midst of
                                our beautiful home. The month of June was made especially beneficial by the visitation
                                of Sisters from Canterbury and Enfield N. H., and on the 18th of July a renewal of the
                                same by the coming of Sisters Isabella White and Louie Bussell from the Groveland fa
                                mily at Watervliet. We are much in favor of the new method for manufacturing ice-cream
                                and when convenient shall adopt the Daisy system, which will be superior to the old plan
                                of employing a crank to perform the work. Genevieve DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">East Family. Aug. 1895. Beloved Elder Hkney;Will you plense give a few Home Notes from
                                the East Family a little corner in The Manifesto? We that are young, are thinking we
                                would like to see how they will look. We sincerely hope our long silence will not give
                                the impression that we have no home, for indeed, we have a beautiful home, or at least
                                it is so to us. It affords many temporal blessings for which we render grateful thanks
                                to the Giver. Then the opportunity it gives to live a pure and unselfish life is
                                appreciated above all things else. We wonder if among the New Hampshire hills and
                                mountains there are as many atmospheric changes as there are here, among the Berkshire
                                hills? We frequently get a sniff from the four seasons in one week; but in spite of the
                                cold waves, frosty air and scorching heat, the prospect for good crops of all kinds is
                                very encouraging. Our garden enclosing over twenty different kinds of vegetables, never
                                looked better. The hay crop, quite as good as usual, apples and pears good; peaches and
                                plums few and far enough apart not to waste by coming in contact with each other. Our
                                mother Hannah A. Agnew, is spending a short season with us, imparting that courage and
                                strength which only the true and faithful mothers can give the children. Such examples
                                should inspire the young to greater efforts to live a high and noble life, doing good to
                                all, whereeverand whenever an opportunity is given. Celia A. Thorpe.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. Aug. 4, 1895. In reviewing the August Manifesto, and noting the excellency
                                of its contents, knowing that the Brethren and Sisters who contribute to its support
                                give of their <pb n="213" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 213 best thoughts, we were reminded
                                of the lines of one of our old hymns, I have thought; the greatest treasure That the
                                universe can sing. There is no material treasure Which can such possessions bring. We
                                may be deprived of the pleasures of the physical senses, but to the being who has
                                advanced in the scale of civilization beyond the boundaries of the barbaric or even the
                                savage stage there is no physical happiness equal to the enjoyment of pure thought. When
                                we read Br. Alonzo's article we exclaimed,Let the gospel fire be renewed in our souls,
                                and let the testimony oi' truth roll through the earth. Only the errors of life feel the
                                keenness of truth's incisive steel. We notice Prof. Edg;\r C. Beali has given us, in the
                                Phrenological Journal for August, a very interesting account o: Swami Vivekananda, a
                                young Hindoo monk who was a delegate to the "World's Parliament of Religions," and who
                                is now traveling in this country, as a religious teacher. One of the most favorable
                                signs of the times is that the demon of religious intolerance and bigotry is retiring
                                into the shades of night, whence it emerged in the past, causing so much suffering to
                                the advocates of advanced thought. The unfolding of the truths of the Divine life is not
                                confined to sects or parties; and the different manifestations of it all move
                                harmoniously together. This young Hindoo monk is teaching celibacy, and maintains that
                                for attaining to the highest unfoldment of the spiritual life the perfect and complete
                                renunciation of the emotions and passions of the lower life is imperative. To all such
                                the hand of fellowship is extended of whatever race, color or creed. The weather for
                                July has averaged cool; some times more resembling October than midsummer, but with
                                plenty of rain for the crops, we have no cause to complain, and on the whole the season,
                                up to date, August 4th has been favorable. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct.</head><p TEIform="p">Aug. 1895. Jesus said, "In the world ye shall find tribulation, but in me ye shall find
                                peace." There is no shield from sin and trouble in a worldly life. Thousands are seeking
                                for happiness and peace in sinful pleasure, but they find it not, that aching void is
                                still in the heart. Sin promises joy, but pays sorrow. Denying self brings a peace which
                                passeth understanding and joy never ending. The path of virtue is the way in which we
                                should walk. Let us exemplify in daily life that which is true and virtuous. Have a
                                noble aim in view, and strive to live up to it. Work in harmony with others and do all
                                you can to progress in the right direction physically, morally and spiritually. It is by
                                united effort that all progress hns been made and lasting good accomplished. "The
                                largest orange tree in the South is a gigantic specimen which grows in Louisiana. It is
                                fifty feet high and fifteen feet in circumference at the base. Its yield has often been
                                ten thousand oranges per season." "The largest apple tree in New York state is said to
                                be one standing near the town of Wilson. It was planted in the year 1815, and it is on
                                record that it once yielded thirty-three barrels of apples in a single season." "Cans
                                made of paper pulp are being introduced to take the place of tin cans for containing all
                                kinds of preserved products. The occasional cases of poisoning from canned goods is due
                                to the contents becoming tainted through the cans not being air tight.'' Daniel Or
                            cult.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1895. Again we renew our bonds of union with all in Christian love. Those who are
                                striving to live the Christ life are one in him wherever located. While the nation
                                celebrated its birth <pb n="214" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 214 THE MA NIFES TO. with noisy
                                demonstrations we enjoyed the day in quietness. Sister Nellie, Brother Kneeland Codman
                                and G. S. Cheney wTith lady, were with us. After feasting on a good substantial dinner,
                                the room was cleared and at 3 o'clock we were recalled to be entertained by the young
                                people. Very appropriate selections were spoken and sung, represented with good taste
                                and becoming costume, followed by impromptu speaking. Mrs. Codman rendered "Anastatia",
                                and Mr. Codman gave us "Spirit Breathings" impromptu. We were then served with
                                ice-cream, cake, watermelon, lemonade, candy and nuts. Our centenarian Br. Ezra Newton
                                was in our midst, and enjoyed all with as much zest as our young people. How beautiful
                                is age, when sits upon the brow the crown of Wisdom. Hay harvest is nearly over. The
                                farmers have had a wet season. By judicious management they have been successful in
                                securing nearly one hundred tons of good hay and none injured by rain, which is a great
                                blessing to us. Marcia M. Dullard.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Aug. 1895. As I write our Home Notes amid the delightful scenes and under the genial
                                skies of a New England summer, I feel like lifting my voice in praise to the Giver of
                                nature's gifts, for, "Beautiful for habitation is Mt. Zion." As usual, at this season,
                                we are entertaining many visitors, drawn hither no doubt out of curiosity to see a
                                people who though conversant with the world, "are not of the world." We are pleased to
                                note that those who visit us are uniformly of the respectable and intelligent class of
                                society. Our fields of ripening grain, and the vegetable gardens proclaim the near
                                approach of autumn. We are not as fortunate as our Florida friends who can raise two
                                crops in one season. With the exception of early peas, we fail to do this in New
                                Hampshire. Our three acres of onions (the larger part raised for seed and now in bloom)
                                call out much comment from city visitors, as does the general cleanliness prevailing in
                                our home. The latter condition may be accounted for, when we consider that we make and
                                use annually from fifteen to eighteen barrels of lye soap. The health of the Society is
                                generally good, which necessary physical force, is a strong aid to make the mind conform
                                to the ennobling principles that create a Christ-like nature; a character not composed
                                of ideas and verbal sounds, but of virtue, sustained by a spirit of self-reliance. Those
                                who obey the dictation of au enlightened conscience, are able by acquired strength, to
                                wade through the waters of tribulation and to help others mount the hights which vibrate
                                with the gospel of truth and are radiant with the purity of the Christ spirit, which
                                overcomes the world. George H. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/> Union Village, O.</head><p TEIform="p">Aug. 1895. August comes in cool and pleasant, and the farmer having his harvesting and
                                threshing done is ready for his fallow ploughing; and the gardener, is bringing in his
                                crops, for the table, and the cow boy supplying the milk and butter: and caretaker of
                                the fowls, adds the eggs and broilers, and the mechanics are in their cool and airy
                                shops, and last though by no means least, the pure, neat, true and faithful Sisters, add
                                their part as the comforters and beautifiers of the home. "Home sweet home, there's no
                                place like home," wrote a richly gifted soul, and surely, "be it ever so humble," there
                                is no place on earth so sacred and so richly cherished as the home. Even when considered
                                as a temporal, earthly abode only, there clusters about it some of the tenderest
                                emotions of the human soul. But when viewed in the light of permanence and perpetuity
                                which the idea of a <pb n="215" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 215 home in the hearts of its
                                occupants presents, the sentiment is enlarged a thousand fold. And such is the object
                                and such the labors of our Shaker homes; the building, in union with the pure and true,
                                homes for both time and eternity. Property may be destroyed, the unfaithful to his
                                trust, the physical senses decay; but a home in the hearts of the pure and loyal can
                                never fail. Watson Andrews.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Aug. 1895. Already we have a forewarning of the winter to come. All the singing birds
                                have become quiet, except occasionally one solitary robin. Some of these birds, however,
                                remain with us but are evidently making arrangements for the southern trip. Our crop of
                                hay has been very satisfactory, and yet we should have been thankful for more. The small
                                fields of grain that we raise has afforded a good yield. Our garden brings to us the
                                best of food for the table, and the supply is sufficiently varied to meet the demands of
                                our large family. Our corn fields on the farm are larger this year than has been seen
                                for many years in the past and the growth is phenomenal. Indeed, it presents a beautiful
                                sight and will, no doubt, be a great blessing in more ways than one. Mrs. McWhirter of
                                Texas, from the home of the "Sanctified Sisters," with her son Eobert of New York City,
                                made us a visit of several days and all were very much interested in learning from her,
                                more about her b,ome in Texas. H. C. Blinn.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The source of final happiness..." TEIform="index"/>The source of final happiness...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The source of final happiness is inherent in the heart; he is a fool who seeks it elsewhere.
                            He is like the shepherd who searched for the sheep which was in his bosom.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vemann, Hindu" TEIform="persName"/>Hindu Vemann.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Carpets" TEIform="index"/>CARPETS.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">We are glad that we are able to say that our home is once more almost free
                                        from the unhygienic carpet. Each year for some time past we have renewed or
                                        repaired one or more floors and dispensed with the carpet, and this year we have
                                        already discarded six, and hope to dispense with four more in the near future.
                                        Three of the rooms and one hall have double floors, laid to deaden sound. The
                                        upper floor is of hard pine, and all of the household are delighted to have the
                                        rooms free from these dust and filth collectors. In our double sitting-rooms we
                                        will not even have a rug. The filth and dust are not the worst features of wool
                                        carpets. There are particles of wool cut loose from them and floating in the
                                        air, and they are breathed into the nostrils. In a bright light o sunshine these
                                        particles of dust can be seen with the naked eye. Think of the breathing
                                        apparatus being clogged with such material, much worse and more irritating than
                                        earth dust and harder for the vital forces to remove. We hope our readers who
                                        are interested in and desirous of bringing better sanitary conditions about
                                        their homes will begin at once to free them from wool carpets. Perhaps the
                                        parlor or reception-room may be an exception, as it is not much used, but even
                                        the housekeeper or domestic must have hard labor and be filled with dust in
                                        caring for even that room. A nicely furnished, uncarpeted floor is more
                                        expensive at first than a carpet, but it lasts much longer than a carpet. If one
                                        does not feel able to lay a new floor, many old floors can be nicely painted
                                        with several coats, cracks and defects filled with putty, and a few bright rugs,
                                        if the mind will not be satisfied without, will make a clean, sweet, and a
                                        passably presentable floor.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Journal of Hygeio-Therapy" TEIform="index"/>Journal nf Hygeio-Therapy.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><pb n="216" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life's mission" TEIform="index"/>LIFE'S MISSION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mathers, Jennie" TEIform="persName"/>By Jennie Mathers.</byline><p TEIform="p">To-xight, as I stand at the window, I am glad that the day has past, And the quiet hours of
                            evening Have settled down at last. I watch the moonlight falling In bars of silver and gold,
                            But I know its glowing radiance, falls On many a heart that is cold. On many a heart that is
                            weary Of worldly contention and strife; On many a heart that is longing For a purer, a
                            better life. And my heart grows sad while thinking Of the many that go astray, Who must
                            answer for all evil doing To God, at the great Judgment day. The shadows, they lengthen
                            around me, The moonlight grows suddenly dim; In the mists, the angels ar bringing A message
                            of comfort from Him. I feel that my prayer is answered; A door of hope I can see. To help
                            the weak and the erring Is the mission Christ has given to me. I find in the hour of sorrow,
                            In days of darkness and sin, That the angels ar earnestly seeking The souls of the erring to
                            win. Then I'll fear not the raging tempest, I'll fear not the angry sea, Be faithful in
                            filling the mission The Christ has given to me. My faith in Christ shal be steadfast, My luv
                            to God shal be true. With hands that ar ever ready, His wil, not my own, I'll do. Sabbathday
                            Lake, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We are building" TEIform="index"/>WE ARE BUILDING.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">[Contributed by Maria Wood.]  are building our home on Eternity's shore While we dwell in our structure of
                                    clay; We are shipping materials onward before, With the close of each hastening day.
                                    We are sending the thought that our spirit has "wrought, In the "wonderful glow of
                                    the brain; And the timber is grown from the seed we have sown 'Mid the shades of our
                                    sorrow and pain. We are building our homes on the beautiful street While we dwell in
                                    the by-way of fears; And the roses that bloom there, so pure and so sweet Must be
                                    watered and nourished by tears; And the light that shall shine in aglory divine Must
                                    be found in the darkness and gloom, And the foundation laid, in the cloud and the
                                    shade Of the road that leads down to the tomb. We are building our home in the
                                    valley of Life By the side of Eternity's sea; And the work that we do 'mid the
                                    scenes of earth's strife Shall decide what that home is to be. Every thought leaves
                                    its trace on that wonderful place, Every deed, be it evil or fair; And the structure
                                    will show, all the life lived below, All the sinning and sorrow and care.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Acrostic--wisdom" TEIform="index"/>ACROSTIC WISDOM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Halford, Alice E." TEIform="persName"/>By Alice E. Halford.</byline><p TEIform="p">Wisdom is the principal thing, therefore get wisdom and with all thy getting get
                            understanding.Prov. i., 7. I wisdom dwell with prudence and find out knowledge of witty
                            understanding. Prov. viii., 12. Say unto wisdom thou art my sister, and call understanding
                            thy kinswoman. Prov. vii., 4. Doth not wisdom cry and understanding put forth her
                            voice.Prov. vii., 1. O ye simple, understand wisdom, and ye fools be ye of an understanding
                            heart. Prov. viii., 5. My son attend unto my wisdom and bow thine ear to my
                            understanding.Prov. v., 1. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Resolve, however nobly formed..." TEIform="index"/>Resolve, however nobly formed...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Resolve, however nobly formed, at best, is but a still-born babe of thought, until it proves
                            existence of its life and will by sound or action.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilcox, Ella Wheeler" TEIform="persName"/>Ella Wheeler Wilcox.</byline></div2><pb n="217" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He was an editor" TEIform="index"/>HE WAS AN EDITOR.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A haggard, pale and wretched man Once I met, Which from that day to this I can
                                    Ne'er forget; Clothed in garb of sundry dyes, Cut in every shape and size Low and
                                    plaintive were his cries Shunning everybody. "Friend," said I, "pray tell to me All
                                    thy woes! Surely I would comfort thee At life's close." "Ah," said he, "the die is
                                    cast All my cheerful hopes are past; Now I must giv up at last Pleasing everybody.
                                    "When I first began my labors," Said the man, "Then to try and please my neighbors I
                                    began; But I've led a scrry race Owning now no resting-place, Save the short six
                                    feet of space Due to everybody. "If you try to please mankind As you go, Plenty of
                                    labor you wil find Here below. First a hit and then a miss, Sometimes No and
                                    sometimes Yes Pleasing everybody. "Should the world declare you wrong, Never heed;
                                    If your cause is true and strong, Sow your seed. On life's stage act wel your part,
                                    Serve your God with honest heart; But giv over, from the start, Pleasing everybody."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Railroader's prayer" TEIform="index"/>A RAILROADER'S PRAYER.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> A railroad man is responsibl for the following prayer: "O Lord, now that I have
                                    flagged thee, lift my feet from off the road of life and plant them safely on deck
                                    of the train of salvation! Let me uze the safety lamp known as prudence, make all
                                    couplings in the train with the strong link of thy luv and let my lamp be the Bible.
                                    And, heavenly Father, keep all switches closed that lead off on the sidings,
                                    especially those with a blind end! O Lord, if it be thy pleasure, hav every
                                    semaphore block along the line to show the white light of hope that I may make the
                                    run of life without stopping. And, Lord, giv to us the Ten Commandments as a
                                    schedule, and when I hav finishd the run, and hav on schedule time pulled into the
                                    great station of death, may thou, the Superintendent of the Universe, say with a
                                    smile: 'Well done, thou good and raithful servant. Cum and sign the pay roll and
                                    receiv your check for eternal happiness.' "</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Rehoboth Sunday Herald" TEIform="index"/>Rehohoth Sunday Herald.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life" TEIform="index"/>LIFE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rullhausen, Jessie M." TEIform="persName"/>Jessie M. RulJhausen.</byline><p TEIform="p">A fallen star, a withered flower. A carol hushed in leafy bower, A sighing wind in forest dim
                            After its sweep from rim to rim. A broken wave on ocean vast, A bubble tossed not long to
                            last, A fleecy cloud in heaven's blue, We watch its change now passed from view. A pearly
                            drop of dew so bright, But ah, it melts in morning light. A day of joy, an evening train Of
                            solemn thought, a night of pain. Oh! these portray our life so dear, Its friendships, joys
                            and hopes that cheer. To-day are ours, to-morrow fled As broken buds all withered, dead. The
                            past may die, but from its tomb A sweeter life comes forth to bloom. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unselfish and noble acts..." TEIform="index"/>"Unselfish and noble acts...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"Unselfish and noble acts are the most radiant epochs in the biography of souls. When wrought
                            in earliest youth they lie in the memory of age like the coral islands, green and sunny
                            amidst the melancholy waste of ocean."</p></div2><pb n="218" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="American institute of phrenology" TEIform="index"/>The American Institute of Phrenology
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The American Institute of Phrenology. The annual session of this school of Phrenology
                                will begin on Tuesday, Sept. 3, 1895, and will continue for eight weeks. Those who n.ay
                                "wish to attend, should write at once for particulars to the Publishers of the
                                "Phrenological Journal," 27 East 21st St. New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sunday school times" TEIform="index"/>The Sunday School Times
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Sunday School Times of August 3
                                con tains a highly readable article by Dr. Charles S. Robinson on the much discussed and
                                little understood question what constitutes "Singableness in Music." Dr. Robinson is the
                                compiler of some of the best books of sacred song that have ever been published, and in
                                this article be draws not only on his theoretical knowledge as a hymnologist and
                                musician, but on his practical experience as a maker of music-books. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>Ladies' Home Journal.
                            </head><p TEIform="p">CONTACT WITH A
                                PARENTAL HEART. Obedience ia Worth More Titan CJeog-rapliy to a Child. This lesson of
                                law and obedience, then, is one that needs to combine with love in the very first
                                instruction given to the child. When a boy hears his father say, "My son do this," the
                                impression made upon him needs to be like that made upon the old Hebrews by a "Thus
                                saith the Lord." His father is the only almighty, practically, that the boy has during
                                the first years of his life. Obedience is worth more than geography.Rev. Charles H.
                                Parkhurst, D. D., in August Ladies' Home Journal.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cosmopolitan" TEIform="index"/>Cosmopolitan
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Not since "The Anglomaniacs" has there
                                been so clever a society satire as Henry Fuller's "Pilgrim Sons," which is published in
                                the A ugust Cosmopolitan. The problems involved in "woman's use of the bicycle are so
                                startling and so numerous, under the rapid evolution of this art, that one welcomes a
                                careful discussion of the subject by so trained a mind and so clever a writer as Mrs.
                                Reginald de Ko ven. The Cosmopolitan illustrates Mrs. de Koven's article with a series
                                of poses by professional models. A new sport, more thrilling than any known to Nimrod,
                                more dangerous than was ever experienced by even a Buffalo Bill, is exploited in the
                                same issue in an article on "Photographing Big Game in the Rocky Mountains," before
                                shooting. The idea that ten cents for The Cosmopolitan means inferiority from a literary
                                point of view is dispelled by the appearance in this number of such writers as Sir Lewis
                                Morris, Sir Edwin Arnold, Edgar Fawcett, Tabb, W. Clark Russell, Lang, Sarcey, Zangwill,
                                Agnes Repplier, etc. Nor can we entertain the idea of inferiority in illusti-ation with
                                such names as Hamilton Gibson, Denman, Van Sohaick, Lix, Sandham, etc., figuring as the
                                chief artists of a single month's issue. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Popular monthly" TEIform="index"/>Popular Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly for September is
                                out in a new dress of type, which, with the artistic cover and the broad, hand;-oii.e
                                pages, gives the firest possible setting to its numerous pictorial and literary
                                features. These latter are always of a timely an.I seasonable nature, mid in the current
                                number include: a fascinating paper upon "Mishaps and Mynteries of the Sea," by Mary
                                Titcomb, reviewing the world's great marine disasters, and superbly illustrated w'th
                                drawings by Overend, Davidson, Schell, Burns and Mont bard; the idyllic diary of "A
                                Quiet Summer on Lake Maggiore," by Lena L. Pepper; "A Holiday Trip in Search of Old
                                China," by Mrs. M. K. Leicester Addis; a charming sketch of outdoor festivity in the
                                South, entitled "Al Fresco," by Martha McCulloch Williams; an intimate study of "The
                                Factory Towns of England," by Edward Porrit; "A Chat from Havana," with some timely
                                pictures, by Anna Cronhjelm Wallberg; The Romance of Early California," by J. M.
                                Scanland; "The Story of the Somovar," by W. S. Harwood; and a sketch of the career of
                                the late Professor Huxley, accompanied with an admirable portrait. The September number
                                of Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly contains the opening installment of a new serial
                                story, "The Magnet Stone," by Frances Swann Williams, which bids fair to prove the best
                                work yet offered by this rising young Virginian novelist. Frank Leslie's Publishing
                                House, New York.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Walter Dunlop, a well-known humorous clergyman..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Walter Dunlop, a well-known humorous clergyman...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Waltek DuNiiOP, a well-known humorous clergyman of Scotland, was talking to a brother of the
                            cloth, who in a facetious manner said, "Well, Walter, I believe, after all has been said,
                            that my head could hold two of yours." "Man," replied Walter, with a smile, "I never had
                            thought before that your head was so empty."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pack, Betsey" TEIform="index"/>Betsey Pack
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Betsey Pack, at South Union, Ky., June 16, 1895. Age 61 years and 1 mo. Sister Betsey
                                spent eighteen years in the Community, and was a faithful Sister. J. C. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Clifford, Angeline B." TEIform="index"/>Angeline B.
                                Clifford
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Angeline B.
                                Clifford, at East Canterbury, N. H. July 24,1895. Age 59 years, 7 mo. and 19 days.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hulet, Elvira Curtes" TEIform="index"/>Elvira Curtes Hulet
                            </head><p TEIform="p">
                                Elvira Curtes Hulet, at West Pittsfield, Mass. Aug. 14, 1895. Age 90 years and 8 days.
                                Came to this Society in 1812. I. R. L.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p27"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
THE   CLIMAX.
This  is an Amorican   Stem-wind3T,   UP to date.    It represents  tlie   must  important step taken in watch evolution in many  years.    It  describes  aline beyond
which nothing radical will pass for years, not only in the matter of pi ice, but quality
Two stylos.   Gilt and nickel,   Snap  Imelt,  Itovci crystal,
 8ct.   T^ullj^ tlmetf a
For $2.00 we  will   sen 1   the Watch', ;"id also a copy of Tijk Maxifksto f t one
year, to any address in the U. S.           Address
The   Manifesto.
EAST    CANTERBURY,    X.    JI.
A Visit to the
SHAE11S
of EAST CANTKR U UR Y,   N.  IT.
POUR
By Pressing the Lid.
LLOYDII.
Liberally Illustrated witli half tone
pictures of pkksons and places.
The Village of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the lovliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price 15 cts.
Tea ,'uui  o !> if, thnt pour by tho lid v itb
out hltni_  (ii   t t i> ti       Minple h(^o!Kl belief
J'r (tical i nd   n -1 (     b> ml for pamphlet.
T.1E ASBURV PAINE MFG. CO., Phila., PaThis i   a nonUi i// -Ld.
Tiiyiirafioiuil ll//nnis and fionr/fi, illx.stratlu of !/>( H .stirrti Iton Life and 7V'imoHy o) flu  bhuLas.                10  cts.
CHANDLER. U. S..N.
<pb n="" id="p28"/>
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
,x i i, am of tsirtur baking p iwi'.er.
Highest of all in lciivcnin^" strength.
 Ijjfcst I'ni'i'l iS/'iitcs' (ioreni meitl
Fnotl report.
Eoyal Baking Powder Co.
106 wan st., n: y.
the altruist;.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united lybor, Community honitv, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members ail
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights, in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free.. Address A. Loxglky
Higbee,   Mo.
Stouid have the beautiful 3e-pag_lfpirtlly
 JXIUSTBATED HOME JQVMMQJb^
M'|a. a.year. Samplefree. ,Agnta wanted.
TMOHAS O. irSWXAZr * MHTjl ,
    CHICAGO, IU*,
SYRUP of SARSAPARILLA,
With 1 oz. HYmuODATi! of Potassa to 12 Bottles.
I'HEl-'ARED AT
Shaker 'Ictillagu, Uflfirrhrrack
This medicine has proved to be most
valuable in the 'following diseases :
Chronic Inflammation of the Digestive
Organs; Dyspepsia, or Indigestion; Weakness and, Sourness of the Stomach; liheumalism; Salt, liheum ; Secondary Syphilis;
Functional Disorders of the Liver ; Chronic
Eruptions- of the Skin, and. all Scrofulous
diseases and disorders arising from impurities, of the blood. It is also an excelhiti remedy for the Erysipelas, Asthma,
Dropsy, Dysentery, and Diarrh&a, and
for the complicated diseases of females,
so apt to end in consumption.
Dose.For an adult, a teaspoonful
four or live times a day, with or without
a little water, which may be increased to
a tablespoonful, as best suits the patient.
To guard against counterfeits, observe &
the signature of the inventor on each *
label and on each wrapper.                      $
HUMAN NATURE
is an illustrated Monthly, now only 50 cts.
per    year,    devoted   to   PHEENOLOGY,
PHYSIOGNOMY, HEALTH, MEDICAL
& SOCIAL EEFOEM.
Would you like a copy?
Send 5 cts. for Sample to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Francisco, Cal.
THE MANIFESTO
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>