<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0103" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><date value="18710301" TEIform="date">March 1871</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">17-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="17" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">" I WILL SHAKE ALL NATIONS, AND THE DESIRE OF ALL NATIONS SHALL COME ; AND I WILL FILL THIS HOUSE
                        WITH GLOKY, SAITH THE LORD." Published Monthly, by, and under the direction of the Mt. Lebanon
                        Bishopric. Vol. I. SHAKERS, ALBANY, N. Y., MARCH, 1871. No. 3.</p><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Poetry" TEIform="index"/>POETICAL</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker" TEIform="index"/>"The Shaker."</head><p TEIform="p">I look upon thy simple page, And feel thy mission in my soul; The light that gleam'd from
                                age to age May now shine forth without control. The myriad watch-fires of the Past, With
                                thine their sacred flames shall blend ; And brazen sceptres there be cast, Until
                                oppression's rule shall end. Let not thy searching power slack, Till honored falsehoods
                                come to shame , Till fettering gyve, and torturing rack, Shall melt before thy burning
                                flame. Those agonies the soul must feel, From Error's grasp upon the mind, More painful
                                are than piercing steel, Or iron chains, that clog and bind. How slow Creation's
                                lengthen'd plan Crept on, through periods untold ; From molten globe, to reasoning man,
                                What lessons we shall yet unfold! And history's demotic leaf, Her primer-books grotesque
                                and rude, The heart no longer chill with grief; For now it reads the March of good! Go
                                forth, thou Shaker, shake the earth ; Let her foundations feel thy power, Until
                                establish'd is her worth, And truth and glory are her dower. Go forth and shake the
                                heavens too ; Let thunders roll and lightnings flash ; Let God's eternal law be true,
                                Though man-made systems rend and crash. 'Tis not for creed, nor sect, nor name, That
                                thou slialt speak the word of might; 'Tis not for mortals' wealth nor fame ; But for the
                                holy cause of Right. Go forth ! Work miracles of love! Heal every soul now sick of sin!
                                Go, like the spirit of the Dove, The weary, hopeless heart to win! Thou art the
                                instrument of God ; Keep pure from every earthly taint; Be simple as the shepherd's rod
                                ; And fervent, as the guileless saint. Go forth, and prayers thy course shall speed,
                                Shall fill thee as a gentle gale ; Bear unto every heart its need : The Angels guide!
                                thou cans't not fail.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="D'V., C." TEIform="persName"/>C. D'V.</byline></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Perfection possible" TEIform="index"/>Perfection Possible</head><p TEIform="p">It surely is within my power To be quite perfect one whole hour— No easier one, than
                                twenty-four, And just as well three days or more. Now, if I'm good three days, or four,
                                Why not as well one hundred more? And if so long I wisely steer, Why not be good
                                throughout the year?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="L., G." TEIform="persName"/>G. L.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion and spiritualism; 'a state without a church'" TEIform="index"/>Religion and
                            Spiritualism. "A State without a Church."</head><p TEIform="p">In the new Era, which opened about the year 1792, two marked and typical characters arose,
                            coming up, or (as it were), being evolved from the general elements of humanity—Ann Lee and
                            Emanuel Swedenborg: Ann as the embodiment of the Religious, and Swedenborg of the
                            Spiritualistic elements. Swedenborg was born in 1688, and died in 1772. Ann was born in
                            1736, and died in 1784. Thus they were cotemporary for thirty-six years, and she lived
                            twelve years after his death. Ann was born of lowly parentage, in Toad lane (now Todd
                            street), Manchester, England, with no genealogical family-tree known to history or fame; a
                            poor and humble Gentile woman. She was one of the " common people " who so gladly heard the
                            teachings of Jesus. From a child, her mind was religiously exercised about right, and wrong,
                            good and evil, holiness and unholiness. She literally hungered and thirsted after
                            righteousness; had deep and powerful convictions of sin, in relation to many things held in
                            high estimation by popular Christians, particularly the use and abuse of the reproductive
                            powers and faculties of human beings. Marriage intensified those convictions, and brought
                            her under great tribulation of soul, which caused her to cry to God for entire deliverance
                            from the thraldom of sin in general. At an early age, she began to have visions, having
                            found an entrance into the spirit world. After some nine years of great spiritual suffering
                            of soul, in 1770, occurred the great event of her life, and of the age in which she lived.
                            Jesus appeared to her in person, and baptized her into and with the Christ Spirit, as John
                            had baptized him. By his ministration, the eyes of her understanding " were opened " to
                            discover the " foundations of the world," and to see plainly that they were "out of course."
                            The primary causes of the alienation and consequent separation from God of humanity were
                            clearly revealed ; and the whole work of redemption, operating through the Four great
                            Dispensations of human salvation, from beginning to end, were made so " plain" that there
                            was no occasion to " err " in coming to practical conclusions. God had set his hand " the
                            second time to redeem Israel" from the bondage of sin. And the Christ Spirit, through Jesus,
                            said to Ann, "' Thou art the woman of sin' who needest redemption (for she was as are all
                            mankind, ' clothed in filthy garments ' of unrighteousness); repent, confess to some mortal
                            being like yourself, as a witness for God; and then forsake ; and thou shalt preach this
                            Gospel to other souls, that they may follow you as you have followed Jesus, and baptize
                            other souls as you have been baptized with the Christ Spirit." Adam Clark says : "In
                            speaking of the second appearance of Christ,—the opening of a new dispensation,—it must
                            commence with some particular individual; in some particular place, and at some specified
                            time." Evidently, the way to redeem humanity, as a whole, was thus to begin with one, human
                            being, as a nucleus, for Christians to gather to, in the founding of a Gentile Pentecostal
                            Church—a Community of goods,—on the basis of Celibacy and Peace. This was religion—cease to
                            do evil; learn to do well—distinct from mere theology. Religion in this illiterate woman,
                            and in her followers, would create its own theology, as the soul creates and shapes its own
                            body. The principal point of her testimony was in relation to human sexuality. While Ann
                            came from the lower strata of society, so far as literary and scientific attainments were
                            concerned, Swedenborg came from the upper classes. His father was a bishop ; and the family
                            was ennobled by the Sovereign of Sweden—Queen Ulrica Eleonora. " Swedenborg's parentage and
                            home," says his biographer, "were happy omens of his future life. He was brought up with
                            strict, but kindly care; was educated by his father in all innocence and scientific
                            learning; and enjoyed the opportunities afforded by the sphere and example of family
                            virtues, accomplishments, and high station, with which he was surrounded." These were great
                            advantages, and calcu<pb n="18" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 18 THE SHAKER. lated to prepare him to associate
                            with the noble, the great, and the learned of " this world.1" In this respect he was the
                            antipode of Ann Lee. Yet there were points of similarity, as when he says, " from my fourth
                            to my tenth year, my thoughts were constantly engrossed by reflecting on God, on salvation,
                            and on the spiritual affections of man." (Swedenborg addressed the understand- ing with
                            logic, and ministered convincement. Ann addressed herself to the heart, and ministered
                            conviction.) "I often revealed things, in my discourse, which filled my parents with
                            astonishment, and made them declare, at times, that certainly the angels spoke through my
                            mouth. It was my greatest delight to converse with the clergy concerning faith." Yet, when
                            eleven years of age, he knew nothing of the "plan of salvation," as it is called. His
                            father, being a Spiritualist, was not very orthodox. He writes: "I am not inclined myself,
                            and would be far from persuading any one to credulity and superstition. But may not the
                            all-wise God, in all ages, think it necessary, by extraordinary instances, to fix upon the
                            minds of mankind some signal impressions of his over-ruling power, and of the truth of his
                            holy Gospel?" This was very significant for those times ; and such a father could not fail
                            to impress his son as a Spiritualist. It is said to be darkest just "before the dawn; and
                            the " darkness which had covered the earth " and the Churches—"the gross spiritual darkness
                            which covered the whole people " —was never more dense than at that Epoch. In Rev. xviii, it
                            is said, " I saw an angel come down from heaven, having great power, and the earth was
                            lightened with his glory." Swedenborg was the leading medium of this angel to the in-
                            habitants of earth. " He was the most transcendent human being that has ever yet shone upon
                            our dark (Gentile) world. Even in science and philosophy, he nobly strode a century before
                            his time. He was a man, take him for all in all, the most nobly gifted of any of the sons of
                            earth, both on the side of nature and of spirit. This opening of the spiritual, was Sweden-
                            borg's tendency from the first. He expected the kingdom of God to come upon him in the shape
                            of clear principles deduced from all human knowledge; a scientific theology, resting upon
                            nature and revelation, interpreted by analogy and synthesis, from the ground of a pure habit
                            and a holy life. His ascent from the natural to the spiritual was step by step from the deep
                            mines and rudiments of the mineral kingdom ('he was known as the Assessor'), passing
                            gradually upwards through the mysteries of organic nature to the human soul itself." " His
                            discoveries and teachings in geology, mineralogy, botany, natural history, animal and human
                            physiology, chemistry, crystalography, mathematics, mechanics, astronomy, and natural
                            philosophy, show how deeply the world is indebted to the labors of this ' great humble man,'
                            in whose works can be found the seeds of principles of all that is known of the essences,
                            forms, powers and uses of universal matter ; and how far he was in advance of Bacon, Newton,
                            Laplace, Kepler, Herschel, Cuvier, or any other man, as a theorist and author, yet free from
                            all jealousies and animosities growing out of any of them, as to who should be the greatest
                            in the kingdom of Nature. It was said of him, that ' He set one foot of the compass of truth
                            in God, and with the other swept all creation, both animate and inanimate, as seer,
                            theologian, and philosopher of spirit.' " These are high claims; but he was the angel of
                            Spiritualism, and the true prototype of Spiritualists; as Ann was the " angel seen standing
                            in the sun (Rev. 19: 17), crying to all the fowls that fly in the midst of heaven, come and
                            gather yourselves together unto the supper of the great God, that ye may eat the flesh of
                            kings, and the flesh of captains, and the flesh of mighty men, both free and bond, small and
                            great. And the beast was taken, and with him the false prophet that wrought miracles by
                            Spiritualism, before him, with which he deceived them that received the mark of the beast,
                            and them that worshiped his image. These both were cast alive into a lake of fire burning
                            with brimstone." And she was a true type of " the remnant that was slain by the sword of him
                            that sat upon the horse, which sword proceeded out of his mouth;" and was the testimony of
                            the Christ Spirit against "fleshly" generation, and all the doleful works of darkness; from
                            which, neither Swedenborg nor his followers have as yet been delivered. Spiritualism is the
                            mother of the sciences, and the esse of all theology. Swe- denborg personified the spirit
                            and truth of the first Gentile Christian Church, including the imperfect theology of the
                            Apostles, and of their Greek and Roman Catholic successors, and claims that Jesus personally
                            appeared in vision to him. There was truth in his claim to be the messenger, or harbinger,
                            of the descent of the New Jerusalem Church on earth. " In 1767, our author was still in
                            Stockholm, observing with care the effect produced by his writings ; he being then 79 years
                            of age, thus replied to the question, How soon is the New Church to be expected ? ' The Lord
                            is preparing, at this time, a new heaven of such aa believe in him, and acknowledge him to
                            be the true God of heaven and earth; and also look to Him in their lives, which is to shun
                            evil, and do good; because from that heaven shall the New Jerusalem mentioned in Rev. 21: 2,
                            descend. I daily see spirits and angels, from ten to twenty thousand, descending and
                            ascending7 who are set in order. By degrees, as that heaven is formed, the New Church
                            likewise begins and increases. The Universities in Christendom are now first instructed,
                            from whence will come viinisters ; because the new heaven has no influence over the old
                            clergy, who conceive themselves to be too well skilled in the doctrine of justification by
                            faith alone.' " Is not this testimony and witness of Swedenborg (whom Ann declared to be her
                            John the Baptist) transcendent!)' interesting ? in view of the testimony of Mother Ann and
                            her virgin followers,— the Shakers,—that the time had folly come for the second appearing of
                            Christ, that the reign of the beast and of Jiis image—the Catholic and Protestant world —in
                            combined Church and State governments, and involving the power of religious persecution, by
                            the sword in the hands of civil rulers, ended in the final success of the American
                            Revolution, and the establishment of a new earthly or civil government by skeptical powers
                            that had grown out of the beast, on the basis of pure materialism ; which government
                            excluded the priests of all religious denominations from civil power, and declared entire
                            liberty of conscience, in matters of theology, from the Hindoo to the Atheist; treating with
                            all human beings simply in relation to their civil rights ; and excluding theology from the
                            Constitution of the United States. And, in 1793, the Gentile Pentecostal Church of "all
                            things common "—the Shaker Order—was founded in New Lebanon, N. Y. Here are two witnesses to
                            the same thing: the creation in this, and in the the spirit world, of a " new heaven and a
                            new earth;" a new Church, which is not of this world, and will not fight; and a new civil
                            government without a Church. Thus the dissolution of the old order of Church and State
                            Governments has commenced—the beginning of the end of the old world. Swedenborg says: "All
                            confirmations in things pertaining to theology are, as it were, glued fast in the brain, and
                            can with difficulty be removed; and, whilst they remain, genuine truths can find no place."
                            " Besides, the new heaven of Christians, <pb n="19" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE S H .A. K E R . 19 from
                            whence the New Jerusalem from the Lord will descend (Rev. 21:1 and 2), is not yet perfectly
                            settled, "—Letters to Dr, Beyer. A practical life of righteousness, by characters formed
                            after the pattern of Jesus, was the only means by which God could work the work of
                            redemption among the human race on earth, and finally create, in the spirit world, a " New
                            Heaven," having for its foundations the New Church on earth ; and having for its founders
                            souls who, while in the body, had accepted the testimony of Mother Ann. Inasmuch as it is
                            not known that Swedenborg was acquainted with Ann Lee, or her testimony, his witness is the
                            more wonderful in its character, and astonishing ifl its accuracy!! " In every view of
                            mankind, and in each fresh system of doctrines which pro- fesses to apply itself to the
                            wants of an age, the subject of marriage can hardly fail to have an important place. In many
                            systems, indeed, it furnishes the experimentum crucis, and at once decides their
                            pretensions." This is emphatically the case with the Shaker system, which claims to be (and
                            really is) the Resurrection Order, and above the marriage relation. " The author affirms,
                            upon a union of experimental and rational evidence, that sex is a permanent fact in human
                            nature ; that men are men, and women women, in the highest heavens, as here on earth; that
                            it is the soul which is male or female ; and that sex is thence derived into the mortal
                            body, and into the natural world. Therefore that the difference of sexes is brighter and
                            more exquisite in proportion as the person is high, and the sphere pure. M The distinction
                            not only reaches to the individual, but it is anatomically minute besides: every thought,
                            affection, and sense of a male is male, and of a female is feminine. The smallest drop of
                            intellect or will, is inconvertible between the sexes; if man's, it can never become
                            woman's, nor vice versa. " The sexual distinction is foundec upon the two radical attributes
                            of God upon his Divine Love and his Divine Wisdom, whereof the former is feminine and the
                            latter is masculine." John the Baptist never approximatec nearer to Jesus, than did
                            Swedenborg to Ann; for this is simple Shakerism in its rudimentals, that God is dual—male
                            anc female; that the Christs are dual; anc that the second manifestation of the Chris was in
                            a woman, for the reason above assigned—difference of sex. the "wilderness" (see Rev. xii.)
                            "Make straight paths" for the coming female Messiah. For, like John, he only taught human
                            beings to return to the paths of virtue from which they had strayed; to turn the hearts of
                            the parents to the children, and the hearts of the children back to the Apostle Paul, and
                            his Gentile associates. How different the case with Ann, who opened a radically-new and
                            living way. While the followers of Swedenborg are known by their complex system of theology
                            ; in their lives they are like all other men and women of the world, in respect to
                            generation, nutrition, and property; the disciples of Mother Ann—" the virgins, her
                            companions, who follow her"— are led unto the King, Jesus, by the Christ Spirit; and, after
                            a hundred years of isolation and obloquy, are known as laving solved the problem that men
                            and women can be " neither male or female ^eneratively ; but are one in Christ Jesus," and
                            live a pure, Christian life; and that, too, under greater temptations than ever Jesus or his
                            Apostles, or any of the celibate Orders under the first appearing of Christ to either Jews
                            or Gentiles were subjected to, and stood the test. For the " stars of heaven
                            "—celibates—still " fell to the earth as figs from the tree, when shaken with a mighty
                            wind." See Dixon's " Spiritual Wives." All human beings, of all nations, sects, tongues, and
                            races, whatever their theology, and whether rich or poor, learned or unlearned, fall under
                            the power of the same passions and emotions, from the Esquimaux to the Swedenborgian; and
                            still seek indulgence through a perverted use of the powers and faculties of their own
                            being. The Shakers are the only exception to this rule; for only they deny themselves of
                            lust, in all its imperious craving, whether in eating or drinking, or in the exceedingly
                            perverted order of reproduction. "My kingdom is not of this world," said Jesus ; " therefore
                            my servants will not fight." Yet Swedenborg had no testimony against war, or any other of
                            the ruling lusts of mankind. Still he " lightened " the earth with the glory of his
                            knowledge, scientific and spiritual; he walked in kings' palaces. The kings and queens, and
                            nobles of the earth—the higher classes of society—were converted to Spiritualism through his
                            agency; while his daughters, the Fox girls, were ministers to the "common people, who have
                            heard them gladly;" they having been the mediums of great power in converting materialists,
                            skeptics, infidels, in and out of the Churches, to a belief in the realities of The
                            Resurrection Order, founded by \.nn is raising sex up from the physical &gt;Iane to the
                            Christ, spiritual plane, where ;here is no " marrying nor giving in mariage." And, while
                            Mother Ann appreciated Swedenborg, and understood his mision better than he did himself, Ann
                            and ler mission were not at all apprehended )y Swedenborg. He acknowledged that le daily saw
                            thousands of the angels human souls) descending and ascending to and from the earth. ~\ye
                            say they visited Mother Ann, to whom many of them confessed their sins. For she affirmed
                            just as did Swedenborg, that she was 1 more familiar with the souls of men and women out of
                            the body than she was with those who were in the body; and that she frequently heard them
                            confess their sins." Here was the dividing line. For, while Swedenborg knew that a new
                            heaven was jeing founded, he knew not by whom; nor did he know of its fundamental
                            princi3les; nor how much himself and his fol- lowers would have to drop and shake off, in
                            order to find an entrance thereinto. For they also belong to the old generative heaven and
                            earth, which are passing away: for Swedenborg never ascended above the beavens of the first
                            Christian Church, composed of Gentiles, in the spirit world and upon earth. But he
                            understood far better than Ann, naturally, what is known as the circle of sciences, the
                            "Arcana" of Nature; Swedenborg being the body, and Mother Ann the soul of the coming
                            order—Spiritualism and Religion. Nor does Swedenborg appear to have ever learned the radical
                            distinction of the two Christian Churches—Jew and Gentile; nor the fact of the existence of
                            the Jewish Pentecostal Church in the spiritual world, —the home of Jesus and his Apostles,—
                            as a sun to this earth, spiritually; nor that that Church embodied a distinct system of
                            natural truths (as Moses declared) pertaining to man's earth life;—nutrition, generation,
                            agriculture, chemistry ; indeed all the sciences along in their order, as they have a
                            practical relation to man as a religious being, who is bound in all things to do right; and
                            that in doing right, all causes of suffering (bodily diseases included) would be banished
                            from that portion of humanity. Though Swedenborg's " knoivledge on earth was marvelously
                            increased; " and holiness was still more marvelously increased through the sufferings and
                            travail of soul of Mother Ann; for, although he was a good man under Christ's first
                            appearing among the Gentiles—was the Gentile Jesus; and, as such, made it possible foi the
                            manifestation of Christ in a female,, being her forerunner,—a voice crying in <pb n="20" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 2O THE SHAKER. the unseen world ; and thus has the spirit of Spiritualism been
                            "poured out upon all flesh." Even handmaids and servants see visions, as did Swedenborg; and
                            men prophesy, as nominal Christians and the followers of the Swedish seer have never done;
                            for, actually and practically, the Swedenborgians have no more spirituality than have the
                            average of common Spiritualists. Yet, while the followers of Ann Lee are also undoubted
                            Spiritualists—believers in spiritual manifestations, the immor- tality of the human soul,
                            the intercommunication between the visible and invisible worlds—they " have no confidence in
                            the flesh; " but, for their justification, rely upon living lives of pure Christianity,
                            similar to that of Jesus and the Pentecostal converts. In conclusion, it may be observed,
                            that there was one point of distinction and most marked contrast, in the different and
                            opposite effects produced by the testimonies of Swedenborg and Mother Ann upon "the world."
                            While Swedenborg personally retained its " friendship," was the welcome and honored guest of
                            European Sovereigns and their courts, and a favorite of the Swedish nation, particularly of
                            the nobles and religious hierarchy ; Mother Ann excited the furious rage of the Clergy, and
                            the dragonenmity of the high, professing Christians of all denominations, without exception.
                            And in proportion to their religious zeal, did they think that they were doing God's
                            service, by pouring out of their mouths, a flood of slanders, to carry away the woman and
                            the remnant of her seed—the Shakers. But "the earth opened its mouth, and swallowed up the
                            flood"— which " earth," being the Materialists, and infidels generally, who hated
                            Christianity as a generative theology, because it was constantly whoring after, and
                            committing adultery with the State, then using it as a cat's paw, with which to hunt and
                            punish heretics, by horrid inquisitions! The Materialists having separated, effectually and
                            eternally, Church and State in the government of the United States, let not the Clergy
                            impiously seek to join together what God, through them, has put asunder. " Eternal
                            vigilance," on this subject, " is the price of the liberty" of conscience.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="E., F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. E.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Genuine Christianity began its career..." TEIform="index"/>Genuine Christianity began its career..."
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Genuine Christianity began its career by dissolving the marriage tie, and making the man and
                            woman nearer and dearer relatives—brother and sister. Popular Christianity has reversed this
                            rule of life ; and all the marriages it can solemnize, so much more honor to its ehnrchee !
                            Jesus and his followers were Tirgins, or became single for a purpose. Millions rely for
                            their salvation upon the merits of Jesus. '• Behold, I come quickly, to give to every one
                            according to their works." In the death of Jesns there is no hope, only as he died unto sin
                            ; in his life there is endless progression for all who will pattern it.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's spiritual house, or the perfected latter day temple" TEIform="index"/>God's Spiritual
                            House, or the Perfected Latter Day Temple</head><p TEIform="p">The order of God's spiritual House (when perfected) will be beautifully glorious. We,
                            Believers in Christ's second appearing claim, that the foundations of the latter day temple
                            are laid; and, who will say that God was not there ? He (speaking in ancient times by one of
                            his Prophets) said, " Mine hand hath laid the foundations of the earth; and my right hand
                            hath spanned the heavens: when I call, they stand up together." The old heavens and earth
                            are out of course. Man and woman were created iD honor; but they abode not in that honor.
                            They were endowed with reasoning powers, and were placed as riders over inferior beings, and
                            executives of those laws which God had established for the guidance and protection of all
                            grades of animal and vegetable life, having less intelligence than themselves in the earthly
                            order. Had they not inverted and perverted those laws, by corrupting the highest functions
                            of their natures, and violated the trust committed to them on the earth plane, they would,
                            unto this day, have remained lords, or just rulers— a central power— a governing wheel; all
                            the rest of the machinery, as wheels within wheels, would have worked harmoniously, each in
                            its proper sphere contributing to aid the central governing force—man and woman. They would
                            have walked together keeping the commands of God, and "the counsel of peace" would have been
                            " between them both." This was God's original plan, that each—the male and female—should
                            have their appropriate sphere of action, working in harmony, with one accord, for the good
                            of each other, and for the accomplishment of one great end. Woman, it is said, was first
                            tempted—first beguiled—and became a leader in the wrong direction; instead of being a
                            connecting link between man and angels, she placed herself on the opposite side of the
                            scale, and drew him down to the inferior; and herself became a servant to the instincts of
                            her own nature, and a slave to the baser passions of man; and, instead of occupying a place
                            in his counsels, according to the original plan, she became an appendage; her will
                            subjugated to his will— not because of abstract right, but because of his might. Hence, he
                            makes laws, and she is forced to obey them ; common justice is denied her because she is the
                            weaker vessel. According to the laws which man frames, without the consent of woman (and by
                            the usages of society) she is forced to work for half pay; and the little wealth which she
                            accumulates by toiling weary hours when he can rest (by means of double pay which he
                            receives for performing the same labor), she is taxed without representation on her part.
                            This is her reward for being found on the wrong side ! But now, God hath again put forth his
                            hand and laid the foundation of a new spiritual building; a new divine order, or heaven, is
                            established upon a new temporal basis—community of goods, new earth. In this new heaven and
                            earth which are being formed, in which righteousness and holiness shall bear rule according
                            to God's will, not man's, the eternal, unchangeable laws of justice and right will prevail,
                            and the male and female will stand in their proper place: " and His right hand will span
                            them both." In this new order of things, woman must be purified and elevated : first,
                            purified ! Then she will stand erect, according to the design of the Master-builder. Side by
                            side, man and woman must walk and work, in all that is honest, pure, just and true, taking
                            harmonious counsel together in all things pertaining to the present and future life. Woman
                            is not man's equal in physical strength; neither, as a general rule, is she his equal in
                            logic and the sterner qualities of the mind; but she possesses some properties which he does
                            not; and combine the faculties of both, and when redeemed from the blight of sin, they will
                            make one perfect whole, without schism, capable of honoring God, and beautifying the earth.
                            It is for man's interest that woman should find and fill her proper sphere, and be something
                            higher, purer, and better than a slave to man's passions, and to make a way for her to
                            become a co-worker with him in elevating the race. How much her influence is needed in all
                            ranks of society ! Let woman use her intelligence to find out her proper sphere of action,
                            and in what consists her adorning, and she will soon cease to desire to be a mere thing of
                            outward beauty, or an idol to be worshipped. Her strongest desire will be, to become a
                            saving power; to send forth her influence to calm the raging passions of perverted nature,
                            and rule the angry waves that roll. There is a great work to be accomplished by woman, on
                            what we term the earthly (or generative) plane. She must work to roll back the the flood of
                            sensuality—the giant sin of our time, which finds its wray into all ranks of society—is
                            destroying the youth of our land by thousands, and is gnawing at the vitals of its subjects
                            and bringing them to premature graves. Sensuality is the parent of war! By it, all other
                            base passions are set in motion which ultimate in bloodshed and carnage, and fill the land
                            with mourning and lamentation. It will devolve upon them (in a large measure) to correct the
                            abuses of the marriage rela- tion in the order in which it properly belongs, and to strip
                            off the cloak of sin which has covered it over, and point out its uses, and in trumpet
                            tongues condemn its abuses. But those to whom the spirit has spoken, saying, " Come up
                            hither on the higher or resurrection plane, and live as do the Angels— live above the
                            marriage order, even in its best estate ; have a high and important mission to perform." A
                            broad field is open, and there is much work to be done. In our own loved home we are solving
                            a great problem : Whether it is possible for human beings, under a sense of duty and deep
                            religious feeling—love to God and humanity — to come together under the same roof, from
                            different nations, different religious sects and non-professors, and form a brotherhood and
                            sisterhood, so unselfish, that we can toil together in harmony-—in honor preferring others;
                            and to eat the bread of industry together (which is always sweet), <pb n="21" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THESBCA-KKR. 21 supporting one interest temporally, creating one joint treasury, as did the
                            Apostles of Jesus. And, as the soul and body are so closely connected, while we learn to
                            break our temporal bread together, so also do we learn to eat our spiritual food together at
                            the Lord's table. Industry, Frugality and Temperance being our motto; Truth, Purity and Love
                            the standard around which we gather. As we do not recognize high nor low, rich nor poor, in
                            this new relation, so neither do we find the male and female, as in the old order. "All are
                            one in Christ, working together for the one universal good." And, while we stand firmly upon
                            the rock, Virgin Purity, and are as angels of purity and innocence to our brethren, our feet
                            wTill never be displaced; in all our relations with them we shall be true helpmates, worthy
                            the dignified name, of " Sisters in Christ," sharing the burdens of life with them, and have
                            a place in their councils, and stand by them in the hour of trial — to light their pathway
                            and make home cheerful and happy. We recognize the law of dependency running through all
                            created things; the lesser leaning upon the greater — the weaker upon the stronger. Man is
                            the lawful head, and is the representative of God in the male order, the Eternal Father, and
                            will always have the supremacy. Woman, the representative of God in the female part of
                            Deity, Mother, must act her part as co-worker, filling her sphere. There is no bondage in
                            the law of dependency, even as there is no bondage in any of God's laws! for, without law,
                            all would be chaos. But when all his laws are faithfully executed, there will a beautiful
                            structure rise up from the ruins of disregarded and broken law, that will stand upon the
                            mountain of pure truth, and overlook all the hills and valleys below, and it will be a
                            "house of prayer for all nations," and unto it many people will gather.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>Antoinette</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The R. C. Church demands of its Pope, Bishops and Priests..." TEIform="index"/>The R. C. Church demands of its Pope, Bishops and Priests...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The R. C. Church demands of its Pope, Bishops and Priests celibacy in the extreme ; very
                            good, much like Jesus. Now, a curious anomaly is here made apparent: a pure head—if celibacy
                            intends purity— and a corrupt body—if marriage, and fleshly lusts are the opposite of
                            celibacy. How can the laity hope, or much less expect to go, where their pure-minded priests
                            are rewarded? "I am the way."</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="But there is a higher life revealed in Scripture..." TEIform="index"/>But there is a higher life revealed in Scripture...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"But there is a higher life revealed in Scriptnre—a life by which an individual may
                            voluntarily forego the mystery of marriage, to become more and more absorbed in devotion to
                            the duties of the spiritual union of Christ and Church; a life in which the love of the
                            antitype may be even so great as to banish from the mind all thought of the type,
                            concentrating all the affections of the soul upon the reality of the substance—a life so
                            entirely free from the temporal, with all its joys, and cares, and entanglements, as to see
                            nothing, to think of nothing, and to long for nothing but the eternalChrist Himself, and the
                            fruition of his glorious Godhead ! How can it lie denied that the Scriptures do reveal to us
                            the the possibility of such a life ; and tha it is the life of the celibate 'for the Kingdom
                            of Heaven's sake ? '—not the life of the mere unmarried, which in itself considered is one
                            of the most selfish of all lives, and which is not nnfrequently chosen foi the sake of
                            selfish and criminal indulgence ; but the life of the celibate ' for the Kingdom of Heaven's
                            sake?' Our blessed Lord said, indeed, ' All men cannot receive this saying, save they to
                            u-hom it is given; bttt he that is able to receive it, let him receive it? "</p><byline TEIform="byline">—From Holy Matrimony, by <persName reg="Bolles, J. A." TEIform="persName"/>Dr. J. A. Bolles</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian distinction, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>Christian Distinction—No. 2</head><p TEIform="p">Self-denial is one of the fundamental laws of growth for man on the primeval, or earthly
                            plane of his existence. Not entire abstinence iom enjoyment, but such abnegation as shall
                            ^reserve all his faculties inharmonious balance. There is a constant tendency in human
                            nature ;o run to excess, so that one needs to keep a perpetual guard over himself. Sometimes
                            he is attracted by the charms of sensual indulgence, and again by what he regards as the
                            pure pleasures of intellectual gratification. He may have become so absorbed in intel-
                            lectual gratification] he may have become so absorbed in intellectual pursuits, as to
                            neglect bis physical and moral natures. It is no excuse that the pleasures of sense plead so
                            powerfully for indulgence ; nor, that the more refined enjoyments of the intellect ask for
                            an unrestricted field for action ; nor that the moral powers, under the delusive plea of
                            serving God assert their supremacy; and their especial right to exclusive indulgence.
                            Intoxication is the word to be applied to all this one-sided self-indulgence of whatever
                            kind. There is no place for indulgence in God's service; every talent must be made to
                            perform its proper and necessary part in the work of life. " Whatsoever thy hand findeth to
                            do, do it with thy might." "Apply thy heart unto wisdom," for, " that the soul be without
                            knowledge it is not good." " Keep thy heart with all diligence, for out of it are the issues
                            of life." These injunctions of Sacred Writ are binding on all men, under all circumstances,
                            just so far as those circumstances allow of their observing them. Their observance is
                            necessary, in order to keep us from running into excess of any kind, as well as to avoid the
                            other extreme of evil—a barren soul. If dissipation, whether of the senses, of the mental
                            faculties, or of the moral powers, is an essential injury to the individual, so are
                            uncultivated, unfruitful faculties. Desolation and death are the results not only of
                            excesses in the use of God's blessings, but of neglect to improve them. In contradistinction
                            to all those whose lives are given to sensual indulgences and whose thoughts are engrossed
                            with earthly things, the genuine Christian lives constantly under the influence and
                            direction of the Divine Spirit, and hence his affections are placed upon heavenly things,
                            rather than upon things of the earth. " Our citizenship or community," (according to the
                            original,) "is in the heavens. As individuals our names are enrolled with those of the city
                            of God, the heavenly Jerusalem, and as a body, we are one with that community in the
                            heavens; our life is the same as their life, our interest the same as theirs ; our loves,
                            our aspirations, our efforts are all tending God-ward as well as theirs; hence, though
                            living upon the earth, we are not of the earth, but really of the heavens. It is true, our
                            present state is one of humiliation compared with what it shal! be, but we are looking for
                            the Saviour who will change this state of things in due time, by the inward operations of
                            his Spirit, so that we shal become, in all respects like his church in glory." There is an
                            interchange of expressions made by Jesus Christ and the apostles, hat is deserving our
                            consideration. Jesus directed his disciples to pray: " thy kingdom come, thy will be done on
                            earth, as it is in leaven." Again he said, " No doubt, the kingdom of God has come unto
                            you," and, "the kingdom of heaven is within you." The apostle Paul said to Christians: " Ye
                            are come to the City of God, the heavenly Jerusalem, to an innumerable company of angels,
                            and the spirits of just men made perfect." The coming of the kingdom of God to us, and our
                            coming to the heavenly Jerusalem, then, are convertible expressions. There is implied,
                            something more than being admitted at some indefinite time in the future to the privileges
                            of citizenship in the heavenly state. The community of believers is already in the heavens,
                            and the life of the heavenly world is theirs now. That being the case, their affections
                            cannot be placed on things of the earth; hence the grief of the apostle on account of those
                            who were sensual, instead of being spiritual; they had in reality severed their relation to
                            Christ and his kingdom. Instead of being dead to sin, and alive to God, they were dead in
                            sin; they had no communion with beings of the heavenly state; the angels of God did not
                            associate with them as with familiar and congenial spirits, as they did with Jesus, the
                            Apostles, and all who lived truly Christian lives. There is hardly anything in the Apostolic
                            writings more evident than the fact of the intimate connection between the body of Christ on
                            the earth, and his body or church in the heavenly world. They are represented as being risen
                            with Christ, sitting together in heavenly places in Christ, and as having Christ formed
                            within them the hope of glory. God's fullness, or complete spiritual possession, was said to
                            be in Christ; the same term was applied to his Church. There was a oneness between him and
                            them as between him and the Father. It is true, the church was expecting another
                            manifestation of him, but it was only a manifestation differing in degree, and not in its
                            essential nature. Christ had already come as a Saviour from sin; they were looking for him a
                            second time, yet that was to be "without sin unto salvation." "We know that when he shall
                            appear, we shall be like him." Salvation from sin, or from the tendency to transgress God's
                            law of love, was the characteristic work of Christ's first manifestation ; a complete
                            deliverance from the nature that is subject to trials, and liable to fall into sin, is the
                            glorious and crowning work of the second. "Ye were sealed with the Holy Spirit of promise,
                            which is the earnest of our inheritance until the redemption of the purchased possession."
                            It was, then, no unmeaning, or self-exalting language that the apostle addressed to the
                            church at Philippi, when he exhorted them to be "joint imitators " of himself. For he,
                            himself, followed Christ in his entire life. If Jesus suffered humiliation, so did he; if
                            Jesus underwent severe trials, he partook of the same, being in weariness and painfulness
                            often;" if Jesus labored incessantly for the welfare of others, Paul also showed that he was
                            actuated by the same benevolent motives, by his abundant labors in <pb n="22" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 22
                            THE SHA.KEH. behalf of others. Jesus, for the joy that was set before him, endured the
                            cross, despising the shame; Paul, also, forgetting the things that were behind, pressed
                            toward the mark, for the prize of his high calling in Christ Jesus. "Let as many of us as
                            are perfect," said he, " be thus minded ; let this mind be in you, which was also in
                            Christ." The exhortation then, to follow himself, was most befitting. It would lead them
                            from this state of humiliation to glory, an object worthy of their highest aspirations. By
                            imitating Paul they would become united to him in spirit, as he was united to Christ, and as
                            Christ was united to God and the whole heavenly host. Thus, they would be made partakers of
                            the life of all—their love, their peace, their joy, and their exalted blessedness. Being
                            imitators of him, they Avould be saved from the evils that were in the world through lust,
                            would keep themselvs unspotted from sin, perfecting holiness in the fear of the Lord. The
                            Spirit of Christ that was effectual to purify them from evil inclinations, was also
                            efficacious to create and maintain in them all, pure af fections. They lived in harmony with
                            each other, and the same power that wrought in them their kind feelings toward each other,
                            also enabled them to conduct themselves honestly and peacefully towards those without their
                            body. Hence, they avoided all occasions of dispute with others as far as pospible. And
                            though they suffered persecutions, they bore all with the same equanimity that Jesus did
                            under similar circumstances. There is no fact better substantiated by history, than that of
                            the peaceable behaviour of the early Christians towards their most bitter opponents, and
                            their refraining from wars and con- tests of every kind, even though they were carried on by
                            those governments of which they were regarded as the subjects. The very genius of their
                            religion required it; and the Divine Spirit of Christ wrought in them an aversion to wars,
                            and enabled them to bear whatever persecutions might arise in consequence of their refusal
                            to engage in them. It is true, the philosophy of their day as well as much of that of the
                            present time, has ascribed their power of endurance amid the severest sufferings to the
                            obstinacy and the sustaining power of fanaticism. That was to be expected from its entire
                            ignorance of the sustaining power which the religion of Christ afforded to its faithful
                            martyrs. If their citizenship was in the heavens, their life should be in accordance with
                            that fact. As a matter of course then, they owed no allegiance to any government whose
                            spirit was in direct contrast to that of which they were the accepted citizens. It was very
                            natural that their enemies should ascribe their avowal of allegiance to Christ to obstinacy,
                            superstition and fanaticism, yet that did not alter the facts in the case. The faithful
                            adherents of Christ, claimed to know what they maintained with so much earnestness ; and
                            their opportunities of knowing were certainly superior to those of their adversaries, whose
                            bare assertions many have been disposed to regard as philosophic truth. The Church of
                            Christ, then, in the apostles' day, was a community separated from the common practices of
                            the world; from its wars and contentions of every sort; from its ambitions, its tyrannies,
                            its slaveries, whether of body or soul; from its monarchies, its aristocracies, its
                            democracies, or whatever form of worldly gevernment. It was also distinct from the very
                            spirit and life of the world. It had renounced all sensuality, whether in the form of
                            gluttony, of drunkenness or of licentious passion, and every thing that was contrary to
                            divine purity and love ; and if any adhered to it who were not of this character they were
                            such as excited the tears of the apostle for their lack of the genuine spirit of
                            Christianity. It was a community sui generis—peculiar to itself, existing upon the earth
                            amid its various governments, and yet having its citizenship in the heavenly world ;
                            acknowledging Christ as its head, and his laws as the supreme rule of its life; whom they
                            were expecting to make a second manifestation to themselves for the purpose of completing
                            the work of salvation he had begun in them, and fitting them for an entrance into the
                            society and blessedness of the church in eternal glory. The Church of Christ in the present
                            day should be no less separated from those things which the apostolic church shunned, than
                            they; and it would not be unreasonable to suppose, that, if possible, it should be more so,
                            after the lapse of so many centuries. It should have greater power of the Divine Spirit to
                            effect a greater work of salvation ; more intimate union and communion with the heavenly
                            hosts, whose life of love, of peace and harmony, should pervade the entire body of the
                            church on earth, animating every member to the completest activity and consecration of every
                            faculty, physical, mental, and moral, to the sole work of Christ— that of establishing the
                            kingdom of heaven everywhere upon the earth, and fitting it for its ultimate destination in
                            the heavens.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., W. H." TEIform="persName"/>W. H. B., Groveland, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Biographical: Ann Lee" TEIform="index"/>BIOGRAPHICAL. Ann Lee</head><p TEIform="p">(Continued.*) Mother Ann was once dragged out of meeting by a mob, and cast into prison in
                            Manchester. Her cell was too small for her to straighten herself. She remained here four-
                            teen days without other nourishment than a little milk and wine mixed and passed to her
                            through the stem of a tobacco pipe, by inserting it into the key-hole. When taken out of
                            prison, her enemies were astonished to see her walk off, apparently hearty. At another time
                            she was taken by a mob upon the highway and ordered to advance; she did so, and was kicked
                            every few steps for two miles, and for variety knocked down with clubs. A nobleman, living
                            at a distance, was so strongly wrought upon by some unknown power, to go abroad, where, or
                            for what, he did not know, but ordering a horse, he rode as if to save his own life, came
                            upon the mob, reproved and dispersed them, and restored Mother Ann to her friends. Being
                            accused of blasphemy, she was taken before four ministers of the English Church with a view
                            to obtain judgment against ier, that would excuse her persecutors for putting into execution
                            their threats — branding her cheek and boring her tongue with a hot iron. Being called upon
                            by these clergymen to speak in tongues, she told them she could not without the help of God.
                            That help came and she spoke for four hours. The clergymen being learned linguists, stated
                            that she had spoken of the wonderful works of God in seventy-two languages I They advised
                            the mob not to molest her; but they, more enraged than ever, determined to stone her to
                            death. Taking her and a few of her companions into a valley ouside of the town, they threw
                            stones at them, yet without effect. Quarreling among tnemselves followed, and they abandoned
                            their wicked design. Mother Ann said : " While they were throwing stones, I felt myself
                            surrounded with the presence of God, and my soul was filled with love. I knew they could not
                            kill me, for my work was not yet done; therefore / felt joyful and comfort- able while my
                            enemies felt confusion and distress." From one of her own brothers she received shocking
                            abuse, by his beating her until he was exhausted; when, calling for drink he repeated the
                            assault with the other end of the staff until it was splintered. She testified she felt no
                            harm from the strokes. Fleeing from a mob, she went out on a pond of ice and laid down,
                            remaining there all night, not suffering any inconvenience therefrom. Her persecutors often
                            met with sudden deaths; one, while on his way to get a license from the king to banish her;
                            others became fearfully convicted of their doings, and desisted; so that for two years
                            before leaving England they enjoyed their faith in peace. On the 19th of May, 1774, Mother
                            Ann, with eight followers, took passage for America in a condemned sea-going vessel, the
                            Mariah, Captain Smith, ot New York. Mother said: "I knew by revelation that God had a chosen
                            people in America; I saw some of them in vision, and when I met them in America, I knew
                            them. I had a vision of x\merica: I saw a large tree, every leaf of which shone with such
                            brightness as made it appear like a burning torch, representing the Church of Christ which
                            will yet be established in this land." The Captain of the vessel was greatly offended at
                            their religious exercises, and forbade their recurrence; but they, disregarding him and his
                            threats to cast tham overboard, went forth in dancing and shouting, when the Captain
                            proceeded to carry his threats into execution. A storm was raging; a plank loosened by a
                            heavy sea caused the water to rise rapidly, regardless of all the pumps in use. The crew
                            quailed; the Captain, alarmed and pale as a corpse, told all of their inevitable fate.
                            "Captain," said Mother Ann, "be of good cheer; there shall not a hair of our heads perish;
                            we shall arrive safe in America. I saw two bright angels of God standing by the mast,
                            through whom I received this promise." Then came a great wave, striking the ship, forced the
                            plank back into its place. After this, the Captain gave full permission for them to <pb n="23" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. worship as they pleased, and treated them with kindness;
                            declaring, in New York, if it had not been for these Shakers, he never would have reached
                            America. They landed in America, August 6, 1774. Not long afterward Mother Ann and company
                            collected at what is now Shaker Village, seven miles north-west from Albany, New York.
                            Accessions were soon made to their faith, and with increase of numbers came tribulation and
                            persecution. The war of the Revolution was in progress; j they were charged with being
                            unfriendly to the Cause, because they would neither fight nor swear allegiance. They were
                            imprisoned; still their numbers increased; many uniting and confessing their sins through
                            the bars of the prison. They were separated : some sent towards Poughkeepsie with the
                            intention of banishment to the British army, but failing here, they were lodged in jail at
                            Poughkeepsie. Gov. George Clinton released them, and they returned to Shaker Village. In
                            May, 1781, Mother and a company left Watervliet on a missionary tour to the Eastern States.
                            They made many converts and established new societies in Massachusetts. They again became
                            the subjects of persecution, and the most dreadful abuse was inflicted. Clubbed, whipped,
                            stoned, dragged about the streets by the arms and the hair of their heads, pulled down
                            stairs by their feet, and otherwise shockingly maltreated, because of their testimony alone.
                            Their lives were often threatened, and were it not for some overruling power, they never
                            could have survived the attacks of their persecutors. Dreadful judgments fell upon their
                            enemies, and it became a proverb that " the Shaker drivers are all coming to naught." Mother
                            Ann departed this life at Shaker Village, Albany County, on the 8th day of September, 1784,
                            in her 49th year. Christopher Love, who was beheaded under Cromwell, prophesied that " Out
                            of thee, 0 England, shall a bright star arise, whose light and voice shall make the heavens
                            quake, and knock under with submission to the blessed Jesus." To whom could this apply ? We
                            purpose, in our next, to pen some of the sayings of Mother Ann. *</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blood signifies life..." TEIform="index"/>Blood signifies life...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Blood signifies life. Blood is the life element. The blood of Jesus was earthly, and
                            powerless for salvation ; his death on Calvary is not worthy of noticeThe blood of Christ is
                            quite another element; it was the saving element of life that circulated in the soul of
                            Jesus ; by it he became Jesus Christ. Being "washed in the blood of Christ," intends that we
                            must die unto sin as did Jesus, and live the life of which he was the pattern. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How easily might the millennium be inaugurated..." TEIform="index"/>How easily might the millennium be inaugurated...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> How easily might the millennium be inaugurated if all would burn up their theologies, and
                            live the religion of Christ. The life of Jesus was a pattern—those who follow that pattern
                            are Christians ; any departure therefrom, is a divergence from "followme,"and the creation
                            of a theology that is erroneous. Let the life of Christ be our only theology and religion. *
                        </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion makes the heart better..." TEIform="index"/>Religion makes the heart better...</head><p TEIform="p"> Religion makes the heart better ; the life more like the model—Jesus ; with Self-denial as
                            its touch-stone, and Virgin purity its standard, its goal is certainly the Angel spheres. H.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Sacrament should impress us..." TEIform="index"/>The Sacrament should impress us with the loving remembrance of Christ...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The Sacrament should impress us with the loving remembrance of Christ—wherein he,
                            Community-like, ate even his last supper with the disciples at one common table! H. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My servants will not fight..." TEIform="index"/>My servants will not fight.
                        </head><p TEIform="p">" My servants will not fight." Would the military genii of our country or of any professedly
                            Christian nation take an affront at the plainness of our speech— " Christ knows you
                        not?"</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>JUVENILE DEPARTMENT</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dialogue" TEIform="index"/>Dialogue</head><p TEIform="p">(Concluded.') Char.—I think that those who reside on the east side of the dwelling are
                                favored, being in such close connection with the grove ; and as we have learned that
                                vegetation imbibes carbon, and exhales the life-giving element so necessary for our
                                existence, I think that in the enjoyment of such salubrious breezes which are wafted so
                                frequently from the hillside, you ought to be remarkably healthy. Mar.—Health is the
                                blessing we seek, and I am thankful that we are not bound by the fashions and customs of
                                popular society, so that we cannot have free use of the elements of existence—air, light
                                and water; they are to be had without money or price, but no wealth can reclaim health
                                once lost. 0.—I often think, as I cast my eyes on the trees, particularly those
                                recently, set out by Elder F. W. Evans, in the grove, in the dooryard and orchard, not
                                forgetting our favorite Norway spruce, so nicely inclosed within a neat, octagonal
                                picket-fence, how unselfishly all his labors seem to be performed for the general
                                welfare, and to the end that our home may wear the aspect of comfort, both within and
                                without, and become more attractive and beautiful. And have we not, in our older
                                brethren and sisters, a practical demonstration of the valued precept of Mother Ann Lee
                                : " To do all our work as though we had a thousand years to live, and yet as though we
                                were to die to-morrow ? " For we know that the worth of the greater part of their labors
                                can never be realized by them in this life. S.—What you have said is true; and I have
                                thought many times, that each breeze that plays among the trees, and each sweet songster
                                that warbles its early matin and evening lay in the future, would be as voices of thanks
                                and blessing to him who reared while young, each tender tree that now forms this
                                sequestered spot. Martha.—I have a few sentiments which I extracted from a book, a short
                                time since; as they are quite applicable to our subject, I would like to read them.
                                All.—(We will be pleased to listen). (Martha reads:) "There is something noble, pure and
                                simple, in a taste for the cultivation of forest trees. It argues, I think, a sweet and
                                generous nature, to have a strong relish for the beauties of vegetation, and a
                                friendship for the hardy and glorious sons of the forest. There is a grandeur of thoughi
                                connected with this part of rural economy It is worthy of liberal, freeborn and aspiring
                                men. He who plants an acorn, looks forward to future ages, and plants for posterity.
                                Nothing can be less selfish than this. He cannot expect to sit in its shade and enjoy
                                its shelter; but he exults in the idea, that the acorn which he has buried in the earth,
                                shal' grow up into a lofty pile, and shall keep on flourishing and increasing, and
                                benefiting mankind, long after he has ceased to tread his paternal field." S.—That is
                                interesting, and as it refers more particularly toforest trees, I would now ask if
                                evergreens shed their leaves every year. Martha.—The fir and pine, and usually all
                                cone-bearing and resinous trees shed their leaves annually; but as the new ones appear
                                before the old ones decay, the tree is always green. Mary.—Leaves have not that
                                brilliancy of color which flowers have; but the beauty of the blossom (like most
                                external beauty), fades, while the less showy leaf remains fresh and verdant after the
                                flower has passed away. C.—Evergreens are beautiful, preserving (heir color throughout
                                the year. I have heard that tiny fir trees push their tardy growth above the perpetual
                                snow that covers the northern regions. It must be a lovely sight, when contrasted with
                                the clean white snow. A.—Indeed it must. A fact has occurred to my mind, which is wrorth
                                mentioning here; it is said, that under the wonderful, magnifying power of the
                                microscope, the most perfect works of art appear quite imperfect; wrhile in Nature's
                                productions, however magnified, no blemish is found; her charms are ever supreme to the
                                works of art. M.—Have any of you ever studied Botany ? and what is the true
                                signification of the word ? S.—Botany is that branch of natural history which treats of
                                plants and their classifications. Mar.—I commenced the study of botany when quite a
                                child ; and found that it opened before my mind, a vast field of interest. The endless
                                variety of plants, with their multitudinous, beauteous forms, with leaves of finest
                                texture, all dyed in the sunlight's varied hues, comprised a theme for study. It was
                                said of Linnasus (the Swedish botanist) that he was so thoroughly versed in the science,
                                that he needed no time-piece to tell the hour of day—he knew it by the opening and
                                closing of flowrers, and the various changes that took place in his plants. S.—The
                                folding up of leaves at particular periods, has been termed the sleep of plants. This
                                may seem a singular term to be applied to plants, but a celebrated Botanist said: " This
                                folding up of leaves may be as useful to the vegetable constitution, as real sleep is to
                                the animal." Almost every garden contains some plants in which this phenomenon may be
                                observed; perhaps we have all noticed the Morning Glory, Four O'clock and Sensitive
                                Plant. C.—The most common plants on wrhich we tread, may be teachers of wisdom to us;
                                for, when closely examined, we find in them that beauty of form and texture, which no
                                artist could picture or poet describe. Neither can man with all his science, cause them
                                to grow; then we look to the God of nature and exclaim : " To the beautiful order of thy
                                wTorks may wre conform the order of our lives !" Mar.—Should we not delight in the works
                                of God, and in the perfection of beauty shadowed forth in all created things ?
                                Martha.—There is nothing in which the goodness of God is more apparent, than in the
                                inspiring flood of beauty wThich is continually poured out upon the earth. Char.—Among
                                these beauties are flowers. It is a pleasing thought to know, that every 23 <pb n="24" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. spot of earth is supplied with vegetation, appropriate and
                                ornamental; scarcely a place is incapable of supporting vegetable life. In the desert,
                                even, a few plants are found and its sandy waste is dotted, here and there, with date
                                and palm trees. Thus, vegetation becomes victorious. In springs, rivers, waterfalls and
                                seas, vegetable life accumulates, and on the margin of lakes and ponds, we often find
                                the most beautiful of all flowers—the Water Lily. The shattered forests of the tropical
                                climes are rich in fruits and flowers. We roam through the massive woods and frequently
                                meet flowers wild and beautiful, growing without culture ; but lovely in themselves,
                                because they bespeak the innocence of their creation. It is sad to think that aught so
                                fair and lovely should be despoiled, by having a language attached to them that is
                                corrupt, and by those who should possess feelings superior to what are bestowed on these
                                emblems of virtue, which are designed to beautify and adorn the home of mankind. Too oft
                                are they the medium, through which passions base and wild find an outbreak. Too oft have
                                they by the aid of man drawn woman from chastity, and her superior powers and
                                intellectual faculties have been perverted by the signification borne in these innocent
                                fruits of nature. But let us turn from this sad picture, and glance at their variable
                                life. A.— Their's is surely a changeable one. In spring, we hail the green grass, which
                                is soon interspersed with the bright Dandelions and Buttercups : flowers wild and
                                beautiful dot the woodland, hills and meadows, and bedeck the verdant vales, as sweet
                                opening notes to the rich anthem which nature chants till harvest time. Then summer
                                comes, with its more ostentatious flowers ; the Violet cannot endure the scorching heat,
                                but passes with the balmy spring. Then we have the Rose and Pink and a variety of sweet
                                flowers, which grace our mother earth; but these cannot alwaj^s last, for Autumn soon
                                steps in, and with its chilling blast destroys the tender plants, and flowers come into
                                the passing scene. Mary—But in our hearts, flowers can always grow; through Summer's
                                scorching heat and Winter's icy reign, lovely flowers may always thrive as emblems of a
                                holy life in Christ. M.—Charlotte spoke of flowers as being corrupted; 'tis true they
                                have been used as a medium through which the sensuous could speak vile passions, yet
                                flowers of themselves are innocent. The testimony of eternal truth, falling on the ears
                                of the carnally-minded, would supply material to feed the sensual appetites; while to
                                the spiritually minded, it would be pure, living bread—something for the immortal soul
                                to feast upon. Flowers stand in a similar relation to mankind. The worldly-minded too
                                often use but to abuse them, but they never were intended for such a purpose; they can
                                be, and are, by some, used for a higher object. To me they are the emblems of heavenly
                                virtues, purity, meekness, innocence and love. These form and beautify the spiritual
                                character. A.—In whatever light they may appear to us, or however strong may be our
                                attachment to them, I hope that we will not for a moment plead for their cultivation to
                                the greatest extent merely to gratifjr our natural taste. A few sweet-scented flowers
                                are not objectionable, but their culture in the extreme requires much time and
                                attention, and would be the means of drawing the mind and feelings away from the more
                                practical duties of life. " Flowers must be redeemed from the blighting influence which
                                pervades their sphere before they can be introduced among us to any marked profit."
                                M.—With your conclusions I fully accord, and have been interested in, and edified by,
                                our conversation. Martha.—I hope that none of us will be destitute of the adorning of
                                heavenly virtue, for we are surrounded by influences which tend to elevate the mind, and
                                bring the soul in rapport with the higher spheres. It is our privilege, while young, to
                                store the suscep;able garners of the mind with that knowledge which will endure forever.
                                For it hath seen wisely said, that " Nothing seen is permanent ; from the dust atom to
                                the world, all is mutable—passing aioay is the mournful ?arewell of the visible
                                Universe." (Closing hymn sung by the company.)</p><div4 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hymn of praise" TEIform="index"/>HYMN OF PltAISE</head><p TEIform="p">In harmony with nature's voice, we'll chant a hymn of praise, [n our Creator's works
                                    rejoice, and glory in his ways. Our hearts are now attuned to sing the glories of
                                    the year. Praise to the source from whence they spring, Our life to bless and cheer,
                                    our life to bless and cheer. The blessings of this social feast, As a rich boon are
                                    given ; Among attractions not the least, To lead our souls to heaven. O happy home !
                                    relation dear ! With these onr hearts are blest, Praise, love and thanks we render
                                    here, This hallowed day of rest.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="F., N." TEIform="persName"/>N. F., Mt. Lebanon</byline></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Selections</head><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="An English journal, descanting on the various degrees..." TEIform="index"/>An English journal, descanting on the various degrees...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">" An English journal, descanting on the various degrees of connubial bliss, states that
                                the official record of the city of London for one year stands thus : Runaway husbands,
                                ..... 2,348 ¦: wives, ...... 1.132 Married parties legally divorced 4,175 i; " living in
                                open warfare 17,345 Married parties living in private misunderstanding ........13,279
                                Married parties living mutually indifferent, 55.34C " " regarded as comfortable, 3.175 "
                                " nearly happy, 127 " " perfectly nappy, 13 Comments.—Where offspring is the result of
                                such wedlock, may we look from it an improvement upon the conditions under which it was
                                conceived, born and bred ? London is not an exception to the general conditions of
                                married life. Something is wrong, or we should have better fruits from this idolized,
                                worldly institution. Would it not be well for religious organizations to discuss the
                                questions : " Is marriage a Christian institution?" "How does marriage compare with that
                                life, eternal in the heavens, now practiced by the children of the resurrection?" "Is
                                marriage engaged in by members of the churches for its holiness, oi for certain selfish
                                considerations ?" "Are virgins like, or unlike, the company standing with the Lamb on
                                Mt. Zion ?" Is marriage eternal, or what shall we do with it to inherit a life that is
                                eternal ?"</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whoso seeks to save..." TEIform="index"/>Whoso seeks to save...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Whoso seeks to save the generative life and rela tions, will lose the.eternal life of
                                Christ; whoso lose that, has an assurance of this. *</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I do not believe the Shakers live..." TEIform="index"/>I do not believe the Shakers live...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">I do not believe the Shakers live as purely as they rofess," said a visitor. "Why not?"
                                asked an at«ndant. " Because I don't think I could live so myelf!" </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We have an earthly nature..." TEIform="index"/>We have an earthly nature...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We have an earthly nature and a spiritual nature ; ;his is eternal, that is transient;
                                one prompts to the jropagation of the race of earthly beings ; the other lrges the
                                propriety of resurrecting the inclinations, o live as the Angels do—the life of " the
                                children of ;he resurrection." </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Virgin life is one of the constituents..." TEIform="index"/>A Virgin life is one of the constituents...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A Virgin life is one of the constituents of eternal ife ; it needs not to change when
                                entering Angelhood. Not so with the carnal lives of husbands and vives. As there are no
                                husbands, nor wives, nor exual lusts in Christ, they cannot be Christians, nor n the
                                enjoyment of eternal life, until they exchange he earthly and transient, for the
                                heavenly and unchangeable life. * </p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">Kotes :—The Shaker is hailed with joy by the United Societies. We issued 7.000 of January
                                number ; think we shall need to use the plates again. Subscriptions come in rapidly. Our
                                object is to disseminate truth far and near. Think it will be what we most desire it
                                should be—a home educator. It is proposed to send free, one copy for every club of five.
                                Samples at six cents, including postage. Exchanges nade with the Press, where desirable.
                                Any person addressing the Board of Editors, or Resident Editor, requesting answers, will
                                enclose stamp. United Societies, let us hear from you; send us your best thoughts, rom
                                three lines to a column of lines. G. A. L., Res. Ed</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Shaker, monthly journal, devoled to the exposition of religion, acording to Shaker theology" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER. MONTHLY JOURNAL, DEVOTED TO THE EXPOSITION OF RELIGION, ACCORDING TO SHAKER
                            THEOLOGY.</head><p TEIform="p">Fifty Cents, Per Annum, in Advance. G. A. Lomas, Resident Editor, Shakers, Albany, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Members of society" TEIform="index"/>MEMBERS OF SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p">Appointed to answer Correspondents, among whom are the Board of Editors. Elder F. W. Evan3,
                            Mt. Lebanon, Columbia Co., N. Y. " Issachar Bates, Shakers, Albany, N. Y. " C. E. Sears, Mt.
                            Morris, Livingston Co., N. Y. '' Simon Mabee, West Pittsfield, Mass. " Stoughton Kellogg,
                            Thompsonville, Conn., Shakers. " Albert Battles, Tyringham, Berkshire Co., Mass. " Wm.
                            Leonard, Groton Junction, Mass., Shakers. " John Whiteley, Shirley Village, Middlesex Co.,
                            Mass. " Nehemiah Trull, Shaker Village, Merrimack Co., N. H. " Henry Cummings, Enfield,
                            Grafton Co., N. H. " John B. Vance, Alfred, Shakers, York Co., Me. " Alonzo Gilman, West
                            Gloucester, Cumberland Co., Me., Shakers. * " O. C. Hampton, Union Village, Warren Co., O,,
                            Shakers. " Ezra Sherman, Preston, Hamilton Co., Ohio, Shakers. " Stephen Ball, Dayton,
                            Shakers, Ohio. " George Rnnyon, Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co., Ky. " J. R. Eades, South Union,
                            Logan Co., Ky. " J. S. Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio, Shakers. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publications" TEIform="index"/>PUBLICATIONS.</head><p TEIform="p">Christ's First and Second Appearing Dunlavy's Manifesto - Millennial Church Compendium of
                            Shakerism Three Discourses on United Interests - Tracts free, \vhere postage is paid. $1 25
                            1 25 1 00 0 50 0 50 " .</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>