<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0107" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><date value="18710701" TEIform="date">July 1871</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">49-56</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="49" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">" I WILL SHAKB ALL NATIONS, AND THE DESIRE OF ALL NATIONS SHALL COME ; AND I WILL FILL THIS HOUSE
                        WITH GLORY, SAITH THE LORD." Published Monthly, by, and under the direction of the Mt, Lebanon
                        Bishopric, Vol. I. SHAKERS, ALBANY CO, N. Y. JULY, 1871. No. 7.</p><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Poetry" TEIform="index"/>POETICAL</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Backsliding Christian" TEIform="index"/>The Backsliding Christian</head><p TEIform="p">TO THE RESCUE. Unbidden views hefore mine eyes appear, Of wasting dignity, and shameless
                                fear ; My vision pains, with sinking vital fires. And quailing firmness that strong hope
                                inspires. My throbbing heart is chilled, I've pallid cheek, My nerves the influence
                                catch, and seem all weak ; My bosom heaves convulsively, to find A cowering courage and
                                demented mind. Integrity seems palsied by the woefnl shock Of faith's abettor, stranded
                                on a rock ; Those patriotic fires that steel the brow, Seem faintly burning, or but
                                smouldering now ; And resolution, ousted from her fortress goal, Leaves her shorn
                                Sampson, a Delilah's fool; Bereft of strength and blinded by the foe, The pillars of the
                                temple now, are razed low. The temple lost, no living sacrifice Is now presented, and no
                                incense rise ; No altar consecrated to the sacred vow— No service dedicated to the God
                                of Heaven now. And love to God, that searching, heavenly flame, Seems evanescent, cool,
                                or meanly tame, The doors of inspiration snugly shut and barred, The soul, a famished
                                visage, deeply marred ! Now, low ambition's regnant in the soul, Fan and refresh the
                                devastating coals ; And worldly flames the holy life destroy ; And lust of pelf, the
                                meaner powers deploy ; Ignoble motives steal the halcyon hours, And rob the soul of her
                                angelic powers; And now, degraded by the world's pursuit, She doffs the Angel form, and
                                dons the brute. And, wretched outcast from the tree of life, Divorced from God, man
                                seeks a sensual life ; And now to pleasure gives the wasting strength 'Till ruin summons
                                him as her's, at length ; Oh, horrid destiny ! replete with woe, A Heaven lost and
                                earthly blessings too, Life spent, the naked, wretched, beastly man Of ruin's army,
                                leads the horrid van ! In this most woeful state of fell dispair, Time, and its
                                treasures vanish into air ; The soul is warned eternity to meet, And there, in judgment,
                                read life's soiled sheet; Then, oh, the anguish pouring on the soul, Whom sin hath
                                crippled, and whose life controlled— In judgment lone, she meets the direful lot, ''
                                Depart, ye cursed, for I know you not! " No sophists here, the dread decree may thwart;
                                No analeptic give, to ease the smart; Who, on the rock, might there been broken found,
                                Lies now beneath it, and '' to powder ground ! " Now, what availeth infidel belief? Now,
                                what philosopher can give relief? Now, where the charm in worldly pleasures' dye, To woo
                                the soul and captivate its eye ? Dread moment! Lord, be merciful, we pray ! And may e'en
                                justice, now, thy love display— And, when by sufferings all the debt is paid, Lord,
                                grant the famished soul some heavenly aid— O gather home, this desolated flock, And give
                                them water, from thy living rock ; And when, by judgment's fires, they're pure and free,
                                Some Angel send, and gather them to thee. Not for thy honor, but, for mercy's weal,
                                Impart thy love, these bruised reeds to heal; And though of glory, they're entire
                                bereft, For Heaven's sake, O let not one be left To chill the nerves of heavenly
                                minstrelsy Or blight the record of'humanity ! A ransom give to all this babel throng—
                                [long! So shall our love, our thanks, and praise, to thee be-</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. A., Mt L.</byline></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sweet innocence" TEIform="index"/>Sweet Innocence</head><p TEIform="p">Sweet Innocence, of beauty rare ! What virtue can with thee compare ! Who can behold thy
                                glory bright, And not embrace thee with delight? O blessed virtue—richest grace ! How
                                brilliant shines thy lovely face ! O could vain mortals know thy worth, And seek thee,
                                in the days of youth. Through every stage of human life, Thou canst appear for man's
                                relief, And greatly wilt thou beautify The soul, that dost on thee rely. We view thee
                                oft in infant state, In child-hood—and, on youth to wait,— But, as wild nature bears the
                                sway We see thee drawing far away. Too oft, in social life, we find A stranger thou, to
                                youthful mind ; And as in years they riper grow, Thy kind address they scarcely know.
                                Oh, sad mistake ! Oh. blinded youth ! How little dost thou sense the worth Of this most
                                precious gift of heaven, Which, to the child of grace is given. No ornament of nature's
                                birth Can e'er compare with thee, in worth : And where thon gainest full control, Thy
                                glory bright will crown the whole. In thee, all other virtues bloom, Diffusing round
                                their rich perfume, Which intermingle with thy own, As in a child of grace is shown. Oh
                                Innocence ! Thou sweetest charm ;— Thou canst the cruel tyrant calm !— The proud, the
                                haughty, and the wild Must bow to thee, thou lovely child : Yea, monarchs, kings and
                                princes, all Must reverence thee—before thee, fall;— And, as thy Christ-like hand is
                                sought, All worldly charms are brought to naught.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., D. A" TEIform="persName"/>D. A. B.</byline></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tattling" TEIform="index"/>Tattling</head><p TEIform="p">And floats upon the atmosphere And plants its noxious presence, where The choicest fruits
                                are growing ; Just so the idle tattler's tongue, Doth work its impious way among The
                                pleasant walks of old and young, And.vilest seeds are sowing. The man who has no higher
                                aim, Than that which satisfies the beast, Must, as a man, be very tame, And pitiable, to
                                say the least.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Virtue and truth are the beauties of youth, While malice and rage are digraceful to age" TEIform="index"/>Virtue and truth are the beauties of youth...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Virtue and Truth are the beauties of youth, While malice and rage are digraceful to age.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="F., E. E." TEIform="persName"/>E. E. F.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakerism and spiritualism in their moral aspects" TEIform="index"/>Shakerism and
                            Spiritualism in their Moral Aspects</head><p TEIform="p">All religions that have attained great proportions, if perhaps we except the Confucian system
                            of China, have had their original base in some sort of spiritual manifestations. Both
                            profane and ecclesiastical history sustain us in this position. Believers have had
                            experiences relating to Spiritualism extending over more than a century ; for our visible
                            founder, Mother Ann Lee, was a visionist, and wonderfully endowed with spiritual gifts.
                            Studying the histories of nations and religions, it becomes clear to us, that com-
                            municating spirits were, in the past, as in the present, good and bad, orderly, disor-
                            derly, and even demoniac. This with us has been a matter of prayerful consideration. As a
                            body of people, we have never exercised these gifts for idle curiosity or worldly gain.
                            Spirits, entrancing, or otherwise controlling certain of our brethren and sisters, in
                            several of our Societies, many years before the famous Rochester disturbances, distinctly
                            informed us that the spiritual manifestations which we had enjoyed (during a period of seven
                            years), would go out into the world, even to the outer court of the Temple of Humanity!
                            These heavenly intelligences further prophesied what the result of this wide-spread,
                            promiscuous spirit-intercourse in the world would be; and these prophecies are being
                            continually verified. Under the providence of God, by the law of eycles, prophecy is allied
                            to cause and effect. And having, for several years, been anxiously expecting the
                            breaking-out of those spiritual manifestations, we, upon the first hearing of the Rochester
                            rappings, appointed a committee to visit the Fox girls in New York city, paying our dollar
                            a-piece for admission. This committee at once recognized the presence of spirits, and
                            believed it to be the prelude to extensive manifestations of different kinds, and so
                            reported upon their return. Subsequently, we witnessed the astounding manifestations then
                            occurring in the family of Dr. Phelps. In brief, for the last twenty years and more, we have
                            seen very much of these manifestations in the outer <pb n="50" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 50 THE SHAKER.
                            court; have been attentive readers of the spiritualistic journals and books; and were
                            visited by the late Secretary Stanton, Dr. Grey and Judge Edmonds, of New York, and many
                            others of the most distinguished spiritualists in the country. Therefore, when we read of
                            spiritualists failing to organize—of their disintegrating elements and tendencies, and their
                            frequent descent into the "snare of the pit," we are in no way surprised, knowing that there
                            will yet be greater and more fiery discussions in the camp ; and many ambitions will meet
                            with a worse than a Sedan defeat. The angels are separating the " chaff from the wheat." The
                            three unclean, amphibious spirits ("like frogs") which issued from the mouths of the three
                            great powers — Paganism, Catholicism, and Protestantism—are already in the land. Selfish,
                            disorderly Spiritualism is the parent of Free-loveism, of inordinate, unclean affections and
                            carnal relations, under the instigation of demons—" spirits of devils." Comparatively, few
                            spiritualists seem to understand the situation; some, however, are seeking a higher plane,
                            and a more religious life; and quite unknown to themselves, are affiliating with the purer
                            principles and practices which characterize our Shaker Communities. In a late anniversary
                            address, delivered in New York, on the 81st of March, by Judge Edmonds, we find this
                            significant paragraph: " From us, the physical manifestations -which once so powerfully
                            excited our wonder have almost entirely departed. Their office was to establish the reality
                            of a spiritual life, and the fact of communion with it. That office with us has been
                            performed. That work is done; and henceforth the appeal is not to our senses, but to our
                            intellects and our hearts; to the reason which God has given us, and to the spirit of
                            devotion—at once the attribute and the badge of our immortality—which He has implanted in
                            us. 14 Our duty is plain and simple. It is to receive, to digest, and to comprehend the
                            revelations which are proflered to us of the existence and the actualities of the future
                            life; to receive and realize the great principles which are to fit us for that life, and
                            which can make it to us a source of happiness, or otherwise." That Spiritualism as an
                            organic movement is making no progress, but rather declining, is as evident to Spiritualists
                            as to ourselves. There are various reasons for this: In the majority of places the
                            management of spiritualistic institutions (Spiritualists themselves being authority), is in
                            the hands of self-seekers; and Spiritualism has fallen into questionable company.
                            Pretension, noise, and confusion, are the stars in the ascendancy. As the tree is known by
                            its fruit, may we ask what these twenty-three years of Spiritualism have done for the world
                            ? Has it discovered a single new truth capable of demonstration as such ? Has it initiated
                            and carried out any new reform movement ? Have mediums excelled all others in the purity of
                            their lives ? Have rich Spiritualists built homes for orphans, retreats for the aged,
                            asylums for the deaf, dumb, and blind; and Bethels for the destitute? Has their morality,
                            generally, excelled that of their neighbors who profess the various sectarian religions ?
                            That " free-love " passion prevails extensively among mediums is proven often by the
                            testimony of mediums themselves. Go to New York, Boston, Chicago—any of the cities—and ask
                            the leading Spiritualists to give you, according to their best knowledge and belief, the
                            moral standing, as regards purity, chastity, and celibacy, of the mediums in their immediate
                            vicinity. Are they truthful, temperate, and chaste ? is the first inquiry of the good man
                            and the philanthropist. What is the moral influence of Spiritual- ism—how does it affect
                            character? how have controlling spirits affected the mediums long under their influence ?
                            These are practical inquiries. Believers have but little sympathy with many of the doctrines
                            published in the spiritualistic papers. They are sometimes unreasonable, and often untrue,
                            besides being expressed in a manner coarse, dogmatic, and irreligious; some are glaringly
                            atheistic. The editor of the " Religio Philosophical Journal,'1'' a spiritualistic weekly,
                            printed in Chicago, in writing up his " Search after God," flatly denies the existence of
                            any Supreme Being. These are his words : "Man. and not God, was connected with the
                            organization of matter into worlds and systems of worlds. A large portion of mankind
                            attributes the creation of this earth and the other planets to an infinite, omniscient,
                            omnipotent, God. They have no foundation whatever upon which to predicate such a
                            supposition. * * * What! Man make a planet; launch into the regions of space a comet; or
                            organize a system of worlds for the unlbldment of other races of human beings ? Yes; we say,
                            emphatically, Yes, and care not a straw for the denial of others. Worlds and systems of
                            worlds bow to the nod of man. Point me to anything in Nature that was made by God.
                            Individualized man is the moving cause of creation. Do we declare that man conceived, made,
                            and launched the earth into the regions of space ? Most assuredly we do. We propose to prove
                            that an infinite God is an impossibility. All the Gods we have found, are myths. No
                            omnipresent God made this earth.'' " Man make a planet! Yes—we say emphatically, Yes,"
                            writes this editor. As it is generally admitted that the heathen gods were once athletic
                            men, we wonder that the writer, considering how fearfully the world is given to " wine and
                            women," did not tell us that this planet was created by Bacchus, the drunken, free- love
                            hero of antiquity. Such verbose dogmatism, and arrant atheism, as make up the warp of these
                            wordy articles is deplorable. These atheistic Spiritualists would do well to remember that
                            Plato, Socrates, Jesus, Kepler, Newton, Locke, Hume, Macauley, Leibnitz, Swedenborg,
                            Voltaire, Thomas Paine, Buckle, Joan of Arc, Ann Lee, and the good of all ages, were
                            Theists—believers in God. Accounting for the creation of man the R. P. Journal of May 22,
                            1869, says: ': Within man is the action of Nature's forcesIn nature there are sixty-eight
                            primal elements—thirtyfour positive, and thirty-four negative; or thirty-four female, and
                            thirty four male, which, after courting for millions of years in the mammoth, in fishes, in
                            reptiles, and various other animals, were brought together in harmonious action or were
                            wedded together, and the result was ' man.''' This explanation disposes of not only all
                            Bible accounts, but also Darwin's " Origin of Species," Sixty-eight male and female elements
                            " courting" a few millions of years in the stomachs of "mammoths " and slimy "reptiles,1'
                            were finally " wedded," and " man " was. Hereafter, let all scientists hold their peace. Not
                            mentioning the doctrine of il Whatever is, is Right," so common among Spiritualists, many of
                            the teachings which appear in their journals, are positively demoralizing, giving those so
                            inclined a plausible pretext for indulging in sensualism and all kinds of Free-love
                            gratifications. In the copy of February 20, 1869, of the above-named journal, the editor
                            teaches, that "Virtue, serene and happy, one of God's most beautiful flowers, blushes when
                            she hears her Father traduced and vilified; and though her eyes are brilliant, and her
                            countenance all aglow with innocence, she has sense enough to know that Vice, traduced,
                            vilified, scorned, looked at with supreme contempt, spat upon, is her sister, and she loves
                            her, recognizing that she, too, is a jewel in that beautiful casket which God himself
                            created. She does not scorn her— no, she would not—she dare not. She loves her. Pure
                            affection, unsullied innocence, a part of the Great I Am, loving her sister, Vice. Strange,
                            bewildering conclusion! Within, without, all aronnd, we feel the presence of angelic
                            influence. Virtue, pure, angelic, no 1 ; Vice, diseased, unclean, and repulsive—they meet
                            and caress; they love each other. * * * Virtue is one condition ; Vice another; both equally
                            commendable in the sight of God, when he considers the cause that created both respectively;
                            yet one not as lovely or beautiful as the other. * * * In licentiousness we find an
                            outcropping of the God element in man, not for the gratification of that element. Oh, no!
                            but for the purpose thereby of inducing certain conditions that would place it in harmonious
                            relations. Scout the idea as you may; deem it absurd, if you wish; say, "Fanaticism run
                            wild,'' if you choose; still the God element in man will constantly work for conditions
                            suitable for its nature, whether in the field of Virtue or Vice." The term "God element"
                            plainly implies Materialism ; hence it would be more proper to term the " Harmonial
                            Philosophy " the Material Philosophy; but what is the tendency of this spiritualistic
                            teaching, that " Virtue is the sister of Vice ? " that Virtue and Vice meet and caress? that
                            they love each other? and are "both equally commendable in the sight of God?" and, further,
                            that "licentiousness is an outcropping of the God element in man?" Saying nothing of the
                            celibacy of <pb n="51" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE. 51 Believers, who " stand on Mount Zion;" in
                            the Resurrection life, it seems strange to us, that clean people anywhere can encourage such
                            teaching; and stranger, that the " Banner of Light " could endorse and extravagantly praise
                            this II. P. Journal, and personally laud the editor. The following occurs in the R. P.
                            Journal of March 6, 1869 : "In the inebriate, in the licentious, the essence of the "God is
                            love." glistens beautifully, though only seen by angels'eyes; and the day is not far distant
                            when its rough exterior shall be washed away, and its heavenly brilliance will be visible
                            even to our eyes. Man does not stand in the relation of a subject to God; but as a part and
                            parcel of him; owing no allegiance but to the God element of his nature, and worshiping no
                            God except by obeying the promptings within." In the paragraph quoted above this, the editor
                            tells us, that " We find an outcropping of the God element in the licentious;" and, in this
                            last paragraph, he assures us that " Man owes no allegiance but to the God element of his
                            nature." We have only to say, that we hope this class of Spiritualists practises better than
                            these journals preach. As a body of Believers, seeking to live as Jesus lived, by dying to
                            the earthy, that we may live the heavenly life, we make but little pretension to mere
                            literary or scientific accuracy; but, be it far from us to ever publish, as original, such
                            matter as is contained in the above-quoted paragraphs. With this kind of Spiritualism,
                            Believers cannot have the least fellowship. It is from beneath, " earthly and sensual:'' the
                            life lived is the test. Some Spiritualists, however, are among the excellent of the earth;
                            they are not far from the kingdom of heaven—not far from becoming Shakers, though calling
                            themselves Spiritualists. We speak of the masses of Spiritualists, and ask, in all sincerity
                            and humility, if their lives are as pure and godly as those of Believers; or even as pure
                            and orderly as those of Swedenborgians and Unitarians ? Does not irreligion and a scoffing
                            spirit prevail extensively among the devotees of Spiritualism ? "A good tree cannot bring
                            forth evil fruit." In our view, then, Spiritualism is one of the elements of
                            Babylon—Christendom; and belongs to the image of the beast— Protestantism. It is the " Angel
                            of Light " re-establishing the communication between this earth and the general spirit
                            world; which, for reasons set forth in previous articles, the early Protestants, as a matter
                            of protection, had broken off. The Shaker Order, standing in the name, i. e., character, of
                            Jesus and Ann, on the foundation of spiritual celibacy, has power with Grod to govern all
                            spiritual manifestations, and to incorporate Spirit- ualism as one of its elements,
                            assigning it its proper place—the Church of God in its day of manifestation; and to its
                            right use—the saving of human beings from causes of unhappiness, and leading them to a
                            joyful recognition of, and baptism into, all Scientific, Moral, and Spiritual Truth.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God, my father and mother" TEIform="index"/>God, My Father and Mother</head><p TEIform="p">The perversion of the social organism in humanity, renders it a difficult task for any to
                            form complete ideas of the social relations in the heavenly world. Physical reproduction,
                            even in its most exalted conditions, now forms only a very imperfect type of the heavenly
                            reality, wherein souls are begotten and born into Godliness; and to feel the truth that "we
                            must be born again," evidences the process of the true resurrection. Our earthly affections
                            are strong; but these are gross when compared with the felicity of that harmony in which
                            Angels dwell. That God is our Father and Mother, is a truth advancing upon, and sup-
                            planting much ancient theology. Thoughts that the social relation is maintained in the
                            heavens, leads us to feel that there is nought on the earth, but would be a vulgar
                            expression of God's paternal and maternal solicitude. Man was imperfect when existing in
                            nature without his helpmeet, woman; for only a part of Deity was represented. As in the
                            physical world, so in the spiritual heavens and earth; the Godhead must be fully
                            represented—male and female—angelic man and woman.. Yet, there is a peculiar philosophy in
                            many existing theologies that recognizes God only as Father, and then, blindly trusts
                            Omnipotence, to balance the incongruity of a home without a Mother, as well it may ! Here we
                            have the reason of female misrepresentation in the nations; and the denial of her individual
                            rights, other than being subordinate to whatever desires prompted her lord, master, husband.
                            The knowledge that woman is represented in Deity, will yet place her in the true position
                            upon the earth, in the natural family; even as she enjoys it now, with those who have chosen
                            to live on earth as the Angels do in heaven. When man was formed, his model was in the
                            heavens; as really so was woman's; "let us make man in our image," and male and female were
                            the results. And now, were not " the invisible things of God, clearly seen by the things
                            that are made, even the eternal power and Godhead" still we feel the heavenly influences of
                            a Mother's love descending from the throne of Deity, while the wise counsels of the Father
                            are ever attendant upon those who "seek that wisdom that cometh from above."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Chauncy" TEIform="persName"/>Chauncy. (Shakers, N. Y.)</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="As the cause of dishonor is often very small..." TEIform="index"/>As the cause of dishonor is often very small...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">As the cause of dishonor is often very small, while the effect is beyond expression ;
                            therefore be guarded in little things ; even in conversation we might drop words that are
                            unwise. "VVe seldom repent of saying too little. "'Tis the little foxes that destroy the
                            vines." Wherefore, professedly Christian friends, are there rich members and poor members of
                            any Church— Brethren and Sisters (!) and yet sharing so unequally ? Poor Christianity!</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life in God, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>Life in God—No. 2</head><p TEIform="p">In the innumerable objects which meet our senses, the best exponent, or representative of the
                            Supreme Being, is the Sun. It is a ruling physical power, around which other bodies of less
                            magnitude circulate and congregate; seemingly dependent on him, for their periods and places
                            in the heavens. Without the permeating influence of light and heat, human beings and the
                            lower orders of creation could not exist; and they are equally dependent on the same source
                            for the vegetable products on which they subsist. Thus on the sun there is a necessary
                            dependence for life, and the continuance of being for animal and vegetable life, whether in
                            the atmosphere, water, or on the earth. Taken as a whole, as far as our observation extends,
                            there is a perfect adaptation between the Sun, and the beings and products of earth. In the
                            structure of the human organization, how wonderful and beautiful are the adaptation of light
                            to the structure of the eye—the most marvelous piece of mechanism — through which, man is
                            made acquainted with the surrounding concomitants of earth; the sun itself; the solar
                            system; and lastly, with its companions of the universe. Continuing the concatenation, by
                            induction, we are carried through the universe, the workshop of the Great lYorkinan, to the
                            Supreme Architect. For, there can be no design without a designer, whose wonderful
                            intelligence and creative power have planned, and put into successful operation, these
                            astonishing combinations of mind and matter ! For there can be no design or adaptation, for
                            specific purposes, without intelligence. Nothing in vain: A complete whole ! Having taken a
                            superficial glance at the wonders, let us take a more specific view of the astonishing
                            connection between the sun and the human organ of light: The rays of light coming in
                            straight lines pass into th© eye, after coming many millions of miles, through a transparent
                            medium; bringing with them the sun himself, together with his innumerable blessings! For,
                            wtatfee* the smt accompanies the rays of 2igh;t and heat, or remains in his place, in the
                            center of the solar system, the effect comes down to, us in his majesty.; and the influences
                            and grand desiga are accomplished! We see the sun, feel his geniali inftueee, and know that
                            he is present with. us,, giving and sustaining life, in his deputed agency! But of the eye,
                            how admirably beautiful and efficient the contrivance; a IMg mirror to admit the creation of
                            God ! The images of surrounding objects come with imperceptible speed, in the pencils of
                            light, which far surpass electricity! Yet, we know the goods have come, for they are safely
                            stored in the warehouse of the human mind; but without thediscriminating influence, at the
                            entrance of the port, in the form of a lens, all the merchandise brought to us, would be
                            stored in utter confusion ! We should be unable to distinguish the moon from a star; a man
                            from a horse, etc.; but this lens makes every object show itself, and pay duty <pb n="52" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 52 THE SHA.KER. before passing into the warehouse of the human sensorium. But
                            to speak more scientifically : the lens has the power of separating the colors by
                            refraction, leaving only enough to represent the animal or tree, and reflecting these colors
                            on the animal or tree, so as to make it specific, and give identity; then the object passes
                            upon the optic nerve, or retina—the white blackboard—and there is a positive horse, and oak
                            tree, to the human understanding. We recognize these objects, but are utterly unable to see
                            the hand, brush, or pallet impainting the wonders of nature! We may now consider the office
                            and structure of the organ of hearing, or, rather, make a guess at the miraculous
                            performances connected with the human ear! Passing in, by the orifice of the ear, we find at
                            the end a thin, clear membrane, in the shape of a watch crystal, and looking like one, with
                            the round to the portal; under it there is a nerve called the auditory nerve; it is about
                            the size of a babe's little finger, reaching out of the brain, and nearly touching the
                            crystal drum; sound presses the drum down on the auditory nerve; the nerve conveys the
                            impression to the brain, and the mysteries of thought are formed or elaborated in the human
                            mind ! Between the ear and the surrounding atmosphere, there is an inseparable connection:
                            like light, the atmosphere comes full freighted with innumerable objects in the form of
                            sound, and passing in at the orifice of the ear, form in the mind all the complicated ideas
                            of the living, outward world of want, pleasure or pain, and myriads of ideas, which can come
                            in no other way at the time. The inspired Orator, in the dark, may pour into our souls a
                            volume of sound, which will make every fibre in our bodies tremble like a leaf. After the
                            blindness of St. Paul, he heard the sound of his Saviour's voice, which renovated his soul,
                            and made him a new man .' And the voice of Ananias gave him more pleasure, and heartfelt
                            satisfaction, than all his previous knowledge: he had heard the voice; it was enough! But of
                            the marvelous and inscrutable contrivance, for the separation of sounds, so as to give the
                            innumerable sensations of music their different chords and parts, we may not pretend to a
                            discrimination ; much less to give an idea of the intonations of the human voice in all the
                            vicissitudes of changing life, infused into the tympanum, the nerve of sound in connection,
                            and it again with the brain, and the brain with the mind, thought and intelligence. The
                            living voice of human beings, of beasts, birds and insects, all come to the human
                            intelligence, on the undulations of the atmosphere, all riding on the wind into the human
                            port, and knock for entrance, and the porter receives their cards or device, and reports to
                            his Lord, as the case may be. But the question arises, how does the discrimination of the
                            living auditory know each succeeding new-comer and his intentions ? The mysteries of
                            feeling, tasting and smelling are equally inscrutable! Now, let man pass into himself, by
                            any oi the senses, and tell his fellows how this complicated machinery operates to give man
                            all iiis knowledge of physics, metaphysics; including the knowledge he has obtained or
                            conceived of the Great Prototype, and his revelation to Iiis children. Is it possible that
                            nonentity, or no cause, should be the cause of all these wonders ! If we are to suppose, in
                            the precincts of eternity, an epoch without mind or intelligence, it is to deny intelligence
                            altogether. Matter, whether created or eternal, is without intelligence; it can have no
                            design; no organization; neither wisdom nor power inherent, for any rational creation. " The
                            fool saith there is no God." Men, who have denied the Eternal, and groping in worse than
                            Egyptian darkness, talk to us of the first great principles coming into congruity,
                            adaptation, and organization: But principles are nothing, only as they are the inherent
                            emanations of a being of intelligence and design. Computation, or the combination of
                            numbers, cannot obtain without the mathematician; he combines numbers, and gives them their
                            utility and powers, here in time. But where is the man of elementary and chaotic
                            combinations, for the production of divine intelligence, and the wonders of the universe ?
                            Let him produce some of the wonder-working machinery, under the illuminations of his
                            phosphorescent chandelier!</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Veritas" TEIform="persName"/>Veritas</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Humility, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>Humility—No. 2</head><p TEIform="p">Why art thou displeased with the censures of men, or elated with their praise ? Thou art just
                            what thou art; praise makes thee no better, nor can censure make thee worse. Oh Flattery!
                            base flattery ! Thou art universally despised in word; but deep down in the hidden recesses
                            of the heart, every one secretly cherisheth thee : Yea, thou art swallowed with avidity and
                            goeth down like oil. Strange that a worm should like to hear himself pronounced an Angel! He
                            that speaks degrading^ of himself and of his performances is quite likely fishing for
                            praise; and they that are wise will not catch at the bait. There are many who are well
                            pleased with offices and titles of distinction, but those who eschew them, do not wish to be
                            thought incapable or unworthy. However mean we may feel in ourselves, we do not like to have
                            others think us so. It is a great Christian attainment to become so dear to self, as to love
                            to be contemned, and to rejoice when all men speak evil of us. If thou hast an enemy,
                            consider diligently his reproaches, and thou mayest be much instructed; he will search out
                            thy faults more faithfully than many friends. Thou livest very abstemiously and on coarse
                            fare. Dost thou therefore think thou deservest extra reward ? Verily such as thou hast is
                            quite as good as thou deservest—should a dependent, a pauper, talk of compensation. A very
                            common motive for speaking of the demerits of others, is to set one's self forth to greater
                            advantage. How selfish and contemptible ! Who so desires to be delivered from pride, must
                            avoid every means of indulging it. Antiochus Epiphanes boasting himself against God, and
                            assuming to himself divine honors, was smitten with a noisome disease which terminated in
                            his death. Before he expired, he was brought so far to his senses, as to exclaim : " It is
                            meet to be subject to God; and man, who is mortal, should not think of himself proudly as if
                            he were God." 0 when shall I see the great and wonderful work of God on the earth? just as
                            soon as thou canst apprehend that His work consists in little things. Will nothing satisfy
                            yon but converting worlds ? You shall be content to plait straws. A wise man said, "An empty
                            spirit God will fill." We cannot be filled with God till emptied of self; we cannot be
                            emptied of self, till we deny self, and in deep humility and self-abnegation find a complete
                            death to a selfish nature. We need not be deceived and think self is dead when it is not;
                            for as long as we can perceive within us an aspiring disposition, self-will, self-seeking or
                            the least movement contrary to the will and order of God, we may be assured that self is yet
                            alive. That which hath in it the power of motion undoubtedly hath life. " The cup that my
                            Father hath given me," said Jesus, "shall I not drink it?" Again he said to Pilate, "Thou
                            couldst have no power at all against me, unless it had been given thee from above. Thus
                            showing his full faith that his heavenly Father was the source of all power—the controller
                            of all wants, and that he must humbly and patiently submit. cc Though Jesus was a son, yet
                            learned he obedience by the things he suffered." Shall the servant be greater than his
                            master ? Nay, verily; yet every one that is perfect shall be as his master. 0 when shall I
                            learn to rejoice in tribulation and to take joyfully every thing that goes to break up and
                            destroy the kingdom of self within me, and make room for him to reign whose right it is !
                            The kingdom of self, is opposed to the kingdom of God; and His reign cannot be perfected
                            within me till self is completely subjugated; let the word be given : " Joshua, arise and
                            begin to contend with him in battle." 0 that the true Joshua may arise in my soul and drive
                            out the old inhabitants of the land, that the kingdom may be the Lord's. If we truly desire
                            humility we must at least abstain from all occasions of pride and ostentation. Should a
                            woman dress herself in all the trappings of fashion, and then go through divers bodily
                            gestures to shake off pride, who would believe in her sincerity ? How inconsistent to dress
                            in fine and costly apparel and then get on bended knees to pray for humility. The ancients,
                            when they desired to humble themselves, rent their garments, put on sackcloth and sometimes
                            strewed themselves with ashes. Fine houses, costly equipage, and fine dress, all tend to
                            destroy humility, exalt the sense, and bring the owners into unison of feeling with
                            Nebuchadnezzar when in the pride of his <pb n="53" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 53 heart he
                            exclaimed: " Is not this Great Babylon that / hare builded ? 0 that I were wholly released
                            from desiring the praise or dreading the dispraise of men; then I would be truly devoted to
                            do the will of God. By how much thou lovest the honor of men, by so much thou art the
                            veriest slave; a slave to the most inexorable tyrant. Because thou ha,st found the honor
                            that cometh of men to be capricious, and not worth seeking, thou shouldst not therefore
                            become reckless to virtuous actions, but shouldst the more diligently seek that honor which
                            comes from God only. It would be unjust as well as unreasonable to forsake God and virtue on
                            account of the faults and frailties of men. So far as thou discoverest in thyself a feeling
                            of disregard to the way of righteousness, when stung with the ingratitude and unjust
                            censures of men, from whom thou hast expected esteem and approbation, so far thou mayest be
                            certain that thy motives have been selfish and impure. He that freely gives up ail, that he
                            may enjoy God alone, having nothing left that men desire or can take from him—nothing for
                            which to contend—will have abundance of peace. 0 Heavenly Father my soul is blessed ! I feel
                            satisfied with thy goodness! yet suffer me not to indulge in any self-complacency. I know
                            that if I am full, it is out of thy fullness; if I am strong, it is in thy strength; if I am
                            ¦rich, it is in the enjoyment of thy bounty; of myself I continually tend to nothing. My
                            strength is weakness; my fullness is but an efflux of vanity, and my riches but a store of
                            diversified evils. He that seeks to honor God in all he does, will be satisfied with an
                            approving conscience though all men rise up against him and cast his name out as evil. As
                            diamonds, gold, and all the precious stones and metals, are the slow and gradual formations
                            of nature in the most secret recesses of her retired operations; so the most glorious and
                            excellent virtues are wrought by divine influence in the silent abstraction and stillness of
                            the soul, while it shuts out the rude influences of all external things; and is wholly
                            concealed from the curious gaze of "outward observation." However deep and clear have been
                            my own convictions at any time of my own degraded and sinful state, yet I have never ceased
                            to implore for myself the mercy of God; and shall I censure and be inexorable to the faults
                            of others ? Shall I ask the mercy of God for myself, and expect him to be so partial as to
                            grant it, and join with me in despising and rejecting my poor offending brother ? If I love
                            my brother as myself, this cannot be; and if I do not, then am I a rebel against God who has
                            commanded me thus to do, and, as such, cannot justly hope for his mercy. "Forgive," said
                            Christ, "and thou shalt be forgiven." When one of my brethren offends and wrongs another,
                            how easily can I forgive him! But if he has injured me how is the case altered! How it
                            sticks in the mind! Why is this ? If I loved my brother as myself this could not be. Nay; if
                            I loved God with all my heart I could not thus feel; I should only be sorry that my brother
                            had sinned against the good spirit of our Heavenly Father, and thus injured himself. I
                            should be more grieved for the sin of the offender than for the offence of the sinner. If
                            when one brother offends another, I am comparatively but little excited, and the same
                            offence committed against myself highly agitates me; will not this show my want of
                            humility—my great self-importance, and that I esteem myself far above my brother ? Things
                            esteemed of the highest importance necessarily excite the deepest interest, and that in very
                            exact proportion. How very important then, is my character in comparison with my brother's,
                            when I can quietly hear him traduced, while the least thing derogatory to myself, arouses
                            all my indignation ? Speak, Lord, for thy servant heareth. 0 teach me the truth respecting
                            myself! Humble me ; prostrate me in the dust, that I may depend no more on self, or on any
                            mere human sagacity, but on the power and gift of God. If I were only a worm, I might well
                            crawl in the dust; but I am by nature a corrupt and sinful worm, and should, like Job,
                            "abhor my selfish nature in dust and ashes," and submit it to the just abhorrence of all
                            intelligences. Who am I, that I should resent reproach and scorn, or complain of injustice?
                            Is it possible that injustice can be done to such a lawless nature, except it be by
                            suffering it to escape merited contempt! Away with complaints; I have ever been blest more
                            than I deserved; and if there were not an infinite fountain of goodness—unmerited goodness,
                            a measure of which is extended to me—I should now be most destitute. We should never
                            consider ourselves sufficiently humble, till we can hear ourselves traduced and slandered
                            without being agitated and losing our serenity of mind. How completely ineffectual and
                            abortive are all the efforts of men to destroy the peace of that soul, who, redeemed from
                            the earth, and dead to self, desires neither the honor of men nor the pleasures of sense;
                            who, disregarding all censure, " rejoices to have his name cast out as evil for Christ's
                            sake," and places his whole confidence in the gift of God and his whole happiness in doing
                            the Divine will! Some men exhort others to humility, that they may the better serve
                            themselves of them ; yet is the humble man infinitely more happy than his proud oppressor.
                            Flee honor, and she will pursue you; seek her and she will conceal herself from your search.
                            When blind Bartimeus heard that Jesus called him, such was his eagerness to receive .sight,
                            that he cast away his mantle, that he might hasten to Christ! 0 that I may thus cast away
                            whatever would in the least hinder my coming to the Saviour; that, poor, blind and naked, I
                            may prostrate myself wholly at his feet, and receive the true inward light of his Spirit;
                            that being thus enlightened I may "follow him in the way," till I become fully imbued with
                            his "meek and lowly" temper and disposition of soul. Thus I shall be enlightened by the
                            Truth; enriched with Love, and clothed with Humility. " Learn of me," said Jesus, "for I am
                            meek and lowly, and ye shall find rest to your souls." Then, as Humility gives peace and
                            rest to the soul, he enjoys most happiness from it that is the most humble.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. P.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plain Talks, no. 4" TEIform="index"/>Plain Talks—No, 4</head><p TEIform="p">Eternal Life. Shakerism is Christianity to us; and Christianity is eternal life. Jesus, as
                            really enjoyed eternal life before his crucifixion, as afterwards. The same is the truth
                            with his disciples, regardless in what age they live. Love may be a veritable mark of
                            discipleship; but the grand feature of a Christian is the ever-present possession of eternal
                            life! death they never will experience. " If any one will keep my sayings, he never shall
                            see death." Death is the wages of sin; there is no sin in Christ, nor in good Christians.
                            "To be carnally minded is death," but this belongs not to the Christian's life. The elements
                            of the world, are death to the Christian's soul; but these are supplanted by the life Christ
                            lived, and this was eternal life. The lusts of the flesh and of the mind deny us the life
                            the Angels are living—eternal life; but, crucified unto the world, as Jesus was ere he
                            ascended the scaffold on Calvary, we become possessors of a new life, Angel life; and Angels
                            on earth, are already Angels in heaven. The true followers of Christ flinch not at the cross
                            that crucifies their fleshly lusts, knowing "these are not of the Father, but of the world."
                            Christ invites us to eternal life; his life was a renunciation of those practices that
                            cannot be engaged in by those who would enjoy life—eternal life. What is eternal life? It is
                            a heavenly, unchangeable, unending condition. The glory of those, not of Christ, is to save
                            the life that must needs change, before eternal life can be experienced; and while many are
                            aware of this truth, they are unable, unwilling to renounce the world, flesh and devil, to
                            be sharers of eternal life. In eternal life there are no husbands nor wives; no private
                            property nor selfish relations ; no war, poverty nor slavery; but the eternal life of the
                            heavens puts these into oblivion. What was there in the virgin life of Christ that needed to
                            change to be eternal, or what is there in any purely virgin character ? Let the world of
                            humanity plead for fleshly indulgences; let them solemnize their marri- ages of the flesh,
                            and direct their churches to wink at their private indulgences (of which, it would be a
                            shame to speak), we declare the same to be the works of darkness and of death, abominable in
                            the sight of God for professing Christians to practice—disgraceful for the heathen! The
                            acceptance of eternal life will be forced work by-the-bye; for, when the opportunities of
                            phj^sical indulgences are cut short by the mortuary process, the mind, writhing in the pain
                            of past incontinence, will accept the situation; but can never be in possession of those
                            sweets of eternal life, rightly belonging to those who have made willing sacrifices of
                            themselves, unto a life of sin and death. *</p></div2><pb n="54" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thoughts on true love" TEIform="index"/>Thoughts on True Love</head><p TEIform="p">" In Christ are hid all the treasures of wisdom and knowledge." Col. 2:3. Jesus, who was
                            baptized with the Christ Spirit, was our Exemplar. He ministered to his disciples True Love.
                            He taught them how to love and what to love, and what not to love. He said, " Love your
                            enemies. If ye love them which love you, what thank have ye?" Worldly lovers—those who do
                            not profess the Christian name—can love when their love is reciprocated; this is Policy. But
                            to love our enemies, those who would return cursing for blessing, and learn to pray for
                            those who would thus use us—this is Principle. The one is natural, the other spiritual—the
                            world versus Christianity. The principle of selfdenial runs through all the teachings of
                            Jesus; and the love which worketh no ill to neighbor, friend, or foe, whatever provocation
                            may be given, will fulfill the whole Gospel law; it will cause its possessor to depart from
                            the iniquity of loving falsely, for the sake of emolument, or pleasure, as well as for all
                            unrighteous doings. If our love is centered in God, then we have a basis to rest upon. True
                            love is self-sustained; it is free from guile, and is not mixed with fear, lest some adverse
                            wind or storm should arise that would sweep away its foundation; but perfect love is devoid
                            of fear. "We can trust it, for it is unselfish; it is not precarious nor circumstantial,
                            like the perverted passion called love. If we are well grounded in the principle of love, we
                            shall never be distressed nor unhappy because we think our friends grow cold-hearted towards
                            us; but, if we feel the tide of love ebbing, then it is well for us to examine our
                            characters, and see if we cannot make ourselves more attractive and lovely, by being more
                            virtuous, striving more to have the image of Christ formed in us. For, if we become his true
                            sons and daughters, he will open his treasures unto us; we may draw therefrom; and the same
                            virtuous principles which made him the chief object of beauty and loveliness among ten
                            thousand, if practiced by us, will produce the same beauty in us. Notwithstanding we are
                            admonished to "love our enemies, to bless and curse not," we must not love indiscriminately.
                            We are as expressly commanded to hate, as to love. But we should learn to both love and hate
                            understandingly, and from a good conscience; to love whatever is virtuous, that is healthy
                            for soul and body. Sin is hateful in the sight of God, because it deforms the soul, and
                            destroys its noblest faculties; leads it away from truth, from God, its home. He is the
                            Source, and should be the center of all souls. We should never love nor hate from momentary
                            impulse. Charity should ever be the handmaid of love. If we would judge righteously of
                            others, we must take into consideration conditions of birth, fortune, education. We cannot
                            justly measure all by one rule; the same degree of abstract truth, if applied to some
                            persons, would blight and destroy; while to others, who are prepared by previous culture and
                            growth, it would be a great blessing. Charity would teach us to be gentle to others; not to
                            magnify faults in them, by evil thinking nor speaking; but to be more lenient to the faults
                            of others, than to our own. And if a brother or sister errs, according to our conceptions of
                            right, if we possess true love, guided by charity, we will, in many cases, see that the
                            cause of their failure is the result of false educations, which they had not yet outgrown,
                            rather than willful neglect. Then, how much better to take them kindly by the hand and lift
                            them up into more progressed conditions; show them by example and word, a more ex| cellent
                            way, than to denounce and say, " stand off; I am more holy than thou ! " "Love is the
                            fulfilling of the law." " Whatsoever we I sow we shall reap." If we sow Love, Peace and
                            Charity, we will thereby increase our capacity to love, by enlarging the sphere of our
                            affections ; and as we love better, ourselves become objects more worthy to be loved, and
                            thus we shall attract the good and the pure unto us, and from them reap the desired i
                            harvest. Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Declaration and caution to the public" TEIform="index"/>Declaration and Caution to the Public</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="United Societies called Shakers" TEIform="persName"/>THE UNITED SOCIETIES CALLED SHAKERS</byline><p TEIform="p">Whereas, circumstances have occurred and may again occur whereby the public are liable to be
                            imposed upon by persons professing to act as authorized Agents for the Society of Shakers in
                            some of its branches or families, who presume to make contracts, and obtain money, or other
                            property on credit, from persons, or companies who may suppose the Society to be responsible
                            for the fulfillment of such contracts. Therefore, the duly constituted Authorities of the
                            several Shaker Societies, throughout the land, do hereby give notice to all whom it may
                            concern, that, in accordance with principles taught by the first founders of this Society
                            called Shakers, the members thereof shall owe no man anything but love and good will, and
                            pay this debt as often as the slightest opportunity serves. This principle is comprised in
                            the written Covenant of the Institution, and confirmed and established by the agreement and
                            signature of all its members; by which no individual is authorized to contract any debt, in
                            the name of the Institution, or any business connection which can, by any means, render the
                            Society responsible for their transactions. Nor will the Society be under obligations to
                            liquidate any demands, of Notes, Bonds, or any other security or obligation given in its
                            name, incurring debt for value received, either by the trustees thereof or of any other
                            individual; but such individual or individuals shall be held responsible for their own
                            transactions. Notices of these principles have been several times published, in the name and
                            by the authorities of the several branches of the United Society called '"Shakers." But, it
                            appears they are not so extensively known as they ought to be, to prevent frauds, and
                            impositions of that nature. It is therefore expedient again to give this public Notice, in
                            the name, and by the Authorities of the United Societies, with a request that it may be
                            extensively published, for the information of all, who may, at any time, be concerned in
                            dealing with Members, or professed members of this Community. Subscribed to by Presiding
                            Ministry and Trustees of all the United Societies of Shakers, who are in Covenant Relation.
                            May 23, 1871. JsOTE.—Any debts which may have heretofore been incurred by any official
                            Agents of the United Society in any of its branches, the beneiits whereof have been received
                            and acknowledged r&gt;y any family or Society of this Institution, if paid at all, as a
                            matter of justice to the creditor or creditors who may have been ignorant of the laws of the
                            Institution at the time such debt was contracted; or in lenity to the contractors of such
                            debt, will be paid only under the protest of the United Society, through its Authorities, as
                            in contravention of its laws and constitution. Ministry of New Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>JUVENILE DEPARTMENT</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear shaker:" TEIform="index"/>Dear Shaker :</head><p TEIform="p">—I wish to say a few words to some one, whomsoever it may concern; but hope it may be
                                one, who is not over 20 years of as;e,-—on the subject of human advancement to better
                                and higher conditions. I hope, also, hereby to elicit a kind response from any one of
                                youthful years, who may deem this worthy the notice of a reply. I think there is a
                                natural and irrepressible desire in every one, regardless how wicked and degraded, to
                                better their conditions, in some way, physically, mentally or spiritually. Indeed, most
                                persons in their moments of sober reflection, wish they were, or could be improved in
                                all directions. Perhaps, there is no human being in existence, who does not possess this
                                instinctive desire to progress. It is more than probable that, upon this little spark of
                                deific goodness in the soul, depends the only hope of salvation; that is, an ultimate
                                development in perfect holiness. Some persons of a very low, and unfortunate
                                organization, may pass many years without discovering to themselves, or others, this in-
                                stinct of progress; but it is no less in existence, and only needs to have its lips
                                touched by a coal from the altar of heaven's inspiration, to resurrect it into palpable
                                consciousness and activity. How this was brought about in my case, while I was quite
                                young, I will try to describe in this article. I was neither very good, nor very bad, in
                                my youthful days; but frequently my attention was called to some particular virtue,
                                trait, or characteristic of progress and improvement, in some person, which I felt I was
                                in want of. If such persons had a sweet, pleasant way of inculcating the advantages of
                                possessing such good quality, or trait, I immediately fell in love with the beauty and
                                propriety thereof; and if they still further exem54 <pb n="55" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 55
                                plifted the sweetness, and heavenly worth, of such good virtue, then I was quite
                                captivated thereby, and would resolve immediately to adopt into my practical life, such
                                valuable and soul-renovating treasure! I remember of reading the life of Francis Lewis
                                Carnaro, an Italian nobleman, who excelled in the virtue of Temperance, as well as many
                                other excellent qualities of character : 0 how I was charmed and delighted with his
                                experience! and how strongly I resolved to be temperate! He had a beautiful way of show-
                                ing up the advantages of a temperate, peaceful life. I read Dr. Franklin's inimitable
                                "Biography," and how I wished I could follow along in his footsteps of industry and
                                economical ways. Again, I recollect, once, when about 14 years of age, and although so
                                young, under many heavy trials and temptations to a sinful life, of unmanly passion and
                                pleasure, that I chanced to go to one of the families of Believers, more advanced than
                                the one I lived in, on some little errand. As I approached, I saw a Brother stirring
                                hay, in the dooryard. I passed at some distance from him, and without speaking; but I
                                distinctly recollect what were my thoughts, at the time: "This good Brother has fought
                                the good fight, and the conflict is over! The evening of his days is being spent in
                                peaceful meditations upon all those earlier trials, sorrows and victories of youth,
                                which, though bitter to bear, are so sweet to remember ! He can now safely and serenely
                                repose on the green shore of the sea of life, and listen to the far-off' booming of the
                                thunder, and the roar of the billows, and fearful surges of sorrow and temptation, which
                                with him are over, and gone forever! How sweet! How peaceful! What a good thing- it was
                                that he made the passage safely. He is now at rest, while I am so tossed and terrified
                                by the storms and tempests of passions unhallowed, and constant temptation to sin, that
                                I am more than three-fourths of my time in uncontrollable sorrow and tears, and constant
                                struggles to ward off the terrible catastrophe of a final surrender to actual, hopeless
                                perdition! " These were my solemn reflections; but notwithstanding the dreadful weight
                                of tribulation I was then under, the sight of this good old veteran, in his clean shirt,
                                dark pants and blue satin vest, filled me for the time, and for a considerable period
                                after, with a great calm; his sphere, and serene spirit psychologized me for several
                                days—nerving me to still greater exertions, if possible, to make my calling and election
                                sure; and culminate, as I felt he had done, in complete victory and peace ! And, my
                                young friend, though I do by no means feel boastful, nor egotistical, yet for your
                                encouragement and comfort, allow me to announce to you, that I am now occupying the same
                                position, on the same green, peaceful shore, that my veteran exemplar occupied, when I
                                passed in sight of him, forty years ago. And if these thoughts, and these little
                                reminiscences of my past actual experience, will do you any good, I shall be glad of it.
                                Remember, I am praying for you all the time, that beyond and above all other
                                considerations, you may somehow find ample ability to live a pure, sinless life; and
                                that your solemn journey toward a higher, holier plane, may culminate in Everlasting
                                Peace! Yours affectionately,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. Hampton</byline></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Henry C. Blinn to the young" TEIform="index"/>Henry C Blinn to the Young</head><p TEIform="p">Accepting the kind offer of " The Shaker," we have joined company with those who are
                                interested in the "Juvenile Department." Kindly thank you, dear Editor, for bearing us
                                in remembrance. We find our spirit closely conjoined to yours, in the hope that our
                                little paper may be a home educator; hence the necessity of a department for the young,
                                one where the children and youth will be as well represented as are the theologians in
                                other sections of the paper. A thorough understanding of the elementary principles, is
                                the securing of a good foundation upon which to build a permanent superstructure While
                                our superiors are earnestly contending for the faith and devotedly advocating their
                                religious views, we may be as acceptably engaged on the subject of good behavior and
                                moral deportment. We should not only be interested in these for our own especial
                                benefit, but at the same time for the blessing it confers upon others. " Suffer little
                                children to come unto me," is the voice of parental care. The spirit of this should
                                indelibly form its impression upon the mind. Good children. Virtuous youth. With what
                                satisfaction we are led to express these titles of affectionate regard. We are
                                influenced to this, in part, from the manifestation of the good spirit that dwells with
                                you at the present time, and also, from the anxious hope of what you may be in more
                                mature years. Now, the question arises, whose names'shall we write under the above
                                titles ? Shall it be the boy or girl who does not use vulgar or improper language ?
                                Shall we write the names of those who "never told a lie," or of those who have never
                                taken anything from father, mother, brother or sister, without their consent ? Poor
                                children! we fear the names would be few, indeed, if you submitted to this examination.
                                What shall we do ? Well, all my young friends may consider themselves as the ones
                                addressed. Not only those who have been called good and virtuous, but we will also
                                include that class who may not have earned a public expression of this title. The "best
                                boy" or girl may hare done wrong, a few times, while the " worst boy" or girl have no
                                doubt been credited with one or more kind and generous acts. A close selfexamination
                                into the motives which influenced you to do, or not to do, can be the only test of your
                                goodness. Do as well as you have learned, and you will find many willing friends to
                                assist you. When we say that it is easier to be good, than it is to be wicked; that it
                                is easier to tell the truth, than to tell a falsehood; that it requires no greater
                                effort to speak a kind word, than it does to speak an unkind word, we simply tell you
                                what experience has taught many who have gone before you. Try it. Be kind to he aged,
                                and be respectful to all. Always speak the truth! No matter what you may liave done!
                                Never conceal it under false stories. Speak the truth! One misrepresentation will lead
                                the way to another, and every false word arries you farther and farther from a correct
                                statement, and you are less able to acknowledge the truth by an honest confession. By
                                all means, speak the truth! In connection with the above, we find this, generally, to be
                                the case. Those who tell falsehoods will steal! If you would sustain a good character,
                                never take that which does not belong to you. If you wish to. possess it, ask for it. If
                                your request is not granted, you may be disappointed, but if you have any respect for
                                yourself, or love for your friends, do not steal! False and wicked stories will grow
                                from it, which may not only injure you for the society of the good, but may at the same
                                time bring hours of sorrow to those who have taken a deep interest in your welfare. If
                                you have ever told that which is untrue, honestly confess it before your father or
                                mother, or before those who are acting as your guardians. If you have ever taken that
                                which did not belong to you, return it to the owner, if possible, and then make an
                                honest confession of it, and promise never to do so again. Be very careful of your words
                                and actions, lest jon acquire these bad habits and lose the honor of a good name.
                                Beware, young friends, of the first temptations to do wrong. They may lead to a ruinous
                                practice.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. B.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>AGRICULTURAL</head><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">By some, it is thought, a few columns of our paper can be profitably devoted to
                                Agriculture, Horticulture, Mechanics, etc., though we are not among the number, we open
                                to those who are anxious, and ask future writers to send only good, practical hints in
                                the fewest possible words. *</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stirring the soil essential to plant growth" TEIform="index"/>Stirring the Soil Essential
                                to Plant Growth</head><p TEIform="p">The season of preparing soils for the growth of plants, and putting the seed into the
                                ground being passed, the prospective crop must now depend not merely on the season
                                (though a good season is essential to a good crop), but largely on the cultivation of
                                the plants. When a boy we worked in the garden, and nine summers of our minority were
                                devoted to the culture, principally of culinary vegetables, medicinal plants, and roots;
                                grape vines, and the seeds of culinary vegetables! Our leader was a reader and admirer
                                of William Cobbett (the English gardener, farmer, lawyer, author and statesman), and we
                                were constantly taught to be trying Oobbett's plans of gardening, as well as to devise
                                originals toexcell Cobbett if possible; and, sometimes we did excell him; and some-
                                times we found, by experience, that we were ignoramuses, relative to the economy of
                                plant growth. But we succeeded in learning how to raise some plants, to say the least of
                                it, to excellence, if not perfection; among these, we will name cabbages, onions,
                                cucumbers and many others. Brigham Young makes it a first lesson in Mormon religion when
                                the Believer has migrated to Utah, to learn to raise a cabbage. The lesson is a good
                                one, and we will give our <pb n="56" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 56 THE SHAKER. version of it. Premising,
                                that all plants derive most of their nourishment from the atmosphere, until they begin
                                to perfect their seeds, then they draw from the soil. But to our lesson: How to raise a
                                cabbage and an onion. First, The plants should be sown in a bed of fine, rich loam;
                                after coming up, thinned to at least one inch apart; second, before transplanting, which
                                should not be done until the plants are six inches high, and stocky, water the plants
                                until the soil is quite wet; select a moist atmosphere to remove the plants in; having,
                                in all cases freshly and deeply stirred the soil with plough or spade, take up the
                                plants with a trowel or shingle, lifting them carefully with as much earth as possible
                                clinging to their rootlets; dig a hole with the tool, much larger than the root is to
                                occupy and set in the plant, filling around the root with fine fresh earth; press
                                lightly around the roots; after a few days' standing, hoe the ground about the plants;
                                if the weather is very dry, every morning, when the dew is on the plant, as the roots
                                drink in aerial nourishment as well as the broad leaves. We have known the finest
                                cabbages raised in this way, even in very dry seasons, when cabbages not thus treated,
                                but hoed only three or four times during the season, made no heads at all! Never hoe
                                cabbages, in very hot and dry weather, after the dew is gone! Dig around a cabbage
                                deeply; but never stir deeply the soil about an onion; simply scrape the surface of the
                                soil, and keep clean of weeds. Of course, if you are no novice, you will never sow
                                onions on coarse, hard, lumpy, wet soil; nor on any soil which is not very rich; as well
                                plant beans in lake Erie! The very frequent stirring of the soil is also essential to
                                raising good vines, as cucumbers and melons; and the best crops are raised on a heavily
                                manured sod, inverted just before planting, and thoroughly pulverized with the harrow.
                                As the seed of plants draws most of its nutriment from the soil, good, full, plump seeds
                                cannot be grown without strong soil, or much manure; thrifty plants may be produced, but
                                not good seed ! The gist of this lesson is, first, that soils, like the haves of plants,
                                drink in plant nutrition from the atmosphere, if stirred frequently and kept loose and
                                friable; second, that the mouths of the rootlets drink up this nourishment from the
                                atmosphere under these circumstances, as the leaves do the dews. fieans.—Never hoe them
                                when the dew or rain is upon them nor when the soil is wet; it burns them like a fire.
                                Stir the soil often when the soil and plants are dry. A field of beans last summer
                                planted on poor soil without manure, had no hoeing, excepting one row; the crop was
                                small, but double on the hoed row, than on either side. What was the cause ? Somebody
                                ought to tell us this in coming numbers of the paper; and, dear Editor, they should tell
                                us too, that each and all kinds of manure are not equally well adapted to each and all
                                kinds of plants; they should tell us, that, while horse manure, and the droppings of
                                fowls are good for corn and cucumbers, they are not so good for Asparagus, as the manure
                                from horned cattle, and why. There is much dear Editor that "The Siiakeb, " might teach
                                on agriculture, and agricultural chemistry, the adaptation of soils and manures to
                                plants; the preparation of soils for plants; the management of manures. This article
                                though it breaks the ground in the Agricultural field of " The Shaker " is not written
                                as a model, but to open the field for better and more work.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. A., Mt. L.</byline></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Agriculture</head><p TEIform="p">The important and exhaustless subject of agriculture necessarily has large claims on our
                                attention. Though one man may not exactly follow the plans of another, to achieve
                                success as the conditions are rarely alike. A slight difference in climate, soil,
                                markets, etc., determine to a certain extent our varied modes of operations. And
                                perhaps, more than all, the knowledge, the executive ability, and means, wanting to
                                secure the desired end. Therefore, may we not with profit make suggestions and
                                experiments, and give practical results, and thus add to the store already acquired and
                                stimulate farther inquiry ? Since " he who makes two spears of grass grow where only one
                                grew before is a public benefactor;" let us all strive to that end and profit by the
                                best experience and bring to our aid a ready and willing ally—Science. Suppose we
                                discuss the question of large farms and earless culture versus small farms and high
                                cultivation? Let us contrast " Farmer Slack with Farmer Thrift." An interchange of
                                thought and experience will be of great benefit to the agricultural interests. The law
                                of gravitation confirms the all pervading declaration, that as mortals our duty is upon
                                the earth to which we are wonderfully adapted; though the fountains whence we draw our
                                spirit is from above. And besides the command, not in the Bible alone, but in that other
                                and more audible scripture, the objective and silent teachings legibly written on every
                                living thing, to " multiply and replenish and subdue the earth" into usefulness and
                                beauty. Then let us study the most feasible and effectual means to " multiply "
                                vegetation and "replenish " the worn-out earth with renewed vigor and "subdue" its
                                spontaneous productions to comfort, convenience and use. Since we take our domestic
                                animals from their native climate to serve us in a forced artificial mode of living,
                                should it not become our duty to provide for their comfort as well as our interest and
                                profit ? A reply to a few leading questions may interest and benefit all. No one objects
                                to the fair exchange of knowledge. "I willingly exchange uay ignorance for knowledge." I
                                trust that at least one well filled column will be devoted to this subject of primary
                                and vital importance. May we have the pleasure of hearing from all, from Maine to
                                Kentucky.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. Myrick</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It Is expected F. W. Evans will leave this country for London..." TEIform="index"/>It Is expected F. W. Evans will leave this country for London...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It Is expected F. W. Evans will leave this country for London, on the 1st proximo. His tour
                            will be of a strictly evangelical nature. He will be accompanied by J. M. Peebles. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Errata" TEIform="index"/>ERRATA</head><p TEIform="p"> InJnnennniber, first page, third column, eighth line omit the word :' not &gt;' to get
                            the author's meaning. Also, in the same column, read " dog-rose " for primrose. It is
                            needless to say, theae were not the mistakes of " i\ W. E.''</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We furnish The Shaker at something less than cost..." TEIform="index"/>We furnish The Shaker at something less than cost...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">We furnish The Shaker at something less than cost. All subscriptions, received during 1871,
                            will date from January of present year. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Particular attention is called to the 'Declaration and Warning'..." TEIform="index"/>Particular attention is called to the 'Declaration and Warning'...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Particular attention is called to the "Declaration and Warning" issued bv Ministry of Mount
                            Lebanon. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When we pray 'Thy kingdom come, thy will be done on earth,'..." TEIform="index"/>When we pray 'Thy kingdom come, thy will be done on earth,'...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> When we pray "Thy kingdom come, thy will be done on earth," do we realize whether there is a
                            distinction or not, between our lives and those we believe are living in heaven ? Are we
                            sincere in our prayer ? * </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker, monthly journal, devoted to the exposition of religion, acording to Shaker theology" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER. MONTHLY JOURNAL, DEVOTED TO THE EXPOSITION OF RELIGION, ACCORDING TO SHAKER
                            THEOLOGY.</head><p TEIform="p">Fiftx Cents, Per Axsum, in Advance. G. A. Lomas, Resident Editor, Shakers. Albany Co., N. Y.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Members of society" TEIform="index"/>MEMBERS OF SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p"> Appointed to answer Correspondents, among whom are the Board of .Editors. Elder F. W. Evans.
                            Mt. Lebanon, Columbia Co., N. Y. " Issachar Bates, Shakers. &gt;i. Y. "„ Calvin G. Reed,
                            Mt Moms, Livingston Co., N. Y. " Simon Mabee, West Pittsfield, Mass. " Stoughton Kellogg,
                            Thompsonville, Conn., Shakers. " Albert Battles, Tyringham, Berkshire Co., Mass. " Wm.
                            Leonard, Ayer, Mass., Shakers. " John Whiteley, Shirley Village, Middlesex Co., Mass. "
                            Nehemiah Trull, Shaker Village, Merrimack Co., N. H. " Henry Cummings, Enfield, Grafton Co.,
                            H. H. " John B. Vance, Alfred, Shakers, York Co., Me. " Alonzo Oilman, West Gloucester,
                            Cumberland Co., Me., Shakers. " Charles Clapp, Union Village, Warren Co., O., Shakers. "
                            Ezra Sherman, Preston, Hamilton Co., Ohio, Shakers. " Stephen Ball, Dayton, Shakers, Ohio. "
                            George Rnnyon. Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co., Ky. " J. B. Eades, South Union, Logan Co., Ky. "
                            J. 8. Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio, Shakers. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publications" TEIform="index"/>PUBLICATIONS.</head><p TEIform="p"> Christ's First and Second Appearing Dunlavy:s Manifesto .... Millennial Church ....
                            Compendium of Shakerism Three Discourses on United Interests Tracts free, where postage is
                            paid. 81 25 1 25 1 00 0 50 0 50</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>