<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm1707" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">23</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">17</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">07</biblScope><date value="18870701" TEIform="date">July 1887</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">145-168</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="17" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="07" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
<pb id="p1"/>
JULY.
MANIFESTO.
Published by the United Societies.
"Every plant which my heavenly Father hath not planted shall be rooted
up."- -Matt, xv., 13.
Canterbury, N. H.
1887,
THE
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
The Gospel Testimony, No. 16.
Family Relations,
Jealousy,
Address to Youth,
Changed Cross,
Things worth Considering,
Christian Love,
Persevere,
Thou art the Man,
Faith,
Beware of Trifles,
Daily   Reckoning,
Notes,- -That Ideal Home,
Rheumatism,           -          - -
Tobacco-Created,
Letter,- -N. Danforth,
An Old Lady,
English Language,
Letter- -II. DeGraw,
Christian Communism, No. 4.
Kind Words,
The Truly so,
From Day to Day,
Books & Papers,
145
149
151
155
156
158
159
160
161
162
163
164
165
167
168
MEDAL   MACHINES.
NEW YOBK STATE AQEIOULTtTRAL WOBES
1st, Premiums at all Competitive   Trials
Railway, Chain and lever Home Powera, Threshers and Cleaners, Threshers
- -V Shakers, Clover Hullers, Feed Cutters, Wheel Horse Rakes, Morse Pitchforks, Shingle Machines, Straw Preserving- Rye Threshers, Portable S- -eam-JEng-ines, Cider and Wine Mills and Presses,
Dog- and Pony Powers, Disc Harrows
& Spring-y Tooth   Harrows.     " Robinson's Hay Press, of four sizes- Will
work as easy with one horse as
others with two. Made with Steel
Gearing which can not be broken."
WHEELER & MELICK Co.,
ALBANY, N. Y.
Send stamp for Circular and report of Centennial
trial.
SHORT HINTS
-O1VT
  SOCIAL ETIQUETTE,
Compiled from the latest and best works
on the subject by "Aunt Matilda.'"
PRICE, 40 cents.
THIS book should be in every
family desirous of knowing "the proper thing to do."
We all desire to behave properly and to know what is the best
school of manners. What shall
we teach our children, that they
may go out into the world well
bred men and women?
"SHORT HINTS" contains
the answer and will be mailed
to any address, postage prepaid on receipt of price.
SPECIAL
Until further notice we will
mail each of our friends a copy
of the above valuable book
gratis and free of postage, if
they will mail us 15 wrappers
of Dobbins' Electric Soap.
By folding up the wrappers
as you would a newspaper, the
postage will only be 2cts.
Always put your full name
and address on the out side of
the bundle and write the word
"Etiquette" also, and then we
will know who sends it.
I. L. CRAGIST & Co.,
PHILADELPHIA, PENN'A.
AGENTS WANTED &canvasaf
established, best-known NurseriesTm^he country. Host liberal terms. Unequaled facilities
Prices low. Geneva Nursery. Established
184- -.   W. - -fc T. SMITH, Geneva. N. Y.
157
<pb n="" id="p"/>
Vol. XVII.
JULY,  1887.
No. --><pb n="145" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the elders, William Lee and James Whittaker no. 16" TEIform="index"/> The Gospel Testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the Elders, William Lee and James Whittaker.
                            No. 16.</head><p TEIform="p"> Published expressly for the several Communities of Believers in 1816. Re-written by Henry C.
                            Blinn. Mother Ann and the Elders visit the towns of Norton, Stonington, Preston and other
                            places. The public service that was held at the house of Joseph Bennett was addressed by
                            Elder Calvin Harlow, who received the best o? attention. In his delivery of the gospel
                            testimony, his voice was clear and pleasant, and the ministration was in such a loving
                            spirit that many wept and prayed with heartfelt devotion. A Baptist deacon was presint who
                            had been very much opposed to the testimony. At the close of the meeting he called and
                            wished to converse with Mother Ann. At first he seemed much interested and was pleased with
                            the remarks that were made. Becoming more familiar, he addressed himself to Mother Ann,-
                            -"Your children do not talk as you do. Why do they not talk as you do? Mother Ann replied,
                            "You must not expect the children to be parents." As the deacon did not wish to have his
                            life brought into the light of the testimony of Christ, nor his Christianity offended, he
                            soon retired. At a subsequent date two men called to see the Believers, but as they were
                            entire strangers they did not know Mother Ann, although she was then present in the company.
                            After an introduction one of the men remarked,- -"Is there not a woman here that is the head
                            of the church?" "No," replied Mother Ann, "Christ is the head of the church." Elder William
                            Lee then added,- - "We do not allow either man or woman to be the head of the church ;
                            Christ is the head of the church." "But," continued the mac, "there is a woman here that
                            teaches, is there not?" Elder William replied, " We do not allow either man or woman to
                            teach, except they have the spirit of Christ in them. Christ teaches through them, and with
                            this spirit, a man, woman or child may teach." Rumors having been received that a mob was
                            collecting only a few miles distant, some anxiety was manifested in the family, but the
                            Elders were not disturbed in their minds, and very fortu-<pb n="146" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> nately,
                            received no personal violence while they remained in the place. The next journey of the
                            Elders was to the town of Ashfield, and by invitation, accepted a home in the family of Asa
                            Bacon. Reaching this place on the first of November 1782, they remained till the next
                            spriug. Ashfield was a central place and on this account it was very convenient for the
                            Believers to meet and hold their seasons of public worship. It was thought also, that the
                            place would be less liable to be disturbed by mobs. So soon as the Elders extended the
                            liberty, a great number of people visited Ashfield from all parts of the country where the
                            gospel had been preached. It was estimated that not less than six hundred persons were there
                            at one time. During this revival season, the spirit and power of God was manifested in a
                            marvelous manner. In their testimonies they exhorted each other '' to contend earnestly for
                            the faith that was once delivered unto the saints." The church of God must be a light to the
                            world, and the people of God must live "soberly, righteously and godly in this present
                            world." But as in the early days of the primitive church, men and women had crept into the
                            fold of Christ; "ungodly men, turning the grace of God into lasciviousness and denying the
                            only Lord God and our Lord Jesus Christ." The voice of Mother Ann and the Elders against''
                            principalities and powers, against the rulers of darkness of this world, and against
                            spiritual wickedness in heavenly places," was like the roaring of thunder. Every heart was
                            searched and the work of purification was manifested in great power. Michael and his angels
                            fought agaiust the dragon and his angels, and so mighty was the noise of the battle that it
                            was heard at the distance of several miles. The sound was like " the voice of many waters
                            and as the voice of mighty thunders." In these operations of the spirit all the combustible
                            material of a depraved nature, "the lust of the flesh, the lust of the eyes and the pride of
                            life were burned as in a furnace. The flames which issued from the souls and mouths of these
                            messengers of God and passed among the assembly, burned and consumed everything that was not
                            in accordance with the testimony of Jesus Christ. The Revelator says "His eyes were as a
                            flame of fire. His voice as the sound of many waters and out of his mouth went a sharp
                            two-edged sword." Rev. i., 14-16. The blessed effects of this purifying fire were soon to be
                            seen and felt. When the evil influences were rooted out, the good fruit had room to grow.
                            The Believers learned lessons of meekness and humility. Peace, love and harmony flowed in
                            among them, and heavenly love and gospel union gained the pre-eminence and was cherished by
                            every faithful Believer. A spiritual light now began to shine more effectually upon them and
                            wisdom and understanding to influence them in all their actions. As the rubbish of the old
                            earth and heavens was purged out and burnt up, they began to see more clearly, and to
                            understand what belonged to the new. In all these things they saw that it was, indeed, a
                            great thing to learn the way of God. As yet they had just entered the work, but the
                            education was<pb n="147" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> producing a remarkable increase of the gospel among the
                            people. As no previous preparation had been made for the entertainment of the Believers in
                            Ashfield, consequently there were no stores of provisions laid up for the multitude, and
                            though the quantity on hand was, sometimes, very small and great numbers of people were
                            continually coming and going, yet with the blessing of God they knew no lack. Multitudes
                            have been fed many times, and under the peculiar ministration of the gift have been well
                            satisfied. Mother Ann would say to the people, "It is by the miracles of God that you have
                            been fed, O ye of little faith." The opposition to the work of the gospel had never been so
                            great in Ashfield, as in several other places, yet the Believers were sometimes disturbed by
                            "lewd fellows of the baser sort," who came for carnal and mischievous purposes. The most of
                            a disturbance was excited by Daniel Bacon. He and his family had accepted the faith, and for
                            a season were quite zealous in leading a Christian life. Becoming weary of the cross, Daniel
                            returned to the old inheritance, but his wife maintained her faith. In the month of March he
                            brought his wife and child in a sleigh, and without going into the house, he put them out,
                            in a very rough and churlish manner, into the street before the house and immediately drove
                            off. When the Elders were informed of the fact, they said, "This is an evil snare, he has
                            done this to produce trouble for us. She is his wife and we must not permit her to remain at
                            our house. One of the Brethren was then sent to convey her and the child to her own home.
                            Failing in his purpose, Daniel openly came out and by slanderous reports gave the enemies of
                            the cross a pretext to bring on a persecution. This furnished a pretext for a lawless
                            company to visit the Believers to inquire into the truth of the report. A large number of
                            the people of Ashfield were very friendly and would have avoided anything that was likely to
                            cause a disturbance. In the adjoining towns, however, there were many busy-bodies and
                            calumniators who were active, in circulating that which was false, and this class seized
                            every opportunity to scandalize the character of Mother Ann and the Elders, and to bring a
                            reproach upon her manner of life as well as upon the testimony she preached. A few days
                            subsequent to this action of Daniel Bacon, about sixty men collected in Shelburne and its
                            vicinity. The people of Ashfield were informed of the fact and immediately appointed a
                            Committee to confer with the leaders of the mob and prevent, if possible all riotous
                            proceedings. The Committee consisted of Thomas Stocking, a captain of militia, and two other
                            respectable men. They called at the house of Asa Bacon and asked to see Mother Ann. On
                            coming to the door, she remarked, " I am a poor, inoffensive, weak woman. I have suffered so
                            much from the cruelty of mobs that it seems impossible that I could endure any more. " The
                            Committee replied, " You need not fear, Madam, we have not come to hurt you, but to defend
                            you. " They then informed her of the anticipated uprising in Shelburne, and said, " We are
                            not willing to have any mobs iu Ashfield, and if you, and the Elders will go to the
                            residence of Philip Philips,<pb n="148" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> you shall be welcome and shall be
                            protected. " Mother Ann meditated upon the subject and considering herself under the
                            protection of the spirit of God, she did not choose to be under the protection of man, and
                            very kindly declined the offer. She then invited the Committee to dine with the family and
                            treated them with the utmost kindness. After dinner the Commitee retired and met the mob
                            about one half mile distant from the house. Here they held a conference with the leaders of
                            the company and found that their object was to search into the truth of some prevailing;
                            rumors, respecting the character of Mother Ann and the Elders. They had heard some infamous
                            reports and concluded that the preaching of the Believers was an imposition upon the people.
                            They strongly suspected her to be a British emissary and working for seditious purposes. The
                            Committee bore testimony of the j peaceable deportment and harmless conduct of the people.
                            The mob, however, could not be satisfied without a full examination of the Shakers for
                            themselves. The Committee then agreed that if the company would proceed no farther, Mother
                            Ann should answer for herself upon conditions that she should receive no harm. This seemed
                            to satisfy the leaders of the mob, but a part of the company, not agreeing with the decision
                            pushed on determining to reach the house of Asa Bacon. They hailed Ephraim Welch, who was
                            standing at the door, with this inquiry.- - '' Where is that woman you call Mother Ann?" " I
                            suppose she is in the house," said he, " What do you want?" " We hear that she ran away from
                            her own country; that she has been cropped and that a hole was burned through her tongue for
                            blasphemy, and we want to see for ourselves." Ephraim soon informed the Believers, of the
                            company at the door, and after the Elders had held consultation it was thought best to meet
                            them. Mother Ann accordingly stepped to the door, and said,- - *- -' What may you want of
                            me?" They repeated the reports that they had heard, as before, and said,- - " We have come
                            to see for ourselves." " It is unkind in you," said Mother, " but will you believe your own
                            eyes?" The speaker remarked, "We shall be obliged to believe. " " Then come forward, " said
                            Mother, " and see for yourselves. " '' Are my ears cropped ? " " Has my forehead been
                            branded? " ;' Has my tongue been burned with a hot iron ? " " Now with this evidence, what
                            do you think of the reports ? " " I think, " said the speaker, " that they tell awful lies
                            about you. " Mother Ann then told them how foolish it was to give credit to such false and
                            inconsistent reports, and how wrong it was to come and disturb the Believers in such a
                            wicked manner. The party made an apology and left the place, apparently much chagrined at
                            their own folly. The Ashfield Committee returned and informed the Believers of their
                            conference and agreement with the leaders of the mob, and then asked Mother Ann and the
                            Elders to go to the house of a distant neighbor, and in this way prevent the mob from
                            advancing. Agree-<pb n="149" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> ably to the wish of the Committee several of the
                            Brethren and Sisters made preparations for the trip. Mother Ann, Elder William Lee, Elder
                            James Whittaker, Calvin Harlow, Aaron Wood, Ephraim Welch and others formed the company. On
                            arriving at the house of friend Smith, they were very kindly received. The leader of the
                            mob, Col. David Wells of Shelburne, soon entered upon the examination of the charges, very
                            similar to those already mentioned, and found them fully refuted in all points. Many unkind
                            accusations were brought against the Believers. Oue was,- - " The Shakers have bought all
                            the hay in the town, that was to be sold, and a poor man cannot get enough to keep his cow
                            from starving. " The next accusation was. "They have also bought up all the grain, and the
                            poor are left destitute of bread to eat. " The Committee replied, " The people of the town
                            have a surplus of hay and find it to their advantage to sell it to the Shakers, because they
                            pay the money for it. We know of no such poor man, in the town, as has been mentioned, and
                            if he can be produced, he shall be supplied with hay. " The Believers had made the same
                            offer, but the poor man was not found. Of the second charge, it was proved that the Shakers
                            had not bought any grain in Ashfield. On the contrary, they had sold some to the people of
                            the town, which the Shakers had brought into the place. The Committee then bore testimony to
                            the honesty and integrity of the Believers, in all their dealings with other people, and
                            expressed an unwillingness to have them molested or to have the town disturbed on their
                            account. Having closed the examination, Mother Ann addressed herself to Col. Wells in these
                            words. " Is it not a pity that a man, professing to be it gentleman and an officer of the
                            United States, should give heed to such slanderous and inconsistent reports ? " '' That you
                            should come here at the head of a mob, away from your own town, to persecute an innocent
                            people is a very singular act." The Col. did not accept the reproof kindly, and threatened
                            to cane Mother Ann if she said any more. Mother Ann replied. " An American gentleman, and
                            are you threatening to cane a poor, weak woman? What a shame it would be ! " The Col.
                            attempted no farther opposition. Elder James Whittaker made a few remarks to the assembly,
                            and closed with these words : ' I am called to stand in defense of the gospel, and that I
                            will do to the losing of my life. " The mob then dispersed without committing any act of
                            violence. In this way God protected his people from the snares of the wicked. The earth
                            opened her mouth and swallowed up the flood of malicious lies and slanderous reports, which
                            the dragon had cast out against the woman. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Higher views of the family relation" TEIform="index"/> Higher Views of the Family Relation,</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>OLIVER C. HAMPTON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> It is generally admitted, that the perfection, stability and permanence of the Government
                            and prosperity of a Nation has its origin in that of the family.<pb n="150" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> In so
                            iar as the conduct and government of the families in a Nation are perfect in the same
                            degree, it is held, will the Nation itself be so in its conduct and government. This family
                            arrangement includes Father, Mother, Son and Daughter, and derives its Origin from Wisdom
                            and Love the primal principles (male and female) of our Universal Father and Mother (one
                            spirit) who is in Heaven. The Christ of the Universe including Son and Daughter are also to
                            be reckoned in this Parental Category. No doubt these views regarding the private families
                            in a Nation are true, as every thing must be of the character of the parts of which it is
                            composed. And it is necessary and important that Parents study and practice the best modes
                            of manipulation by which to render their families in the highest degree serviceable to the
                            Nation at large. But there is a Spiritual Parentage of far higher import and covering ground
                            of far higher glory and perfection than the very highest state attainable by any or all
                            families on the rudimental plane of animal existence. This has sometimes been denominated
                            the family of Christ. Considered in its largest meaning it includes not only Humanity on
                            this our planet, but all Intelligences in all worlds. As a hen gathereth her brood under her
                            wings, so this Heavenly Parentage gathereth all Angels and Arch-angels all saints and all
                            sinners within the Fold of its Divine Economy ;- -under the wings of its Infinite goodness
                            and charity. It is back of all development and moves us on from glory to glory and from
                            perfection to perfection from the start. The Christ of the Universe- -the Divine Son and
                            Daughter, emanate from the Divine Father and Mother and complete the Divine Parentage. Their
                            mission is to project iuto objective form and systematic order and arrangement, the thoughts
                            of God (the Infinite Father and Mother.) They are the Incarnated Word, which the beloved
                            apostle John declared, "was made flesh and dwelt among men." This unspeakable boon, this
                            incarnated word was represented by Jesus and his successors in the Pentecostal Church, and
                            during that dispensation was the visible medium or order through which mankind could and did
                            find and enjoy salvation from sin, and Brotherly Love and self-abnegation for the benefit of
                            Brethren and Sisters. But the ghastly ignorance of mankind and the terribly abject condition
                            in which woman was held, precluded all possibility of the representation of the mission of
                            the female at that time. Our spiritual Mother however, appeared and claimed her place and
                            mission in the Divine Economy about one hundred years ago and now the Incarnated Word in its
                            complete order and systematic arrangement and organization is consummated. The Lamb and the
                            Bride have made themselves ready, and invite mankind to the feast of good things, a,nd to
                            the higher planes of progress. The Pentecostal system of church organization has been
                            supplemented and perfected in this latter Dispensation by superadding to the requisitions of
                            celibacy and community of goods, another of grand and unspeakable value and Almighty
                            magnitude and importance (viz.) that of admitting to woman an equal share in the<pb n="151" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/>parental government and manipulation of the affairs of the church in all
                            matters Temporal, Intellectual- -Spiritual of our life and existence as an Institution. Our
                            church therefore under the panoply of these eternal principles of organization is ready and
                            able to lead its votaries into all degrees of evolution and progress;- -into all that is
                            high, holy, pure and happy. To this glorious privilege we most earnestly invite all who are
                            seeking a sinless life of peace, purity and love to come and share with us the joys of a
                            Heaven here, and eternally hereafter. Union Village, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jealousy" TEIform="index"/> JEALOUSY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/> MARTHA J. ANDERSON.</byline><p TEIform="p">Jealousy outrivals all the contemptible vices of human nature ; insomuch as it embitters
                            life's sweetest springs ; destroys the lovliest buds of virtue ; warps mental expansion, is
                            godless and irreverent of the feelings of others, bears no good will to superior excellence;
                            and strives to bring everybody and everything to the level of its own meanness. It carries
                            into all its projects and intentions, the blind unreason of intense selfishness; tampers
                            with heart-love, sincerity and friendship, and many a broken tie bespeaks its cursed power.
                            Its scathing blight is felt in the home, in the social circle, in the religious assembly,
                            and throughout the broad arena of life's pursuits, where humanity compete for fame, station
                            or renown. What contumely, scorn, bitter hatred and falsehood it heaps on those, who, by its
                            very contempt it acknowledges superior to its own base self-hood. It seeks position it does
                            not merit; claims wealth it does not earn ; libels character it cannot attain; belittles
                            knowledge because of ignorance; and bars the doors to all advance in virtue, wisdom and
                            goodness. Its curse returns in cursing. Only he who blesses has the promise to be blessed.
                            In honor preferring one another is the lofty ideal given by the divine master. Love,
                            consolation and peace, bloom only in the garden of sweet contentment. Our talents can only
                            be measured by the good we accomplish ; position alone determines not our real worth. There
                            are nobler themes to engage our attention than the mere petty strifes of human and
                            terrestrial affairs. Live to be good, not great. The lowliest may drink the nectar of bliss
                            denied the great ones of the earth ; and those who have no treasures here, may secure them
                            in heaven. We shall receive whereof we are worthy, no more : The lovable shall be loved, the
                            honest trusted, and the meritorious rewarded. Then let us not harbor this base passion ; for
                            the wind of fate shall turn the flame it kindles, to scathe and scorch our souls, to the
                            extinction of every green and living thing, that might otherwise spring up to gladden and
                            beautify our being. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Address to youth" TEIform="index"/> ADDRESS TO YOUTH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/> DANIEL FRASER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> By the good providences of God you have a privilege to see and hear of, and practice
                            Christian principles. There are many who are educated in schools and colleges, and called
                            Christians, who preach and pray, and yet have not begun<pb n="152" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> to practice
                            the first Christian principle. Indeed have not yet begun to practice the first just natural
                            principle- -that is, to get an honest living with their own hands. Your opportunities to
                            become truly learned greatly exceed theirs ; and if you receive the principles and truths of
                            the gospel- -the glad tidings that Christ and Mother brought; and put them into practice in
                            your every-day life- -in all your goings forth, you will become truly learned, and finally,
                            you will be assured that in Christ Jesus is hid all the treasures of wisdom and knowledge.
                            My object in writing to you is not to open up any branch of knowledge, but to point where
                            some of the treasures of wisdom and knowledge may be found. The Old Testament is a wonderful
                            book- -it contains a system of law adapted to the natural man which exceeds all other
                            natural systems of human law; and portraitures of human character so truthful, and
                            applicable to human conditions, that even after the lapse of three thousand years, they are
                            still fresh, new and instructive. In the above respects, the Bible is without a parallel
                            among books- -it is above and beyond them all. And of the New Testament, the parables alone
                            are caskets of wisdom and knowledge, to say nothing of the great leading principles which
                            underlie Christianity- -lived otit by the Savior and opened in his teachings. What can be
                            more comprehensive, or fuller of simplicity than Christ's interview with the young man who
                            came to him and kneeling, asked, "What shall I do to inherit eternal life ? In a few words
                            he conveyed to the young man, a knowledge of the work necessary to be done as a preparation
                            to entering his kingdom. To' keet) the Moral Law- -that is. do nothing to injure others, and
                            give his all, and himself to God. Then he would be in a condition to learn of Jesus. The
                            reading of the parables as presented in the scriptures, is very much like unto a rich man
                            having a casket of precious things, who comes along and shows you a nice box ; he opens it,
                            and every little compartment is stored with jewels ; he shuts it up, and takes it away with
                            him, and you are none the richer for what you have seen. So of the sayings of Jesus, you may
                            read them, and get an outside understanding of them, but if you do not practice nor square
                            your life by the contained teachings, you will not be any richer in heavenly things. Jesus
                            spake from the life he lived, hence he was able to say "the words that I speak unto you they
                            are spirit and they are life. " Now, if you will make his life your life, so in your degree,
                            you will be able also to speak from your life. But if you fail to do so- -have not the life
                            of Christ in you, you will be able to speak of natural things only, for out of the contents
                            of the heart the mouth speaketh. It may be observed here, that all human beings have in them
                            a two-fold life- - an inward or spiritual life, and an outward animal life. Before I close,
                            perhaps I will say a few words on this subject. In the mean time I will open one of the
                            caskets, on the outside is written the following words "I will open my mouth in parables, I
                            will utter things which have been kept hid from the foundation of the world"- -the natural
                            man. Parable first. A sower went forth to sow his seed, and as he sowed some fell by the
                            wayside and was trodden down, and the fowls of the air devoured them.<pb n="153" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/>
                            And some fell on stony places, and forthwith the seed sprung up because there was but little
                            depth of earth, and when the sun shone the plants withered. And some fell among thorns and
                            the plants were choked. And some fell on o-ocd orouud and brought focth some one degree of
                            fruit and others a greater measure. When Jesus had opened this casket, he said, l he that
                            hath ears to hear, let him hear. " He then shut the casket up, and took the treasure away
                            with him, aud left the multitude to think about what might be the meaning of the parable. No
                            doubt you would like to know the reason why Jesus did not explain it to them. He would have
                            been well pleased to have done so, but he considered their state of preparation to hear his
                            word, and wisdom forbade committing further knowledge to their keeping. And with pleasure he
                            turned to his disciples and said, " blessed are your eyes for they see, and your ears for
                            they hear." " Hear ye therefore the parable of the sower. " And he began to open to them its
                            interior meaning, which you may read by turning to Luke, viii., 5. But before he began, he
                            said, " Many prophets and righteous men have desired to see what you see, and hear what you
                            hear and have not heard them. " To the language used by Jesus in explaining the first part
                            of the parable, I would draw your attention. "Those by the wayside are they who hear, then
                            cometh the devil and taketh away the word out of their hearts." Now how did the devil manage
                            to take the good word out of their hearts ? they gave way to lightness- -"the fowls of the
                            air devoured it." Here we see that g-viug way to lightness in sacred things is an act of the
                            devil. Young persons are greatly exposed to receive from their own hearts, and from others
                            this spirit of lightness ; to many, it is just as natural to be light as it is to breathe,
                            or in other words, they willingly work the works of the devil, and minister the same spirit
                            of lightness to others and think nothing about it; aud that is the way the devil wishes his
                            work to be done; do it and never think about it afterwards. Christ knowing how exposed souls
                            are, said, " Watch and pray that ye enter not into temptation " that is, into the spirit of
                            the evil one. The devil has the easiest access to young people through the avenue of
                            lightness ; they think there is no great harm in it, and will actually sing the songs of
                            Zion in a light careless sense. When a soldier is placed on guard, it is his duty to watch
                            and see that no enemy goes over the line or gets a foothold in the camp. So of all the
                            thoughts that enter your head, except you gather and keep the gift of self-examination you
                            will find that the devil will enter your premises every day, and instead of you being a
                            guard to keep out evil, you will be an avenue to receive and admit it. Without watchfulness
                            and self-examination, you cannot progress a single inch- -without selfexamination you will
                            stumble as you go every day ; not ouly so, but you will be a stumbling block in the way of
                            others. A lack of the gift of self-examination is the reason why young people need so much
                            laboring with. They do things from an inward pressure of evil. Against this pressure of evil
                            a cross has to be borne. That is the reason why<pb n="154" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/>Jesus taught h's
                            disciples to bear a daily cross ; and it is just the same with you today, as it was with the
                            young disciples in Christ's day. And when he warned his disciples to watch and pray, in the
                            course of his labors he added another word- -Pray aud faint not- -do not give up to the
                            enemy. One of the reasons why youth do not examine themselves, is, because they do not want
                            to change. They want to be the same kind of persons that they have been- -to follow their
                            own natural way, and not God's way. Now that will never do- -Christ and Mother changed- -
                            turned from their own ways. Christ came not to do his own will, but the will of his Father.
                            The youth who stands stiff in his own will, is of the wicked one. Another reason why youth
                            do not lik': to examine themselves, is, they do not like to read the record of their own
                            doings as written on their memory. Do not like to look at themselves, because they havj b
                            'en giving way here and there, and so been co-workers with Satan ; and so much under his
                            power, as to be afraid to -ay to him '* get thee behind me Satan." Have -not simplicity
                            enough to tell themselves and their Elders the truth, and so shame the devil. In examining
                            natural objects men are not content with their ordinary vision, they use helps- -examine
                            things microscopically, and are much pleased to have the microscope open up something they
                            could not see with their naked eye. Now how is it possible for any person to know himself,
                            if he will not examine himself with his own eyes. Those who do, will have the help of other
                            eyes that see clearer and farther than their own ; in this way, -kGod helps those who help
                            themselves." But those who have eyes and see not, shall wander- - - - stumble and fall in
                            the dark- -the darkness of their own will. It may be asked, how can the gift of
                            self-examination be gained and kept? the answer is, by continually exercising it on all you
                            do, by night and by day. Persevere therein till it becomes pleasant so to do- -becomes a
                            delightful duty. Then ye will know for yourselves experimentally, and truly, that Christ's
                            yoke is easy, and his burden light. I omit saying anything further on this interesting
                            parable. Exercise your mind upon it, and gather information from others on the subject. And
                            when you get through with this parable- -this beautiful casket, there are others equally so.
                            There is the casket of the Fig tree, of a grain of Mustard seed- -of a little Leaven- -of
                            the Prodigal- -of the unjust Steward- -of the Beggar aud the Rich man- -of the man who
                            thought too highly of himself- -of the unjust Judge, of the man who went into a far country-
                            -of the man who planted a Vineyard- -of the Woman aud the lo.-t money- -of the lost Sheep-
                            -of the Tares- - of the Shepherd and the Sheepfold- -of the Net aud the Fishes- -and of the
                            Casket of the Pearl of Great Price. Every one of these Caskets contains gems illustrative of
                            the kingdom of Heaven where lust has no place- -where they neither marry, nor are given in
                            marriage. Blessed are those who have a part in that kingdom never to go out. I will now say
                            a few words on the twofold life in man. Jesus said, "flesh aud blood cannot inherit the
                            kingdom of heaven." Now all the animal creation are flesh and blood, and are brought<pb n="155" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> forth through the action of the propensities. Aud we in common with
                            the lower animals, have the same kind of life, and the same propensities ; therefore, that
                            life can have no part in heaven. Intellect in connection with our animal life does not make
                            it any better nor change its nature. In addition to that life, we have another- -a life that
                            the word of God can quicken ; but no mere animal can be quickened by that word. The Apostle
                            said twye hath he quickened who were dead in trespasses and in sins." Ye hath he quickened
                            into a higher life, who were wont to live in the lusts of the flesh and of the mind. Again,
                            the Apostle said, "If ye live after the flesh ye shall die, but if ye through the Spirit do
                            mortify the deeds of the body ye shall live. And as maay as are led by the spirit of God,
                            they are the sons of God," And no longer the sons of Adam. The testimony of the gospel which
                            you hear from time to time, is the testimony of life to the inner man ; and no soul can ever
                            be quickened except in obedience and subjection to it. You may gather from these few words,
                            an understanding, which life is acceptable to God, and to your Brethren and Sisters, and
                            which is not; remembering at all times, that ye cannot serve two masters. Which will ye
                            serve, an old fleshly nature, or will ye strive and pray that ye may be quickened into a
                            newness of life ? Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Changed cross" TEIform="index"/> THE CHANGED CROSS.</head><p TEIform="p"> It was a time of sadness and my heart Although it knew and felt the better part, Felt
                            wearied with the conflict and the strife, All, all the needful discipline of life. And while
                            I thought on these as given me, My trial test of faith and love to be, It seemed as if I
                            never could be sure That faithful to the end I should endure. And thus no longer trusting to
                            his might Who says, we walk by faith and not by sight, Doubting-and yielding almost to
                            despair The thought arose. My cross I cannot bear, For heavier its weight must surely be
                            Than those of others which I daily see; O! if I might another burden choose Methiuks 1
                            should not fear my crown to lose. A solemn silence reigned on all around, E'en nature's
                            voices uttered not a sound, The evening shadows seemed of peace to tell And sleep upon my
                            weary spirit fell. A moment's pause, and then a heavenly light Beamed lull upon my
                            wandering, raptured sight, Angels on silvery wings seemed everywhere And angel's mnsic
                            thrilled the balmy air. Then one more fair than all the rest to see, One to whom all others
                            bowed the knee Came gently to me as I trembling lay And " Follow me " he said, " I am the
                            way " Then speaking thus, he led me far above And there beneath a canopy of love, Crosses of
                            diverse shapes and size were seen Larger and smaller than my own had been. And one that was
                            most lovely to behold A little one with jewels set in gold; All this methought I can with
                            comfort wear, For it will be an easy one to bear. And so the little cross I quickly took But
                            all at once my frame beneath it shook. The spark'ling jewels fair they were to see, But far
                            too heavy was their weight for me. This may not be, I cried, and looked again, To see if any
                            here could ease my pain, But one by one I cast them slowly by Till on a lovely one I cast
                            mine eye, Fair flowers around its sculptured form entwined, And grace and beauty seemed in
                            it combined; Wondering I gazed and still I wondered more, To think so many should have
                            passed it o'er. But O, that form so beautiful to see, Soon made its hidden sorrows known fo
                            me Thorns lay beneath those flowers and colors fair, Sorrowing I said. This cross I cannot
                            bear. And so it was with each and all around Not one to suit my need could there be found;
                            Weeping I laid each heavy burden down As my guide gently said, " No cross, no crown. " At
                            length to Him I raised my saddened heart, He knew its sorrows; bid its doubts depart, Be not
                            afraid, he said, But trust in me My perfect love shall now be shown to thee, And then with
                            lightened eyes and willing feet Again I turned my earthly cross to meet, With forward
                            footsteps turning not aside For fear some hidden evil might betide.<pb n="156" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/>
                            And there in the prepared appointed way, Listening to hear and ready to obey, A cross I
                            quickly found of plainest form, With only words of love inscribed thereon. With thankfulness
                            I raised it from the rest And joyfully acknowledged it the best, The only one of all the
                            many there That I could feel was good for me to bear. And while I thus my chosen one
                            confessed, I saw a heavenly brightness on it rest, And as I bent my burden to sustain, I
                            recognized my own old cross again. But Oh! how different did it seem to be Now I had learned
                            its preciousness to me; No longer could I unbelieving say, Perhaps another is a the better
                            way. Ah, no ! henceforth my own desire shall be, That He who knows me best shall choose for
                            me, And so whate'er his love sees good to send, I'll trust it best because he knows the
                            end.- -Anon. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Things worth considering" TEIform="index"/> THINGS WORTH CONSIDERING.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Thomas, Ida A." TEIform="persName"/>IDA A. THOMAS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> I would bring my soul nearer to God that I might be a partaker of His unbounded goodness,
                            knowing through Him and His ministering angels I have been gifted with faith which if obeyed
                            will support me through all trials. Many times when weighed down with trouble and grief and
                            looking about for that soul craving something I have found comfort in the faith given, that
                            omnipotent power surging within my soul which holds firmly within the bounds of love and
                            duty. Beautiful gospel I love thy principles, and all the true and noble souls who live and
                            carry them out; to such I would gather closely that I may gather new life and strength ;
                            with this support I can with many valiant soldiers in the battle more courageously meet the
                            foe. I love the hour of worship when in union with my Brethren and Sisters I can come forth
                            and worship God freely in spirit. Our body could not exist without its natural food and it
                            is just as essential that the soul be fed with spiritual food to keep it alive and quickened
                            and I want to be constantly kept awake knowing I am doing my duty; that I am pleasing and
                            not grieving the good spirits around me, and when I feel grieved or tried in spirit to bend
                            at the mercyseat in prayer that I may receive new strength to take up my cross anew. To all
                            honest souls I know a helping hand will be extended and the light of everlasting truth will
                            stand plainly revealed before them. For truth alone will stand forever. I will take new
                            courage and press on more bravely with my Brethren and Sisters, I know the way of the cross
                            is the way to salvation. Jesus says if you would be like me take up your daily cross and
                            follow me. I am willing to forsake all, to crucify a worldly nature that I may dwell in, and
                            know the everlasting joy and peace of the spirit. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian love" TEIform="index"/> CHRISTIAN LOVE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tatterton, M. J." TEIform="persName"/> M. J. TATTERTON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> By Christian love is meant the spirit Christ manifested towards mankind, a love not for his
                            followers alone, not merely for those who believed in him, but for all. The more degraded or
                            diseased in mind or body, those whom he met iu his path of life, so much more did his loving
                            compassion reach out toward them; and by the great gifts and power that were his, he healed
                            them of their infirmities; and by his words of love, and encouragement, he taught them of
                            the Higher Life, and filled their souls with that comfort and joy which always follows
                            obedience to<pb n="157" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> new light. Oh! the grandeur of the love of Christ as
                            portrayed by him when with lips white with the agonies of death, he prayed for his enemies,
                            "Father forgive them for they kuow not what they do. " Such an example of true charity and
                            Christian love, was never before witnessed. Knowledge and appreciation of the love of God is
                            the result of soul growth and development. When the Christian is in full possession of this
                            love he is then able to bear with patience all burdens, endure the buffetings of temptation
                            and suffer persecution for Christ's sake. Jesus said, "Greater love hath no man than this,
                            that a man lay down his life for his friends" and also declared the seal of discipleship to
                            be, " If ye have love one for another. " Well might the disciple whom Jesus loved, when
                            grown too feeble and aged to render service, physically, in the Master's cause, often
                            present to the church the words of him they professed to pattern. "Little children love one
                            another. " " Love one another, love, love, each other, By this Christ's followers are known.
                            " Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Persevere" TEIform="index"/>PERSEVERE
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Rugged toiler, son of labor, Stoutly battling every day, For
                                    existence, O my brother, Thou shalt triumph in the fray. On life's changeful scene
                                    of action, Though defeat may oft appear, Thou shalt win the victor's laurels, If
                                    thou wilt but persevere. Though thou art obscure and lowly, You may reach the
                                    wished-for goal, Grasp the prizes wealth and station, If thou hast a dauntless soul.
                                    If thou hast a resolution, Which misfortune cannot shake, One on which the angry
                                    surges, An impression fail to make. Art thou sneered at and derided By the
                                    self-styled lofty born, Heed ye not the fool's contumely, Nor the weak mind's
                                    harmless scorn. Art thou friendless, friends will gather As do courtiers king
                                    around, When thou hast achieved distinction When thou hast position found. Strong in
                                    faith let nought repel thee, Thou shalt in the end prevail, What if years of fierce
                                    endeavor, H^s been spent by thee in vain, What if thou hast met disaster, Up and
                                    take the field again. Wreck and ruin all about thee, Give not up but struggle still,
                                    Stubborn courage is resistless, Ye can conquer if ye will.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thou art the man" TEIform="index"/>THOU ART THE MAN
                        </head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by Clarissa Jacobs.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">There is room for all sorts of preaching; but the good preacher
                                    comes to the point which is, after all, personal. If the people are as good as they
                                    ought to be, let the preachers take a vacation until the people are not as good as
                                    they ought to be. If the people are not as good as they ought to be, let the
                                    preacher make them see it- -if in no other way by plainly saying "I mean you." This
                                    is the point. We are in great need of being thrust through and through with it until
                                    we are humbled into repentance. Dearly beloved pastors, please come to the point.
                                    The average church-goer has no idea that you mean him. You might preach to him for
                                    fifty years, pleasing him every Sunday, and yet never suggest to him that you are
                                    dealing with his sins and seeking the salvation of his soul. The kind of preaching
                                    wanted is that which will set men to asking "What shall we do to be saved?" "Who
                                    shall deliver me from the body of this death?" "What good thing can I do t 5 inherit
                                    eternal life?" Your sermons go over their hearts, up to their<pb n="158" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/>
                                    heads. They enjoy it. Try hitting them in the old fashion, when m.-n "were pricked
                                    in their hearts." We don't say it is easy to do it. We only say it is necessary to
                                    do it. It is the art- -it is fast becoming a lost art, which every preacher should
                                    learn. How to make men dissatisfied with themselves, ashamed of themselves, sick of
                                    their frivolous and worldly lives- -it is your business to lear-i that. The devil
                                    can give them lessons in self-complacency. They can instruct themselves in having a
                                    pleasant and enjoyable meeting. What they need of you is another sort of influence,
                                    an influence which shall reveal their sin and need. They need it now, at once. They
                                    are growing in sin. They are on the way to the judgment. Come to the point. Be quick
                                    about it. They will die on your hands, unrepentant and unsaved, if you do not
                                    convince them of sin. Pointed, awakening preaching is the want of the time. We have
                                    all other good sorts in superfluity. This we are short of. Somehow the sinners get
                                    harder, or the shots of the pulpit get weaker or more aimless. Surely it is possible
                                    to do better, to hit the personal conscience. Try it. Pick out your sinner, and let
                                    fly this shaft: "Thou art the man."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith" TEIform="index"/> FAITH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barrett, Andrew" TEIform="persName"/> ANDREW BARRETT.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The Scriptures declare in many places that by faith we can lay hold of Omnipotent power. By
                            faith all things are possible. Mark ix., 23. We claim to be the people of God, having
                            accepted into our souls the second advent of the Christ spirit we are made able to live
                            without sin unto full and perfect salvation. Yet for some cause not to the public explained
                            we are realizing a decay in bodily strength of numbers even to do physical duty, and a far
                            greater decay in the realization of that life-giving, spiritual and regenerating power that
                            the followers of Christ when they lived up to the true standard always had in possession.
                            ktAsk and it shall be given you, seek and ye shall find, knock and it shall be opened unto
                            you. " We claim these premises before God. But why is it when we ask we receive no answer,
                            we seek but nothing is found, we kuock but the door remains shut? What is the matter? The
                            promises of God are all true. Ah, faith, that eternal principle, the key that unlocks all
                            mysteries, is lacking. "Verily I say unto you he that believeth on me the works that I do
                            shall he do also, and greater works shall he do because I go to my Father. And whatsoever ye
                            shall ask in my name that will I do that the Father may be glorified in the son." In the
                            times of sternest trial the true followers of Christ look with faith to that Almighty Power
                            that can give aid and certain relief to their wants aud necessities, and should we not
                            Brethren aud Sisters, in this day of trial, have our faith anchored firmly in those eternal
                            principles, knowing in God's own time he giveth aid aud help to those who ask aright. Faith
                            has nothing to do with circumstances but rests solely on the Almighty power of God. Its
                            answer does not come by some successful combination of events or stroke of good luck. It
                            comes from God in his own way and through his own instrumentalities. The arm of flesh often
                            faileth its nearest and dearest friends in days of trial. Riches sometimes take wing and
                            leave the individual bankrupt and to the mercy of those who have stronger faith in more
                            substantial things. A genuine faith holds fast, undis-<pb n="159" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> turbed and
                            persistent. While desire and hope will fluctuate and change, faith knows the answer will
                            come. The child is ar example of faith in its simplicity, its rest is certainty. Give it the
                            mere rudiments of knowledge about God, his works, his promises and his love as has often
                            been manifested, and it will go to God with its small and large wants as readily as to its
                            parent. And should we Brethren and Sisters, be wanting in this faith. While looking
                            throughout our Zion and seeing the paucity of numbers that are willing or able to carry
                            forward these blessed principles, how can we but exclaim,- -What is the cause of this
                            falling away? Have we lost faith in that mighty Arm of strength that has held and sustt iued
                            us as shining lights of truth and goodness to earth's inhabitants thus far? Alas, has the
                            gold become dim and the most refined gold changed? As a vine in a fruitful field did our
                            heavenly Father plant hid church. With the tenderest of care has he cherished it that it
                            might bring forth fruits of righteousness. His language is, "What more could I do to my
                            church? But shall I say the vine is inclining to the earth aud entwining its tendrils around
                            human support? Harvard, Mass. </p></div2><div2 type="story" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beware of trifles" TEIform="index"/>BEWARE OF TRIFLES
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Beware of trifles, for you can never tell to what they may
                                    grow. Even a drop of honey has before brought about the death of many men, as may be
                                    seen from the following Arabian tale, which represents a common state of matters in
                                    the East. "Petty wars," says Mr. Lane, "occasioned by events as trifling as that
                                    here related, have been frequent among the Arabs to the present day. " There was a
                                    huntsman who hunted the wild beasts in the desert, and one day he entered a cave in
                                    a mountain, and found in it a hollow which was filled with honey. So he placed some
                                    of that honey in a water-skin which he had with him, then he carried it upon his
                                    shoulder and conveyed it to the city, having with him a hound that was dear to him.
                                    And the huntsman stopped at the shop of an oilman to whom he offered the honey for
                                    sale; and the oilman, agreeing to buy it opened the water-skin and emptied from it
                                    the honey, in order to see it. But there dropped from the skin a drop of honey, and
                                    a bird pounced down upon it, and the oilman had a cat, and it sprang upon the bird;
                                    and the huntsman's dog saw it, and sprang upon the cat and killed it; and the oilman
                                    sprang upon the dog and killed it; and the huntsman sprang upon the oilman and
                                    killed him; and the oilman was of one village and the huntsman of another, and the
                                    people of these villages heard of this event, so they took up their weapons and
                                    ro.-e against each other in anger: the two ranks met, and the swords ceased not to
                                    lie brandished about among them until there died a great multitude, the number of
                                    whom none knoweth but God, whose name be exalted.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our daily reckoning" TEIform="index"/>OUR DAILY RECKONING
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Ik you sit down at set of sun, And count the acts that you
                                    have done, And, counting find One self-denying deed, one word That eased the heart
                                    of him that heard, One glance most kind, That fell like sunshine where it went, Then
                                    you may count that day well spent. But if through all the live-long day, You've
                                    cheered no heart by yea or nay ; If through it all, You've nothing done that you can
                                    trace That brought the sunshine to one face, No act, most small, That helped some
                                    soul, and nothing cost, Then count that day as worse than lost! </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New England journal of education" TEIform="index"/>New England Journal of
                                Education.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="160" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/> NOTES.</head><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> THE MANIFESTO. JULY, 1887. Office of publication. The Manifesto is published at Shaker
                                Village, Mer. Co. N. H. All articles for publioation should be addressed to Henry C
                                Blinn, and all letters on financial business to A. Y. Cochran. TERMS. One copy per year,
                                postage paid, ' six months, " Send for specimen copy, free. .75 .40 </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="That ideal home" TEIform="index"/> THAT IDEAL HOME.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">It is one of the greatest of blessings to have a well ordered, comfortable home, while we
                                are privileged to dwell upon the earth. Our happiness in this life is largely influenced
                                by this treasure. To obtain this home may require much personal self-denial and rigid
                                economy, and when obtained, in order to secure the possession, a patient perseverance is
                                demanded from day to day and from year to year till time is no more. A great deal is
                                said and sung about the beauties and loveliness of this much to be desired inheritance
                                and, indeed, it becomes quite necessary in order to stimulate the mind to work
                                diligently while obtaining this desirable place of abode. An association of friends, in
                                whom we can confide, and with whom we can walk with assurance, helps to make the
                                pilgrimage of life one of satisfaction and peace. Our gospel home which is built on the
                                foundation of the new heavens and new earth wherein dwelleth righteousness should embody
                                all that has been stated, and from this so enlarge that its borders may touch the
                                heavens of heavens. Au hundred fold, said Jesus, will be the warranted increase that
                                shall be given into the possession of those who will accept my burden or wear my yoke,
                                and we are assured that the yoke was easy and the burden light. If au earthly home,
                                ruled by selfish love can have the primary lessons of government and order and neatness
                                and peace, then the gospel home upon which the spirit of Christ rests, must have all
                                these beautiful gifts much more abundantly. '- -k Thy will be done on earth as in
                                heaven. " And this can only mean for us to make our home upon earth, the same as we hold
                                iu anticipation concerning the City of God, "an abode not made with hands, eternal in
                                the heaveus." It would be folly to pray, Thy kingdom come, and then exercise no care
                                over our lives, and over the conditions that immediately surround us. The ideal home
                                must be brought so near that it may be distinctly seen, and that we may learn of the
                                very great care that has been given to it has proved so effectual that it is said to be
                                without even a spot or wrinkle. Thy kingdom come, is the fervent prayer of the faithful.
                                Whatever sacrifice it may demand, whatever discipline it may enforce, it will be
                                thankfully offered to secure the confidence that the spirit of God will dwell in our
                                home. In it must be found the pure in heart, the meek, the merciful, the peacemakers and
                                those who hunger and thirst after righteousness. The Kingdom of God ! It comes upon the
                                earth and in it there can be nothing that " defiles or makes a lie." It is an abode for
                                the angels, a home where<pb n="161" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> the fruits of the spirit shall most
                                freely abound; love, joy, peace, gentleness and temperance. In this home the apostle
                                informs us that man becomes the temple of the living God. If he defiles this temple, him
                                will God destroy. Christ can bring no less than this and the kingdom of God cannot
                                maintain a healthful existence in an atmosphere less pure. It is a redeeming feature
                                that this fact is being better and better understood. If the temple is defiled it will
                                be destroyed and earthly homes cannot be expected to dwell any more securely. A law of
                                retribution necessarily follows every deviation from right. Our gospel homes may be
                                destroyed if they become defiled by the elements of the world. Hatred, variance, strife
                                or sedition would soon accomplish the sad work, and that which God has planted a noble
                                vine would become the degenerate branch of a strange vine. Paul may plant, Apollos may
                                water, but God only can give the increase that will make a Christian home one of
                                holiness and through his divine care keep it unspotted from the world. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary. </head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rheumatism" TEIform="index"/>Rheumatism
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">At this season of the year rheumatism is usually prevalent. Some
                                        of our most distinguished men were included among the sufferers during the past
                                        month. It is one of the most democratic of diseases, for it spares neither rich
                                        nor poor. Exposure to cold is the only known exciting cause of acute rheumatism.
                                        Sleeping in damp sheets, and sitting in cold, damp rooms, after having been
                                        heated by physical exercise, are examples of the kind of exposure likely to be
                                        followed by this disease. Standing in the street to chat to friends after a
                                        vigorous walk, is equally dangerous. In fact, any condition which prevents the
                                        skin from throwing off exhausted matter by perspiration is liable to result in
                                        acute rheumatism. Prevention is far better than cure, especially in this
                                        disease, for the reason that those who have once been afflicted are almost
                                        certain to become victims again. Some doctors consider that it is hereditary.
                                        Injudiciously changing the weight of underclothing brings on the twinges. Not
                                        long ago there was reported to us the case of a man who had had a very severe
                                        attack caused by substituting wide woolen drawers for an old tight-fitting pair.
                                        The lesson taught by this is that the new ones should be washed a few times
                                        before it is safe to put them on. The pleasant drafts of air which render life
                                        more endurable during the hot summer nights too often pave the way for the
                                        rheumatic affections of the winter. Europeans in very hot climates, to secure
                                        sleep, make such free use of the punkah, or fan, that they acquire a form of
                                        rheumatism against which no remedy can be wholly successful. General Briere de
                                        PIsle, of France is one of the number. He was so exhausted from lack of sleep
                                        that he had to instruct his servants to work the punkah without ceasing.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/> Herald of Health.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tobacco-created" TEIform="index"/>TOBACC0-CREATED
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">I once knew a little boj' who was able to smoke, apparently
                                        without any disgust about as soon as he was able to hold a rattle! This case
                                        might be adduced by some in proof of the idea that all are not compelled to
                                        learn to use the " vile weed." This boy was really brought under the influence
                                        of this potent narcotic poison before he was born, the transforming influence
                                        was really in progress, the nicotine actually entering his vital organism. Both
                                        father and mother used it, adding the baneful tendencies, the corrupting and
                                        degrading influences of rum ! The house contained an atmosphere of tobacco and
                                        rum. while all of the surroundings were of a degrading character. While the
                                        mother's body was saturated with tobacco and rum, her whole mental and moral
                                        being permeated, it was not strange that her child was a tobacco-babe, with low
                                        and groveling<pb n="162" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/>tendencies, nor is it strange that he never
                                        ;irose to anything like manhood, never rose above the beasts of the field. When
                                        one can make a fine gold watch from iron, then, and then only, can we reasonably
                                        expect that children born under such circumstances, subjected to such
                                        de-humanizing influences, will be human beings in the highest sense of the term.
                                        I know an older lad us he passes in the streets at any and all times, who has
                                        the look and manners of one in a state of intoxication. His father used both
                                        tobacco and whiskey; was often drunk. \Vho can doubt that this lad may date his
                                        ex. istenceback to a fit of intoxication? Fathers and mothers cannot recklessly
                                        disregard all of the laws of their being at the most important period of their
                                        lives- -so far as the future generation is concerned- -and not curse society,
                                        entailing the natural and necessary penalties of violated laws on their progeny.
                                        If they choose to be carnal, to live a sensual life, or could do so, alone
                                        bearing the results, we might not think it advisable to blame them, but, when
                                        the innocent must suffer, when the results of their sins must follow along the
                                        line of succeeding generations, to "the third and fourth generations," they are
                                        heartless, unsympathizing, who are willing to create so much misery, just for
                                        the sake of a few moments gratification. I also knew an infamous boy, the most
                                        brutish, degraded and deformed of all ever met by me, the deformity, etc., being
                                        easily traced to the conduct of the so-called mother. As if the intention of an
                                        overruling Providence to so maim the creature that the least harm might be done
                                        in the world, three fingers were brought together under one nail, with other
                                        deformities too numerous to specify. Previous to his birth the mother had a
                                        perfect mania for killing snakes, contending with one monster for hours,
                                        conquering at last. He was below the average brute, snake-made! When will the
                                        mothers in an enlightened land rise to a point where they will be able to
                                        understand more of their influence in the generation of offspring, and see that
                                        the same generative laws control the human species as are wellknown to obtain in
                                        the animal world, being as careful of themselves in all respects as the fancy
                                        stock-raiser is of the prospective mother of a "high-bred" colt or calf?- -Dr.
                                        J. H. Hanaford, in </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Health monthly" TEIform="index"/> Health Monthly. </bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Respected friend: It is not from lack of appreciation..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Respected friend: It is not from lack of appreciation...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Shaker Village, April 1887" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Village, Mer. Co., N. H.
                            April 1887.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> E. V. HlGGINS, Respected Friend :- -It is not from lack of appreciation of your kind
                            interest, but from sickness in the family that 1 have so long delayed to reply to your
                            letter. Thank you for the papers, they were quite interesting. You ask if there are any
                            Seventh Day Adventists near me. I do not know of any within about forty miles, but am
                            somewhat acquainted with their faith, having read many of their publications. You say the
                            signs are fast fulfilling. As I understand the Scriptures as compared with history, the
                            prophetic times are all fulfilled, the last period of waiting having expired in seventeen
                            hundred ninety two. I believe that Christ is already manifested the second time, not the man
                            Jesus, but Christ, the Anointing spirit. Not in regal pomp or splendor does he come, for
                            this is not God's manner of dealing with man, as witness the parables, "a grain of mustard
                            seed," "alittle leaven," 'a hidden pearl,' all of which proves that the kingdom of God has
                            its origin out of sight of the haughty and worldly wise of earth. "The Lord whom ye seek
                            shall suddenly come to his temple." Mai. iii., 1. Where shall we find the temple of God?
                            Paul says, "What! know ye not that your body is the temple of the Holy Spirit." 1 Cor. vi.,
                            17, and again, "Know ye not that ye are the temple of God, and that the spirit of God
                            dwelleth in you." 1 Cor. iii. 10. Paul also says that '' woman is the glory of the man."<pb n="163" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> 1 Cor. ii., 7. We also read that Christ should come in his glory.
                            That he has so come, many witnesses can now testify, for they are saved from sin in the
                            present time. He was manifested in a chosen female, who with her Lord constitute the
                            parentage of the '' New Creation of Grod." As the old creation could not be complete without
                            both a father and mother, no more could the new, of which the old was a type. This testimony
                            is very humiliating and pridestaining to the carnal mind, but that alters not the purpose of
                            our God, who has promised to stain the pride and glory of the humau heart. I belong to the
                            Church of "Believers in Christ's second appearing," more commonly called "Shakers." This
                            church was established in seventeen hundred ninety two, at which time the prophetic dates
                            expired. Concerning our calculation of those numbers I will write if you desire to know. The
                            twelve Christian virtues are the foundation pillars of the church, namely, Faith, Hope,
                            Honesty, Continence, Innocence. Simplicity, Meekness, Humility, Prudence, Patience,
                            Thankfulness and Charity. These with the seven moral principles of Duty to God: Duty to man
                            ; Separation from the world ; Practical peace : Simplicity of language : Right use of
                            property and a Virgin life form the base of our institution. All of these we are striving by
                            the grace given us to manifest in our daily lives, else we do not experience a present
                            salvation, and one in the future we never realize. Hope I have answered your inquiry to your
                            understanding. If you should wish to inquire further, you are at liberty so to do. We have
                            some standard publications, as, " Testimony of Christ's Second Appearing," a volume of over
                            six hundred pages, also a "Summary view of the Millennial Church or United Society of
                            Believers," of three hundred pages, and others. Respectfully,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Danforth, Nancy G." TEIform="persName"/> Nancy G. Danforth, </byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved elder Henry: I enclose letters..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Beloved elder Henry: I enclose letters...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, June 29, 1887" TEIform="index"/> Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. June 29, 1887. </dateline><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Henry :- -I enclose letters received from Elder Frederick anil Brother James.
                            The Albany Journal as you will see has published James' letter, and has got it in very
                            correctly. Elder Frederick would like, if you would plea.se put it in the Manifesto, with
                            his postscript. Would write more but have not the time now. We received the letters on the
                            25th. inst. after waiting over three weeks. General time of health. Our Ministry will be
                            home this P. M. and we expect the Ohio Ministry to-morrow. Be so kind as to remember us in
                            your prayers, in the absence of our father. Accept our kindest gospel love and extend as far
                            as you feel. Daniel Offord. P. S. The music splendid in the June Manifesto ; and all is
                            good.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="O., D." TEIform="persName"/>D. O.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER MISSIONARIES.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Arrival of elder Evans and his companions..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Arrival of elder Evans and his companions...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Arrival of ELDER EVANS and His Companion in Glasgow on their Trip Abroad. We have
                                received the following: To the Albany Journal:- -We have received letters from Elder F.
                                W. Evans and brother James M. Peebles, giving an account of the voyage across the
                                Atlantic, and their reception in Glasgow. It is some seventeen 3'ears since the elder,
                                in company with J. M. Peebles, visited Great Britain. At that time they held a large
                                number of meetings and sowed a good deal of Sha :er seed, which they are now
                                cultivating, and we are in hopes of reaping a harvest in due time. Shakerism is not of
                                such a fascinating character as to easily draw natural people to it. A daily cross and a
                                life of virgin purity, with the crucifixion of the old man with all his affec-<pb n="164" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/>iions and lusts, is not very inviting, except to those whom the
                                spirit has touched. It is very rare for people to move out of their old tracks until
                                necessity drives them. Our ranks have been made up in some degree by those who felt the
                                need of something to eat and a place to live. However, it is a poor gospel indeed if the
                                soul and the future a' e all that are to be ministered to, leaving the bodily needs of
                                the present life to take care of themselves. One of the greatest inducements of
                                Shakerism is that the Shaker gospel gives all enough to eat and wear, and a place to
                                live. A good wholesome meal and a nice clean bed is a mighty testimony to reach the
                                hearts of some of the children of men; and sometimes through these means we enter the
                                wedge that separates them from the world and lets the light of Christ into their souls.
                                We expect that before long the mission of Shakerism to Great Britain will he consummated
                                by the establishment of Shaker societies in England and Scotland, and be a sort of
                                recruiting station for our societies in America. The English government has now
                                progressed so far that the Shaker order will be welcome there. Respectfully,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Offord.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Letters from the missionaries" TEIform="index"/> LETTERS FROM THE MISSIONARIES. </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, June 28" TEIform="index"/> Mount Lebanon, June 28.</dateline><p TEIform="p">The following are the. letters received from the missionaries: Drummond's Temperance
                                Hotel, 28 Glasgow Stbeet, Glasgow, June 14, Tuesday.- -Brother Daniel and JSldress Anna:
                                Dear Friends : Knowing the anxiety you must have to know of the welfare of the elder, I
                                write to you the first letter that I send backward over this three thousand miles waste
                                of waters. The voyage seemed to me unusually rough and rainy and foggy. I did not enjoy
                                it at all being deathly sea-sick two or three days; but the elder seemed to enjoy it,
                                standing and withstanding the storms like an old oak upon the hill top. The crew might
                                be called Babylon, made up of all professions nearly, including four or five preachers.
                                The elder lectured one evening upon the principles of Shakerism, and it was like
                                throwing a bombshell into a crowd; some were killed, some were wounded, some were
                                convicted, and all were made to think upon the most important subject or subjects that
                                can be brought before the minds of rational beings. Upon reaching Glasgow, there was a
                                party of Spiritualists watching and waiting for us. I had met and lectured to these
                                people seventeen years ago, and their faces looked familiar. We did not expect to meet
                                them; it was a perfect surprise. They would not hear a word of our going to our hotel to
                                even wash and look decent, and while we were pleading and parleying, Mr. Dugmid, a
                                Spiritualist medium, slipped away, got a carriage, we were hustled into it, and whirled
                                off to the residence of Mr. Robertson, where were awaiting us warm hearts, a fine large
                                room, a well spread table of wholesome food, including good Graham bread. The repast
                                over, people began to come in by ones and twos till the large room was well filled. "
                                Mine host " Mr. Robertson then arose and in a very neat and pleasant speech introduced
                                us. The elder replied in his happiest mood, and in his reply incidentally referred to
                                Robert Burns, which so echoed along the shores of the spirit world, that soon two or
                                three mediums were entranced, the spirits speaking finely of life immortal, as well as
                                recognizing the mission of Elder Frederick to this country. The spirits say that they
                                will help him in his mission- -a mission planned by heavenly intelligences. The
                                beginning is grand, it seemed like a baptism- -a day or an evening of Pentecost. The
                                elder seemed on fire- -the fire of enthusiasm and inspiration. To-morrow evening we
                                attend a seance, and Sunday we are to hold a meeting in the spiritualists' hall. The
                                elder cabled home last evening. You doubtless received it. His health is good- -as good
                                as his grit to brave difficulties and do his work as a missionary. He and self send love
                                to all. Most sincerely yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/> J. M. Peebles.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder Frederick writes..." TEIform="index"/>Elder Frederick writes...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="June 14" TEIform="index"/></dateline><p TEIform="p"> Elder Frederick writes: June, 14.- -James is unassuming, helpful and modest. But he is
                                highly appreciated in England and Scotland. If you could have heard the blessing and
                                thanks by some in the<pb n="165" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> meeting, of the good they had derived from
                                his "Round the World " and " Homes in the Spirit Land, " you would have realized what an
                                influence for good he has exercised over thousands of minds. And he has done much to
                                spread a correct knowledge of Believers. He will have his reward. It is in a practical,
                                unselfish spirit- -an interest in gospel truth- - that he is with me in Scotland. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="E., F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. E.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editor Manifesto: I have been repeatedly..." TEIform="index"/>Editor Manifesto: I have been repeatedly...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Sonyea, May 1887" TEIform="index"/> Sonyea, N. Y. May 1887.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Editor Manifesto :- -I have been repeatedly questioned by individuals, residents of your
                                village and elsewhere in regard to .the position that we take as a religious society in
                                reference to the temperance movement and what is our practice in regard to the use of
                                spirituous and malt liquors ? In answer to such inquiries I would say that we take the
                                ground of total abstinence in every case where it is possible. Liquor is used as a
                                medicine only in very limited quantities by a very few. One of the principles taught by
                                the founder of our Order was, "Temperance in all things,"both in eating and drinking.
                                Even the use of tobacco is discouraged, and very few use it. The writer was reared in
                                the society from a small child and has never used intoxicating drinks or tobacco in any
                                form whatever, and believes he has been benefited in both body and mind by such
                                abstinence. We extend our hearty sympathy and support to the noble band of workers who
                                are striving for the suppression of the evils of intemperance. And this brings another
                                question that is repeatedly asked by our friends. "Why do you not vote with us as well
                                as pray for the success of the Temperance cause?" In reply to this I would state that as
                                a religious body established on the principle of a community of interest in both
                                temporal and spiritual things, it would be a disintegrating force that would cause more
                                harm to us as a society than all the good we could possibly do by the use of the ballot.
                                I think our friends will understand our reasons and respect us for striving to maintain
                                our principles intact from forces that would teni to weaken and overthrow oue of the
                                fundamental principles of the society. Hoping this will place us right before the
                                public, I remain, Yours lvspectfully,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/> Hamilton DeGraw. </byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian communism no. 4" TEIform="index"/> CHRISTIAN COMMUNISM. NO. 4.</head><p TEIform="p"> [TAKEN FKOM THE CINCINNATI POST.] How They Live in a Shaker Village. What of the Future of
                            Shakerismt An Institution which does Divine Deeds can Never Die. Life with the Shakers is
                            very simple and uneventful. The "brothers" and "sisters" of each "family" live in the same
                            great four-story "family house." The brethren have their rooms on one side of the wide,
                            clean halls, and the sisters theirs on the other side. Two, three, four or five brethren
                            occupy one room with as many single beds. Two, three, four or five sisters also share their
                            room with one another and each has her single bed. The rising bell rings at 5 o'clock in
                            Summer and at 5-30 in Winter. Upon rising the brethren take off their bed clothes, fold them
                            neatly and lay them across the backs of two chairs. They then go out and do the morning
                            chores. The sisters likewise, after properly caring for their rooms, attend to their morning
                            chores. An hour after the rising bell, the breakfast bell rings, and all repair to the big
                            diningroom, which they enter in two files, one composed of the brethren, from the oldest in
                            regular graduation of age down to the youngest,<pb n="166" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> and led by the elders,
                            the other composed of the sisters from the oldest down to the youngest, and led by the
                            eldresses. In this order they enter the dining hall and march down the long, spotlessly
                            clean, but clothless table, the brethren on one side of the house and the sisters on the
                            other. Arrived at their places, they all kneel for a moment in silent thanksgiving and
                            prayer. Then all seat themselves and eat the meal with speechless assiduity. The table is
                            completely furnished with food at intervals of four plates, and waiting sisters who take
                            monthly turns at this work, replenish the food-plates as fast as emptied. At the end of the
                            meal all, at a signal from the elders and eldresses, kneel again, and thereafter pass
                            quietly out in two files, but in inverse order from that in which they entered. Breakfast
                            over, the work of the day follows. The brethren disperse over the farm and to the shops. The
                            sisters go to the laundry the ironing-room, the shops, or about the housework. Those sisters
                            detailed for that work make the beds and arrange the rooms of the brethren. Others sweep the
                            halls and polish them with their curiously hooded brooms. Others work in the kitchen. All
                            have work assigned for them to do. The endeavor is to give to each that which he or she can
                            do best and for the best good of all. It has been remarked of the Shakers that special
                            talent is speedily recognized and appropriately utilized. At 11-30 all are summoned from
                            work, and at just noon sit down to a silent but bountiful dinner. After dinner all work till
                            their assigned task is done or until summoned from work at 5 or 5-30. At 6 supper brings all
                            silently together again, and a couple hours quiet in their room for reading, writing, or
                            study prepares for bed at 9. Sunday is preceded by a special service of song and silent
                            prayer on Saturday evening. The great meeting of the day is in the afternoon, and consists
                            of singing, marching, silent prayer and exhortation. This meeting is held in the meeting
                            house, or in the meetingroom of the family house of the " center "or " church " family, and
                            all are expected to attend, if not ill. A song and prayer service in the evening closes the
                            quiet day. The industries of the Shakers are various. It is held among them as a settled
                            principle of their political economy that all such communistic enterprises as theirs must
                            have their industrial basis in agriculture. Hence, all the Shaker societies have large
                            tracts of land. The one at Union Village has about 4,500 acres, nearly a third of it in
                            woodland. When the society was strong in young men, it cultivated this land and made money;
                            but now that its numbers are few, and its members mostly along in years, it rents a good
                            part of its land, and on very easy terms. The Union Village Shakers also make brocms, raise
                            and dry sweet corn, make some simple herb medicines, and raise some cattle, sheep and hogs
                            for the market. In this way they a little more than make their income meet their
                            expenditures, besides living very comfortably indeed. A cyclone last May broke its way
                            through some of their best woodland, broke down a good many chimneys, unroofed some of their
                            buildings and made necessary about $3000 worth of repairs. The society had to borrow the
                            money, but has since repaid it. What of the future of the Shaker societies? My opinion is
                            that they have a great future before them, but that to attain to it they must abandon their
                            spiritualism and recover the intense, self-denying religiousness which characterized Ann Lee
                            and her converts. The Christian religion undoubtedly contemplates the existence of societies
                            of religious celibates, and as originally founded the Shaker societies more nearly realize
                            that New Testament institution than any other societies that I know anything about. " If the
                            Shaker institutions could be rehabilitated after the pattern Ann Lee set, and if the Shaker
                            theology could be replaced in the New Testament simplicity in which Ann Lee established it,
                            the Shaker societies would soon become a great power in the social, industrial, political
                            and religious world. The weakness of Shakerism lies, I think, in the fact that it has put
                            Ann Lee since her death up into its theology, where she herself would never have consented
                            to be put, and down out of its life and spirit in which she would have delighted to
                                remain.<pb n="167" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> 10' Ann Lee, as I read her wonderful and inspiring story,
                            was a true saint of God and a humble follower of Jesus Christ, her Savior. She had a
                            wonderful, self-denying, holy, consuming zeal for the conversion of the world. She saw that
                            her Lord countenanced and recommended celibacy, and she herself, upon that authority, taught
                            it. Her selfdenial, her patience, her wisdom, her love, her zeal, were admirable. The same
                            selfdenial, patience, wisdom, love and zeal in her followers would work wonders in this day,
                            when the thought and desire of all the world is turned toward Christian communism. Christian
                            communism, to succeed and to have any propagandist power, must be essentially, and entirely
                            and absorbingly Christian. Self-denial for its own sake is not only foolish, it is unworthy.
                            It is only self-denial in a holy cause that is inspiring, contagious and triumphant. It only
                            remains to say that the Shakers welcome all who come to them sincerely desirous of adopting
                            their mode of life and form of doctrine. Such applicants are received in what is called "
                            the gathering family," where they make a trial of Shakerism, meantime devoting the income
                            from their property- -which still remains under their own control- -and the labor of their
                            persons to the common good of the society. If satisfied with the life and doctrine, these
                            applicants are admitted into full fellowship by final consecration of all their property to
                            the society, and entering for life the Shaker family. If at any time previous to this final
                            act they wish to depart they can go and take all their property with them, but after their
                            final act of renunciation and consecration they cannot take their property with them if they
                            return to the world. Children have a very happy life among the Shakers. They go to the
                            district school, as good as any in the State, and are taught also many useful things in
                            relation to morals, politeness and cheerful industry. An institution that does such divine
                            things can never die. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kaiandri, Theodore" TEIform="persName"/>Theo. Kaiandri.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nothing can in beauty equal truth..." TEIform="index"/>Nothing can in beauty equal truth...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Nothing can in beauty equal truth, Truth alone is lovely.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Boileau" TEIform="persName"/>- -Boileau.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/> KIND WORDS.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manifestos were duly received..." TEIform="index"/>Manifestos were duly received...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Vermont, East Fletcher" TEIform="index"/> East Fletcher, Vermont.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> My Dear Friend, Hannah Wilson. The Manifestos were duly received. I was glad to see them
                                and have read them all. I enjoy the pure Christian teachings they contain. I cannot see
                                just as you do in some points yet I bid you God speed and truly feel that we are one in
                                Christ.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blaisdell, F. M." TEIform="persName"/> F. M. Blaisdell. </byline></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truly so" TEIform="index"/> THE TRULY SO.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, Amelia J." TEIform="persName"/> AMELIA J. CALVER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The truly patient suffer the inevitable trials of life without a murmur. The truly unselfish
                            relinquish their own pleasure for others, and serve themselves last. The truly philanthropic
                            will not '' let the right hand know what the left doeth," and the discriminating point is
                            the needy, not the lovely. The truly good never deviate from principle, for favor or gain.
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="From day to day" TEIform="index"/>FROM DAY TO DAY. 
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bird, Nelsia" TEIform="persName"/>BY NELSIA BIRD
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> The days go out and the days come in, A struggle
                                    for right, a battle with sin. A song half sung, and a prayer half said, A work
                                    unfinished and daylight dead. God knows the reasons- -I cannot know- - Taking His
                                    hand I will trustingly go-, It is better thus, and I only pray- - To be led by Him
                                    who knows the way, [complete, Till the fragments of work are each And the perfect
                                    song is sung at his feet, Till the broken prayer is a hymn of praise, And light and
                                    joy are not measured by days. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God-like soul is like our sun so bright...." TEIform="index"/>A God-like soul is like our sun so bright....
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> A god-like soul is like our sun so bright, At one with God the mind its lunar light; Their
                            rays are reason and deep reflections might, With wit as lightening practiced speech for
                            fight. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leopold" TEIform="persName"/>Leopold.</byline></div2><pb n="168" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers
                        </head><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Primary Fridays no. 3" TEIform="index"/>Primary Fridays No. 3</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Story without an end" TEIform="index"/>The Story without an end</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mayflower" TEIform="index"/>Mayflower</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="School songs" TEIform="index"/>School songs</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>Phrenological Journal and
                                Science of Health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> Fridays No. 3. Original and selected recitations for the little ones. The Interstate
                                Publishing Company, Chicago and Boston. Price 25 cents. The skill displayed in the
                                selection of these beautiful little poems is worthy of the highest commendation. There
                                is not a single worthless selection in the book. Mothers and primary teachers will find
                                them admirably suited for recitation by the little tots. They are all for the very
                                youngest children. The Story Without an End, by J. C. Pickard. The Interstate Publishing
                                Co., Chicago and Boston. Price 6 cents. School Songs.- -Primary Nos. 1, 2, 3 combined,
                                consisting of new and pretty melodies for primary schools. 96 pages. Price, 25 cents.
                                Chicago and Boston: The Interstate Publishing Company. This little book is filled with
                                the sweetest melodies adapted to the choicest words. Any primary teacher would be
                                delighted with it. Nothing seems so essential to a good primary school as sweet, pretty
                                songs, simple and easy for little children to sing. The songs in this book are all very
                                easy, and yet there is the greatest variety. Most of them have been written expressly
                                for this collection by wellknown teachers, such as Wm. W. Keays, George D. Herrick, Kate
                                L. Brown and II. W. Fairbank. Ellen M. Cyr contributes several pages of "blackboard
                                music," and Annie" Chase half a dozen or more excellent "Motion Songs." The book is
                                divided into three parts, any one of. which may be obtained in manila covers at half the
                                price of the three in one. THE 1HAYTLOWEB, 4QrThe Congregational Sunday School &amp;
                                Publishing Society began with this year the publication of a four-page weekly for
                                youngest readers in the primary department of our Sunday schools, the name of "The
                                Mayflower" being given it as appropriate to the "Pilgrim" Series of publications for
                                Sunday schools, of which it was to form a part. The Society has recently learned that a
                                newspaper bearing the same name had for some years been published at Yarmouthport,
                                Mass., by Mr; George Otis. This has led to a friendly correspondence, and Mr. Otis, with
                                evident sympathy in the work of the Society, cordially acquiesces in the use which is
                                made of the title, "The Mayflower," in connection with the juvenile publication above
                                referred to. Acknowledgments are due to Mr'. Otis for his great courtesy in this matter,
                                and it should be clearly understood that his right to the title* "The Mayflower," as
                                applied to a newspaper, is in no way affected by this use which is made of it, with Ms
                                knowledge and consent,, by the Congregational S. S. &amp; Pub. Society. Mr. Otis's
                                "Mayflower" is an attractive weekly paper (secular) of eight pages, and is intended for
                                the family. It has a large variety of reading matter adapted to old and young, is
                                carefully edited, and its price, $1 per year, places it within the reach of many readers
                                who cannot afford the higher-priced papers.- -[Congregationalist, May 26th, 1887. We
                                understand correspondence is being had with Oliver Optic, James Otis, Horatio Alger,
                                Jr., and other eminent writers for the young, in order to secure their interesting
                                contributions for the Mayflower. The Mayflower will be sent on trial for two months for
                                only ten cents. Try it. The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health. June, Contents:
                                Capt. Samuel Samuels; Familiar Talks with our Young Readers; The Christian Religion; J.
                                W. Lowber; Dormant Ability; Our Corner Man; Wonderful Triplets; Reciproca Influence of
                                Mind and Body; Mathematically One-Sided; Heredity; Leading Elements in Washington
                                S'iciet}'; Health Papers,- -No.4.; Emergencies; Inebriety and its Cure, etc., etc.
                                Fowler &amp; Wells Co., Publishers, 775 Broadway, New York</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oh fear not in a world like this..." TEIform="index"/>Oh fear not in a world like this...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Oh fear not in a world like this, And thou shalt know ere long- - Know how sublime a thing
                            it is To suffer and be strong. </p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A: 'I thought you were a vegetarian..." TEIform="index"/>A: 'I thought you were a vegetarian...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> A : "I thought you were a vegetarian, and now I see you eating mutton !" B : "Well, T am
                            only an indirect vegetarian,- -I eat the meat of such animals only as live on vegetable food
                            "</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Living with God" TEIform="index"/> LIVING WITH GOD.</head><p TEIform="p"> To live with God, is to live above the woild, and nothing moved by its wrongs or trials.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/> M. W. </byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.
                        </head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Salisbury, Lavinia" TEIform="index"/>Lavinia Salisbury</head><p TEIform="p"> Lavinia Salisbury, at Watervliet, N. Y. April 22, 1887. Age 88 yrs. and 6 mos. </p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute of love to Sister Lavinia" TEIform="index"/> A Tribute of Love to Sister Lavinia.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Aurelia" TEIform="persName"/> AURELIA WHITE.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Gone ! but not dead is the tremulous voice, As we bend o'er the cold silent form; So
                                grand in its loving, so noble and true, The spirit that this did adorn. [grasp Dear
                                Mother, be with us, hold our hand with that You often expressed while yet here, To lead
                                us along till we join you at last In heaven, with love and good cheer. From youth to old
                                age her whole life was given, A willing and full sacrifice, To follow the Savior, and
                                gain that bright haven, Prepared for the good and the wise : A Teacher and Leader, wise,
                                generous and true, Her counsels were loved and believed; And many will bless her, ever
                                will and now do For the guidance and strength they received. Watervliet, N. Y.
                            Primary</p></div3></div2><pb n="169" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><!--  
THE MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
This powder never  varies.     A   marvel  of!
purity, strength and   wliolesmnenoss.     More j
economical   than   tlie   ordinary   kind*,   and
cannot be sold in competition with the multitude (if low test, short weight, alum or phosphate powders.    Sold only in cans.      Royal
Bakinu Powder Co., 106 Wall-st., N. Y.
SIBLEY'S
S*TESTED*
EEDS
SEND - -SSr.Otalniid CATALOGUE
Vegetable, Flower, Field O CT SS* f% C
Plants, Bulbs Implem'ts. O EL E...U W
C D KT BT  by mall on application.
r f% E- - Ka  Don't neglect writing for it.
HIRAM SIBLEY & CO.
ROCHESTER, N. Y.
322-32S E. Haiti St.
 CHICAGO, ILL
 12-14 N. Clark St.
CHEAP Reading.
Sendi .10 cents
and    receive   6
back numbers qf THE, HOME . COMPANION, no two alike, filled with good
reading  for   all homes.            Address,
The Home Companion,
Troy, N. H.
 A MONTH   and BOARD Guaranteed
 3 'YoilB{j;Meu oriLadies in each  country,
and  highest co.jnmission paid (often $150
a mouth )    KKtr  BOOK alrei.dy on
tidal wave
of success
iii North and South America, at-the Ice-Bound
Poles, over the lands of the Midnight Sun, under the
Equator, through the Dark Continent, among the Old
Temples of India, in the Flowery Kingdoms of China
and Japan, amid the ruins of Incas. /ztecs and Zun;j within Canons, Cliff Bvilldivg*, and Gardens of
the G-ods, on the Isles of the Sea, and in all parts of
the globe. 300 engravings, L'/w Price- - .Quick Sale*.
Snid for Circular, p, W. Ziegler, & Co., 720 Chestnut St. Philadelphia) Pa.
AGENTS "WANTED to sell '  BE    INISCENCES"
of 60 YEA3S in the   NATIONAL METKOPOLIS,
BY BEN PERLEY POORE
Illustrating the Wit, Humor i- -ud Eccentricities of
noted wlelM'itiew. JL riclily illustratt'il treat of inner Society History, from " ye
, olden time" to the weddingof Clevciand. Wonflerfnlly Ponulai*. Agents report I'apit!
sal- - - -s. Address for circular and terms.
HIBBAHU UltOK.. Pub's, Boston, Mass.
-^   THD LIGHT-RUNNING
NEWHOMESEWING MACHINE aORANCE,MASS
CHICAGO -30 UNION SQUARE.N.Y-   DALLAS,
ATLANTA.GA.        - -       TEX.
ILL.
ST.LOUI!
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
[From The World's Advance-Thobght.}
WOELD'S SOUL COMMUNION.
A limited number of copies of The
World's Advvsce-Thoiight, the nivswagebearer of Spiritual Light and Love for all
the race, now reaching every quarter of the
globe- -its periodical visits extending to tlve
principal cities of the earth, and reaching
the song-hallowed Vale of Cashmere, in
Central Asia,
"Where the Magian his urn full of perfume is swinging"
it hereby gives world-wide notice that A
WORLD'S SOUL COMMUNION will be
held on Tuesday, the 30th of August, 1887,
at 12m. solar time at Salem, in the State of
Oregon. It will occupy thirty minutes' time,
and must be held at all points simultaneously. Time at different points will be calculated upon the basis of 12 m. Greenwich
time, which would correspond to 3-49 a. m.
at Salem, in Oregon, and 7-4 a. m. at New
York City.
The object of this World's Soul Communion will bo to DISSEMINATE SPIRITUAL
LIGHT AMONG THE INHABITANTS OF
THE EARTH.
Let peace and harmony prevail in the
minds and souls of a'l who unite in this,
THE FIRST WHOLE-WORLD SOUL
COMMUNION. Through all diversities of
faith, and among all nationalities, let the one
prayer be, "ON EARTH PEACE AND
GOOD WILL TO MEN."
The foregoing are intended to be the initial
ones of "a series of National and WholeWorld Soul Communions, for the evolution
and direction of soul-forces that will lift humanity into higher and happier conditions,
and for the interchange of inspiring thoughts
between mind and mind. All are invited to
participate who will unite in the right spirit.
The Watsaka Wonder is a narrative of
startling phenomena occurring in the case of
Mary Lurancy Vennum. Written by Dr
E. W. Stevens. Published in Chicago, 111.,
by the E- -Iigio-Philosophical Publishing
House.    Price 15 cts.
While dreams and visions and trances
have been, no doubt, familiar to man since
the day he came from God, and an almost
endless variety of phases have been illustrated and placed before the public, still a fresh
demand is manifested even at this date, to
know more of this wonderful condition into
which people pass, and at once become so
strange and the objects of such intense interest.
INTERESTING TO LADIES.
Our lady readers can hardly fail to have
their attention called this week to the latest
combination of improvements in that most
useful of all domestic implements, the "sewing machine."
As we understand it, a machine for family
use should meet first of all these requirements : It should be simple in its mechanism;
it should run easily: it should do a wide
range of work; it should be as nearly noiseless as possible; it should be light, handsome, durable, and as cheap as is consistent
with excellence throughout.
These conditions the "Light-Running NewHome" certainly meets. It has also several
very important and useful attachments and
"notions" of its own, which go far to make
good its claims to popular favor.
The "New Home" specially recommends
itself to purchasers on account of its superior mechanical construction, ease of management and reasonable price. Over half a
million have been sold in the last three years,
all of which are giving universal satisfaction.
This unrivalled machine is manufactured by
the NEW HOME SEWING MACHINE
CO., Orange, Mass., and 30 Union Square,
New York.
MAYNARD &NOYES,
MANUFACTURERS  OF
SUCK WRITING INK.
COPYIKG and MARKIKG IIT
CABMIFE, BED and BLUE UK,
WEITDTG FLUID, mPOWPER - - - -.
- - - -SVttlT, KAMI
<pb n="" id="p"/>
 --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>