<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0507" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><date value="18750701" TEIform="date">July 1875</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">49-56</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="49" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">Vol. V. No. 7. F. W. EVANS, Editor. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. Mt. Lebanon Col. Co. N. Y.
                        July 1875. Sixty Cents per annum.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tools—temporal and spiritual" TEIform="index"/>TOOLS-TEMPORAL AND SPIRITUAL</head><p TEIform="p">Man has been denned as a tool-making animal. Certain it is, that no other animal fabricates
                            so great a variety of tools, as does the head of the animal creation — Man. If this be
                            granted, may it not be that the, progress of our race, from the Nomad, or Savage state,
                            toward the highest form of civilization, is indicated by the tools, including machinery, and
                            by the inventive ingenuity displayed in their construction ? The degree of progress, as thus
                            indicated, made by an individual, will be nowhere more clearly expressed — better, or more
                            sharply defined — than in a Shaker Family. The Brother, who comprehends and appreciates the
                            full value of a tool, will prove his comprehension and appreciation by the care exhibited in
                            the use of it, and by the disposal made of it when not in use. Property is largely the
                            result of the invention, construction and care of tools. Rich and poor are terms that simply
                            express the acquired, or improved natural capacity for making and employing tools, in
                            accomplishing the purposes of life. Individuals, coming from the outside world, into a
                            Shaker organization, soon manifest their status, as regards being self supporting, or
                            dependent upon the labor and care of others, by their relation to tools. The selection of a
                            light tool for heavy work, by which it is soon broken, or spoiled; or of a heavy tool for a
                            light job, in which the strength is exhausted before the work is accomplished, determines
                            their inefficiency. Again, is the tool set in a proper place and position, when not in hand
                            ? When done with, is it cleaned and cared for according to its value and importance ? These
                            are vital considerations, affecting the character of the brother who has the tool in
                            possession, — temporary, or permanent. Often, light implements, when out of hand, are thrown
                            down to be lost, or broken by being driven over. Sometimes, tools are wrongfully employedto
                            strike dumb animals, to the injury of the man, the tool and the animal. Such things ought
                            not so to be. A careful enumeration of each tool used in a given job, so that all may be
                            replaced, in good order, when the work is done, is profitable in a property point of view,
                            and commendable as a Christian practice. Of Father Joseph, it is recorded, that he joined to
                            each act and step, a thought of its use. If, in the day of judgment, an account be rendered
                            of every idle word, will not preceding thought avert the idle words ? To us, now is the day
                            of judgment. Let us not despise it, by inattention to small things. What is Spiritualism but
                            a science, instrument, or tool to be used in the great work of human redemption ? It
                            originated among Believers, did its work for seven years, went into the world, with a
                            promise of its return to Zion — was operative, both here and there, through earthly mediums
                            — natural seers and seeresses. Is not the return, thus prophesied of, at hand ? And will not
                            the next step, of demonstration, be in the form of 'materialization? These are the questions
                            to be answered — the problems to be solved. Man comes into being, like the beasts that
                            perish — helpless, dependent and ignorant. The Spiritual faculty exists in him, as a germ,
                            to be unfolded in the future. In Catholicism, was the perversion of the Spiritualism of the
                            Primitive Church. Protestantism was a protest against Spiritualism, per se, because of such
                            perversion. It compounded, into one system, the incongruous elements of great faith in past
                            revelations of God, with infidel denial of all present revelation — of the existence of a
                            living, pulsating Spirit World, with whose inhabitants the good and the bad could hold
                            intelligent intercourse. Protestantism is abnormally materialistic — earthy — was and is
                            "the second beast that came up out of the earth with power like a Lamb, and like a Lion — of
                            opposite characteristics — believes in no Prophet, until it has killed him. Then it worships
                            him — even as it incorporates animals into its own body, after it has taken their lives. It
                            will give Christian burial to those whom it has slain in heathen warfare — will deal kindly
                            — tenderly— with the men it has wounded and maimed, with infernal instruments — tools — in
                            unchristian battles. In this Babylon, one of the two sexes esteems the other as created for
                            their own use, as part of the animal creation. Yet, that sex brings the other into being and
                            nurses them into masters, who make the Laws and execute them. Protestantism apportions the
                            earth to the few, and feeds the non-producers — aristocrats, soldiers, criminals and paupers
                            — out of the charity that should have equally divided the land, the product whereof it now
                            unequally divides. Is there not incongruity in this system, that materialization will remedy
                            1</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thou shalt not kill" TEIform="index"/>"THOU SHALT NOT KILL."</head><p TEIform="p">Our Gospel Messenger—The Shaker and Shakeress — like the tree of life, yielding its twelve
                            manners of fruits — Christian Virtues, — twelve times each year, is before me. And what a
                            feast it affords!—experiences, declarations of living faith, and progressive ideas, drawn
                            from Christ, the living fountain, in whom are hid all the treasures of wisdom and knowledge.
                            The two-edged sword of the Spirit, severing, from the soul, the sins and elements of the
                            world, with the habits incorporated into our life system, by long usages, is ably wielded.
                            And as its keen edge is felt, separating us from our self-loves, who wonders we cringe, feel
                            pain and cry out to the Prophets, " Speak unto \is smooth things "— when likely to lose a
                            darling idol, whether of food, or some long cherished theologic idea ? I well remember that
                            Elder Frederick once told a Boston audience —'' We Shakers are learning to become good and
                            true Christians." This is true. Were the revelations of God, through Mother Ann, a finality,
                            any more than the mission of Jesus was God's Last Will and Testament ? There can never be a
                            departure, with impunity, from the foundational principles of the Church established by
                            Mother Ann and those who helped to plant the Gospel in this land — Virgin life, community of
                            interest and separation from the world. To prepare our bodies, as fit tabernacles for the
                            temple of the Holy Spirit, in which God may be worshiped in the beauty of holiness, there is
                            yet much to learn. Many evils, already abandoned, show the progress made. Prominent among
                            them, are Cider and Pork — Tobacco, almost obsolete — Use of drugs greatly diminished — many
                            believing they can die happier without doctors, if not quite as quick. Lingering are many
                            habits, yet to be abandoned. Slaughtering animals for food! — Is it not a barbarism,
                            unbecoming our profession, which Believers will abandon ? Did not the Prophet allude to the
                            Church of Christ in the second Manifestation — the " New Heavens "— when he said, " They
                            shall not hurt nor destroy in all my holy mountain " — " He that killeth an Ox is as he that
                            slayeth a man"—" Violence shall no more be heard in thy land — wasting and destruction
                            within thy borders"—" Thy walls shall be salvation and thy gates praise ?" Some, from
                            inherited disease, may not be prepared to abstain, wholly, from animal food. As many as are
                            able to abstain — Let them. Has not the time arrived when the Virgin Sons of Zion should
                            keep their hands from pollution of blood guiltiness ? Are we, in building New Heavens, to
                            retain slaughterhouses and executioners ? Every Society and Family employing hirelings, more
                            or less, — until we are sufficiently progressed to leave the use of animal food entirely —
                            Let the slaughtering be done entirely by the hirelings, who still live in the <pb n="50" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 5O SHAKER A.ND generative order. And let the Sons of Zion, who have confessed
                            their sins and are living the pure Angelic life, be exempt from imbuing their hands in blood
                            — violently taking the life of any animal. Are they not called to become a holy Prophetic
                            Priesthood — to be daily rising in the resurrection — keeping themselves unspotted from
                            every pollution of the world, its habits and fashions — keeping their hands clean and their
                            hearts pure — progressing on from perfection to perfection — possessing their souls in
                            innocence — becoming deeply spiritual and so filled with the Holy Ghost that their very
                            countenances shall be radiant with the Glory of God, realizing the call of God, to plant
                            vineyards and eat the fruit thereof ? Then shall Peace be as a river, and Righteousness as a
                            flowing stream — and nations will come up to Zion, to behold her Glory, and the Lord will
                            rejoice in the increasing purity of his People.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sawyer, Otis" TEIform="persName"/>Otis Sawyer, West Gloucester, Maine</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Man who never tasted meat" TEIform="index"/>A MAN WHO NEYER TASTED MEAT</head><p TEIform="p">One half-mile south of Holmesdorf, Pa., lives an old fanner by the name of Abraham Blatt, who
                            is about sixty years of age, is healthy, robust and as strong as a horse, who has never in
                            his lifetime tasted the least bit of meat of any kind. He says he never tasted beef, pork,
                            mutton, or veal, no kind of poultry, no kind of fish, no kind of game, in fact nothing
                            pertaining to meat. He has such an abhorrence of meat that when they kill a cow or hog on
                            his premises, he generally leaves home and goes about other business. He is the father of a
                            large family, all healthy children. Among the lot is also one boy, who, like his father,
                            eats no meat of any kind. In reply to the questions put to the father how he could work so
                            hard without eating any meat, he says he believes he is much healthier than if he ate meat.
                            He uses very little butter. The popular error that flesh meat creates more muscular strength
                            than do grains, fruit, or vegetables, was equaled by the once popular belief, that to the
                            farmers and hard working laborers, Alcoholic drink was a positive necessity. We are apt to
                            forget to reflect. The Horse after his kind. The Ox and'Buffalo; the Camel and Dromedary;
                            the Elephant and Mastodon, were and are Graminivorous. Do they lack muscle, as compared with
                            the Carnivora ? Is the fact, that no animal living habitually upon other animals, will ever
                            work, presumptive evidence that Man, who performs so much physical labor, does not belong to
                            the Carnivora, and that he will progress beyond it?</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ascot, Victoria, Australia, February 1875" TEIform="index"/>State School, Ascott, Victoria,
                            Australia, February, 1875</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Friend and Brother, Along with this I send you a few papers as a second article on Diet.
                            Deal with it as you are directed by Spirit Monition. I have done as you desired, viz., I
                            have written, and as you have predicted, the writing has done me good. It is away from me,
                            and there my responsibility ceases, while yours begins. Understand me clearly, I have no
                            desire to be seen in print, before I can better bear inspection by the spirit-eyes that are
                            constantly upon me. I have much, oh how much! to regret having ever given occasion to
                            spirit-eyes to witness in me. But I sincerely thank God that I have entered the valley of
                            humiliation, and find something sweet even in the very bitterness of confession and
                            repentance. My intercourse with the Spirit Sphere increases in power, in quantity and
                            delight. The power and influence that draws me thither grows visibly stronger every day, and
                            the river grows wider that bears me on its bosom to the Ocean of Being. Last evening, in our
                            family circle of three, viz., myself, wife and little daughter — among other friendly
                            messages from on high, we had one from Ann Lee, inquiring after my health, as she had not
                            time that night to visit me in person. I need scarce tell you how delighted I was, and still
                            am. I have suffered pretty much through ill-health this' season; but it seems as if any
                            amount of ill-health almost would be welcome to me, that brought with it the expressed
                            sympathy of Ann Lee. I am following instructions sent by Ann Lee in regard to medicine and
                            diet, and find benefit therefrom; but my chief joy is, that it will not be very long now
                            before I go to live beside my spirit guides and instructors ; this is a joy so great to me
                            as to leave little room for any other joy to possess me at the same time. Except it be that
                            I too may become a blessed instrument for Good, in the service of my Father and Mother God.
                            I send you regularly the Harbinger of Light. I trust that it reaches you safely — but there
                            again I am wrong. When it leaves me, it is in the keeping of Him who keeps all things, and
                            will therefore, of necessity, go on its proper mission. When last in Melbourne, I found one
                            with whom I previously had corresponded, till he allowed the correspondence to drop. He was
                            actively engaged in the promotion of a co-operative, or communistic, scheme, called
                            "Aurelia." My remarks and replies to his and other correspondence were not in harmony as
                            they then thought with a more rational mode of procedure recommended. But here again
                            disappointment has brought reconsideration, and this person, a widower, seeks for a higher
                            basis on which to build. While pointing out to him the foundation-stone — Christ, I referred
                            him also to you, as both able and willing to assist by counsel and advice. His name is
                            William Yates, and from all I can learn, if he does not succeed in obtaining a communistic
                            home in this colony soon, he is likely to visit you. He promised to follow my advice in
                            writing to you. So you see, dear Brother, I have no thought of sparing you. We, that is,
                            Catherine and myself, read with great satisfaction your messenger of love, the Shaker and
                            Shakeress. Will you, dear Brother, remember Catherine and myself, in love to all the
                            fraternity of Brothers and Sisters at Mount Lebanon ? We shall meet you, by-and-by, at the
                            holy Mount Zion above. As it is, we are often with you now, dark and dimly, it is true.
                            Still we can make you out, and through the gloom of this night-side of Nature hear your
                            friendly hail, " All's well" — " All's well." And so it is, dear friends all, it is really,
                            truly, and everlastingly— "All's well." For a brief time again, we bid you all Farewell.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Finlay, John (and Catherine)" TEIform="persName"/>John (and Catherine) Finlay</byline></div2><div2 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Few thoughts on diet" TEIform="index"/>A FEW THOUGHTS ON DIET</head><p TEIform="p">In my last, I spoke of food being decomposed before it left the system. To this some may
                            offer the objection that the decomposition effected by digestion differs widely from that
                            effected by putrescence. While admitting this difference in its widest extent, it still
                            remains a fact, that the law runs parallel in both cases, i. e., the decomposition effected
                            by either process is most hateful to all our senses of observation in animal substance, next
                            so in animalized substances ; then in roots, vegetables, etc. The whole may be summed up
                            thus: The lowest condition of human existence will be exhibited in ATMOSPHERE. In small,
                            badly ventilated bed-rooms, especially over-crowded ones. Air, over-charged in drinking
                            rooms, with fetid breath of gin, rum and beer drinkers; tobacco smokers and chewers,
                            products of combustion, defective drainage, etc. DRINKS. Ardent spirits, alcoholic drinks,
                            fermented liquors, stagnant water, and water defiled by contact with decayed or decaying
                            matter, through bad drainage, etc. FOOD. Blood, livers, hearts, flesh of swine, especially
                            those fed on garbage, half putrescent and badly cooked animal food and roots. UNNATURAL AND
                            ACQUIRED HABITS. Smoking or chewing tobacco, taking snuff, opium, narcotics, bitters, etc.
                            The highest possible condition on earth, AN EXCLUSIVELY FRUIT DIET. The rationale of this
                            however, is: Do not attempt to stride over the Andes at one step. The path upward and onward
                            is not only progressive, but constant and eternal. There is a " Hill of Difficulty" for
                            every pilgrim to climb, and perhaps an equally good name for this " Hill" would be the hill
                            of Self-Denial. He or she, that would live to God, must take up the cross daily. Never look
                            back like Lot's wife, or the foolish Israelites, to the flesh-pots, the leeks and garlic of
                            Egypt. Press onward, ever upward and forward. " Nearer my God to Thee," be all thy song, be
                            all thy life's effort. And when at any time the weakness of the flesh may cause thee to
                            stumble — though you should even get drunk and debauch your stomach — rise and shake the
                            dirt from you, do not elect to roll down the hill again into the filth at the bottom from
                            which you have, in part ascended with so much effort. Fools and sinners will laugh and
                            scoff, they will invite you to descend lower again into their own depths ; heed them not.
                            Sing with the Apostle, "Rejoice not against me, O mine enemy, when I fall I shall arise
                            again." Speed onward again and again. If you fall a thousand times, make one thousand and
                            one efforts to go forward, and sure as fate you will succeed. Remember, your better life
                            must be a daily progress, not a single act; and it is only by degrees that you can overcome
                            self. Again, remember that all natures are not alike. In some persons the process of
                            assimilation with new kinds of food, goes on more slowly than with others, and a mixture of
                            that very kind of food you mean to abandon, may for a time be necessary for you. The mixture
                            may of course be purified gradually, till in course of years, the old element be completely
                            eliminated. You must be g aided by conscience and due regard to possibilities combined. In
                            all reform however, observe the golden rule of charity to your neighbor; never rejoice at,
                            nor magnify his fall. Judge yourself with the utmost severity, but let oharity be ever with
                            you in judging your neighbor. Lastly, whatever indulgences in old habits you may
                            conscientiously require, not as a deliberate sacrifice to devils, but as a real mile stone
                            of progress, to give you fresh strength as it were in all. good faith and conscience to go
                            forward — never on any single occasion let the eyes of young persons ever find you so
                            engaged. With the young, example is allpowerful. Let them as much as possible be surrounded
                            with an atmosphere of purity and kept free from all that is even suggestive of evil. P. S.
                            It may be well to remark, that it is quite possible the utmost power in humanity for reform
                            and being manifestation, might require three generations in the effort to produce a true
                            frugivorous race of beings.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Finlay, John (probable author)" TEIform="persName"/>Australia</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, New Hampshire, February 15, 1875" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, Mer. Co.,
                            N. H., I February 15,1875</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Frederick : I have written a few thoughts upon Ventilation, which I forward to
                            you for perusal, and hope that as you read you will be kind enough to criticise, erase, add
                            or diminish, as the case may require — or consign them to the waste-basket. I shall not feel
                            slighted at any measures you may take to make all right. I have tried to handle the subject
                            as candidly as I could, and leave out the sweeping remarks that would very naturally glide
                            from my pen, when it ia moved on by thoughts that burn with indignation,- as they sometimes
                            do when obliged to sing in a close atmosphere. <pb n="51" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> 8HAKEEB88. 51 I have
                            envied the Chameleon in the fable, where the writer states that " He saw him eat the air for
                            food"—provided it was pure air —many times when thus engaged. If there could be some simple
                            means devised for ventilating our large assembly rooms, especially, I would sing praise to
                            God for the means. These long, inclement winters in Northern New England create such a
                            scarcity in fuel, that it is considered wasteful, by the majority, to open windows and doors
                            for the admission of air, and doing thus, expose some, in a crowded room, to much
                            inconvenience from drafts, which induce colds, etc. Our Meeting Room, as yet, has no means
                            for ventilation, except by raising and lowering the window sashes, and, it being low posted,
                            it is rarely that it is, or can be, well aired, while the audience is assembled, without
                            great inconvenience to some one, or ones- Our Brethren, though in favor of good air (or the
                            theory), are not yet able to decide on any particular method for ventilation, which will
                            supersede lowering or raising the sash. We sisters have pleaded for our rights to breathe,
                            more than any other rights, save the rights vouchsafed to the virgin life. And since having
                            made the art of breathing a study in the " Vocal Drill," as taught by Dr. Guilmette, we are
                            more keenly alive to the benefits arising from pure air. Could this theory be accepted
                            throughout Believers, I believe there would be a greater revolution in the physical habits
                            of many, than that which herbs, drugs, or quack medicines can induce, Asking pardon for my
                            long talk, I beg you to accept herewith a renewal of love from our beloved Elders, Brethren
                            and Sisters. Your Shaker Sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stickney, Aseneth C." TEIform="persName"/>Aseneth C. Stickney</byline></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What better evidence than is contained..." TEIform="index"/>What better evidence than is contained...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">What better evidence than is contained in this private note, that ours is the Everlasting
                            Gospel ? It was not until Woman became converted to the high and holy vocation of Christian
                            Celibacy, that the Eesurrection of mankind became an assured fact — a fulfilled prophecy.
                            Man may appoint, but Woman can disappoint. Man may beget — Woman alone can bring forth. The
                            stars of heaven fell continually to the earth, throughout the long night of Anti-Christ.
                            They ceased in Israel until I arose, until that I, Deborah arose, a Mother in Israel. Now
                            that the Sisterhood begin to add to their Spiritual faith the virtues of physiological
                            truths, we look, without a doubt, for the Gospel to increase. To cleanliness in the house,
                            not easily exceeded, will now be added a purity of atmosphere in those houses, like the
                            purity of life in the Sisterhood, which is Angelic.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Editor</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dr. Miller's conversion" TEIform="index"/>DR. MILLER'S CONVERSION</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Father Evans : For several years I have been an opponent of Spiritualism. I believed it
                            was all the work of deceivers and frauds. I had seen so much deception amongst those who
                            called themselves mediums, and so many who had been made converts by these frauds, that I
                            had come to the conclusion that all so-called mediums were deceivers. I had, on several
                            occasions, been selected by public audiences to act on committees to test the manifestations
                            of mediums, and had, on almost every occasion, found in these mediums such evidences of
                            fraud, that I had lost faith in the whole of them. I had examined several mediums in
                            private, and among them the Hough boy at Apollo Hall before 2,000 people, and at Tammany
                            Hall I was chosen to test Warren. All the parties mentioned positively refused to submit to
                            the tests I thought necessary to convince me that their manifestations were not tricks. I
                            still think the mediums referred to, many times, practiced deceptions on their audiences. In
                            December last I went to Chittenden, Vermont, to see the Eddy brothers, and I expected to
                            find the biggest kind of a fraud there. When I left home I expected to be gone three or four
                            days, and to be able to come back and show just how they managed to deceive those who go to
                            see them; but, to my surprise, when I had been there that time, I found I did not know any
                            thing about how it was done. The result of my visit was, I staid fifteen days and came away
                            thoroughly convinced that however much deception and trickery there might be amongst other
                            mediums, there was something genuine at the Eddys. I staid there long enough to examine
                            every thing about the seance room, as well as every part of the premises, and I am now fully
                            satisfied that spirits do materialize, and large numbers of them too, and they appear in
                            substantial form, can be seen and felt, and heard to speak, and they are recognized by their
                            friends, and often take them by the hands and kiss them and give the most positive
                            assurances of their identity. During the fifteen days I was there, I saw as many as twelve
                            different spirits a night come out and show themselves. There were representatives of
                            several different nations, amongst them were Egyptians, Italians, Hungarians, Indians,
                            Americans, Europeans and Asiatics. Some of those who were present saw and recognized their
                            own friends, and conversed with them about matters with which none but they and their
                            friends were familiar. Mrs. Eddy, the mother of the Eddy brothers, came out several times,
                            and one night she spoke for half an hour nearly, and some of the time she spoke so loud she
                            could be heard more than twenty yards distant. Honto, an Indian girl, came out several
                            times, and on different occasions she danced, played on musical instruments, materialized
                            shawls and other articles, smoked a pipe, shook hands with different persons, kissed them,
                            sat in their laps, and did many other things. No one could have made me believe that what I
                            saw there was the work of spirits materialized, if I had not seen them with my own eyes, and
                            felt them with my own hands, for I was a regular doubting Thomas. I could not believe except
                            I could test them with all my own senses. This I had a chance to do at Chittenden, Vt. What,
                            then, are the proofs of spirit manifestations that I saw there ? Let me sum them up in a few
                            words. The medium goes into a closet twenty-seven inches wide and seven feet long, that is
                            lathed and plastered on the sides and on the ceiling, with only one small window, and that
                            is covered with a piece of netting, so sealed, that no one could disturb it without its
                            being known, and a door for the medium to enter. The floor and every part is examined and is
                            found in such a condition that no one could get into it except through the door. The closet
                            is examined before the medium goes into it, the medium is examined before he goes in, and we
                            know he has nothing about him but his ordinary clothes on. The seance room is made about as
                            dark as it would be with an ordinary fire in a grate. Within a few minutes after the medium
                            goes in, out comes form after form till as many as thirty-five have come out in one evening.
                            They laugh, dance, sing, jump about, play on musical instruments, materialize shawls and
                            various articles, recognize their friends, talk with them, give them advice, etc., etc.
                            These spirit forms appear and disappear while you are looking at them, as Jesus is said to
                            disappear after the resurrection while talking with the disciples. Hands, arms and faces
                            appear and vanish instantly ; the names of your own friends are written on cards by these
                            hands, amongst those to whom you have never mentioned the name of one of your friends,
                            either living or dead; musical instruments are moved about the room, passing over your head,
                            all the time discoursing sweet music; tables, chairs and other articles are moved about the
                            room by invisible hands; iron rings are put on the arm of the medium and on that of other
                            persons in the room; scores of voices are heard at one time ; six or eight musical
                            instruments are played in concert. All of these things are taking place while the mediums
                            are tied securely, and where there is no chance for confederates to assist in the
                            performance. People tell me I am deceived by these mediums, and that all these things are
                            done by trickery. I used to think so once, but when I had a chance to investigate for myself
                            I was obliged to admit that deception was impossible under the circumstances. I, however, do
                            not expect others to believe what I say about it, any more than I believed what others said
                            when I was told about it. All I can say is, others must go and see for themselves as I did.
                            The bible is full of instances where spirits appeared and talked to those with whom they had
                            missions to perform. I am disposed to think that the spirits that appeared in bible times
                            were of a higher grade than those that appear to modern mediums. I judge the spirits, that
                            are materializing now, are of the lower class; and after a time a higher type will appear,
                            and then we shall get communications that will be of more importance to the human family
                            than any we have up to this time. When we get the highest type of spirit communications we
                            shall develop the highest condition of society, and then Shakerism will be much better known
                            and appreciated than it is at the present time. If there are great truths in Christianity,
                            then there are great truths in Shakerism. I believe the Shakers are putting in practice many
                            of the truths that were taught by the early Christians. The community of property, as
                            inculcated by the disciples of Christ, is certainly carried out in practice by the Shakers.
                            The subjugation of the animal, or of the body, to the spirit or mind, was a doctrine of
                            Christians, and I believe it is also of the Shakers. In my view of things, full
                            three-quarters of the human family ought to be compelled to live celibate lives ; for they
                            are not fit to beget children, and ought to be prohibited from doing so. The race should be
                            perpetuated by the other quarter. Is it not about time to stop entailing disease, deformity,
                            vice and crime in this world ? Let Spiritualism and Shakerism join hands and see what they
                            can do for the salvation of the race. But in thus joining they need to incorporate the
                            hygiene and the baptism of fire and water as it is used at the Home of Health. Yours, for
                            truth,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Miller, E. P." TEIform="persName"/>E. P. Miller</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Matter and spirit" TEIform="index"/>MATTER AND SPIRIT</head><p TEIform="p">All matter, so called, is spirit as much as ice is water. Matter is simply congealed spirit,
                            or solidified ether and gases. Philosophers assure us that heat is everywhere, even in ice,
                            but in a latent state or as a less active principle. Heat or fire is merely the indications
                            of change, which is in degree proportionate to the activity and intensity of the change or
                            combustion. Hence the heat that is required to fuse or melt one metal is cold compared with
                            that which is required to fuse another. These somewhat abstruse questions, we are glad to
                            see, are beginning to attract the attention of many spiritualists, and with others that of
                            Col. Olcott, who has lately published a book entitled "People from the Other World." A
                            communication from his pen lately appeared in a Hartford journal upon these subjects, from
                            which we make the following quotations: "The philosophical chemist uses a balance so
                            delicate that it will render sensible a weight of one-ten-thousandth of a grain, and yet no
                            one could see the thing weighed. A metal in common use, not only in the shape of coin, but
                            also in many branches of the mechanic, arts — nickle — has recently been detected in the
                            atmosphere, and it need not surprise us if in time every other form of matter on this earth
                            is discovered to exist in sublimation in the air we breathe. As science marches apace the
                            secrets of nature will more and more yield themselves to our search. What may be spirit, and
                            what pure matter, where the one ceases and the other begins, I cannot pretend to say, for no
                            man of science has hitherto pushed his experiments that far. If I might hazard a guess upon
                            the basis of the progression of ultimates and the doctrine of evolution, I should suppose
                            the point of juncture would be where pure matter had reached its last degree of sublimation,
                            and spirit— God-descended and God-attracted—stooped downward to that union of which the
                            product is man. I can say one thing at any rate (and I think I am the only one who can, up
                            to tlie present moment), I have weighed what we call "spirits," upon a platform scales, as I
                            would a bar of steel, and, moreover, at my request they have caused their weight to vary
                            about forty per cent, in ten minutes. How they do this I do not know, but they made their
                            evanescent bodies, in the first place, by concentrating and making visible and ponderable
                            invisible atoms from the atmosphere by an effort of will, and then, by a further voluntary
                            effort, threw off as much of this matter as was necessary to poise the beam of my scales at
                            the lesser mark of weight." <pb n="52" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 52 SHAKEE A.ND Certainly, " every form of
                            matter on the earth " exists in a state of sublimation in the atmosphere we breathe. Every
                            mineral substance grows,which has been satisfactorily, proved by examining and working old
                            and long deserted mines. The Lake Superior copper mines bear unmistakable evidence of having
                            been worked many thousands of years ago, by an extinct and forgotten race, the mound
                            builders ; and where they had evidently well nigh exhausted the ore, the miner now finds
                            copper in abundance; which for unknown ages has been accumulating by growth or aggregation
                            from the surrounding atmospheric elements, where not only copper and nickle exist in
                            sublimation, but gold and silver, as well as all of the sixty odd primates or basic metals,
                            that float about in a state of sublimation. Gold has been detected in sea water, also. From
                            this sublimated strata of matter which surrounds this globe and presses everywhere upon it
                            with an inconceivable pressure, the earth is continually aggregating in bulk, and instead of
                            having been made in six days, or in any specified period, it is not yet made, but is yet, as
                            it ever has been since its birth into the great family of worlds, still growing and
                            enlarging and increasing its outward crust. Each successive growth and decay of vegetation
                            is but adding to the bulk of the earth and the fertility of the soil. For vegetation or
                            vegetable matter is not, as is generally inferred, drawn or extracted from the earth. This
                            truth is daily verified by putting earth into pots, boxes, tubs and other vessels, in which
                            flowers, shrubs and even fruit and vegetables are raised, and yet it is evident that the
                            earth never loses a single grain. They who doubt this truth can easily try the experiment by
                            planting a pumpkin seed in a small pot or tub of earth and note the result. As we observe
                            the ascending scale and progress of animal existence we note the fact that all animal bodies
                            are composed and formed from the surrounding elements or atmosphere, partly from the
                            absorption of vegetable matter taken into the stomach in the form of food, but mainly by
                            direct absorption from the atmosphere just as the vegetable grows. It was not preposterous,
                            therefore, for an ancient inspired writer to say " all flesh is grass." The body is not the
                            real man or real woman. No one ever sees the real man or real woman, which is the essence or
                            spirit, and it is self-evident always existed, aggregating to itself a body according to the
                            mobility of chemical law and action upon the imponderable elementary substance existing in
                            what is flippantly termed space; and which in time being better understood, or by progress
                            being enabled to act more freely and directly, the spirit will be enabled to materialize and
                            dematerialize a body for the occasion at its will and pleasure from the surrounding elements
                            in sublimation, from whence it is apparent to every reflecting mind all animal bodies are
                            evolved. Viewed in this scientific or natural light, spirit materializations appear no more
                            mysterious or miraculous than the formation of our every-day bodies or other aggregations in
                            nature. In fact it would be a mystery.if it could not be done, since the human mind can
                            conceive" of no limitation to the power of materialization and dematerialization of matter.
                            Spirit materialization, therefore, becomes a natural and unavoidable sequence in the order
                            of progress on this planet, as well as upon all others; since nature's laws are universal,
                            applicable alike to all worlds and all time. Kingdom of Heaven.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watch" TEIform="index"/>WATCH</head><p TEIform="p">How very expressive and rich in significance is this little word. It is, verily., a
                            photograph of thought;—a living, breathing picture of actuality, and an indispensable
                            attribute of the Christian, Shaker life. The soul should vigilantly guard its spiritual
                            interests. Watching is its picket guard, its beacon light, its fog bell, giving timely
                            warning of approaching danger. Chastity of body and purity of spirit — inseparable adjuncts
                            of a Shaker's life, and blessed fruition of the Cross — are obtained only by the strictest
                            watchfulness. Beautiful, among the fairest and rarest gems in our Father and Mother's
                            Kingdom, will appear the souls of those who are unstained by the sins of a generative life,
                            who conquer passion and every animal proclivity; nobly triumphing over all physical
                            weaknesses. These will be the Flowers of Heaven and the Glory of Paradise. My dear young
                            friends, to you is the attainment of this hope possible. Watch well your ways, your words,
                            your thoughts, and guard your youthful innocence with the most jealous care. The reward is
                            sure. Years of deep suffering of soul and floods of repentant tears are not as useful to the
                            spirit as a few hours of watching. " What I say unto you I say unto all, watch." Never was
                            this injunction more necessary than now. To no class of people was it more applicable.
                            American youth and children can vie with the world in vitiated and abnormal appetites. They
                            are impregnated at birth with an almost insatiable desire for excitement and unnatural
                            stimulants. Parents have, indeed, great need to watch. The world seems aglow with pleasure,
                            full of sweets and bliss. Glittering charms of the wanton gild a false life ; music and
                            poetry in beautiful cadences depict joys - never actualized, and the brightest talent of
                            earth's most gifted ones is prostituted to the basest of purposes. How powerful their
                            influence thousands of poor suffering souls can sorrowfully attest. The vile literature
                            which floods the nation is a curse of immense magnitude. The abominable trash is sapping the
                            spiritual life of our young people at an alarming rate. Sound the tocsin of alarm from ocean
                            to ocean, and let us equip for a fierce battle with this monster of iniquity. Let every
                            Christian parent and every lover of virtue unite in a universal and overwhelming protest
                            against this nefarious traffic for lucre. Let us, above all things, keep the plague from our
                            households, and from contact with our darling ones. Watch ! ye guardians of the nation's
                            hope, watch ! !</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Thomas Smith, Canaan, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pittston, 21 February, 1875" TEIform="index"/>Pittston, 21st February, 1875</head><p TEIform="p">To Timothy Rayson : Respected friend — Yours of the 14th inst., was duly received and I offer
                            a few words in reply. 1 had previously read in the Tribune of your great misfortune and that
                            with feelings very different from, what I generally experience in such cases, for though
                            yourself and friend Fraser make the total of my personal acquaintance with Shakers, yet from
                            you I learned, that a great many of your distinguishing characteristics are identical with
                            those eccentricities of thought and feeling, which, in a measure, isolate me from my kind,
                            even while living, and necessarily in some degree acting with them, and as " a fellowfeeling
                            makes us wond'rous kind." I read of your misfortune as if I had had a direct personal
                            interest in it, heightened probably by your very recent visit to us. When a calamity of like
                            nature overtakes the great trading communities as the Chicago and Boston instances,
                            generally in a great measure the result of recklessness and selfish greed, though the
                            suffering may be great even among those not involved in, the guilt, yet I am prone to forget
                            the individual losers, and regret mainly that so much of the accumulated results of labor
                            has been swept away which can only be made up by the renewed exertions of the already
                            over-worked toilers of humanity, but when the like happens to a community striving to live
                            on the most j ust, correct and brotherly principles, though the resulting suffering may not
                            be proportionately so great, yet as it is much less likely to have arisen from carelessness
                            or other preventable cause, the sympathy is also for this reason naturally greater, and
                            though the great multitude of haphazard livers may affect to laugh and even sneer at what
                            they choose to call eccentricities, yet after all, they are fully sensible of your worth as
                            public examples, and, whatever may be said of " total depravity," I think mankind as a whole
                            are more naturally disposed to sympathize and assist in calamity, than to laugh or rejoice
                            at it. But when the thing has happened what next ? One of the most profitable practices of
                            my life has been a careful mental registration of mistakes and shortcomings of whatever
                            nature or kind, always emphasized in proportion to the resulting loss. To remind you of this
                            principle would be indeed " Carrying coal to Newcastle." Nevertheless it is well when we
                            count up what we save from such wrecks, not to forget the value of experience, no
                            inconsiderable item to those who have wisdom to act upon it. Accept my worthy friend, for
                            yourself personally, and also convey to your community as a whole, the expression of the
                            sincere sympathy of myself and other friends in this place, also my thanks for the two
                            papers you sent me, which I read with great interest. I had also a little pamphlet from
                            friend Fraser, and would like to write to him, but in common with most working men, writing
                            is slow and painful work for me, so be pleased to renew my respects to him when you write.
                            The weather continues very severe here and water pipes nearly all frozen, and a famine
                            imminent. Hoping for your friendly visit when you next have occasion to be here, I am,
                            sincerely yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Law, James" TEIform="persName"/>James Law</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Adventists again disappointed" TEIform="index"/>THE ADVENTISTS AGAIN DISAPPOINTED</head><p TEIform="p">The Adventists of Chicago, after making their own interpretation of the Book of "Daniel,
                            fixed upon Monday last at midnight for the end of all things here below, and the coming of
                            the Son of Man. They gathered to the number of nearly 200, in their accustomed place of
                            worship, where the day was spent in waiting and suffering annoying visits from unbelievers.
                            At night they sought a secluded hall, where the ceremonies of feet-wash-" ing and eating the
                            paschal lamb were observed. With the approach of evening came a thunderstorm, during which
                            the skies were filled with a peculiar yellow light, giving temporary hope and courage to the
                            Adventists on the appearance of the promised sign from heaven. After the fulfillment of
                            their services in the hall, the company knelt, awaiting the coming of midnight and the hour
                            of triumph. The early hour came, but the solemn ticking of the clock continued, and the
                            darkness of night gradually melted into the light of dawn before which the hopes of the
                            self-deluded band vanished. Slowly and sadly they wrapped the mantles of earth about them
                            and stole quietly away; let us hope to learn that " the Kingdom of Heaven cometh not with
                            observation." In what respect do these consistent Adventists differ from their inconsistent
                            Orthodox Critics? Both read and understand the Scriptures as the very Word of God. All
                            Christendom — Catholic and Protestant — looks for the Second Coming, as do these Adventists.
                            In all respects they are at one, except that the Adventists set the time of the end in their
                            own days — j ust as the Shakers have done. The latter differ from them all, in the manner,
                            and are living in the fruition of the Kingdom of Heaven.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Editor</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Duty" TEIform="index"/>DUTY</head><p TEIform="p">Remember your duty to God, Though sorely afflicted you be ; Not through fear of the rod, Nor
                            yet because danger you see. Remember your duty to man — Your Brothers and Sisters on earth ;
                            The surest of ways that you can Prove your claim to a heavenly birth. Remember your duty to
                            do, As well as your duty to know; Talk may be well — prayer is, too ; But add to them works,
                            and keep low. The true " faith which worketh by love," Has no need for fear of the rod; Our
                            duty, below or above, Will lead us in safety to God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whiteley, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Whiteley. Shirley Village, March 14,1875</byline></div2><pb n="53" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: contrast" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: CONTRAST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">In ancient times there was a marked contrast in the practical lives of the Epicurean and
                            Pythagorean philosophers. The former were extreme in devotion to pleasure derived through
                            the medium of external bodily senses. The latter were extremly ascetic, renounced every
                            thing worldly and self-pleasing, devoted their lives and energies to the cultivation of
                            their spiritual faculties, and counted no sacrifice too great, to secure divine favor. If we
                            bring down the history of those ancient philosophers, and place it side by side with the
                            history of modern philosophers, we find a large class of Epicurean, and very few of the
                            Pythagorean type. If history speak truly, some who were cotemporary with Jesus and the
                            Apostles, were stern in self-discipline, pure in morals, philanthropic in works, and
                            religiously devotional in their feelings. It is related of Apollonius, an admirer and
                            follower of Pythagoras, that to prove himself worthy to be called a self-conqueror, he sub|
                            sisted entirely on fruit and vegetables, drank water only, would not marry, and took a vow
                            of silence which he preserved unbroken five years, during which time he accumulated a large
                            amount of spiritual wisdom and power; not only learned how to command and govern his own
                            spirit, but to exert a controlling influence over others in the same direction. While he was
                            affectionate and gentle in his manner, j udicious in his counsels, he was powerful in
                            reproving sin and vanity, which he never failed to do when opportunity offered. His power
                            consisted in having conquered those things in himself. How much we stand in need of such
                            philosophers in our own time, who will both practice and teach. The doctrine of the trinity,
                            vicarious suffering and atonement, that was decided by the learned Bishops of the council of
                            Nice in the fourth century (who happened to be more powerful than their opponents), lifted
                            the weight of responsibility from the professed followers of Jesus, and Christianity (so
                            called) has grown more theoretical and less practical, until the present time. If the
                            philosophers of the nineteenth century, instead of spending their energies in admiring Jesus
                            and lauding him with praises in word and song, while in practice they deny his teaching and
                            put him to open shame, would bring their wisdom and knowledge to bear upon all the
                            transactions of daily life, in public and private, would they not by so doing exalt their
                            own characters and help to elevate others ? Jesus exalted himself by the practice of virtue,
                            laying down the natural life and taking the higher spiritual life. In that way he was "
                            lifted up " and became an example to others. Some of the oriental polytechnic students, who
                            were familiar with the history of Jesus, said " Some great and good Spirit descended upon
                            him at his baptism, and united with his soul. Thus he became Jesus the Anointed, or Jesus
                            Christ." By co-operating with that good Spirit he was " lifted up," and drew others unto
                            him, and helped them to be better and purer in morals and more spiritual in their
                            aspirations. We need the kind of philosophy to-day that will result in chastened thought and
                            purified imagination ; a philosophy that will lift the soul above morbid sensibilities,
                            selfish loves and affections and sensual deeds, make us Christ-like, and cause us to feel
                            the power of the " new commandment" which he gave to his disciples when he walked with them
                            in mortal form, " Love one another as I have loved you." Then Science and Religion, bound
                            together by indissoluble ties, will march hand in hand and keep step with the music of the
                            higher spheres. Thus a " new earth" will be formed, wherein the righteousness which belongs
                            to that Order, in a rectified condition, will dwell; and it will be tributary to the new
                            heavenly Order, which will be as a garner to receive the ripened grain of the earth — those
                            souls who have progressed beyond the natural, generative order — the seed plane — and are
                            ready for the visitation of the harvesting angel with the sharp sickle, to reap them from
                            that field and gather them into higher, broader fields, to work for and with the angels, in
                            replenishing the heavens with resurrected souls. It occurs to us that many of the
                            philosophers and learned divines of our own time might study the ancient Vedas with profit
                            to themselves and for the benefit of the people whom they profess to guide and teach, if
                            they would make practical application of many truths therein contained. All nations have had
                            their standard of faith and morals ; and when we lay aside traditional education and
                            prejudice, we shall be willing to look fairly at every thing within our grasp or vision, and
                            as far as we are able, accept the true and reject the false. The Veda asks " Of what use is
                            it to seek corporeal pleasures? The inhabitants of the body are cupidity, anger, desire for
                            wealth, envy, sadness, disappointment, hunger, thirst, disease, old age and death. Of what
                            use then to seek pleasures through the body ?" " Through strict veracity, uniform control of
                            mind and senses, abstinence from sexual indulgence, man should approach God, who, full of
                            glory and perfection, works in the heart, and to whom only votaries, freed from passion and
                            sensual desire, can approximate. God is the final refuge of all who are firm in virtue, who
                            do not destroy their own purity. There is nothing desirable but the Science of God. To be
                            attached to material things is to be chained. To be without such, attachment is to be free !
                            " Who will say that, the above scripture, if considered and practically applied, would not
                            benefit the people of the nineteenth century ? Do we hear voices saying " Look unto Jesus as
                            the author and finisher of faith ? " Then we reply " Faith without works is dead." Jesus,
                            for the joy that was set before him, endured — took up — the cross and despised the shame."
                            Let us do likewise.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ventilation" TEIform="index"/>VENTILATION</head><p TEIform="p">I am so pleased to find a paragraph in the (January number of the Shaker and Shakeress, dated
                            1875,) treating upon ventilation, that I am quite solicitous that the writer continue the
                            subject, until its importance is fully realized, by those to whom it is addressed. The
                            paragraph to which I refer, embraced fifteen lines only. In my view, fifteen columns in
                            favor of proper ventilation, would hardly be too many to be devoted to this subject,
                            (provided each of these could be rationally studied,) to combat, or arouse the giant of
                            public indifference, in this respect. Should there not be some further means used to
                            disseminate this phase of gospel truth, and some more efficient methods taken to help the
                            public to rightly estimate the amount of physical suffering induced by breathing impure air
                            ? Without any doubt nine-tenths of the colds experienced in these northern United States,
                            with their train of unaccounted ills, owe their origin to non-vitalized air. Dr. Jarvis, in
                            his Practical Philosophy, tells us, that we spoil for all purposes of inspiration, about
                            four cubic feet of air per minute ; and also, that seven feet is necessary for the
                            maintenance of healthy inspiration! How long then, we shall be content, (in the face of
                            Science,) to subsist daily upon an atmosphere laden with poison ; or, how long we shall be
                            willing to " die daily," for want of breath, are questions to which I find no solutions
                            given in any of the Scientific Reasons why, extant; I, therefore, trust that you will pardon
                            me for referring them to you. By using the word subsist, I mean what an eminent British
                            writer once suggested, when he stated that " man subsists on air more than upon his meat and
                            drink " This may not be literally true in all cases, but if we inhale a pint of air at a
                            time, a hundred thousand times in every twenty-four hours, we must receive into the lungs
                            every day about fifty hogsheads of this fluid, which should be considered a generous " bill
                            of fare " at least. Dr. Griscom, also, enjoins upon us to return thanks to God for the air
                            we inhale, eighteen times a minute, as well as for the food we eat three times a day, since
                            without the former, the latter would be useless. Philosophy assures us it is estimated, that
                            there is an ocean of air forty-five miles in height continually encircling our earth. This
                            fact alone, proves to me that air was intended for the most liberal use. Anatomy, again,
                            presents the fact that the healthy human lungs are capable of holding a gallon of air,
                            especially, when the six hundred millions of air-cells which they contain are fully
                            inflated, and further proves that pure atmospheric air is not only one of the greatest
                            blessings ever bestowed upon physical life, but that the Divine Master-Builder created ample
                            reservoirs for its reception. This array of facts may be more interesting to me, than to my
                            friends ; for, having given some attention to singing as a mode of worship and a vocal
                            exercise, both in public and private, and having so often realized the necessity of
                            breathing pure air, I am prepared to state that of all the inconveniences inflicted upon
                            professional singers and speakers in public, none equals the exclusion, or the nonadmission
                            of pure air, when engaged in these efforts. I look upon it as a species of torture which a
                            system of civilization that builds air-tight school-houses and churches is willing to
                            tolerate, and of which the savage tribes are innocent. According to Dr. Charles A.
                            Guilmette's Vocal Theory, " Voice is breath made vocal, and pure tone the essential element
                            of all music." Does it not follow, the-refore, that the vocalist is unable to manufacture
                            pure tones out of impure air ? We, who profess to be true Shakers, strongly advocate, purity
                            of thought, of heart and life, believing that from purity alone proceeds that " Cleanliness
                            which is next to Godliness." In view of this profession, therefore," ought we not to strive
                            to maintain as much as is practicable, an atmosphere comparatively pure, in every apartment,
                            and especially in our public halls dedicated to divine worship? An atmosphere out of which
                            pure thoughts are molded and holy aspirations rise. It is my belief that the mind and body
                            are so intimately connected that the former is very sensibly affected, oftentimes, by the
                            condition of the latter, and that the mind, fettered by physical suffering, rarely acts up
                            to its highest conceptions of Godliness. From this <pb n="54" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEE I infer, that
                            no physiologically enlightened mind, can worship God in an illy-ventilated Church, with that
                            singleness of heart, and freedom from earthliness, that he ought. In conclusion, let me add,
                            that, perchance I may have expressed some views which do not exactly accord with those of a
                            higher religious experience, yet what I have stated is a part of God's truth, to my
                            understanding. I have so long meditated upon this subject, and found so much more real
                            satisfaction in studying the Laws of Ventilation, and the Art of Breathing, than I could
                            possibly realize, in studying the Laws which pertain to Generation and its belongings, that
                            I have often heartily wished that some of the able writers and speakers of the " Present
                            Age," would treat the former subject with as much fairness and liberality as the latter has
                            been treated, during the last forty years. Would they do thus, I venture to predict that
                            one-half the " ills that flesh is heir to," would speedily fall in disrepute. And if
                            Physiology, as a study, could be placed within reach of every pupil in the land, instead of
                            insipid novels, and the Laws of Hygiene practically enforced by parents and teachers, not
                            only health of body would be secured, but that rare mental quality Common Sense would
                            everywhere prevail.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stickney, Asenath C." TEIform="persName"/>Asenath C. Stickney, Shaker Village, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dawn of a new era" TEIform="index"/>DAWN OF A NEW ERA</head><p TEIform="p">Materialization is among the beautiful and important wonders of our day. But what is it, and
                            how produced? As yet there is no definite answer to these questions. The vague theory, that
                            spirits draw material from the mediums and circle, out of which to fashion tangible bodies,
                            clothing, etc., must be proven before it is accepted; mere belief is not knowledge, and
                            skepticism is not investigation. The doubting mind of Washington Irving's Governor
                            Vantwiller, could not see through the clouds of tobacco smoke, the railway upon the land,
                            nor the telegraph beneath the ocean, yet the achievements of science were still advancing
                            toward these culminations; and though skeptics have been wrapped in the smoke of their
                            egotism, spiritualism has steadily advanced to its present point of importance. Before the
                            inventor Morse ticked messages from city to city, from continent to continent, communication
                            was opened, upon a similar plan, by dwellers in the Spirit World, with dwellers in this. If
                            you give a magnet nothing to do, it will lose its power; and so with the organs of the head.
                            Cramped reason, flagrant combativeness, and a weak, ghostly ideality, made up the Trinity of
                            Protestantism, by which Spirituality was branded, and sent into the society of
                            marvelousness, to find her abode with the simple and ignorant. This was the last act of the
                            old monarchical Church and State. But in the new Republic —the system of School and State —
                            the scars and distortions of ages are measurably outlived ; and now the inhabitants of the
                            earth may learn righteousness; for the lightnings lighten the world. We. must not ignore nor
                            transgress the laws that govern materialization, any more than we would ignore or violate
                            those which temper the sun's rays. The most familiar things with which we are acquainted are
                            dependent on conditions. One person may see with the naked eye distant and small objects,
                            while another can only enjoy that degree of vision through the aid of glasses. From the
                            lonely ship voices can be heard for miles over the tranquil star-lit waters, while amid the
                            roar of the tempest, or the density of the fog, they are inaudible, or husky, even on her
                            own deck. If the high winds of human contentions and the simooms of sandy or earthly
                            individuality, are likely to extinguish the beams that are just breaking upon us, it is
                            needful — for a time at least — that they should be shaded by a cabinet, and that the
                            contending minds be harmonized by even such " music as charms the savage." We differ as one
                            star differs from another; but we each have a place. Like the metals in the mine, we differ;
                            some of us resemble the load-stone, while others are similar to the iron which is capable of
                            being suffused with its magnetic power. We need to patiently learn the lessons of life
                            eternal. Astronomy tells us that a common-sized man, removed, to the surface of the sun,
                            would weigh between two and three tons; becaiise a bulk weighing here one pound would there
                            weigh nearly thirty pounds, so great is the sun's power of gravitation. May not a spirit
                            that weighs here fifty or eighty pounds have in its own home a weight appropriate to its
                            dimensions ? We readily avail ourselves of the dark telescope and microscope, when we seek
                            knowledge of the vast and minute works of the Creation; but we do not imagine that the
                            darkness has materialized the stars — that the sunlight can extinguish them — or that the
                            animalcula draw their existence from the glass which reveals them any more than we think
                            that the friends and furniture in our room are composed of particles emitted from the lamp
                            which brings them to view. What we call materialization is, perhaps, only the result of
                            conditions, which combined, present to us the " bodies celestial," and make visible the
                            unseen. Our intellectual faculties are enhanced by natural science ; but where is the
                            science of the soul ? The morning stars may continually sing together, and the whole
                            Universe pour its grandly varying oratorio into the ear of God ; but we are deaf ; the
                            shining vault holds for us only silent stars, and the bright sunlight only an empty void.
                            Through the atmosphere of our earth, we perceive sights and sounds, and may not the
                            atmosphere of a clairvoyant, or a number of clairvoyants, become so strengthened, and
                            expanded, as to visiblize the spiritual beings around us, and to reverberate the music of
                            the spheres ?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>Cecelia Devyr, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Funerals and flowers" TEIform="index"/>FUNERALS AND FLOWERS</head><p TEIform="p">One impressive feature of the Shaker reformatory system is the mode of conducting funeral
                            ceremonies. In times of extravagance and folly, it is refreshing to find one nook in the
                            World, reserved for those who prefer unostentatious ways of journeying through life.
                            Believer's faith — growing into knowledge of the translation of the living entity of
                            mortals, to a Spiritual state of existence, losing no mental qualification gained by Earth
                            experience— gives a freedom of thought and action between those just departing therefrom,
                            and those performing the last acts of kindness in smoothing the passage to their prospective
                            home. There is neither the reward of Heaven, nor the punishment of Hell to distort or
                            torture their minds by uncertainty concerning God's rewards or penalties ; but a clear
                            consciousness of one's own right or wrong doing, day by day, causing the spirit to render
                            its own verdict of happiness or misery. As life's burdens are borne with a reference to the
                            Soul being moulded by its present surroundings, every incentive is given to a true Believer
                            to enable the living acting part to progress — to travel from ignorance to knowledge ; and
                            to become enlightened according to its desires. In the outside World, circumstances often
                            tend to demoralizing ways and fashions; or to lose cast in society, which few have the moral
                            stamina to meet. In united body, a few determined souls have passed beyond the bounds of
                            popularity and Avorldly reputation, especially in regard to interring the dead. They
                            practically discard all display of silver mounted coffins, conveyed in an elaborately
                            finished hearse, ornamented with white or sable plumes, denoting age and wealth of the poor
                            perishing remains. Nor do habiliments of grief, of latest style, have to be procured by a
                            rational Shaker, knowing that the spirit needs no mockery of sorrow at its departure.
                            Sincere affection will not resort to external trappings as a manifestation of sorrow. In
                            plain cofHn, the lifeless form, clad in fitting garment, simply fashioned as when worn in
                            every-day life, rests its head as peacefully, as if clothed in the finest fabric, with kid
                            gloves, and costly slippers, merely to feed the pride of the living. At a plain Shaker
                            funeral, we see no display of ministerial oratory to eulogize the dead. Gospel brethren and
                            sisters—true hearted friends — give expression to feelings of love and affection, as they
                            well up in their hearts, speaking of the good deeds and worthy examples of the deceased
                            brother, or sister, as they have mingled in familiar intercourse in home duties and
                            pleasures, also of their travel and toils together, in the spiritual work of redemption. The
                            foregoing simple exercises, together with the hymns and sacred songs, on such occasions,
                            mostly known by the departed one, can but buoy up the freed spirit to continue in good
                            works, and become more and more worthy of the endearing remembrances of kindred friends on
                            earth, strengthened by the laws of attraction to return, and reveal the knowledge of spirit
                            power, to help the weary and faint-hearted to more exalted attainments ; while they continue
                            to progress in the life beyond, and by an increase in truth, overcome all errors committed
                            while in this rudimental life. While I am an admirer of the plain and unpretending manner in
                            which obsequies are performed by Believers, I would like to advance an idea, which to me
                            seems rational. I am young in the faith, and have not had an opportunity of getting very
                            deeply baptized into the spiritual work ; I cannot understand how the introduction of
                            flowers, at Believers' funerals, would detract from the simplicity of their burial rites.
                            Flowers are the loveliest specimens of Nature's works; and it" seems to me that at such
                            seasons they might be used to profit. They are sweet emblems — given for man's spiritual
                            culture — and it is well ever to have an eye to the beautiful and good, in all the relations
                            of life. Those gems of Earth's production, surround the soul with refined atmosphere,
                            guiding the mind into higher channels of thought; even as harmonious strains of music subdue
                            the ravings of a disordered brain.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dwyer, Annie" TEIform="persName"/>Annie Dwyer, South Union, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Remarks" TEIform="index"/>REMARKS</head><p TEIform="p">Allow me to suggest to my new sister Annie, who has quite recently been gathered from the
                            broad expansive plane, where pleasure seeking, in outward external things, is the chief
                            desire and aim, that if the flowers of Earth are beautiful, fragrant and refining, are not
                            heavenly flowers more so ? Would it not be a desirable and beautiful attainment, to become
                            so thoroughly spiritual and inspirational, by holy living, that all the senses be
                            sanctified, and we enabled to see Angels, hear them sing, walk with them in the celestial
                            gardens and cull the flowers which never fade? If we become thus ethereal, when our Gospel
                            friends pass on before us to their home in the spirit spheres, we will be so closely allied
                            to them that there will be a harmonious blending of spirit with spirit; and natural material
                            things, pertaining to earth life, however good and true in their proper place, would not
                            enhance the pleasure and worth of soul communings. The glory of the terrestrial is one
                            thing, and the glory of the celestial another.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Ed.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian life" TEIform="index"/>THE CHRISTIAN LIFE</head><p TEIform="p">How good and pleasant it is, when the toils of the day are over, to feel that we have
                            striven, to the best of our ability, by faithful performance of every duty, to honor and
                            glorify God and benefit humanity. Then no bitter reflections follow on account of misspent
                            time. No harsh or unkind words suffered to escape our lips, will rise up to reproach — to
                            sting the conscience and bring remorse. The evening of a well-spent day is calm, the
                            meditation serene and the repose peaceful and unbroken. When, on bended knees, we give
                            thanks to God for blessings received, we can also with confidence ask a continuance of the
                            same through the medium of angel guides, for obedience to Christian principles brings souls
                            into A.2STD 54 <pb n="55" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEEE88. 55 harmony and communion with angelic beings.
                            Through their rainistrationwe receive strength, are inspired with holy thoughts and
                            feelings, our hearts are filled with sweet melody, and we are led to sing " "Tis joy to walk
                            in Wisdom's way, Her laws and precepts to obey." When thus exercised, worldly pleasures seem
                            valueless, effete, and lose their hold upon the affections. However severe the trials and
                            sorrows of life, as we sail upon its stormy sea, our Heavenly Parents will guide the Bark,
                            order all things aright, and bear us safely over the billowy deep to the voyager's blissful
                            home of rest in that haven where the raging winds of passion never blow, where we can drink
                            to fullness of Christian love, of which we have a foretaste here. True Believers in Christ
                            exemplify their faith by works, and let their light shine brighter and brighter as they
                            practically grow into the true, leaving all that is false. Such constitute a Living Body. If
                            we become members of that Body, our conceptions of God — of Truth — will expand, grow
                            broader and deeper. The divine life will become our element in which we live, move and have
                            our being. All darkness will flee before us, and suffering, the product of sin and wrong
                            doing, with us will cease. Then like Jesus, our elder Brother, we can say " The prince of
                            this world cometh and hath nothing in me." Like him, we shall overcome the world, and like
                            him, " triumph over death and the grave." " The sting of death is sin." The grave over which
                            we need to gain the victory is the love of the world in our own hearts. The human heart is
                            the receptacle of evil thoughts and desires, which, if unrestrained and unsubdued, swallow
                            up , and entomb all the nobler faculties of the mind and hold the soul within its walls,
                            which was justly described in olden times as the " chambers of death." From this sepulchre
                            of sin and sensual pleasure, the desires, affections and powers of the human soul need to be
                            emancipated, resurrected, by coming into Christ, receiving his baptism. Then, like him, we
                            shall triumph in victory, and appear in the glory that fadeth not away.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Randall, Joanna" TEIform="persName"/>Joanna Randall, Shirley, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Eldress Antoinette:" TEIform="index"/>Beloved Eldress Antoinette :</head><p TEIform="p">Having enjoyed the luxury of feasting on the savory contents of the excellent paper, Shaker
                            and Shakeress, I think it but just to try to render something to add to its columns. I have
                            been much edified in perusing the soul utterances of my dear Gospel Brothers and Sisters who
                            have thoughtfully contributed to the union feast, and would express thanks to every one for
                            the same. I was specially interested in reading the beautiful production from the pen of
                            that consecrated "Mother in Israel," Eunice Bathrick, in the May number. Such breathings
                            diffuse spiritual life and true soul inspirations which must do good, having been produced
                            from long experience in the blessed higher life. May we aim to copy her living example, and
                            heed her wise exhortation to " Zion's daughters," thus preserving the unity of the spirit,
                            and be able to do good and help others less favored. Abundant thanks to the managers of the
                            Shaker and Shakeress for your evident pains-taking to gather and prepare wholesome food, not
                            only for the immediate guests who have been'called in to sit with you at the table in a
                            spiritual order, but for the multitudes as well — those who are still on the earth plane.
                            May you be blessed and strengthened in yonr arduous duties and many burdens in the labor of
                            enlightening souls, and opening to their understanding the distinction of the spheres,
                            earthly and heav.enly, and how to attain unto the latter, is the sincere and earnest desire
                            of your sister.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hastings, Marcia E." TEIform="persName"/>Marcia E. Hastings, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A passage in the Turkish Scriptures reads..." TEIform="index"/>A passage in the Turkish Scriptures reads...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A passage in the Turkish Scriptures reads as follows : " Take care that your final accounts
                            shall be settled before you die. Undergo here your indictment and your trial. Pass on
                            yourself just sentence and punishment. Then will you pass into the future without further
                            chastisement or fear."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beautiful day" TEIform="index"/>BEAUTIFUL DAY</head><p TEIform="p">Night's silvery stars melt in morning's soft blushes, Her dark spectral shadows glide
                            noiseless away, While nature, enwrapped in her deep silent hushes, Awakes to the call of the
                            beautiful day. The light-hearted songsters mount upward in gladness, And trill their sweet
                            music all blithesome and gay. What heart could respond with a feeling of sadness? For joy
                            crowns the beautiful, beautiful day! The sun gilds the crest of the forest-clad mountain,
                            And brightens the vale where the early mist lay, From woodland and meadow, from streamlet
                            and fountain, Come voices of welcome to beautiful day! From flowers, the honey-dew fragrance
                            asceuding Is wafted along by the breezes at play; Creations of beauty around us are blending
                            In praise of the glory of beautiful day! We gratefully share of life's bounties external,
                            Which come like a day-dream, nor yet come to stay; But still look beyond to that region
                            supernal, Where beameth forever a beautiful day 1 The forms we are wearing, the scenes we're
                            beholding, Are subject to change and the blight of decay; But germs of the spirit, God's
                            light is unfolding, To bloom in eternity's beautiful day.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Martha J. Anderson, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love" TEIform="index"/>Love</head><p TEIform="p">There is great power in love. Addressing his disciples, Jesus said, "As the Father hath loved
                            me, so have I loved you ; continue ye in my love." He was moved by this spirit of love when
                            he said, " Be of good cheer, I have overcome the world." He overcame the world in himself by
                            energy of spirit; he wrestled against the temptations which were presented to him, and
                            contended with principalities and powers, and spiritual wickedness in high places; and by
                            love to God, to truth and to humanity, he conquered the powers of darkness, and left an
                            example that we all can safely follow. He was not content merely to love those who loved and
                            honored him ; but he learned to "love his enemies, to bless those who hated and persecuted
                            him, and to pray for those who despitefully used him." So strong was his love to
                            righteousness that he laid down his life in its defense ; and all who find a true joining to
                            Christ as the Head of the Church, must live as he lived, bear the same cross of self-denial,
                            rise into the divine life and become one with him, as he became one with the Eternal
                            Parents. Then, we shall so dwell in love that our offerings God ward will all be made in
                            love. In love we shall serve and pray for one another and for all souls. Through love we
                            shall intercede for the lost and erring, that God would send mediums to open the eyes of the
                            spiritually blind, that they may behold the light of the truth, that the deaf may hear the
                            sound of the everlasting Gospel, and be guided in paths of holiness and peace.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sampson, Rachel" TEIform="persName"/>Rachel Sampson, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirituality" TEIform="index"/>Spirituality.</head><p TEIform="p">The Apostle Paul said: " To be carnally minded is death ; but to be spiritually minded is
                            life and peace." Those words are as true to-day as when spoken. So far as the mind expands
                            to receive wisdom and knowledge from the Divine Source, so far does the soul incline to
                            heavenly things, to drink of living waters, and to receive the treasures of immortality.
                            Life, light and love abide with the spiritually minded. In true consecration there is peace
                            which the world cannot give. Earthly things, however beautiful they may appear to the
                            outward senses, perish with the using, and pass away. Heavenly things abide forever.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The sick squaw of a dusky chief in Washington Territory..." TEIform="index"/>The sick squaw of a dusky chief in Washington Territory...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The sick squaw of a dusky chief in Washington Territory lately told her noble husband that
                            she didn't think that she should ever feel any better unless he killed her doctor. This is a
                            novel and startling view of medical matters, and interesting to the profession. The doctor
                            was duly killed ; and upon being tried for his murder, the chief was acquitted on the ground
                            that he acted in defense of his wife's life! The doctors in those regions must feel a little
                            doubtful about continuing in the business under such circumstances.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Divine earnestness" TEIform="index"/>DIVINE EARNESTNESS</head><p TEIform="p">The Apostle Paul, in his stirring letter to the Philippians, said " This one thing I do,
                            forgetting those things which are behind and reaching forth unto those things which are
                            before." The soon succeeding words " Brethren, be followers together of me," would imply
                            that the strongest wish of this devoted servant of Christ was to have those who had been
                            attracted to the truth by the inspiring zeal of his testimonies awake to their highest duty.
                            To forget all things that ought to be forgotten. Their sins and errors had been confessed
                            and repented of, as their first step in discipleship. There were many things in their past
                            lives which it were better never to have learned, but which now must be forgotten; for all
                            things were to become " new." Having thus dropped all needless incumbrances, what was the
                            next duty 1 " Beaching forth " unto the better, higher and more spiritual; '' press toward
                            the mark," etc. As runners for an earthly prize lay aside every weight and impediment, so
                            must the winner of the heavenly state become inspired with a holy enthusiasm and a living
                            earnestness to win the prize of the high calling of God in Christ Jesus, or become like Him.
                            Viewed outwardly, there was little or no success in his life; but what a glorious result was
                            that when he could say " I have overcome the world." When that natural organism through
                            which he was manifested had become so pure a receptacle that Satan could find nothing in it;
                            that the pure unselfish doctrines which he taught had found their exponent in his life.
                            Certainly that life is most a benefaction which is most fruitful in good works, and has done
                            the most to lighten the burden of misery which weighs so heavily on earth's groaning
                            children. As a poet has so beautifully expressed : " They whose great souls were great
                            beyond compare, They whose high Prophet brows did ever shine, They who made earth most
                            beautiful and fair, Drank not while here of pleasure's purple wine; But were content the
                            cross and scorn to bear, Enduring all things in a calm sublime; And He who did the
                            weightiest sorrow wear, With noblest heart bloomed into the divine. Then let us never murmur
                            nor complain When the night darkens and the icy rain Of wrong and hatred beats around our
                            way, But joy that we " are counted worthy," so With blessed martyrs toil to undergo The hero
                            labors, while the children play." Not, we presume, that there should be no play, but that
                            our souls should glow with so divine an earnestness that play would be impossible when the
                            needs around required work, and that would speak its silent voice of reproof to our souls if
                            we would allow ourselves to shirk the burdens of life. If a soul should become wrecked on
                            the dark strands of despair through our indifference, will not some accusing angel of mercy
                            lower us into some hell of condemnation long enough to convince us that " inasmuch as we
                            have done, or not done, it to one of the least, we have done, or not done, it to Him ? "
                            Nothing but the daily justice and purity of our lives can make us winners of that richest
                            prize, a sweet, subdued and self-sacrificing love for God, manifested in our love for each
                            other, until the human temple from which this light streams forth becomes beautiful and
                            glorious, even though it be worn with the furrows of age, or otherwise " marred in the hands
                            of the potter."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. Webster, Harvard, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scandal" TEIform="index"/>Scandal.</head><p TEIform="p">A woman confessed to a priest that she was guilty of circulating a scandal. He gave her a
                            ripe thistle top, and told her to scatter the seeds, one by one, in every direction. She
                            obeyed, and returned after her task was done. He then ordered her to go back and collect the
                            scattered seed. She said it would be impossible. He replied it would be more impossible to
                            gather up and destroy all the evil reports that she had. circulated about others. Blessed
                            are they who walk uprightly and speak truth in their hearts. That back-bite not with their
                            tongues, nor take up a reproach against their neighbors.</p></div2><pb n="56" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Threshold" TEIform="index"/>THE THRESHOLD</head><p TEIform="p">Canaan, N. Y. 1. We stand upon the threshold of another world to-day; We wait with patient
                            spirit, and we 2. We read of sacred mysteries engraved on pages bright; But view fair heaven
                            opening up watch each sunset ray; We linger in the valley, and labor while we pray, And scan
                            Time's changing scroll, on our inner sight; We feel its love immortal, its glowing beams of
                            light, Nor aught of dark'ning gloom. 'Tis joy to know that ev'ry day brings heaven nearer
                            earth, That we are leaving all its scenes of gross and sinful mirth, Today we live in
                            harmony with Wisdom's rich increase, Tomorrow brings its hallowed life, and promises of
                            peace, That we are seeking progress in the pure angelic birth. The glory of the soul, And
                            future prospects proffer us the joys that never cease, Bright hope of fadeless bloom.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dispensations" TEIform="index"/>DISPENSATIONS</head><p TEIform="p">Brightly a star over Bethlehem beamed, That shepherds and wise men discerned, And followed
                            with gladness, 'till over a child Its glory effulgently burned. Born of the highest
                            unfoldment of law, Prophesies grand in his life to fulfill, From faith and obedience the
                            power to draw, To be the earth's Saviour through God's holy will. Whenithe meek heart sought
                            the Jordan baptism. Where was an outpouring of heavenly love, The spirit of Christ to Jesus
                            was given — The pure, holy spirit, in the form of a dove. Now was commencing a New
                            Dispensation, The Father revealed in the Son, A High Priest who show'd a lost world
                            salvation, And taught how its prize must be won. He liken'd the kingdom of God to the
                            mustard, The smallest among the small seeds, And showed how the increase of life would
                            expand it To come to humanity's needs. He likened it also unto the leaven A woman concealed
                            in three measures of meal. The laws Patriarchal, previously given, The power of the New
                            Dispensation must feel. He taught on the mountain without peradventure To pray for the
                            kingdom of God among men ; He taught that they never that kingdom could enter Until of the
                            Spirit they were born again. He gave them the cross as a means of salvation, For those who
                            would rise from the first Adam's fall, And whoso would follow in regeneration, Must hate
                            their own life and relinquish their all. He noticed the gift of the widow's last farthing —
                            'Twas all, in her penury, that she possessed ; But more in His eyes than the rich man's
                            great offering— It showed her heart's effort to bless and be blessed. The Pharisees
                            temptingly brought Him a woman, And cited the law that was given of yore ; He put them to
                            shame by the power above human, Then pardoned and bade her to go sin no more. Wisely He
                            spoke to Samaria's afflicted, All irrespective of cast or degree ; And many she called, for
                            her soul was convicted That He was the Christ whom they wanted to see. When one much
                            afflicted took hold of His garment, With faith, th'at through sorrow, had gained its
                            control, He said to her, " Daughter, my peace I give to thee, The strength of thy faith hath
                            indeed made thee whole." He came to the sick and dispelled their diseases ; In mercy the
                            leper and lunatic healed; Gave sight to the blind, and voice to the speechless, And called
                            back to life some whom death's hand had sealed. Among His disciples there was not a woman,
                            Though Mary and Martha His gospel He taught; And many with reverence ministered to Him, And
                            gifts from their substance most lovingly brought. The Spirit of Truth was the Comforter
                            promised Unto the disciples, who could not yet bear The many deep things which he needed to
                            tell them, That they for the kingdom might truly prepare. But when on Mount Calvary,
                            painfully dying, He said to His mother, " Behold now thy son! " And to His disciples, "
                            Behold thou thy mother! " Then was His life-mission finished and done ! Thus was the woman
                            oft blest by the Saviour, Though humble and low was her place ; He knew that with man she
                            would yet be anointed To work for the Order of Grace. The woman must be in the fourth
                            Dispensation: The gospel of Christ is for all; Her name must be raised from the old
                            accusation Of being the cause of the fall. On woman the spirit of God has descended, And
                            Mother in Daughter revealed ; On the right hand she stands, in wrought gold of Ophir, Her
                            leaven is no more concealed. The Bride and the Bridegroom that long were expected, Achieved
                            the true Order of Grace ; A Father and Mother, in the New Creation, Have brought forth a
                            heaven-born race. The kingdom has come which the ancients long prayed for — The empire of
                            Daughter and Son ; And souls born again heaven's fullness inherit — The Lord's will on earth
                            is now done. The Lord is beginning to shake every nation ; Salvation the woman has won; In
                            purity now she in Zion is dwelling, Where righteousness shines like the sun. The truth is
                            established, in glory and beauty, And yet for an increase 'tis rife; The voice of the Spirit
                            and Bride are proclaiming, Ho ! come to the waters of life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Agnew, Hannah A." TEIform="persName"/>Hannah A. Agnew, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tann, Charlotte" TEIform="index"/>Charlotte Tann
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Tann, Charlotte" TEIform="persName">Charlotte Tann</persName>, April 15, 1875, South Union,
                                Ohio.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harris, Polly" TEIform="index"/>Polly Harris
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Harris, Polly" TEIform="persName">Polly Harris</persName>, April 15,1875, South Union,
                            Ohio.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Addison, Hannah" TEIform="index"/>Polly Harris
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Addison, Hannah" TEIform="persName">Polly Harris</persName>, May 20, 1875, aged 85 years,
                                North Union, Ohio.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watson, Rhoda" TEIform="index"/>Rhoda Watson
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Watson, Rhoda" TEIform="persName">Rhoda Watson</persName>, May 21,1875. aged 74 years, North
                                Union, Ohio.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fuller, Lucy" TEIform="index"/>Lucy Fuller
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Fuller, Lucy" TEIform="persName">Lucy Fuller</persName>, April 16,1875, aged 62 years,
                                Watervliet, New York.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>