<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0302" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><date value="18730201" TEIform="date">February 1873</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">9-16</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="9" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
                    <p>Vol. III. No. 2. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. F W EVANS Fifty Cents Editok. ' MtLebanon, Ool. Co. N. Y.
                        February, 1873. PER ANNUM></p>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love, the bond of our union" TEIform="index"/>LOVE, THE BOND OF OUR UNION</head><p TEIform="p">Christmas and New Year, with all their joys and sorrows, have come and gone throughout our
                            happy land, but not so their remembrances. These remain, and, like newmown hay, send forth,
                            from the storehouse of memory, a fragrance very grateful to the providers, but still more so
                            to the recipients of and participants in their festivities. As these have been religiously
                            rational, so will the pleasures of the past be ever present — always "green," a "joy
                            forever." The people of God, of the latter day — the day of His spiritual "power" — were to
                            be emphatically " a willing people." The North Family, whence the " Shaker and Shaheress"
                            issues, is the head of the Novitiate Order (composed of three families), where all the
                            inquirers into ShaJcerism, who come to Mount Lebanon, do congregate, and where all new
                            converts to it find a home, during their initiatory and probationary period of the new life,
                            into which they may have been ushered. Anciently, one asked, " How are the dead raised, and
                            with what body do they come forth?" Modernly, many ask, "How can you Shakers and
                            Shakeresses, who are dead to the world, and to its (to you) sinful pleasures, enjoy
                            Christmas and New Year, or any other social holiday season ? " And we make answer, that
                            "Godliness is profitable to all things, to the life that now is and that which is to come "
                            — to all things relating to the soul and body. Our Christmas and New Year's tables did not "
                            groan under" adulterated, poisonous compounds, and costly viands, either liquids or solids;
                            nor did they groan over the ruined health which the consumption of such things occasion;
                            for, although bountifully supplied, their contents were gustatory and enjoyable to the
                            palate, and agreeable to and easily digested by the stomach. This, though earthly, is no
                            trifling blessing in this day of artificial dressing and feeding, and of superficial,
                            highlyseasoned cookery. Then we had a mental feast of spiritual union and love; hearty,
                            happy greetings from soul to soul, and presents from all the Brethren and Sisters to the
                            Elders, as the Representatives of the Family. These were in the form of little missives, of
                            which the following are specimens, the first two from the more advanced in years and
                            experience, and the last from the youngest convert to our Order: "North Family, Sabbath
                            Morning, "Dec. 25, 1872. " To the Elders: May the blessing of our Heavenly Parents ever rest
                            with their representatives in care — the Elders — and bless them with Heavenly courage,
                            fortitude and Divine Love, and when their labors of love are closed, may an abiding peace be
                            theirs. '• Be so kind as to accept from my spirit, on this occasion, a Christmas blessing.
                            "D. P." ANOTHER. " Beloved Parents: It is with deep feelings of love and respect that I
                            address you at this time. I am truly thankful for your heavenly ministrations, so fraught
                            with wisdom and love. " I bless you for your fatherly and motherly tenderness to all your
                            little flock. Justice and mercy are yours to impart; while condemning the evil you cherish
                            the good. The spirit of Jesus, and of our ever blessed Mother Ann, shines brightly in your
                            daily lives, which to me is evidence of the true and holy anointing wherewith ye are
                            anointed. I know that I am blessed in many ways, and have cause of great thankfulness for my
                            privilege in the Gospel. I feel especially thankful that I am permitted to live and asso-
                            ciate with those in whom I have the utmost confidence as Leaders and "Watchmen in Zion. " I
                            love and bless you, kind parents, and it shall be my constant labor to strengthen and build
                            ap the walls of our Zion, according to my small capacity. In this way I can gain and retain
                            your love and blessing, which I hope ever to possess. Levi." ANOTHER, FROM THE YOUNGEST IN
                            PRIVILEGE. "My dear Elders: I am happy that I have this opportunity of expressing my growing
                            love and respect for you, and of acknowledging my appreciation of the influence you are
                            holding over me. My prayer shall ever be, that I may prove myself worthy of your love and
                            confidence, and, at the sacrifice of every thing earthly, I pray that I may be simple, and
                            keep my union with you perfect at all times. Hoping that you may live long to encourage
                            others, as you have encouraged me, is my sincere wish. " With kind wishes, and the
                            compliments of the season, I am yours sincerely, "Elmer." Thus it is, that from the heaviest
                            and most faithful burden bearers to the babes in Christ, the love of truth and goodness, of
                            God, of each other, and of humanity, is the only real Bond of our Union, that holds us
                            together in a Community of goods, in an arbor of Peace, with the Communion of Saints.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Extract from an English letter, dated October 30, 1872" TEIform="index"/>Extract from an
                                English Letter, dated Oct. 30tft, 1872.</head><p TEIform="p">" I see, by this week's 'Medium,' that the Bishop of Chester takes the position that
                                Jesus was the first to enter Heaven ; and that even David was not in the (Christ)
                                heavens, although more than ten centuries had passed since his death." Turning to the
                                October (25th) No. I find the following : " The Intermediate State. A Sermon on the
                                Intermediate State by the Bishop of Chester, just published." " The clergy, for many
                                years, have regarded the intermediate state of the soul (between death and the physical
                                resurrection) a sealed subject, until Dr. Bartle, Principal of Frestifield College,
                                Liverpool, brought out his novel work, in 1869, entitled ' Hades,' for which he was
                                charged with heresy. Now the Buhop of Chester comes to his support, making his own views
                                on the ' Intermediate State' identical with those expressed by Dr. Bartle in his work."
                                —Ed. of "Medium." Dr. Bartle: In Hade?, we read (p. 113): " The portion of Scripture
                                from the Acts proves that the soul or spirit of Christ was in Hades; because St. Peter
                                declares that God did not leave it there. It must of necessity have been in that region,
                                otherwise its removal thence would have been an impossibility. (Page 38.) Death is
                                simply the separation of soul and body." Page 194. " We find St. Peter stating that the
                                patriarch David, who, he said, was both dead and buried, yet had not at that time
                                ascended into the Heavens, although his death occurred a thousand years before." Page
                                226. " With St. Paul, to die was gain; but the crown of righteousness would not be given
                                him till that day; meaning the day of judgment." Chapter VII. " Let it be clearly
                                understood, then that the expression ' sleeping' implies ' waking;' and, therefore,
                                whenever we find the word ' sleeping ' used of the deceased, it never means that the
                                soul is in a state of unconsciousness." Page 202. "Hades is a Greek word, and literally
                                means the invisible place; and the word 'heK,' in its primary meaning, signifies the
                                hidden place; and in this place it is almost identical with 'Hades.'" The editor of the
                                '• Medium" presumptuously advises these two great Orthodox lights (or balls of darkness)
                                to attend some of the seances, and there learn that the disembodied souls of men and
                                women have no idea of attempting to gather the identical materials ot their long-ago
                                discarded bodies. As to the day of judgment, it is when a man (or woman) brings himself
                                (or herself) to judgment by the confession and the discontinuing the com- mission of sin
                                — missing the mark.—Ed.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Postscript of a letter since received, dated December 8,1872" TEIform="index"/>Postscript
                                of a letter since received, dated December 8,1872:</head><p TEIform="p">" P. S.—I sent you a London ' Standard,' in which you will see our good friend, Mr. Hep-
                                worth Dixon, has been figuring in Court. Sir <pb n="10" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 1O SHAKER .A.ND J.
                                Eastlake, counsel for defendant, is teported elsewhere to have spoken in the highest
                                terms of the Shaker communities, saying that' Dixon's description of them was the
                                redeeming feature of all his books.' " I shall not fail to either write, or send you a
                                paper every week, until I come amongst you.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="W., E. J." TEIform="persName"/>E. J. W.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Berlin, New York, December 18, 1872" TEIform="index"/>Berlin, Camden Co., N. Y., December
                                18,1872</head><p TEIform="p">Editor of" Shaker and Shakeress : " It is a source of joy to me, to know that the Shakers
                                are sending forth, into this wilderness world of sin, Christ's doctrines of " peace on
                                earth, good will to man." Since the commencement of the late war, the rising genera-
                                tion have been taught, by the popular clergy, and the religious papers, that war is an
                                essential part of Christianity; that men shot down in battle, while filled with hate and
                                wrath, and striving to kill those who had never injured them, are taken directly to
                                heaven, and crowned as saints and Christian martyrs, and placed on thrones of honor and
                                glory at the right hand of God. During the war, ministers went to steamboat and railroad
                                stations, to take leave of soldiers leaving home for the scene of slaughter, and there
                                went through the blasphemous ceremony they call prayer; and then presented the soldiers
                                with flags and New Testaments, and exhorted them to go and fight manfully, like
                                Christian heroes. And should any one have been faithful enough to the true testimony of
                                Christ, to declare that Christians never did, and never can, fight, he would have been
                                denounced as a heretic, a traitor, and antichrist, and threatened with forts, prisons
                                and assassination. There was not a priest, nor a paper, to be heard of, that dared to
                                say that God is true, and that Christ is the Prince of Peace. Seeing and knowing these
                                things to be so, I wondered whether God would permit the rising generation to grow up
                                under the teachings of this Balaamitish priesthood, with none to tell them that their
                                preaching was antichristian lies. But, in the darkest hour, " The Shaker " appeared,
                                saying emphatically and truthfully, " Christians never did, never can, fight! " And now
                                I rejoice with joy unspeakable, and have only to add : Go and prove to honest inquirers
                                after truth, that all the Churches that believe in and practise war, are but the "
                                synagogues of Satan," with no shadow of right to name the name of Jesus. This you can
                                readily do, beyond all controversy or cavil, by comparing their practises with the
                                precepts and practise of Jesus, as set forth in the New Testament, in which they all
                                profess to believe. Your friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hacker, Jeremiah" TEIform="persName"/>JEREMIAH HACKER</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We receive requests like the following..." TEIform="index"/>We receive requests like the following...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">We receive requests like the following : " I should like to see some of the internal workings
                            of your Order published in your very excellent paper, if consistent with your rules, etc. I
                            feel satisfied that your mode of life has a purifying tendency, producing a contentment and
                            love that the world knows not of." In this number we shall somewhat minister to this demand.
                            Novitiate experience ofT. Stroud, of Enfield, Connecticut. He thus writes: " December, 1871.
                            On the 6th inst., thinking to confess what I believed to be the last of my bad sins and
                            thoughts, and feeling that, in my own strength, it was impossible — that, indeed, it was
                            like taking my life — I entered into such a labor of prayer as before I had never been able
                            to bring myself to. I knelt, in strong cries to God, was absorbed in intense abstraction ;
                            and there fell upon me a remarkable power, as of a wave of electricity flowing through me.
                            It came and went suddenly, and another succeeded. * * * I went in all earnestness, and
                            confessed in deep humility. At night, a few minutes after retiring to rest, this power
                            returned, filling my muscular system, as though charged from a strong elec- tric battery. I
                            remember that I lay and speculated upon the nature of this spiritual operation. The shocks
                            lasted in full force for two and one-half minutes, and the effects for hours. The charging
                            process commenced in my breast, and proceeded upwards to the top of my head, and downwards
                            to the tips of my fingers and the ends of my toes. " Knowing that there was no visible
                            agency to create electricity, I was forced to the conclusion that it came from an invisible
                            source. But, whether directed by some intelligent beings or agents, under some general law
                            or otherwise, I am unable to determine. It has been often repeated, but always when my mind
                            and feelings have been earnestly engaged in endeavoring to gain power over some evil passion
                            or propensity of my fallen nature."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKERS</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Bradford, A. B." TEIform="persName"/>A. B. Bradford, late Consul to China</byline><p TEIform="p">" A city set upon a hill that cannot be hid." In the valley and along the sides of a mountain
                            which flanks the Hudson River, in Columbia county, New York, dwell the Mount Lebanon Society
                            of Shakers, one of a number of settlements that compose the Shaker Community of the United
                            States. Besides this one, New York has two other settlements ; Massachusetts four ; Maine
                            and New Hampshire each two; Connecticut one; Ohio four, and Kentucky two. Each of these has
                            one or more " Families " — offshoots that branch out from the parent stock, and are helped,
                            by common consent, to independent landed estates. As this remarkable people are almost
                            wholly unknown to us in Pennsylvania, I propose, on this occasion, to give some infor-
                            mation as to their origin, their religious views, their community principles, their econ-
                            omy, by which I mean their mode of living, and any thing else that occurs to my mind of
                            interest to you concerning them. Of course, what I have to say does not purport to be a
                            thorough discussion of a most interesting subject, but only a few items of fact and thought
                            — all the result of a visit I made to Mount Lebanon during last summer. 1. Their origin.
                            When we read Josephus's History of the Antiquities of the Jews, we find that there was a
                            class called Essenes, who, although they make no figure at all in the New Testament history,
                            produced great effect in the Christian Church. These were, no doubt, the prototypes of the
                            Shakers. To this class Jesus of Nazareth belonged; from them he got many of the ideas which
                            he inculcated in his public teachings, and by their rules he regulated himself in regard to
                            a celibate life. If any one will make himself acquainted with the history of the Essenes, he
                            will find it hard to discover in their system any thing to criticise, unless it should be on
                            the subject of marriage. For while they allowed marriage to be a good thing for those who
                            occupied a lower plane of spirituality, for themselves," they neither married nor gave in
                            marriage, but were as the angels of God in Heaven." A second class of Essenes, to meet the
                            obvious objection that the race would run out on their principle of celibacy, did practise
                            marriage; but it was the marriage of love, not lust. It was to provide offspring that should
                            be strong to bear the responsibilities of human life. Truth is the daughter of Time ; and
                            Time goes long with child. These embryonic ideas of the Essenes, and some other wise people
                            among the Greeks, two thousand years ago, in regard to the right method of propagating the
                            race of human beings with a view to their improvement, have come to the birth in our day. We
                            have now college professors who have discovered at last the old secret, that the same laws
                            for improving the lower order of animals, if applied rigidly and scientifically to the human
                            species, would, in due time, make it certain that every child born, being sent for, and not
                            coming by chance, would come into the world beautiful in person, intelligent in mind, happy
                            in disposition, and good in character. I live, I shall die, in the hope that, in a century
                            or so, if the world preserves its peace, and gives science and religion a fair chance to
                            solve their problems, that the human race, in the four respects I have named, will not
                            occupy the low plane we now do, but when every mother's son shall enjoy the inheritance he
                            is entitled to by virtue of his human origin. The Shakers then, whether they intended it or
                            not, are, I think, a reproduction in our age of the severe morality and heroic life of the
                            primitive order of the Essenes, one of whose chief characteristics was celibacy, and to
                            which order Jesiis of Nazareth belonged. 2. Their Religious Views — Mother Ann. As science
                            reveals to us the magnitude of the universe, and the comparative nothingness of the planet
                            which forms our dwelling place, the mind is oppressed with the thought that the individual
                            may be overlooked by the Almighty Father in the care He exercises for the whole. Hence it is
                            natural for every child to love its mother best, since the mother, by her watchfulness,
                            knows and cares for the small and multifarious needs of her offspring. So, the human soul,
                            when on the one side it speculates like an angel concerning God ; on the other, brings its
                            human wants and weaknesses with it, and longs to find in the Divine character the maternal
                            idea. The Jewish Psalmist expresses the feeling which every properly-developed man evinces,
                            who takes an outlook upon the vastness of the universe, when he exclaims, " As the hart
                            panteth after the water brook, so panteth my soul after Thee, Oh God." Theodore Parker, in
                            those wonderful prayers he offered in the beginning of his religious services in Boston,
                            seemed to regard God as Dual — as possessing the peculiar love of a mother for her child, as
                            well as that of a father; and therefore with great reverence, yet with the deepest filial
                            feeling, and with a marked effect upon his audience, addressed God as a dear Father and
                            Mother, If this childlike trait of character is developed as men become spiritual, it is not
                            difficult to see that, whereas the Shakers regard Jesus as a Divine Prophet, and believe in
                            his mission, yet, to meet their conception of the dual character of God — to satisfy the
                            longing for a mother's love, which all men feel when they think of their loneliness in the
                            great universe, they should accept Mother Ann Lee as an avatar of the Christian economy, as
                            Buddha was in the Brahminical, and as Mohammed was among his countrymen, and that they
                            should yield her honor and reverence. According to the old ideas, that ruled the world until
                            astronomy and geology corrected them, man was the center of the universe. For him alone the
                            sun shone by day, and the moon gave her light by night, and the stars of heaven twinkled in
                            the firmament, and the seasons rolled around, giving the beautiful alternation of summer and
                            winter. But now we see that man, glorious as he is in intellect, and more glorious as he is
                            yet to be in the future, is only an incident in the vast creation — that he has come up from
                            a low origin to his present place by the great law of evolution, which is to carry him
                            onward <pb n="11" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> 8HAKEEE88. 11 gfcill in his grand career. But we must pay the
                            price of every thing we have, and if we glory in the results of scientific research, and are
                            proud to know what the telescope and the spectroscope have revealed of the magnitude and
                            composition of the universe, we must experience a reaction and feel oppressed and
                            discouraged at the comparative nothingness of the world we inhabit, and the ephemeral
                            duration of the generations of man, as one appears upon the stage to-day, and tomorrow
                            passes away into the oblivion of eternity. If, then, science, from a material point of
                            observation, represents man as a lonely orphan, calling for his father and mother, from a
                            moral point of view, and on a level which the multitude have not reached, but which has been
                            attained only by the spiritually minded, it may represent the dual nature of God, and meet
                            the desire we all feel for a mother's sympathy and love, as well as a father's care For
                            reasons such as these, probably, the Shakers have an uncommon reverence for woman as such.
                            In all their affairs of government and advice she is the equal of man. Her desire and right
                            to lead a celibate life are religiously respected and protected, and although the tongue of
                            slander, as might be expected, has in some cases vilified the Community, there is no person
                            who has made himself acquainted with them that for a moment suspects any thing against their
                            character on this score. The grand idea in their religion, to which all the rest is
                            auxiliary, is, that for them, as true believers, making Jesus their model, a celibate life
                            is the highest Christian attainment. To carry out this idea as an end, they use, as means,
                            simple diet, constant, but not exhaustive labor, natural periods of rest, freedom from
                            worldly associations, the most perfect cleanliness of person, and of all their surroundings
                            ; in short every thing that will enable them to maintain purity in heart, speech and
                            behavior. In noticing the com- plete victory which strong men and beautiful women have
                            achieved over what they call the generative lusts of the flesh, I could not help saying to
                            myself, give me this stern unbending principle, this lofty, organized devotion to an idea,
                            and let me infuse it into an army of a hundred thousand men, and I could conquer the world !
                            Away then with the sneering suspicion that the continence of the Shakers is only an outside
                            show, and that human nature is too strong for such restraints. The religious instinct is a
                            part of human nature, and it can control all the rest. The history of monks and nuns, of
                            anchorites and flagellants, proves that when men and women really feel an act of
                            self-sacrifice to be a duty, they can accomplish it; for the will is controlled by the
                            strongest motive, and it is the prerogative of the human soul to pause in the moment of
                            temptation and call into its presence all the opposing motives, and thus stand strong in its
                            integrity of purpose. Some of us affect to pity the Shakers, in their retirement from the
                            world and their cir- cumscribed limits of enjoyment, and practise of a celibate life. But
                            they don't thank us for our pity. The principle of compensation comes to their aid, and when
                            they compare the miseries of the world with what the world calls their privations, they are
                            more than thankful for their quiet and happy homes. How little do people dream, when, in our
                            present type of civilization, they see thousands of men and women swirling around in the
                            vortex of temptation, and going down, the victims of vice and of overwork, that there is a
                            sweet home among the Shakers where temptation is comparatively unknown; where vice is a
                            stranger; where contentment and plenty reigns; and where what shall we eat 1 what shall we
                            drink ? wherewithal shall we be clothed ? — those three questions that produce the eternal
                            moil and turmoil of the world, and keep up the courts of law, and fill the penitentiaries
                            with victims, never harass a single soul! Some, indeed, sickened with the emptiness and
                            heartlessness of society, strike their sails and heave their anchors when, on the voyage of
                            life, they approach this haven of rest. Others wish to introduce their children there, if
                            they cannot go themselves. One New York lady has three daughters at Mount Lebanon, all
                            endowed with beauty and talent, and their education is conducted by the best of teachers, in
                            one of the best and most thorough schools I ever knew. 3. The Shakers are all Spiritualists.
                            Before the Rochester knockings, the fame of which has become world wide, these people
                            claimed to hold communication with departed spirits. In this, except among the followers of
                            Swedenborg, they were alone among the churches. I have often wondered at this fact; for the
                            first article in the creed of all the Protestant churches is the dogma of the plenary
                            inspiration of the whole Bible ; and both the Old Testament and the New clearly teach that
                            living men may hold converse with the dead; in other words, that the dead have only departed
                            from our sight by assuming the spiritual body of the resurrection ; that they still live,
                            still take cognizance of us, and sympathize with us, and afford us help and comfort. This is
                            as clearly taught as human language can teach it in the Scriptures, and especially in the
                            recorded interview which King Saul had, through the woman of Endor, with the departed
                            Prophet Samuel, in 1 Samuel, 28th chapter. The record states that Samuel actually appeared
                            to the king, and announced to him the issue of the battle which was to be fought next day.
                            Whoever reads the passage attentively will see that clairvoyance was then practised; that
                            mediumship was the connecting link between the two worlds, and that when conditions were
                            favorable, it was possible for those in this world to receive truthful communications from
                            those in the world of spirits. This passage of Scripture history was robbed of its meaning
                            by M. Henry, the commentator, who said it was not Samuel who appeared to Saul, but the devil
                            personating Samuel. We, however, live in a day when the ipse dixit of a clergyman will not
                            overrule both facts and philosophy, and this passage stands as it was written With all their
                            reverence for the Bible, the Shakers do not regard it as a final revelation, teaching for
                            good and all what we are to believe concerning God, and what duty God requires of man. They
                            do not believe that God, as a Father, has forsaken His children upon the earth, leaving
                            behind Him only a composite book, made up of sixty-six tracts, which have been exposed for
                            centuries to interpolations and alterations that have given birth to all the jangling creeds
                            of Christendom, and that are known even in their present condition to but only a small
                            portion comparatively of the human race. On the contrary, they believe that Heaven still
                            vouchsafes its revelations of truth and duty to mankind everywhere, as in the olden time,
                            when men went to " inquire of the Lord." They think that God commissions his angels and the
                            glorified spirits of just men to give to mortals who, on the high plane of holy
                            consecration, keep their minds in a state of receptivity, that knowledge of the present and
                            the future, and that sense of duty which all men feel to be so desirable. When, therefore,
                            our age was surprised by what was believed to be communications from the spirit world, it
                            was nothing new to the Shakers, who, in their retired position from the busy world, were
                            familiar with the idea. This explains the sympathy which everywhere prevails among the
                            Shakers and the Spiritualists, and which, on this one subject, forms a bond of union between
                            them. — Beaver (Pa.) Madical.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Non-originality" TEIform="index"/>NON-ORIGINALITY</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Prescott, J. S." TEIform="persName"/>J. S. Prescott</byline><p TEIform="p">" There is a divinity which shapes our ends, Rough-hew them as we may." Man did not originate
                            himself, and therefore cannot comprehend his own existence. Solomon, who was wiser in his
                            generation than many others, said that there was " nothing new under the sun." An apostle
                            said, " Since the fathers fell asleep, all things continue as they were from the beginning.
                            The history of the world to-day is " history repeating itself." Jesus, the author of
                            primitive Christianity, did not claim to be the originator or source of truth, because truth
                            existed before him. He said, " To this end was I born, to bear witness unto the truth." This
                            was his peculiar mission, and in the execution of it, although violently opposed, he proved
                            his fidelity and faithfulness, his steadfastness and integrity, to that degree that he was
                            called " the faithful and true witness." His memorable sermon on the Mount, containing the "
                            golden rule," which meets with a hearty response in every man's breast, was not original
                            with him, but was one ot the maxims of Confucius, a Chinese philosopher, who lived long
                            before him. Then where was the originality ? Not with Jesus, nor with Confucius, but with
                            God. For the principle existed in the creation of man, and was worthy of being handed down
                            to the latest posterity. When Columbus discovered America, it was called a "new world," but
                            such was not the fact. America was as old as any other part of the globe — it was new only
                            to those who discovered it, and on this right of discovery the King of England based his
                            claim to give charters to English emigrants to lands belonging to the Indians, who were then
                            the original inhabitants and proprietors of America. William Penn called in question the
                            justice of the King's claim, and argued the point with him at some length, in which he
                            obtained the victory of " right over might." The facts are that the English crown was
                            largely in debt to the Penn family, and King Charles proposed to liquidate those " old
                            claims " by ceding vast territories, three thousand miles away, be- longing to the North
                            American Indians. Penn accepted the payment, after first proving to the king that he had no
                            more moral or legal right'to the lands thus proposed to be ceded or chartered, than the
                            American Indians had to the island of England. Penn inquired of the king how he would feel
                            and act if some American Indians, cruising about in some of their big canoes, should
                            discover the little island of Great Britain, and straightway should take formal possession
                            of it, and then proceed to apportion it out as hunting and fishing grounds for their several
                            chiefs. "Zounds," said Charles, "I should think it a great piece of impudence, and would
                            light them with my army and navy—my brave English soldiers and sailors."— Ed. And when Wm.
                            Penn came over to America, before settling a colony himself, he called the natives around
                            him, under the shade of a large tree, and there made a treaty with them, on the most
                            friendly terms, offering them a reasonable compensation for all the land he wished to
                            purchase of them, by which he gained their entire confidence, and secured their friendship.
                            He looked upon them not as savages, but as the legal owners of the soil — as children of the
                            forest—and treated them kindly as such, and they, in return, ever afterward called him "
                            Father Penn," and do the same to this day. This was placing originality where it belonged.
                            The influence of this admirable example of Wm. Penn, and his "Peace Policy " toward the
                            aborigines of our country, is still felt in the old Quaker city of Philadelphia in
                            "brotherly love," and no doubt has more or less influence on the policy of President Grant's
                            administration toward the present races of Indians. If a man writes a history, and records
                            facts, those facts did not originate with the historian — they existed before him — all he
                            had to do was to compile them, and bring them up to the surface in book form, and bear
                            witness to the truth of them. The Bible is held sacred because of the truth it contains; but
                            the truth itself did not originate with the Bible, nor with the compilers of it ; it existed
                            before either of them. Then, where was the originality? Not with the Bible, nor with man,
                            nor with the Son of Man, but with God. So it is with the revelations given in our day. If
                            there is any truth in those revela<pb n="12" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 12 8HA.KEH A.ND tions, that truth did
                            not originate with man nor with woman, but with God. All that mortals can claim as to
                            originality is their mediumship — being called to bear witness to the truth revealed — and
                            if they fail to do this, they fail to fulfil their high and holy calling. " Ye are my
                            witnesses, saith the Lord." It is now generally admitted that God is dual — Father and
                            Mother — that these divine attributes do exist in the Deity, and have always existed, from
                            time immemorial, yea, "from everlasting;" that the dispensation under which we live is
                            emphatically the Reign of the Eternal Father and Mother principles; hence, mercy is mingled
                            with judgment. Truth is applicable to both sexes, it being both male and female —
                            self-existent— hence it is written, "As for the truth, it endureth and is always strong; it
                            liveth and conquereth forevermore. With her there is no accepting of persons or rewards; but
                            she doeth the things that are just, and refraineth from all unjust and wicked things, and
                            all men do well like of her works." " Neither in her judgment is any unrighteousness ; and
                            she is the strength, kingdom, power and majesty of all ages. Blessed be the God of truth.
                            And with that he held His peace. And all the people then shouted and said, ' Great is truth,
                            and mighty above all things.'" " True to Thee, my God, forever, True unto Thy word and way,
                            I will stand, and no affliction E'er shall turn my heart astray. Deep within my soul are
                            anchor'd Faith, and hope, and love divine, And my early vows to serve Thee Hold me, hold me
                            ever Thine."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ a communist" TEIform="index"/>CHRIST A COMMUNIST</head><byline TEIform="byline"> By <persName reg="Pratt, William A." TEIform="persName"/>William A. Pratt</byline><p TEIform="p">Communism is denounced by Christians as opposed to the spirit of their religion. That it is
                            opposed to the egotism and self-righteousness that is so marked a trait among those who
                            style themselves Christians, cannot be denied; but it ia not opposed to Christ's teachings.
                            The recorded sayings and doings of that religious hero show every where a communistic
                            spirit, and it is reasonable to suppose that what is unrecorded partook in a greater degree
                            of that same spirit, for biographers are prone to conceal the more unpopular qualities of
                            their heroes. The kingdom of heaven, so often spoken of by him, instead of being construed
                            into a mysterious spirit home for a select few, 1 believe can be understood better in a
                            common-sense way — to have reference to an ideal earthly home of a communistic nature which
                            he lioped to institute as a home for his followers; a home into which no man could enter
                            unless he was born again, or in other words until he became dead to the customs and
                            conventionalities of society as it now is and became like a little child again with a mind
                            more impressible to natural habits; a home into which he said it was hard for a rich man to
                            enter, doubtless for the same reason that it is hard to get rich men in our day to enter a
                            community on account of their selfishness; a home where, if treasures were deposited, no
                            fears need be entertained of their destruction by moths and rust, for in such a home every
                            thing will be utilized for the good of all, and nothing hoarded up for the gratification of
                            a selfish few, where thieves could not exist, for every thing would be common property, and
                            where there would be no distinctions of age, rank, or sex. . The Golden Rule, enjoined by
                            Christ upon his followers, contains the essence of all his religious teachings, but it is
                            not practicable outside of a community. An individual, adhering to that rule in the present
                            homogeneous state of society, is like a sheep among wolves and must certainly be devoured.
                            The first Church instituted by Christ's immediate followers, was a community, moulded,
                            doubtless, after the fashion of that which they had so often heard described from the lips
                            of their master. Let sectarians denounce, then, as they will, our communistic theories; they
                            know not what they do, and therefore should be forgiven. Did they read the Scriptures with
                            their own instead of dead men's eyes, they would see that to be a true follower of Christ is
                            to be a communist.— The Communist.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit communication" TEIform="index"/>SPIRIT COMMUNICATION</head><p TEIform="p">Aurora, N. J., Aug. 14, 1872. To Dr. G.Haskell: "Spirit Child: Through the Divine assist-
                            ance of spirits from higher spheres than the material plane of life, I have been permitted
                            to come here and communicate a few thoughts expressive of my views of the Resurrectionlife
                            of the Shaker Institution — as we view it, another and higher plane of spiritual existence
                            than the animal, sexual or social plane in the external life. In this you are educated that
                            a life of trtie sexual moral purity, or womanly virtue, is the only road that leads to true
                            happiness — the happiness that leads through the endless spheres of present and future
                            spiritual existence. As the happiness of the future depends upon the life of the present,
                            you know what your early instructions were. The principles taught by true Quaker Friends do
                            not differ so widely from the Shakers as do those of the world. " As these were the
                            principles you were taught when a child, and the principles imbibed and practiced till you
                            arrived at mature age, what I would here express is my thanks to the good Father of all
                            life, animate and inanimate, that the Shakers have an existence in the land. I consider it
                            the saving Institution of the age. In it is cultivated true spirituality and strict
                            morality, and all the higher affectional elements of the nature of the individual are
                            cultivated in the highest, grandest and broadest fraternal sense; the Fatherhood of God, the
                            Motherhood of Nature, and the Brotherhood and Sisterhood of all Humanity's children, as they
                            become quickened in spirit, resurrected from a life in the flesh — that more glorious
                            Resurrection-life of the Spirit. Hoping this will reach you, and thanking the friends for
                            giving me this opportunity of communicating to you, I am yours in spirit,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barry, Ruth" TEIform="persName"/>Ruth Barry To F W. Evans and Antoinette Doolittle.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trinity duality" TEIform="index"/>TRINITY DUALITY</head><p TEIform="p">A Trinity is an innovation upon the theology of the human race. All mankind — from the most
                            enlightened nations and classes down to the most benighted heathens — believed in the
                            duality of the Deity until the creation of the Trinity by antichrist. However distorted
                            their views of the character of the Supreme Being might be, this one truth, that God was
                            Male and Female, still remained to them. It is an axiom even with the Chinese phi-
                            losophers, that the world was created by the male and female principles. It remained for the
                            smoke from the bottomless pit of antichristian, sin, ignorance and spiritual darkness to
                            becloud and obscure this most beautiful, simple and self-evident of all truths. Mosheim, in
                            his "Ecclesiastical History," says, that " Theophilus, Bishop of Antioch, was the first who
                            ever made use of the word Trinity to express the distinction of what divines call persons in
                            the Godhead." And Maclaine saith: "The Christian Church is very little obliged to him for
                            his invention. The use of this and other unscriptural terms, to which men attach either no
                            ideas at all, or false ones, has wounded charity and peace without promoting truth and
                            knowledge. It has produced heresies of the very worst kind." Mosheim continues : " There
                            were deplorable divisions kindled, throughout the Christian world, on the subject of three
                            persons in the Godhead. So that the Emperor Constantine, seeing the flames of controversy
                            daily spreading through the empire, called the Council ot Nice to settle the question. At
                            this council the Emperor — the great ' infallible' head of the Church — took one side, and,
                            five months after, changed to the other; and the Trinity became an orthodox doctrine by vote
                            and by authority." And thus men have worshipped, and still worship, a triune monster, having
                            no existence, and whose "likeness" or "image" does not exist, and therefore cannot be
                            "clearly seen" in any part of the universe of God, visible or invisible. All the religious
                            sentiments of the ancients, whether written or oral, attest the principle of male and female
                            in Deity. Not only do the Gentile records universally confirm this fact, but in the Hebrew
                            writings and Scriptures also the same truth is maintained.</p><byline TEIform="byline"> —<persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Ed.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Celibacy and longevity" TEIform="index"/>CELIBACY AND LONGEVITY</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Bushnell, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>Elder Richard Bushnell</byline><p TEIform="p">Now in his 82d year. A brother whom I esteem as one of the best men now living upon the
                            earth. — Ed. It has often been stated, by physicians and others, that a married life is more
                            conducive to longevity than an unmarried life. Now, if the term unmarried, is meant to
                            include all such as are not joined in lawful wedlock, no doubt the statement may be true.
                            For, of both sexes there are vast numbers whose lives are incompatible with decent modesty,
                            and much more so with a life of chastity and virgin purity. But, as it regards a life of
                            entire abstinence from sexual commerce, or carnal indulgence of any name or nature, I think
                            the following will disprove the above statement: In the society at Mount Lebanon, within
                            about ten years, there have deceased, of male and female members, 36, whose united ages
                            average over 86 years. The great majority of them came into the society in their youth, and
                            lived a virgin life, agreeable to the faith and principles of Believers. And there are now
                            living in the Society four members, who came in their youth (under twenty years of age) one
                            of whom is now in the 102d year of her age; another over 98; and two in their 92d year;
                            also, about ten or twelve more, whose ages are between 80 and 90 years. Most of them united
                            with the society at an early period of their lives. See also our report (on page 45 of the
                            June No. for 1871) of a family of ten —eight males and two females — all of whom but one,
                            who is now living and in his 95th year, died among Believers. Their respective names and
                            ages, (which average near 63 years) are given as above.—Exchanges, please copy.</p></div2><pb n="13" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: Paul and the bishops" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: PAUL AND THE BISHOPS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">When the bishops of Rome, in solemn conclave, decided that they were sole arbiters of
                            theological truth (an erudite historian asserts they almost conceived they were Deity
                            itself), and created an imaginary Triune God for man to worship, did they not falsify the
                            declaration of the inspired Apostle Paul, who testified that " the invisible things of Hiru,
                            from the creation of the world, are clearly seen, being understood by the things that are
                            made, even his eternal power and Godhead ? " Monstrosities do not proceed from Deity.
                            Creative forces are orderly, and they form and produce their kind. The creation is a reflex
                            of the Creator. If we pass through thewhole realm of the natural, which is a correspondence
                            of the spiritual, where shall we find the likeness of a Triune God — three male beings
                            conjoined in one ? Do we not see the dual principle, positive and negative, male and female,
                            manifest in all of God's creation, from man, the apex, down through all grades of animal
                            life, continuing to the vegetable and mineral kingdoms? Can we marvel that the imaginary
                            Trinity in the heavens should be reflected upon the earth, and a duplicate be formed here ?
                            The ruling power on the earth, at the present time, is a trinity of doctors of divinity,
                            civil law, and physic. Through the God Trinity, which man has formed for man to worship, the
                            sun " of Divine revelation has been darkened, and the moon (ruling earthly governments)
                            turned to blood;" and through the power and influence of the trinity of doctors, the war
                            spirit has ruled. Doctors of divinity have invoked the blessing of the Holy Trinity upon the
                            deadly weapons of war, and the doctors of law, through the power vested in them, have forced
                            fathers, brothers, and sons, to leave all that was dear to them on earth, and enter the
                            ranks of those who were marching to the gory battle field, there to face the cannon's mouth;
                            while the doctors of physic followed in their wake, ready to amputate shattered limbs, and
                            bear the bleeding and dying to hospitals or to the grave. But thanks are due from many
                            hearts, that, in the fullness of time, the light of divine revelation has pierced the dark
                            clouds which, through a false theology, have for centuries been gathering over Christendom.
                            Now the cloud is lifted, and we see a Heavenly Father and Mother, instead of three male Gods
                            in one. We have caught a glimpse of the true dual God, full of wisdom and love, and begin to
                            understand the mission of the Christ Spirit manifest through earthen vessels. The angels who
                            came to Jesus and Ann, and ministered to them, always sang the song of peace and good will.
                            The spirit and element of war can never enter the inner spiritual Christ heavens ; nor go
                            beyond the world's trinity of gods. And 0 how joyful we feel in believing in a Heavenly
                            Mother ! Children in nature love and revere their father, who provides for them; but who can
                            understand and feel their needs, and supply them, like a true mother ? Her ears are ever
                            open to their cries; and, when in distress, she gathers them to her bosom. No longer do we
                            remain in a semiorphan condition, having a Father in the interior heavens, without a loving
                            Mother. And, as this beautiful truth shall come to be more generally recognized and
                            acknowledged, their dual likeness will manifest itself in the outward governments; and in
                            the various relations of life, woman will occupy her proper sphere, and all will eventually
                            see that the visible creation is an outgrowth from the invisible, and that it is God's
                            purpose that we should all progress from inharmonies into the beautiful, good, and true.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Is woman a slave?" TEIform="index"/>IS WOMAN A SLAVE?</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Webster, E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. Webster</byline><p TEIform="p">John Stuart Mill says, " The law of servitude in marriage is a monstrous contradiction to all
                            the principles of the modern world, and to all the experience through which these prin-
                            ciples have been slowly and painfully worked out. Marriage is the only actual bondage known
                            to our law. There remains no legal slaves, except the mistress of every house." Strong,
                            brave words! but are they true ? Paul said, "The wife hath not power of her own body, but
                            the husband." If she has not possession of her own body, and is in subjection by the law to
                            the will of her husband, who, though exhorted to be her saviour and deliverer as Christ is
                            of the Church, we fear that the charge must be admitted. Paul gives, as the occasion of this
                            servitude, that, although " man was first formed, woman was first in transgression ; and if
                            it were any more excusable in man to sin in consequence of the seduction of the woman "whom
                            the Lord had given him for a helpmeet," than it was in her to yield to the serpentine nature
                            which allured her, he certainly has the case. The consequences resulting seem evidence that
                            her part and lot was exceedingly sorrowful. " Thy desire shall be to thy husband and he
                            shall rule over thee." A condition of freedom was prophesied of in the forty-fifth Psalm,
                            under the figure of one who is called to leave her father's house and all her kindred. " The
                            king's daughter is all glorious within." She, as well as the virgins, her companions, who
                            follow her, accept the heavenly Bridegroom, instead of any earthly marriage, and serve Him
                            with gladness and rejoicing. Jesus who was most emphatically woman's friend and Saviour,
                            alluded to her sad condition when speaking of the weeping women who followed him: "
                            Daughters of Jerusalem, weep not for me, but weep for yourselves, and for your children; for
                            behold the days are coming in which they shall say,' Blessed are the barren,' " etc. " THE
                            TRUTH SHALL MAKE YOU FREE." His new manner of life broke the spell of slavery for all who
                            would live it, whether Jew or Gentile, male or female, bond or free, and they could
                            henceforth "serve the Lord day and night in his temple." " Ye are the temples of the living
                            God." " The temple of God is holy, which temple ye are." " Ye are bought with a price, be
                            not ye the servants of men." BE WITHOUT ANXIOUS CARE. Searching and critical as is their
                            meaning, we find a whole volume of tender and pathetic teaching in those simple words of
                            Jesus to Martha, when troubled, that Mary was not more active with her in temporal care and
                            ministrations, " Mary hath chosen that good part, which shall not be taken away from her." "
                            Martha, thou art careful and troubled about many things, but one thing is needful." He did
                            not directly say that her burdens were unnecessary; but the inference is fair, that he
                            considered them not more needful than the one which held Mary a learner at his feet. From
                            his lips such teachings as these are often found among his utterances: " Seek first the
                            kingdom of heaven and its righteousness, and all needful things shall be added," etc. So to
                            the multitude of women to whom life is more a season of anxious care : " What shall we eat,
                            and wherewithal shall we be clothed ?" do not the words of Jesus most fittingly apply ? "
                            Thou art anxious and careful for many things;" but there is something more of life than
                            these; there is something more necessary, the neglect of which can never be compensated with
                            any earthly gain. How we belie our profession, and trail it in the mire of earthliness, when
                            we subordinate the higher, the spiritual and eternal to the sordid and earthly ; and is it
                            any marvel that with such a maimed and distorted Christianity, earth still groans under the
                            slavery of sin ? In what church or home would the lowly Nazarene be recognized, could he
                            return ? "Careful and anxious about many things!" but not of the one thing needful. Careful
                            that the body be well fed, and clothed, and housed ! Careful that the latest style be
                            faithfully adopted, and the outward fair and irreproachable; but not equally careful that
                            the soul be growing beautiful in the sight of angels and the pure in heart. The Martha and
                            Mary type may still be found on the earth. The one too material and engrossed in the
                            carking, consuming cares of life to heed the beatific vision, which still whispers to her in
                            every lull of worldliness ; the other too exclusively spiritual. To our mind nothing shows
                            more plainly the subjection of woman than her voluntary slavery to dress. Whether it be to
                            please a husband, or to secure one, it matters not; the slavery is there, and obliges her to
                            sacrifice health, conscience and gleams of purity and holiness which have flitted by all
                            souls who have had any comprehension of Christly profession and imitation. " Marvel not that
                            I said unto you, Ye must be born again." Strange, yet sublimely rudimental, transforming you
                            from the earthly into the spiritual. One badge or sign of your freedom, or servitude, is the
                            dress you wear. If it is fitly symbolized by the " white raiment pure and clean." modest and
                            useful apparel, though mocked at by the worldly, it may prove you to be in possession of the
                            principles and integrity which will yield you a solace and joy such as can be found in the
                            banquet halls of none but those who are truly married to the Lamb. Man is more free; but,
                            while showing most deeply the contamination consequent on having a burden-bearer at hand,
                            instead of a companion, he has suffered far less than woman in many things. He has had the
                            hardihood, after years of tinsel and ruffles, to discard them all for a more suitable, warm,
                            and convenient clothing, while woman, hampered with confining skirts, shriveled and squeezed
                            with pain producing ligatures, is so deformed that one would never imagine her part of that
                            humanity that was " created upright." Submitting to fashion, which she despises, and which
                            the better part of men also despise, but have not the strength to<pb n="14" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 14:
                            8HAKEE AND lift her above (for who would be seen with a plain or unfashionably-clad female
                            friend), evidences her weakness and imbecility. From whence, then, is to come woman's
                            rescuerand freer? Christ did it, when, in the person of" Paul, he declared that in Him "
                            there was neither bond nor free, male nor female," etc. Christ did it again in every woman,
                            who, like Mary, dared to learn Christly principles. Christ did it in Ann Lee, who ground the
                            head of the serpentine nature in herself, and taught her followers to do the same. And those
                            only become most truly free who thus gain the victory over themselves, and become redeemed
                            from the earth. " Stand fast, therefore, in the liberty wherewith Christ hath made us free,
                            and be not entangled again with the yoke of bondage." —Harvard, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Work of the present" TEIform="index"/>WORK OF THE PRESENT</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna White</byline><p TEIform="p">Time, with hour-glass in hand, marches on with great rapidity; none can stay its progress.
                            Science has kept pace with time as it passed, and has brought forth many inventions, through
                            which great results are produced. Telegraphic wires now almost belt the earth from pole to
                            pole, and bear hourly tidings of weal or woe from continent to continent. One nation can
                            commune with others beyond the isles of the sea; and friends can greet friends with kindly
                            salutations in an almost incredibly short space of time. Fleet vessels,, impelled across
                            oceans and seas by the power of steam, like so many floating palaces upon old Neptune's
                            broad expanse, all bespeak the growth of ages. Modern inventions may compete with this
                            honored sire — Time — in swiftness ; but are not more constant and steady in their flight
                            than are the " sands of life " as they fall from Time's measured glass. And, as we are borne
                            along on life's journey, eternity opens her pearly gates to our mental vision; and, as
                            immortal beings we peer out into the unknown future, as before us it rises in grandeur and
                            beauty. We sing of the "better land," where brothers and sisters will " meet to part no
                            more." Very few profess to believe that the partial, selfish relations of the generative
                            order will be recognized there; but all seem to think that, by some metaphysical process,
                            parents and children, husbands and wives, etc., will be changed into angels, and that G-od
                            will show particular favor to them; and that families from the earth-sphere will be
                            re-united in heaven. But, may it not be asked : what makes that land, to which we are all
                            hastening, the letter land t Is it the place, or the changed condition of individuals, that
                            will augment their happiness ? If it depend upon changed conditions, cannot that change, by
                            some means, be effected now ? and thus produce the ability to sing and speak of the good
                            time that has already com,e, in the present ? Is there not too much indulgence in ideal
                            dreams of the future, to the neglect of present duty, or failure to comprehend it ? Would it
                            not be better to cast about, and see if there cannot be found an existing order on the earth
                            where the will of God is done, "as it is done in heaven ? " and, if not successful in
                            finding it, why not make individual efforts to establish such an order of things? Is the
                            price too great ? Would it require too much self-sacrifice ? Or, is it more convenient to
                            wait until compelled by what is termed death t G-od loves the cheerful giver; and he will
                            not fail to reward all who will diligently seek him, and make willing sacrifices to promote
                            his cause. If this were done, then would our eternal parents be honored; and every such one
                            would be a blessing to humanity; and would be able to render due praise to the past; to
                            revere the good and true, and reject the false ; and to sacredly hold to all the treasures
                            of wisdom and knowledge, which have come down to us as an inheritance. Thus should we all
                            live in the present, doing the work of our own time properly and profitably, receiving
                            beautiful inspirations of the Spirit to aid us ; and should be fully prepared for the great
                            future, in which we hopefully expect to wear the laurels that we have justly earned. So we
                            will say: " Let time continue its march, hour-glass in hand." We would not lessen its speed;
                            and there will be no cause of regret, if every duty is well done. — Mt. Lebanon.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To youth" TEIform="index"/>TO YOUTH</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Osbourne, Lucy J." TEIform="persName"/>Lucy J. Osborne</byline><p TEIform="p">While perusing the November number of The Shaker, my attention was particularly drawn to the
                            article headed " Angel Eyes are Upon Us," and to the beautiful poem appended thereto,
                            entitled " We are Seen." Those sentiments appeal so directly to the conscience, that it
                            seems to me they cannot fail to awaken thoughtful considerations in every reflective mind,
                            and I felt an ardent desire that all youthful readers, whose eyes might trace those
                            impressive lines, should feel the great necessity of " applying their hearts unto wisdom,"
                            and of remembering that youth is the time to form a good character, and so lay a foundation
                            for future usefulness and happiness, which can be done only by self-culture. And if youth
                            and children could be impressed with the allimportant truth that "God is Light," and that
                            their every action is open to the inspection of angels, and must eventually be brought into
                            judgment, would it not be a powerful inducement to many to speak the truth, and to live more
                            innocently ? And would it not lead them to honor their parents and guardians, by obeying
                            their counsels, thus fitting them to become useful and ornamental members of society ? Many
                            temptations beset the youthful mind, and if all could be impressed with the simple truth,
                            that it is far more noble to acknowledge a fault than to dissemble, and seek to hide it, how
                            much trouble of mind and remorse of conscience it would save. I earnestly and affectionately
                            exhort my young friends to lay aside all that vain and foolish pride which would hinder them
                            from confessing their faults. Remember that " God is Love," as well as Light. He is merciful
                            and forgiving, and all souls belong to him. He is not a respecter of persons, but of
                            character; and his love flows to all repentant hearts, whether in savage or civilized
                            nations — in the palace or the humble cottage. Let us trust in Truth; there is strength and
                            beauty in it. Let it be our motto, and it will prove an unfailing friend to both aged and
                            youth, in sickness and health, in life and in death. — Hancock, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hannibal, Missouri, November 16, 1872" TEIform="index"/>Hannibal, Mo., November 16,1872</head><p TEIform="p">Bear Brother Frederick: Please accept my thanks, and the fifty cents for " The Shaker "
                            another year. I would not be without it for twice its price. Its sweet influence comes to me
                            like angel whispers from that better land, cheering me along the sad and lonely way of life.
                            O when may I join those " brave conquerors," for so you are, who battle with your own
                            affections, and the whole army of the world's desires. God bless you for the good you are
                            exerting. My heart is with you all.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Jenkins, Sylvinia" TEIform="persName"/>Sylvinia Jenkins</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Forgiveness" TEIform="index"/>FORGIVENESS</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Blake, Rhoda" TEIform="persName"/>Rhoda Blake</byline><p TEIform="p">Forgiveness is a lovely grace. Any one who can, in sincerity, say to an enemy, " Thou art
                            forgiven," feels the peace of Heaven. Such possess the spirit of the dying Jesus, when he
                            said "Father forgive them, they know not what they do." But, were the murderous designs of
                            his persecutors changed by his tender words? Did his forbearance destroy their venom, or
                            appease their cruel rage ? Ah, nay; but it was the crown of his own glory, and a lesson for
                            all succeeding generations ! With sorrow, not malice, he viewed their unsubdued passions;
                            and, while they reviled, he was tender and compassionate. The cross which He had borne
                            proved effectual in that hour of trial and need, and he triumphed over that measure of death
                            and hell which compassed his enemies How unlike was the spirit of those persecuting Jews,
                            when compared with the Heavenly Dove spirit which the lovely Jesus possessed, which was
                            genuine forgiving love. This power of forgiving love is gained by self-denial, watchfulness,
                            and prayer, and flows from true principle ; it is not emotional, nor circumstantial, and
                            will not flee the grasp when tried in the furnace of affliction. A. loving, forgiving spirit
                            is not the companion of pride, hatred, and revenge; between them, there is no concord. The
                            Christian spirit teaches love and forgiveness, not merely in word, but in deed, and
                            possesses a healing power. When Jesus, through the anointing of the Christ Spirit which
                            rested upon him, healed the sick, the halt and the blind, of their physical infirmities, his
                            word to them was, " Go and sin no more." And now, the united voice (or word) of the dual
                            Christ Spirit, which administers a healing power to sin sick souls, as well as to diseased
                            bodies, is " Deny self; take up the cross, and bear it; go, and sin no more." In this, "the
                            two anointed ones"—Jesus and Ann — are our exemplars. Jesus, according to Sacred Writ,
                            rejected the tempter when he promised all the kingdoms of the world to him, if he would
                            serve him and bow down to the principles which constitute the world ; but he bade the
                            tempter depart, and bowed his spirit in submission to the will of God. It would appear that
                            the power of forgiveness, depends upon the co-operation of the forgiven, with the for giver.
                            Peter said " How often shall I forgive my brother ? till seven times ? Jesus answered, until
                            seventy times seven." Again, " If thy brother trespass against thee seven times in a day, if
                            he will repent, forgive him." Sinning against humanity, and our own bodies, often arising
                            from ignorance and force of circumstances, can more easily be forgiven, than sin, or
                            rebellion against spiritual, divine light, given to guide and lift the soul into union and
                            communion with God. This is called sinning against the Holy Grhost, or Holy Spirit. Those
                            who thus sin to a great extent, do not often repent so deeply that forgiving love and power
                            can reach them.— Mt. Lebanon.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Promptitude" TEIform="index"/>PROMPTITUDE</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Martha J. Anderson</byline><p TEIform="p">" Delay shortens life, and abridges industry; while promptitude enlarges both." This is an
                            essential element of character, and should be incorporated in every person's code of
                            individual laws, to enable them to properly and profitably perform the work assigned them in
                            life's busy sphere of action. Said one anciently : " To every thing there is a season, and a
                            time for every purpose under heaven." But dilatoriness, and disinclination to labor, allows
                            proper seasons to slip by unimproved, while good purposes are too often frustrated for the
                            want of descisive action at the right moment. There is a competency ot <pb n="15" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/>
                            SHAKBEESS. 15 time for the fulfilment of noble ends and aims, if we rightly improve the
                            present. It is procrastination that breaks the golden threads of life's fair web, and causes
                            us vexation. Like a weird ghost, he haunts the scenes of our daily avocations, and plausibly
                            guarantees a pleasanter time than that which now is for the accomplishment of our allotted
                            duties; but the by-and-by only superadds to accumulated labors; and, when necessity assumes
                            her rule, we are fretted into a state of fevered excitement, and then leave our work but
                            half performed. It is not fitful strokes of zeal That add the most to human weal, But
                            patient labor, hourly wrought, Has wealth amass'd and increase brought. But few persons are
                            habitually prompt; a natural disposition to ease, combined with mental inertia,
                            incapacitates the many for necessary activity, which incites to promptness of action. It is
                            well to be punctual; better to be ready beforehand, meeting appointments, fulfilling
                            agreements in an orderly and punctual manner, keeping pace frontguard of the marching hours.
                            Promptness is a point of culture that all may attain unto by self discipline. Those who are
                            dilatory should feel the just censure which persistent tardiness often incurs from those who
                            know the precious worth of time, and are instant in duty. Some individuals are regularly
                            inattentive to regulations, being a little late on every occasion. If the bell rings at the
                            accustomed hour, it is five or ten minutes too soon for their convenience; if a special call
                            is made for concentration of labor on some extra branch of business, their leisurely
                            movements in preparation leave them in the rear of the active, who are prompt in every
                            motion, evincing an interest to sustain and carry forward to its ultimate any project the
                            intent of which is for mutual benefit. Suah have, for their motive power, determined will.
                            It is just this push-ahead and promptness that completes the thorough business man and
                            woman, gives character and effect to any enterprise, and makes the machinery of life run
                            smoothly. The blacksmith draws the red-hot metal from the glowing furnace, but does he form
                            his model after he has taken the iron from the fire ? Not so; he is ready to strike while
                            yet the heat is luminous, and the material malleable, that he may fashion it according to
                            his will, and the living sparks that fly tell us that to "strike while the iron is hot" is
                            not a meaningless phrase. Here is a lesson for the young, who are now moulding their
                            characters on the anvil of life (for good or evil just as they will it). Now is the time to
                            straighten the crooked places, while there is ardency of purpose and pliancy of will. The
                            hammer of truth is effective in shaping aright; do not delay to use it with wakeful vigor,
                            to the end that you may be fitted for useful and substantial members of society, the
                            healthful condition of which is dependent on the qualification of its members, who should
                            each fulfil their office so perfectly and actively that a glow of health and invigorating
                            life may add to the structure, strength and beauty. Delay has stamped on human acts the
                            blight of misspent time and uncompleted purpose, while magnificent thought-built project
                            towers reel and crumble to the dust for the want of solid foundations, laid in actual labor
                            and experience. 'Tis hands that do and hearts that bear Which lift the burden, lighten care,
                            And give to life an aspect fair In this wide world of ours. So, let us heed each
                            burden-freighted moment that speaks of the blessed "now" to do and bear, that light-winged
                            they may glide into the sunny side of eternity, to smile on our future existence. " We
                            should cultivate that althletic frame of soul which rejoices in abundant occupation, that we
                            may find the sweetness of that repose which follows finished work, and the zest of that
                            recreation in which no delinquent feeling mingles, and on which no neglected duty
                        frowns."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Evolution" TEIform="index"/>EVOLUTION</head><p TEIform="p">It was held, by philosophers, that all worlds were originally projected from their respec-
                            tive suns, and were then in a gaseous nebulous state, owing to the intense heat of those
                            luminaries ; and that, as they cooled, they became planets, and are now gradually
                            condensing, and will continue so to do, until they fall back into their respective suns, to
                            be again projected in the form of gaseous nebula.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prophets" TEIform="index"/>PROPHETS</head><p TEIform="p">By whom were the Prophets inspired ? Or whence came their rythmical song ? That Avators have
                            play'd on their lyres, As they march'd with the ages along ? Was it not by the angelic
                            throng, Who inhabit Eternity's strand, The Christs of the innermost spheres, Who await the
                            Deific command ? The heaven of heavens their home, Where all primal cells were first form'd
                            : By these all creation has come, Have never by evil been storm'd. From thence were the
                            Prophets inspired, ' Mid the races and nations of earth: Prophetesses, too, tuned their
                            lyres, As they sang of the heavenly birth. Pure glory on glory I see, For ever and ever
                            advancing, Rolling on like the billowy sea, With the grandest of music enchanting. To the
                            sun, the bright sun, we ascend, Returning from whence we proceeded; As planets, when roll'd
                            to the end, In oceans of fire are bathed.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Ed.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Analogy" TEIform="index"/>ANALOGY</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Bullard, Marcia M." TEIform="persName"/>Marcia M. Bullard</byline><p TEIform="p">Deak Editkess—Observing in the January number of the " Shaker and Shakeress," an appeal for
                            the Waste Basket, I contribute my mite for the support of this honorary appendage of an
                            editor. While contemplating the beauties of God's work with his creatures from the earliest
                            ages to the present time, I see a beautiful analogy of the past in the present. That work
                            which was foreshadowed in Israel finds its anti-type in Zion. In ancient Israel, animal
                            indulgences were atoned for by animal sacrifices ; thus typifying the present work of God,
                            wherein the animal nature of man and woman is slain, and the inspirational influence of
                            Divine Love lifts the soul above the base desires of that nature, up to a higher plane,
                            illumined by the light oi his countenance. When I look abroad upon the face of the earth,
                            and behold the Spirit of God " moving upon the waters," striving to raise souls from the
                            horrible pit of indulgences, by the many reform movements in operation, I ask, is there one
                            spot on this fair earth, so far redeemed from the blight of sin, that purity can reign
                            supreme ?—a place where woman no longer forms a part of man ; but, as pre-figured in the
                            prophetic allegory of creation, is taken from his side, and made an independent entity,
                            united to him only in works of righteousness, pure love, kindly feelings ?—where the highest
                            aspirations are to form the Angel character, by a total denial of all wrong appetites, and
                            unchaste desires, thus completely ruling over self? And an echo rolls across the troubled
                            waters, from the dual-masted " tiny craft," in answer : There is! and we delight to bear the
                            glad tidings of peace, love and joy in the life of Christ to all people.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To contributors" TEIform="index"/>TO CONTRIBUTORS</head><p TEIform="p">Write, but not unless you have something to say upon some one or more of the Principles of
                            the paper. Having an idea, express it in the fewest words possible, and in the strongest
                            terms at command. We wish to accumulate matter for several numbers of the paper ahead.</p><byline TEIform="byline"> —<persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Ed.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>GONE HOME</head><p TEIform="p">Since last account published in our paper we have the following obituary report:</p><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kimball, Polly" TEIform="index"/>Polly Kimball
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Canterbury, <persName reg="Kimball, Polly" TEIform="persName">Polly Kimball</persName>, aged 94, de-
                                ceased Sept. 5th, 1872. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mead, Stephen H." TEIform="index"/>Stephen H. Mead
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Mead, Stephen H." TEIform="persName">Stephen H. Mead</persName>, aged 13 years, drowned Nov.
                                1872.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lyon, Catharine" TEIform="index"/>Catharine Lyon
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Lyon, Catharine" TEIform="persName">Catharine Lyon</persName>, aged 72, deceased Dec. 9th,
                                1872.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sweet, Dorcus" TEIform="index"/>Dorcus Sweet
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At New Lebanon, <persName reg="Sweet, Dorcus" TEIform="persName">Dorcus Sweet</persName>, aged 39, died Nov.
                                18th, 1872.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="McLean, Mercy" TEIform="index"/>Mercy McLean
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 20th, 1872, <persName reg="McLean, Mercy" TEIform="persName">Mercy McLean</persName>, aged 83
                            years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Youngs, Alexander" TEIform="index"/>Alexander Youngs
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Watervliet, N. Y., <persName reg="Youngs, Alexander" TEIform="persName">Alexander Youngs</persName>,
                                business agent of Second Family, aged 57. His demise is a sad bereavement to this family
                                —deceased Dec. 29th, 1872.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hawkins, Daniel J." TEIform="index"/>Elder Daniel J. Hawkins
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At New Lebanon, <persName reg="Hawkins, Daniel J." TEIform="persName">Elder Daniel J. Hawkins</persName>,
                                deceased Jan. 15th, 1873. He was brought up from infancy in the Gospel of Christ's
                                Second Appearing, was a trustee for about 40 years or more ; at the age of about 81 or
                                82, was appointed leading Elder of South Family, which place he occupied until his
                                demise at the age of 92 years.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth of inward life" TEIform="index"/>TRUTH OF INWARD LIFE</head><p TEIform="p">The truth cannot be compressed into a sermon. The reply to Pilate's question, "What is
                            truth," cannot be contained in any verbal form. Think you that if Christ himself could have
                            answered that question in a certain number of sentences, he would have spent thirty years of
                            life in witnessing to it ? Some men would compress into the limits of one reply, or one
                            discourse, the truth it took Christ thirty years to reach, and left unfinished for the
                            Spirit to complete. The truth is infinite as the firmament above you. In childhood both seem
                            near and measurable; but with years they grow and grow, and seem further off and further,
                            and grander and deeper, and vaster, as God himself; till you smile to remember how you
                            thought you could touch the sky, and blush to recollect the proud and self-sufficient way in
                            which you used to talk of knowing " the truth." Truth is made up of principles ; an inward
                            life, not any formula of words. God's character — spiritual worship ¦— the divine life in
                            the soul. How shall I put that into a sentence, ten or ten thousand? How could Pilate's
                            question be answered except by a life ? The truth, then, which Pilate wanted — which you and
                            I want — is not the boundless verities but truth of inward life. Truth for me ; truth enough
                            to guide me in this darkling world ; enough to teach me how to live, and how to die.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Robertson, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Robertson</byline></div2><pb n="16" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blessings for the faithful" TEIform="index"/>BLESSINGS FOE THE FAITHFUL</head><p TEIform="p"> Enfield, N. H. 1. Saith God, Unto those who keep my way pure, I'll open my fountains above;
                            On those who are faithful, my blessings I'll pour, And comfort their souls with my love 2. A
                            cloud in the day I'll spread o'er my flock ; A pillar of fire, by night, Shall lead them,
                            and show them I am their sure Rock, And they my peculiar delight. I'll be unto them a kind
                            Parent and Friend, And they shall be children of mine; My wings of protection shall o'er
                            them extend, And make them in glory to shine. Then, be not dismay'd nor yet be ye cast down;
                            Tear not, though some trials you meet; But wing your way through to my mansions in heaven:
                            You'll there have a beautiful seat.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lincoln and Stanton" TEIform="index"/>LINCOLN AND STANTON</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Devyr, Cecilia" TEIform="persName"/>Cecilia Devyr</byline><p TEIform="p">Strange was their station, call'd to guide a strife That shook a continent from sea to sea ;
                            To order death along the ranks of life, And wrap in flames the blessings yet to be. 'Twas-
                            their's to speak the word of stern command That gave the inspiration to the hour, As if they
                            knew an earnest spirit-band Sustain'd and aided every human power. They struck with deadly
                            shafts the monstrous crime That fiends had fortified with walls of lies ; They made it feel
                            the weight of judgment time In crimson earth, and more than crimson skies. They made the
                            wrath of man conduce To aid the plans of Wisdom and of Love ; To turn the raging passions
                            into use, They sent the Vulture to precede the Dove. 'Twas their's to make the red-mouth'd
                            cannon speak, And call the warrior to his gory field; And it was their's to screen the low
                            and meek, And be, for God, their guardians and their shield. When storms of fury swept
                            across the land, We sought protection only from on high ; They broke the cloud, to show us
                            Mercy's hand, And bade us on the Nation's heart rely. In faith we prayed that duty might be
                            done; That Freedom might her heritage possess ; That peace and victory, through terrors won,
                            Should " come to stay," and banish all distress. And is not prayer a focalizing power, To
                            draw the fires of truth, to burn the dross ? Ah, well we proved it in that fearful hour When
                            human vision saw but human loss. 'Twas not for party, nor for section proud, That Zion's
                            ardent supplications rose ; But that the land should be with right endow'd, And God should
                            his progressive laws disclose When hung the Proclamation's shining page All
                            bright-triumphant for the world to feel, Then came the spirit of unconquer'd rage, And
                            stamp'd it fiercely with a sable seal; And it became the death-decree of him Who was the
                            instrument of hosts unseen, And then a passport through the valley dim, And through the
                            gates that weighty forces screen. But Prophecy, the child of fervent prayer, Gave Zion light
                            to view a future grand, And bade her faithfully herself prepare To aid the work immortal
                            spirits plann'd. We saw the tears that mingled near and far Wash from that seal the
                            blackness of its face ; And now it beams a brilliant changeless star, The pledge of freedom
                            to an injured race. How gratefully our hearts recall that time ; How place we Btanton close
                            by Lincoln's side Amid his toils, his sacrifice sublime, And 'neath the burdens of whose
                            weight he died. One balmful thought, to which he oft referr'd, And drew its solace round his
                            closing life, Was, that his heart compassionately heard The claims of Zion to be free from
                            strife. Oh, not with hero-worshipers we bend ; But honor give to whom is honor due : Pray
                            God to bless whoe'er will truth defend, While yet perchance " they know not what they do."
                            Mt. Lebanon.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ancient pilgrims" TEIform="index"/>ANCIENT PILGRIMS</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Johnson, Julia" TEIform="persName"/>Julia Johnson</byline><p TEIform="p">Lord, make our spirits whiter— White as the driven snow ; Like to the ancient pilgrims, Who
                            suffer'd here below. Give us a heart that's humble, Touch'd with the martyr's zeal; Clothe
                            us with truth and wisdom, And make pure love our seal. Fill us with thoughts of heaven, Of
                            worthiness, and prayer; And with thine arm, O save us From ev'ry earthly snare. Lead us unto
                            the fountain Whence flows the living streamSweet waters of repentance, Which will the soul
                            redeem. Where bloom the fairest flowers That flourish here below ; Where walk the brightest
                            beings That earth can ever know. O lead us, Holy Spirit, Down in the lowly vale, Where fear
                            and mortal bondage The soul cannot assail; Where tears of sinful sorrow Flood not the pure
                            in heart; Nor sense of earthly yearning, Life's piercing pangs impart. Lord, make our
                            spirits whiter— White as the driven snow; Like to the holy ancients Who conquer'd death
                            below. Hancock, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Independent tract society" TEIform="index"/>INDEPENDENT TRACT SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p">The subject of this society is to counteract the efforts of ecclesiastical despotism, seeking
                            to unite Church and State in the United States. 25 cents means membership. Address A. B.
                            Davis, Clinton, Mass. Why should we not accord to the second Christian dispensation the
                            authority for a revelation of God correcting the theological views of former revelations,
                            since the attainment of absolute truth is a work of progress ? Our credentials are to be
                            found in the work of God itself among us. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. A.</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker and Shakeress. Addresses of the Local Editors and Publishers" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER
                            AND SHAKERESS. Addresses of the Local Editors and Publishers</head><p TEIform="p">Elder F. W. Evans, Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co. N. Y. G. A. Lomas, Albany, N. Y. Shakers. Calvin G.
                            Reed, Sonyea, Living'n Co. N. Y. Simon Mabee, West Pittsfield, Mass. H. S. Kellogg,
                            Thompsonville, Conn. Shakers. Albert Battles, Tyringham, Berkshire Co. Mass. Wm. Leonard,
                            Ayer, Mass. Shakers. Jonas Nutting, Shirley Village, Middlesex Co. Mass. B. H. Smith, Shaker
                            Village, Merrimack Co. N. H. .. Henry Cummings, Enfield, Grafton Co. N. H. .. John B. Vance,
                            Alfred, York Co. Maine Shakers. Nehemiah Trttll, West Gloucester, Cumberland Co. Me.
                            Shakers. Charles Clapp, Union Village, Warren Co. O. Shakers. Ezra [Sherman, Preston,
                            Hamilton Co. Ohio Shakers. Stephen Ball, Dayton, Ohio Shakers. Jacob Kulp, Pleasant Hill,
                            Mercer Co. Ky. J. R. Eades, South Union, Logan Co. Ky. J. S. Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio
                            Shakers.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>