<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2912" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">29</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><date value="18991201" TEIform="date">December 1899</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">177-192</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="29" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                        <pb n="t.p." id="p1"/>
                        THE MANIFESTO 1899. WONDERFUL strange REVELATIONS EXPLAINING DANIEL'S & STJOHNS
                        PROPHECIES. 48 page pamphlet. Price 10 cts. 13 for $1.00. Address, H. B. Beak, Preston, Ohio. A
                        SUMMARY VIEW OF THE MILLENNIAL CHURCH, OR "United Society of Believers" It treats of the Bise
                        and Progress of the Society, together with the general Prin ciples of the Faith and Testimony.
                        Price, 50 cts. Sketches of Shakers and Shakerism. A synopsis of the United Society of Believers
                        in Christ's Second Appearing. Illustrated. By Giles B. Avery. Price 15 cts. BRIEF EXPOSITION OF
                        The Principles and Regulations of the SOCIETY OF BELIEVERS. Price, 10 cts. THE ALTRUIST. Is a
                        monthly paper, partly in Phonetic spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor,
                        Community homes, and equal rights to all. It is publisht by the Altruist Community, whose
                        members all live and work together, and hold all their property in common, all the men and women
                        having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by their majority
                        vote. It now has 5,000 acres of land in Southeast Missouri on which it offers a home and
                        employment for life to all acceptable persons who may wish to join it. 50 cents a year specimen
                        copy free. Address A. Long ley, 2819 Olive St. St. Louis, Mo. DECEMBER,
    --><pb n="0" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books &amp; Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>The Ladies' Home Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Columns of figures are seldom interesting, yet I fancy the two which register the receipts and expenditures
                                of the United States year by year from 1791 to the present time will, without illumination, stimulate the
                                curiosity even of those ordinarily indifferent to statistics. If some modern Rip Van Winkle were to be
                                handed this table, which annually appears in the report of the Secretary of the Treasury to Congress, he
                                would know at a glance that in one instance, at least, some great and tremendous event had happened in his
                                country's history. Beginning with gross receipts, which includes revenues and loans, of $4,771,000 in 1791,
                                he would notice a steady growth, until they reached $83,371,640 in 1861. Next year, 1802, they were
                                $581,680,000—an increase in a twelvemonth of nearly half a billion dollars; in 1863, $889,379,652; in 1864,
                                $1,393, 461,000; in 1865, $1,805,939,345; and for three years thereafter receipts in excess of one billion
                                dollars annually. From then until this day he would see, also, that the Government's ordinary revenues have
                                been counted annually in the hundreds of millions. If, after seeing such a picture, one were to tell him
                                that this country, a generation ago, suffered four years of strife such as the world had never seen, it
                                ought to occasion in his mind no surprise. The plain cold figures are sufficiently graphic to tell the story
                                of the magnitude of the Civil War.—Hon. Lyman J. Gage, in Franlc Leslie's Popular Monthly for November. An
                                important pictorial feature will shortly begin in The Ladies' Home Journal in a series to be called "Through
                                Picturesque America: In 100 Pictures." Through the medium of the most superb new photographs, taken
                                expressly for this feature, the series will start where American land begins on the Maine coast, take in the
                                greatest points of magnificence and marvelous scenic wonders in every part of America, embrace Alaska, Cuba,
                                Porto Rico, and end where American possessions stop—at the farthest point in the Philippine Islands. Bright,
                                popular explanatory text to accompany the pictures will be supplied by Luther L. Holden, of Boston, who has
                                crossed the American Continent over one hundred times and knows every step of the way. The series will run
                                through the magazine for a year. It was my privilege to attend Mass on the Olympia during the voyage from
                                New York to Boston and I shall never forget the emotions it excited. The little portable altar, formed of
                                sections of gas pipe, was set up on the starboard side of the gun deck, almost amidship. It was draped with
                                the Stars and Stripes and covered with linen and lace. Over the tabernacle hung a crucifix, and on either
                                side was a single lighted candle. One side of the altar was flanked by the frowning breech of a gun. On the
                                other side, and only a few feet away, was the galley, where the cooks were busy preparing dinner. Behind the
                                altar was located an orchestra composed of members of the ship's band. The devotion with which the sailors
                                and marines followed the Mass was something remarkable to behold. Father Reaney's little discourse was an
                                instruction based on the devotions of the month of October. He referred to the power of the Blessed Virgin
                                as a mediator, and how, as the Star of the Sea, she had a special oversight of those who went down to the
                                sea in ships. Then there was a deft touch in referring to the earthly mothers, and the sermon was
                                ended.—Donahoe's </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of hygeio-therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of Hygeio-Therapi\ The October number comes to us full of good things. The
                                article by Dr. Gifford on "Discouragement and the Law of Cure," is excellent for those who are sick or well.
                                A lesson after that order is eminently educational. Many other interesting articles are found in the same
                                Journal till it is well filled with good things. Pub. by Dr. T. V. Gifford &amp; Co. Kokomo, Incl. In
                                the November Magazine Number The Outlook prints a portrait and brief sketch of Mr. James Barnes, now on his
                                way to the Transvaal as special correspondent for The Outlook. The articles from Mr. Barnes on the Transvaal
                                War and on the problems of South Africa will undouDtedly prove as attractive a feature in this journal as
                                have the two series of articles on Cuba by Mr. George Kennan. Another series of equal importance will be
                                that on the Philippines by Mr. Phelps Whitmarsh, author of "The World's Rough Hand." Mr. Whitmarsh is now in
                                the islands as a special commissioner for The Outlook. An article on Hawaii in its present relations to the
                                United States, including an interview with ex-President Dolo, appears in The Outlook for October 28th, and
                                forms the first of Mr. Whitmarsh's series under the general title "Colonial America." ($3 a year. The
                                Outlook Co., N. Y.) The Cosmopolitan Magazine is the first to exploit the beauties and attractions that are
                                to come at the Paris Exposition. It has secured a notable contribution for its November number from Vance
                                Thompson, who is now in Paris, who has been over the ground especially for The Cosmopolitan and who is,
                                undoubtedly, the most brilliant of the younger American writers. The article is copiously illustrated. There
                                will be a second Paris Exposition article in The Cosmopolitan, for December. This one is written by the Hon.
                                Charles A. Towne, the eloquent Minnesota Representative in Congress, and it, also, will have many fine
                                pictures.</p></div3></div2><pb n="177" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Still small voice" TEIform="index"/>THE STILL SMALL VOICE</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>Elder Henry C. Blinn</byline><p TEIform="p"> simplicity of action in accomplishing any desired result should never be overlooked. So long as there are many
                            men with many minds there must be as many corresponding forms of expression in order to manifest the thoughts
                            that are evolving in the minds of individuals. Cultivation goes far in its ameliorating influence to make better
                            the general character, and also in refining the manners and fitting them for the best societ}\ One of the old
                            prophets in order to be able to preach an effectual sermon to an idolatrous king of Israel, was sent into a
                            mountain and remained there several weeks. While in his hermitage he witnessed scenes like an earthquake, and
                            then of a whirlwind and finally became so spiritually sensitive that he thought he heard "a still small voice,"
                            coining from the Lord. This wonderful season of meditation, no doubt, aided him very much in his subsequent
                            message to the king. The potent influence of this remarkable gift of inspiration has never yet been lost,
                            whether it be for an Ahab or a Herod that is to receive the divine word. Whether these exhibitions of the
                            earthquake and the whirlwind that the piophet witnessed on Mt. Carmel were representations of the manners and
                            customs of the people at that place, we may not be able to solve. But of all that he heard and saw in that
                            remarkable retreat, the greatest excellence was readily admitted to be found in the still, small voice.
                            DECEMBER, 1899. THE <pb n="178" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 178 THE MANIFESTO. The whirlwind and the earthquake characters may
                            have their legitimate place among men, and be able to accomplish wonderful results, but faith, hope and love
                            have a far deeper influence to eradicate wrong. Too much care can not be exercised in the ministration that
                            passes from mind to mind. Men sometimes do heroic deeds in order to accomplish a certain end. While the point of
                            the finest needle ma)? cause intense pain to a sensitive patient, the skillful surgeon does not hesitate if the
                            case demands it, to use his scalpel, even though the loss of a limb be the result. With his knife goes his
                            prayerful thought for the best good of all concerned. It required n. term of not less than forty days of fasting
                            for Elijah to be able to discriminate the benefits arising from the ministration of the "small voice," over that
                            of the whirlwind or the earthquake, with which he had for so long a time been very closely associated. Some of
                            the old prophets who were being educated under the Mosaic Law, partook largely of the spirit of that Law, and in
                            their ministry for religious benefit, framed their discourses on the principle of an eye for an eye and a .tooth
                            for a tooth. If justice only rules, and mercy is kept in the rear, there may be some judicial decisions rendered
                            that might seem even heroic under the rule of the Medes and Persians. The Lawgivers and .Judges conducted their
                            administration very much after this same spirit. How nice it would be for those temperaments tliat are cither
                            moulded on this plane, at the present day, or have been educated on this rigid, despotic line, to follow the
                            course of the mountain prophet and after eating a little meat, begin a fast of forty days. For once we may rest
                            assured that we should enter a new dispensation and be obliged to solve our diflicuities in a "still, small
                            voice," much to the satisfaction of all our hearers. On the other hand there may be occasions when necessity
                            demands volume of voice, when we must "cry aloud and spare not," and use good Anglosaxon words as the potent
                            influence that is to consummate the anticipated good. Even the evangelical prophet, so pleasantly perused, and
                            so literally quoted gave utterance, at one time, to those emphatic words as demanded by the mission for which he
                            was sent. "Cry aloud! Lift up your voice like a trumpet! !" The prophet was in earnest. There was no time to be
                            wasted in smooth soft words while the enemy of our souls and of God's kingdom of righteousness was in danger of
                            invasion. To cry aloud was an evidence of life, and that something was wanted immediately. Isaiah was well
                            acquainted with the customs of the priests and prophets of Baal. In the days of Elijah as a test of spiritual
                            influence the priests called upon Baal from morning till noon without being able to get a response. It was on a
                            fast day that the children of Israel were doing as did the woishipers of Baal, and the good prophet urged the
                            faithful to make as much effort in the interest of their (rod as the idolators did for Baal. What a lesson for
                            those who believe in God ! What a lesson for those who <pb n="179" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 179 believe as said
                            the Apostle—"we know that we are of God, and the whole world lieth in wickedness ! !" Jesus like Elijah was a
                            man of meditation, and of fasting. He said there were certain conditions that could not be eliminated from the
                            souls and bodies of men. except thi'ough prayer and fasting. As yet we have many lessons to learn. "Though
                            heralded with naught of fear, Or outward sign to show; Though only to the inward ear, It whispers soft and low;
                            Though dropping as the manna fell, Unseen, yet from above, Noiseless as dew fall, heed it well— Thy Father's
                            call of love." East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Voice of the 'Manifesto'" TEIform="index"/>THE VOICE OF THE "MANIFESTO."</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Stickney, Asenath C." TEIform="persName"/>Asenath C. Stickney</byline><p TEIform="p">"jETo/c beautiful upon the mountains are the feet of him that bn'ngeth good tidings, that publisheth
                            peace."—Isaiah Hi., 7. T I 1HUS sang the inspired prophet of long ago, while the sweet strain, seemJL ingly
                            floating down through the centuries, rests upon the thought like liquid music. I quote this beautiful passage in
                            respectful recognition of the value it has been to me during my pilgrimage as a messenger of "good tidings."
                            Perhaps my patrons are not all aware that I, The Manifesto, first became conscious of existence as an entity at
                            Watervliet, N. Y., in February of 1871, nearly twenty-nine years ago, where I learned from the veteran editors
                            of that date that 1 was to become an itinerant missionary in behalf of the Shakers as a sect. Those worthy
                            pioneers have long since joined the army of intelligences in the Realm of Souls. For the past eighteen years, my
                            temporary home has been at East Canterbury, where the faithful editor, Elder Henry C. Blinn, has kindly
                            superintended all my various needs, to whom I am now deeply indebted. Having recently heard it announced that my
                            mission will close with the present century, 1 come once more to present my thanks to all who have in any way
                            patronized my efforts. To the stanch contributors, who have so long fed me with substantial thought, loving
                            words and hopeful aspirations, I tender my warmest congratulations. To the liberal subscribers, who have paid my
                            fare in advance to different localities, I offer grateful acknowledgements; while to all my patrons, far and
                            near, I owe a debt of especial thanks. Just here let me assure you, it is with much regret that I part company
                            with so maii}r noble friends, yet feel that 1 must abide (he decision of my <pb n="180" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 180 THE
                            MANIFESTO. superiors, only giving way, however, I trust, to a greater, stronger missionary agent that will more
                            effectually further the Christian work I have faithfully sought to accomplish thus far. Having traveled
                            extensively through the past twenty-nine years, and having found my way into many homes in foreign lands as well
                            as in our own free country, I am happy to state that I have been treated with such consideration that no uncanny
                            memories are to be found in my life record. I am well aware that my mission has been a lowly one. No popularity
                            has been sought after by my contributors. No illustrations, no attractive pictures of material objects have
                            graced my pages, no romantic stories told, no state prison records of unfortunates ever found room in the
                            columns consecrated to the publishing of "good tidings." Each tiny volume has been chiefly devoted to the grave
                            responsibilities of the soul life of the peculiar people it has been my privilege to represent. They glory only
                            in self-conquest, one for one, in financial honesty, in sincerity of purpose, in devotion to the pure principles
                            of self-abnegation taught by the Pattern of nearly nineteen hundred years ago. In my Home Notes, I have given
                            the enquirer a glance into the domestic social life of their happy communal homes, and methinks, by so doing,
                            may have answered somewhat the oft-repeated query; "What would become of the world if all were Shakers?" In
                            conclusion, I would say that I trust the dawning century will evolve some feasible method of publishing more
                            effectually and more gloriously than 1 have been able to do, the "good tidings" of gospel liberty to all true
                            seekers after righteousness. Please accept, herewith, as a parting benediction, the kindest regards of Yours,
                            The Manifesto.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our Mother Ann" TEIform="index"/>OUR MOTHER ANN</head><p TEIform="p">HISTORY informs us that Mother Ann Lee, landed on the American shores with her band of loyal volunteers, one
                            hundred and twenty-five years ago. From that event we date the birth of religious freedom for woman, in this,
                            our favored land. Although we love to read the history and life of Mother Ann Lee and her labors of love, a
                            century of events can hardly cancel from thought the memory of the cruelties she suffered, or repress the rising
                            tear as we realize she was only a woman like ourselves by nature, but who by the grace of God, became a marvel
                            of goodness to her people. We revere her memory ! "Many daughters have done virtuously ; but thou excellest them
                            all." Many are her followers who have perpetuated in their lives the principles which she taught. Many spiritual
                            mothers have arisen during the last one hundred years whose posterity to-day, rise up and call them blessed. <pb n="181" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 181 Those who embrace and live according to the universal principles upon
                            which the virgin church is founded, are able to perfect a spiritual fatherhood and motherhood which far
                            transcends in wealth of affection and genuine love that of which a mere child of nature can boast. Let us
                            faithfully perpetuate their practical Christian teachings that the youth of the dawning century now so near may
                            realize from our life consecrations, other Mother Ann's who will walk the same highway of Christian excellence
                            and thus continue to perpetuate the kingdom of heaven life here upon the earth. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Messenger" TEIform="index"/>THE MESSENGER</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Rupe, Nancy L." TEIform="persName"/>Nancy L. Rupe</byline><p TEIform="p">North, east, west and southern household, Children of our heavenly king, All in harmony together, Let us one more
                            offering bring. We've been passengers, dear kindred, In the Messenger of Thitii, Met each month in blest
                            communion, Aged, middle-aged and youtn. Blessed voyages ! How pleasant, As we sailed from shore to shore,
                            Proving love a heaven-born token "God is Love"—we ask no more. Had we eloquence of language To portray the grand
                            career Of the wisely guarded vessel, As it moved from year to year, Strewing bread upon the waters, That in
                            future will return, Setting starlights in dark places That will never cease to burn. Sowing seed for future
                            ages, Plants from which can never die, These are watered from a fount Of living streams that never dry. But like
                            autumn leaves and flowers Childhood, youth and middle age, All succumb to final changes Passing from life's
                            active stage, Precious treasure, "Manifesto," Dost thou in like manner pass ? <pb n="182" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 182 THE
                            MANIFESTO. Hast fulfilled thy glorious mission, Must we bid adieu at last? Brethren, let us chant a requiem,
                            Sisters, join the plaintive strain, That our greetings, as in past times, Never will return again ! But a
                            glorious day is dawning When earth's conllicts will be o'er, Rapturous thoughts, O glorious meeting On the grand
                            immortal shore. Pleasant Hill, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Introspection" TEIform="index"/>INTROSPECTION</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Evans, Jessie" TEIform="persName"/>Jessie Evans</byline><p TEIform="p">THERE are deeps and shallows in life. There are heights and depths in L the realm of thought. The earth has its
                            seasons, and in their order they bring about sowing, cultivation, bud, blossom and harvest. No less so is it in
                            the mind world. Thoughts take root, they lie seemingly dormant, but the blade comes to light and later the "full
                            corn in the ear" is ready for distribution or transplanting. The agriculturist always selects carefully the
                            choicest specimens for transplanting, and the thoughtful are equally wise n their selection of what shall be
                            reinstated in the garden of the soul. The seasons of the year have passed in their usual succession, and the
                            earth has brought forth after its kind. God's blessings have redeemed, his promises. Obedient nature has exerted
                            her utmost, and the fruits have been garnered. The leaves fall, and the trees, lately so radiant in their
                            various colors, lately so burdened with many fruits, appear in their bare uniform. With the eye of the ignorant,
                            one might pronounce them dead, so unsuggestive are they now of foliage, shade, blossom or frirt. But, on the
                            contrary, they were never more truly alive. They have simply adapted themselves to their circumstances. The law
                            that sends the killing frosts, forbids them now to present the beautiful fragile blossom, yet the power to
                            produce the outward beauty is all conserved in the wonderful organism of the tree. Souls, too, have their
                            seasons, but they come not to all at the same time. We turn and find, side by side, souls hoary with the
                            whiteness of winter almost ready for transplanting; others laden with the golden fruit of gospel experience and
                            wisdom; many in their spring-time are just putting forth the first leaves, while upon others we may find the
                            promising bud and blossom. Many souls, like the vine, instinctively seek a strong support, yet upon them hang
                            the ripe clusters of well-formed, timely fruit. It is an acknowledged fact that no two persons are exactly alike
                            in either <pb n="183" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 183 structure or emanation. for this reason, it is of great
                            importance that we individually study to know our mission. In the physical world we have our place, we select
                            the occupations for which nature has fitted us. If we attempt duties which we are unable to complete, we turn to
                            others until we find the sphere in which nature is satisfied to have us move. Some restless personalities pass
                            from this life, having never found their legitimate avocations ; but it is our right, our duty, to pass with
                            honor through the term of service on earth which God has permitted us as a preparation for the higher life
                            beyond. Restless minds may, likewise, pass out of this existence with no definite knowledge of the part they
                            were appointed to play in the great drama of thought. God hides his secrets deep, but he who treads the depths
                            finds them unshrined. Shallows engage no divers. Our thought life is the supreme life. We pass before the eyes
                            of men, and too often only the superficial is known. One writer truthfully asserts that we have never really
                            seen each other. Nothing could be truer. We are not the personalities that hold in trust for a season the
                            immortal faculties. They express what we are, they are the vehicles of our thought, but in the thought itself
                            lie the real ive. For this reason, it bshooves us to find what place we occupy in the great realm of mind. God
                            has stationed us in this beautiful world of his to fulfill an appointed mission. As each mind is distinct in its
                            conceptions, so it is distinct in its responsibilities. The true Christian is as conscious of an under life as
                            he is of his material existence. Deeper than the nerve that responds to human touch, is the current that
                            connects him with the Divine. More distinct than the beating of the heart is the throb of his soul toward all
                            that furthers Zion's interests. This higher self is of primary importance. The law that gives it birth provides
                            for its growth and development, and we should study until on comprehension of it is as perfect as is that of the
                            law governing the physical. The mission of our Savior was to bring men to a knowledge of the real life of the
                            soul. Nothing so strongly incurred his displeasure as the sin of hypocrisy. When the hypocrites fast, he said,
                            "they disfigure their faces, that they may appear unto men to fast." "But thou, when thou fastest, anoint thine
                            head and wash thy face ; that thou appear not unto men to fast, but unto thy Father which is in secret; and thy
                            Father, which seeth in secret, shall reward thee openly." The branch abiding in the vine referred to a vital
                            connection with the productiveness of God and the barren fig-tree withered under his rebuke. In secret God
                            chastens the human soul, silently his mysterious processes take place, they have no human witness. "The wind
                            bloweth where it listeth and thou heareth the sound thereof, but canst not tell whence it corneth and whither it
                            goeth; so is every one that is born of the Spirit." God acquaints every soul with its work at its birth. "Where
                            much is given, much will be required." If the issue is a critical one, the discipline will doubtless <pb n="184" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 184 . THE MANIFESTO. be long and severe ; if the form is to illustrate perfect symmetry, the
                            chiseling must be deep and constant until not an uncouth atom remains. We have not all, like the trees, passed
                            the season of fruit-bearing ; but, like them, we must grow from a centered vitality. The shallows of life refer
                            but to the transient, the immortal explores the depths and scales the heights. There is no time for the trivial,
                            we turn from the superficial with disgust. The signs of our day call for living souls, adamant character,
                            indomitable courage. Ke, whose under life is at peace with divine intentions, stands through all seasons, a
                            branch of God's planting which is as the oak that grows but the more sturdy when assailed by tempest and storm.
                            East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="From Wesley's writings" TEIform="index"/>FROM WESLEY'S WRITINGS </head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by Sarah S. Woods.]
                            A LLOW me the liberty of conscience. Allow me the right of private -LJL judgment. Allow me to use the expression
                            just as often as I judge it preferable to any other expression and be not angry with me if I can not judge it
                            proper to use any one expression every two minutes. You ma}7, if you please, but do not condemn me because I do
                            not. Do not, for this, represent me as a Papist, or "an enemy to the righteousness of Christ." Bear with me as I
                            do you; else how shall we "fulfill the law of Christ?" Do not make tragical outcries as though I were subverting
                            the very foundation of Christianity. Whoever does this, does me much wrong ; the Lord lay it not to his charge!
                            I lay, and have done for many years, the very same foundation with you. And indeed, "othei foundation can no man
                            lay than that which is laid, even Jesus Christ." I build inward and outward holiness thereon, as you do even by
                            faith. Do not, therefore, suffer any distaste, or unkindness, no, nor any shyness or coldness of your heart. If
                            there were a difference of opinion, where is our religion if we can not think and let think? What hinders but
                            you may forgive me as easily as I may forgive you? How much more, when tliere is only a difference of expression
                            ! Nay, hardly so much as that! All the dispute being only whether a particular mode of expression shall be used
                            more or less frequently. Surely we must earnestly desire to contend with one another before we can make this a
                            bone of contention. Oh, let us not any more, for such very trifles as these, give our common enemies room to
                            blaspheme. Rather let us at length cut off occasion from them that seek occasion! Let us at length—oh, why was
                            it not done before?—join hearts and hands in the service of our great Master.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Wesley, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Wesley</byline></div2><pb n="185" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obedience" TEIform="index"/>OBEDIENCE</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Phelps, Lillian" TEIform="persName"/>Lillian Phelps</byline><p TEIform="p">IN order to insure success in the Christian life it is necessary that this important principle, should become
                            firmly established within the heart. "To obey is better than sacrifice and to hearken than the fat of rams."
                            Every soul must have proved, in some measure, the truth of these words. The effect of disobedience to wise
                            counsel or to the voice of conscience, will ever be a loss of spiritual streugth and consequently of power to
                            resist evil. Whereas a soul that renders obedience to the spirit of truth wherever it may be found will obtain a
                            growth in spiritual life and thus become fortified against the powers of evil. There are different phases of
                            obedience which come with different stages of growth. For instance, one may obey from the power of love for an
                            individual, even as the dutiful child obeys his parents. This will answer for a time, but unless obedience
                            becomes a fixed principle in the heart the foundation for a Christian life can not become established. Again one
                            may obey from fear of punishment and thus never conceive of the spirit of the law, or know the blessings arising
                            therefrom. Mother Ann said, "Once I served God through fear, but now I serve him through love," showing that
                            with advancing growth in the spiritual life our love for God and his word prompts a willing obedience thereto.
                            True Christian obedience requires humility, self-denial and the resignation expressed in the words of the
                            Savior: "Thy will, not mine, be done." East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Request" TEIform="index"/>A REQUEST</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="McKechnie, Frederic" TEIform="persName"/>Frederic McKechnie</byline><p TEIform="p">0 Tuou of truth and grace I am Thy clay. Yet let me see Thy face, I do not pray For riches ; these have wings And
                            flee away. Nor yet Lord would I have A world's acclaim, Worlds go, and with them goes Their thing called fame ;
                            1 would not have of them Their proudest name. But let me see Thy face, And at the sight, <pb n="186" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/>
                            186 THE MANIFESTO. My soul shall wake and rise From out its night To day that never dies, Eternal Light. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memory of our brother, Frank O. Libbey" TEIform="index"/>In Memory of our Brother, FRANK O. LIBBEY</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Griffen, Ellen" TEIform="persName"/>Ellen Griffen</byline><p TEIform="p">"In the midst of life we are in death." When the deepening shadows of evening Began to darken our way,— When the
                            twilight came softly stealing To shut out the light of day,— The Angel of Death came near us, And took from our
                            fond embrace, One who was loved and cherished, To dwell in a holier place. To a bright and happy mansion, He has
                            striven to prepare; Where no pain can ever enter, Neither sorrow, grief, nor care. He has gone, the reward of
                            his labors To receive, at the blessed throne ; For bearing the cross of the Savior, He shall wear the promised
                            crown. He was almost too young to be taken ; His place we can not fill;— But in loving and true obedience, We
                            will try to do the will Of our Father who art in heaven, And knoweth what is best. So with joy we will let our
                            brother, With the angels in heaven rest. 'Tis hard we know to be parted From friends who seem so dear, But this
                            is no abiding place, We can not tarry here. For soon we shall all hear the summons. The call to the evergreen
                            shore, Where with friends we shall be united, To part with them nevermore. Alfred, Me.</p></div2><pb n="187" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Manifesto, December, 1899. Office of Publication" TEIform="index"/>THE MANIFESTO. DECEMBER, 1899. OFFICE OF
                            PUBLICATION.</head><p TEIform="p"> The Manifesto is published by the "United Society of Believers, and is the only work issued regularly by the
                            Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious views of the Order and to
                            inculcate the spirit of lighteousness. Address, Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, N. H.</p><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notice" TEIform="index"/>NOTICE</head><p TEIform="p">Our little Magazine which at the present time is known as "The Manifesto," issued its first number in
                                January, 1871, at Watervliet, N. Y. At that time it bore the very pleasant but modest title, "The Shaker."
                                It was the messenger of "good news," and in its advocacy of the testimony of the Christ, gave no uncertain
                                sound. Its publication has been sustained by the liberal contributions of the several Shaker Communities, as
                                they have manifested a deep interest in its success as a medium for good to its own members, and no less to
                                those who were not residents of the Community. Possibly it may be after a term of some thirty years, "The
                                Manifesto" has accomplished all the good it can for the present, and may now go into retirement till another
                                wave of enthusiasm calls it again into action. To all who have ministered to the success of the little
                                paper, as writers or readers, or to its circulation, we extend our kindest thanks. Times have changed. Money
                                is scarce and the several Societies have suffered with the laboring classes in the common distress. It is
                                now proposed that the December number of "The Manifesto" for 1899, shall be the closing of the publication.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Directors" TEIform="persName"/>Directors</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">October. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Rain. 1898. 54. 7.75 in 1899. 51.35 1.5 " Highest
                                Temp, during this mo. 74 above 0. Lowest " " " " 26 Number of rainy days " " 6 " clear " " " 7 " cloudy" " "
                                18 Nov. 1899. The items of greatest importance, ad valorem, should have the first place. This being so,
                                seriatim, I must say: our itinerant Ministry at present are located at Hancock, Mass., reviewing the
                                progress of the Community there, in things spiritual and temporal. So far as my information extends, their
                                relationship is a bond of peace, love and union, a three fold cord not easily broken. At Mt Lebanon, Church
                                family, the burden of the Brethren is the harvesting of the fall crops, preparatory to meet the inclemency
                                of a cold, frost-bound, snowmantled winter. We are quite well prepared for the unwelcome visitor. According
                                to the Indian maxim; "Before winter sets in, the swamps must be filled with water," which at present is not
                                the case, and our springs are very low. The Sisters are busy as bees in the season of flowers; besides their
                                ordinary round of duties, they are favored with orders in the line of making cloaks for citizens not of our
                                Community. This employs a number of the Sisters from morning dawn till dewy eve. So both Brethren and
                                Sisters have enough to do, leaving no time to be sick or to be unkind. This is a blessing, that should be
                                appreciated, even if some of us do at times snap the hygienic law and get ourselves into a trap of troubles.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reed, Calvin G." TEIform="persName"/>Calvin G. Reed</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South family" TEIform="index"/>South Family</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1899. Well here we are, witnessing the eighteen hundred and ninety-ninth November. And other Novembers
                                will come and go, but will they revive our Manifesto? We hope it may be. We will not hope in vain! We will
                                try to believe that what is, is for the best. The Manikk.sto should have a rest <pb n="188" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 188
                                THE MANIFESTO. We hope a short rest it only will get, 'Tis not very old—'tis not thirty yet. At twice its
                                age we'd deem it quite young, And think its good work was scarcely begun. But rest is the law that must be
                                obeyed, So on the high shelf it soon will be laid. Then after a time to light 'twill be brought With newness
                                of life and richness of tho't Brighter 'twill be for its rest on the shelf, Dependent not then on base
                                worldly pelf. Its pages will glow with beauty untold And gladly be read by young and by old. The gospel
                                proclaimed by Jesus, we'know Will then fully fill our Manifesto. Till then—until then our patience we'll
                                keep Back numbers read and much pleasure reap Call up the good we have found in the past Thro' writers
                                unseen and seen to the last. Thanks we extend to our editor kind And trust that he will good health truly
                                1ind And find his way back where Berkshire hills grow There rest for a time like our Manifesto. To his
                                honorable staff our love we inclose And hope they will now find rest'and repose. We have had a beautiful
                                October more like summer than fading autumn. The bright sunshine and singing birds have reminded us of the
                                Summer land where all is life, light and beauty. Sister Fannie Tyson of Enfield, Conn, paid us a visit on
                                one of October's sunny afternoons. We all enjoyed her coming. Arthur Dowe, of California, in company with
                                Brother Alonzo Hollistcr called on us a few days ago. We find pleasure always in meeting with friends both
                                near and far. Our family are usually well and all are busy doing good and trying to make hay while the sun
                                shines.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Genevieve" TEIform="persName"/>Genevieve DeGraw</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North family" TEIform="index"/>North Family</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1890. These autumn days—for whatever mere almanacs may say, winter has not yet come—we have gathered up
                                all the cider apples findable and sent them off to the mill. Of good apples, our cellar is now quite full.
                                Greenings, smooth and sound being the main part of our crop, but we have also got in quite a quantity of
                                Baldwins; of these latter, more than we had at one time expected. In the very mild weather we have been
                                having, the Greenings are not keeping as well as they might (in this respect being inferior to the Baldwin
                                apple,) and it may be, we shall have to dispose of them before Christmas, although in former seasons we have
                                kept them along into .January and February. The continued spell pf dry weather is allowing us to get fields
                                and gardens ploughed and fertilized and we have also got in our supply of coal for another winter. But
                                still, we would be glad to see some rain come along and fill up ponds and reservoirs before winter sets in.
                                It would give us some water power with which to do a little sawing and other necessary things. This winter,
                                if we can get at it, we expect to make a lot of carpet whips, a useful article to have in the house and one
                                for which there should be a fair demand when once they are known. This is about all there is to write about
                                home this month; only one thing now remains to do; bid adieu to our little magazine. It is a pity. Like a
                                friend, it has called at our gates these many years, passed a few pleasant words and gone away again until
                                another month came round, and has always been welcome in a quiet way each time it came. But now it is not
                                coming back and this time we are to say farewell. But nay! we look forward to that "wave of enthusiasm" of
                                which our good "directors" speak and say—not farewell but only, au revoir.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="McKechnie, Frederic" TEIform="persName"/>Frederic McKechnie</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass</head><p TEIform="p">Xov. 1809. So we meet in the "Home Corner," this month to sound the finale of our notes, or is it only to
                                institute a pause in the music? Some one has said that a rest is as necessary to good music as is sound, for
                                the following notes will acquire force by the preceding quiet. Best is not inaction. The soldier on
                                picket-duty who faithfully performs his task, helps as truly as he who advances to meet the foe. We are
                                commanded to "Let our light shine," and do we think that if one medium of communication be closed, we are to
                                sit in darkness? It is not the polishing of the lamp or the ornamentation of its stand, that we now need,
                                but it is the steady glow of a bright light. Such lights as by their loyal beams, send help and hope over
                                life's troubled waters. Such lights as shine in little unnoticed places but just there the danger is
                                greatest. The stars that lighten the darkened world, only produce their brightness by steadily glowing, each
                                in its place of the vast firmament above us. Each one twinkling bright and clear, yet all their beams
                                uniting in the flood of light illumining the distance. So may we shine, "You in your small corner and I in
                                mine" each one individually shining, yet all uniting in the one truth which our lives portray. Because we
                                are called to a halt in the onward march, we will not lay our weapons down but build for ourselves walls of
                                defence, and by daily drill strengthen our <pb n="189" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. forces. Is not the command
                                to "halt," as truly a command as the "onward march?" Our duty as soldiers, is only to receive the order and
                                obey. If the command is issued from our Leader, it can not fail to prove to have been for the best. We know
                                our cause is one of truth. We are sure it will not bejforgotten or that its people will be forsaken. We must
                                not "run before"' our Leader, it is the faithful following that brings us to the kingdom. As we follow, new
                                doors will be opened to us and we shall advance nearer and nearer the desired goal. We shall miss the little
                                monthly chat with our Brothers and Sisters in other homes, but must learn to converse by thought waves. The
                                inventor of the wireless telegraphy must work still farther and give us the power of wordless speech. So to
                                the north-land and south-land, the east and the west, we send the mizpah benediction of old. "The Lord watch
                                between thee and me when we are absent one from another." The Lord between us! Are we not then safe and
                                sure? Though we see not each other, we are all stepping toward this divinity and since He is between us,
                                there we shall meet united in Him, one spirit, one life. So now, dear members of the circle, can not we all
                                join in the sweet parting song, that shall send its echoes to every one in our homes. "God be with you till
                                we meet again By His counsel guide, uphold you, With His sheep securely fold you, God be with you til) we
                                meet again."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Estabrook, Fidella" TEIform="persName"/>Fidella Estabrook</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>Union Village, Ohio</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1899. Ovn health is very good at the present writing. In fact, for salubrity of climate, Union Village
                                is hardly to be exceeded by any region of country on this earth. Our crops are nearly all in and have been
                                such as to elicit thankfulness and gratitude on our part to the great Father and Mother of us all. Our
                                business is moving on in the usual routine of duties and labors pertaining to the success and perpetuity of
                                o u r C o m m unity. To be true followers of Jesus, does not in these days, seem to have any attractions for
                                the .average worldling, but one of these days there will come a radical change in all this. The good Lord
                                knows when, and how to bring it about. In connection with these meditations, how often I recall those
                                remarkable lines of Rev. John Newton,— "Destruction's tlang'rous road, What multitudes pursue, While that
                                which leads the soul to God Is known or sought by few. Kncompassed by a throng, On numbers they depend; So
                                many surely can't be wrong, And miss a happy end. Hut numbers are no mark That men will right be found, A
                                few were saved in Noah's Ark For many millions drowned. If self limsi be denied, And sin forsaken quite;
                                They rather choose the way that's wide Anil try to think it's right. Obey the Gospel call, And enter while j
                                ou may, The flock of Christ was always small, But none are saved but they." I lately had a petition
                                presented to me to sign, praying for the abolition of capital punishment. I signed the same gladly. I hope
                                it may receive so many signers as to move our Legislature to the abolition forever, of that awful relic of
                                barbarism. It should have been wiped from our Judicial system long ago. One man is writing us from AVaco.
                                Texas, to be received as a member but there are those who oppose his uniting with us. Thus it is;—scarcely
                                one in two hundred makes application for membership, who has not some insuperable barrier standing in his
                                way, but Jesus said, "Take no thought for the morrow." In due time, doubtless, all things will be adjusted
                                in the wisdom of the Highest, and for our greatest good and success.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. Hampton</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1899. Beloved Editok:—The last Notes about Home are certainly due you for your kind and prompt service
                                to the public for so many years. While the last echoes of our written notes will soon die away on the wintry
                                breezes that King Winter has already briskly set in motion, the music of grateful acknowledgment in the
                                hearts of the many readers who have profited by the faithful circulation of our beloved "Maxifksto" Avill
                                not soon be hushed. One writer happily asserts, "We live in deeds, not years," and in this sense the
                                magazine has lived long and well. We thank you as the motive power of its success. To the staff of printers
                                we bid an affectionate farewell. If they have been unfortunate enough to make j&gt;t'.s behind the
                                scenes, we have no proof of the fact, and while we know they must have needed many a stick in their work the
                                public have been spared the sight. It is pleasant to cast a loving glance ininto every home at this season
                                and believe 189 <pb n="190" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 190 THE MANIFESTO. that all are working toward the upbuilding of our
                                holy cause. We shall not greet each other again, perhaps, through this medium, but we can never forget that
                                we are children of one rich inheritance, and as such, are pledged to a loving consecration to which there
                                are no boundary lines and upon which the sun can never set. Farewell, dear faithful "Manifesto;" and to our
                                beloved gospel kindred, we say, God speed thee and us to higher trustworthiness, broader conceptions of our
                                Christian work and to a deeper abiding love to the Zion of our God which can never be destroyed.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, Jessie" TEIform="persName"/>Jessie Evans</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1899. A few days ago we had a short visit from Elder Joseph Holden and Elder Ira Lawson who called here
                                on their mission of love and good-will. We were glad to have them w ith us if only for a short time and were
                                spiritually benefited by their presence. As these are to be the last Notes for Tmo Manifesto we think they
                                had better not be too lengthy, therefore we shall have to write our final adieux as The Manifesto dies with
                                this issue. How sad it is to part with a friend and such a helpful friend, too, as The Manifesto has been!
                                Is there no doctor that can be called in to administer the right kind of medicine that would restore it? If
                                not we must bid all our readers a kind farewell, for the little book on whose pages we have scanned the
                                growth and prosperity of our various homes, will be no more,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cummings, Ada S." TEIform="persName"/>Add S. Cummings</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Alfred, Me</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1899. The fall months keep us busy w7ith their various duties. We have no place for drones. "Hands to
                                work and heart to God," is our motto. We have just stored twenty-two tons of grain in our cow barn. We are
                                getting sixty-four gallons of milk a day, two thirds of which is shipped daily to Boston. Have a good stock
                                of cattle and have raised twenty-four calves this season. The fall term of school has closed after a
                                successful season of ten weeks. Number of scholars, fifteen. During the past month the angel of death has
                                made us a call and taken our Brother, Frank Libbey: a faithful worker in the interests of Zion. It reminds
                                us that this is no continuing city. The present is ours the future we know not of, so we will strive to do
                                what good we can and be working for those treasures which are immortal and perish not. In parting with The
                                Manifesto we feel that we are parting with an old friend. We hope that some time in the future we can
                                welcome it again to our home.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Libbey, Eva M." TEIform="persName"/>Eva M. Libbey</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1899. At date of writing these Notes, the 5th inst. we are enjoying a visit from a delegation from
                                Enfield, Conn., comprising Eldress Marion Patric and Sisters Phebe Farnham and Irene Ashley. We prize all
                                seasons of social and spiritual communion with our gospel relation. It was refreshing to peruse the lines of
                                that grand old hymn, "Soldiers of Christ,"' published in November Manifesto. But such productions never grow
                                old; they are immortal treasures that never decay. The spiritual energy of the testimony ministered by those
                                illuminated and resurrected souls through whom those hymns were given is needed at the present time. Their
                                warfare was not with their fellow beings but with the principalities and powers of darkness enthroned in the
                                human soul. They not only pointed but led the way to the higher life; to an emancipation from the lower,
                                into the spiritual resurrection. We would extend thanks to Elder Ernest Pick for "speaking out in meeting"
                                in November Manifesto. The nail was hit square on the head. The truth can not be compromised by a bold
                                proclamation of its position, but only by those who with fear and trembling are cowed by the phantom lions
                                in the way and which disappear when bravely met. With this closing essay we would extend thanks to the
                                Editor and printers of The Manifesto and to all who have given their best thoughts silently and through the
                                medium of the pen for its support.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>Hamilton DeGraw</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Russell, Sanford J. K." TEIform="index"/>Sanford J. K. Russell
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Russell, Sanford J. K." TEIform="persName">Sanford J. K. Russell</persName>, at Union Village, Ohio. Nov. 10,
                                1899. Age 81 years, 5 mo. and 28 days. He has been a good Believer many years and held many places and
                                offices of trust—all of which he discharged with fidelity and faithfulness. O. C. II.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Libbey, Frank O." TEIform="index"/>Frank O. Libbey
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Libbey, Frank O." TEIform="persName">Frank O. Libbey</persName>, at Alfred, Maine. Oct. 20, 1899. Age 29 years
                                and 8 mo. Been among Believers seventeen years.</p></div3></div2><pb n="191" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">INDEX. Abutilon/The Another, Help One Able, We Are B. 1'sigc. 128 - ICO 1(54 Book, A Xew - - - - 3 Be, I Will Be
                            What I Will To 15 Below, Always Some One - 45 Best, My ----- 48 Busy, Keeping - 57 Best, Bring the 73 Bellmire,
                            W. W.—Letter - - 152 C. Careful, Martha, Thou Art - - (58 Can, The Best You - (54 Communism, Christian - - 84
                            Culture, ----- yg Christ, The Mission of Disciples of 102 Character, The Mellowing of - 120 Christ, The Love of
                            - 139 Come, Thy Kingdom - 155 Christ, The Soldiers of - - 162 Conference, The Peace - 160 D. Dole, Soplironia In
                            Memory of 44 Doctrines, Strange - - - 65 Discovery, A - - - - 72 Page. East Canterbury, A Visit to - 9 Eat, The
                            Food We 45, (52, 78, 95, 111 Experience, ----- 120 Enemy, My - 127 Forgiveness,..... 160 Faint, He Giveth Power
                            to the - 163 Forgiveness, Retaliation and - 171 Fire, The Refiner's - - - 176 G. Growth, ----- 38 Gilead, Balm
                            in - 67 Gospel, Blessings of the - - 94 Glory, Scenes of - 147 Government, The Art of - - 149 H. Home, Notes
                            About 11, 26, 42, 58, 74, 90, 100 122, 140, 156, 172, 187. Harvard Shakers, Eldress of the - 23 Hazzard, Mary,
                            Autobiography of 53 Hands, The Heart and the - 161 Heartily, Do Your Work - - 176 I. Illustration, An - Invalid,
                            Thoughts Penned by an 41 52 A. <pb n="192" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 192 THE MANIFESTO. Pa rage. Inheritance, The Old 113 115
                            Instrumentalities, ... 169 Relation, The Virgin - 147 Introspection, - ... 182 Reform, - 151 .T. Request, A - -
                            - - - 185 Jesus, The Disciples of 17 S. K. Sanitary, ----- 31, 47 Kaime, Joanna J., In Remembrance 38 Spirit,
                            The Holy ... 39 Kindness, - 87 Suffering, Perfect Through 41 L. Self-denial, - - 70 Life, Lay Down Thy 7 Shine,
                            Let Your Light 81 Lewis, Polly C, Tribute to - 37 Smith, Eliza R., In Memory of - 86 Life, The New - (59
                            Soliloquy, - 100 Love, The New - - 80 Shepherd, The Kind - - . - 128 Love, ------ 121 Scriptures, Search the 129
                            Loved, If You Want To Be - 128 Side, On the Other - 131 Lee, Mother Ann - 138 Smith, Benjamin II., A Farewell to
                            134 Lee, Mother Ann - 154 V. Light, A Search - 108 Trifles, - 33 Libbey, Frank 0., In Memory of - 18(5 Truth,
                            Reign of - - - 82 M. Thyself, Know - 83 Mediation, The Order of 20, 85, 55 , (58 Think? Why Not - - 99 Manna,
                            The Hidden - 49 Trust, - 125 Messages, Easter - 93 These,"The Least of - 149 Magnets, Cycles and - 104 V.
                            Manifesto, The Voice of The 179 Vision, A Dream or - 1(5 Mother Ann, Our ... 180 Voice, The Still Small - 177
                            Messenger, The ... - 181 w. Wilderness, Wandering in the - 30 O. Weaving, - - 47 Overshadowing, The Divine 185
                            Wanted, - - - . - 118 On, Move ----- 145 Work, Finish Thy - - - - 137 P. Worrying, - - - - - 175 Peace, - 5
                            Wesley, From John - 184 O'.J Promises, God's ... 97 Y. Yore, Days of 7 Principle, Unerring - 101 Yet, Not .... -
                                176<pb id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. DEATHS. Bloomberg, Andrew Bullard, Marcia M. Bruce, Willa Copley,
                            Elizabeth, Sr. Dole, Sophronia Dole, Laura Hardin, Tabitha A. Hazzard, Mary Hart, Charlotte - - Johnson, William
                            Kaime, Joanna J. - Kirsten, Caroline W. Lewis, Polly C. Libbey Frank O., Mayer, Philip J. McGaughey, Huldah
                            Minor, Philinda Massie, Charles Pilot, Maria . . Prouty, Harriet Russell, Sanford J. K. Smith, Zelinda Steadman,
                            Thomas Smith, Eliza R. Smith, Benjamin H. Taylor, Caroline Ward, Maria L. Page. 32 - 96 112 - 64 48 )) 96 - 32 -
                            160 32 - 192 16 32 ii - 112 80 - 176 192 - 48 - 96 128 - 80 48</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hands drop off—the work goes on" TEIform="index"/>THE HANDS DROP OFF-THE WORK GOES ON</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Bradley, B. F. Kent" TEIform="persName"/>B. F. Kent Bradley</byline><p TEIform="p">Whether it he to rear in stone Vast pyramids in Egypt's sand; Or girdle with defensive zone, The boundaries of a
                            mighty land; In all the grandest "works of time, That human power or thought hath won, Recruits fill up the
                            broken line, The hands drop off—the work goes on. Man's thoughts reach out beyond their age, Like lanterns
                            shining in the dark; Transmitted through the bard and. sage, God guards with jealous care, each spark. What
                            needs to live will live; the truth Waits centuries for a tongue of fire, And in its own immortal youth Springs
                            up from gibbet, stake and pyre. We stand sometimes in mute dismay To see a great man die. "His place, What
                            living man can fill?" we say; "Histho'ts what lesser mind embrace?" "Such loss!" we murmur in despair; So much
                            devised, so little done." A voice sounds through the viewless air, "His hands drop off—the work goes on." Time
                            proves it so. ISTo wheels are stopped, Progress and science claim their own; The mantle that our hero dropped,
                            On other shoulders has been thrown; Worn loosely for a time perchance, But as the sire, shall grow the son; God
                            leads, himself, the grand advance, The hands drop off—the work goes on. Who rights the wrong, who breaks the
                            chain From limbs long fettered without cause, Or from our statutes wipes the stain Of evil and oppressive laws,
                            Must work, and trust to God and time, Nor hope with mortal eyes to see The dawning of the day sublime, The
                            harvest white of victory. Sad leader of some noble cause, Measuring thy work by life's few years, Thou reckonest
                            but by finite laws, Give to the winds thy idle fears. Though in the conflict face to face Thou fall'st before
                            the day be won, Some heart inspired shall fill thy place, The ranks close up—the work goes on. Grand hope! Sweet
                            comfort! Build thy plans And sow thy seed with careful thought; In God's good time if not in man's The miracle
                            of growth is wrought. Thine eyes may close before the day That crowns the work so well begun; "He sowed, the
                            grateful gleaners say, That we may reap—his work goes on."</p></div2><pb id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><!--
                        <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>"GENTLE MANNERS." A Guide to Good M'obals. Published at East Canterbury, N. H. "Nothing on earth is more beloved
                            and honored in the world's great heart, than a noble youth, whose aims are high, and whose life is a moral
                            essay." Gilt edged—20 cts., postage 4 cts. Boards, 16 cts. postage 4 cts. Paper, 10 cts. postage 2 cts.
                            Address—H. C. Bljnn. East Canterbury, N. H. SHAKER HAMAMELIS (WITCHHAZEL,) A. remedy for Cuts, Burns, Scalds,
                            Headache, Sore Throat and all cases of external inflammation Taken internally for Bowel Complaint, Bleeding of
                            the Lungs or Bowels, and for all aohes and pains. For use externally, bathe the parts and lay on a cloth wet
                            with the Extract. Internally, take one half teaspoonful three times a day. Use hot or cold. Ask your druggist
                            for it or send your order to Arthur Bruce, East Canterbury, N. H. "INTERPRETING PROPHECY" AND THE "Appearing of
                            Christ," is the title of a neat little pamphlet of some forty pages, just sent out by A. G. Hollister of Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y. The many at the present time who are interested in the fulfillment of prophecy, and in its
                            mathematical calculation, will find themselves by the side of the good old prophet Daniel, and with him
                            illustrating the Coming of Christ so clearly that no occasion can arise for the least doubt. Price, 10 cts. 60
                            YEARS' EXPERIENCE Trade Marks Designs . . Copyrights &c. Anyone sending a sketch and description may
                            quickly ascertain our opinion free ¦whether an invention is probably patentable. Communications strictly
                            confidential. Handbook on Patents sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents. Patents taken through Munn
                            & Co. receive ipecial notice, without charge, in the Scientific American. A handsomely illustrated
                            weekly. largest circulation of any scientific journal. Terms, $3 a year; four months, f 1. Sold by all
                            newsdealers. MUNN 4 Co.881*—-* New York Branch Office, 625 F St., Washington, D. C. FREE to advanced thought
                            people—sample copy of the most original and practical occult journal of the age. The exponent of West Gate
                            Philosophy. A. new occult system.—-An unlimited field of labor open to teachers, lecturers and healers.
                            Address,— The OMACLE, Sta. A. Boston, Mass. HAVE YOU ''COMMON SENSE?" If not, send at once for a free copy of
                            this liberal-minded advocate of advanced thought, which brings health and success. Address— "Common Sense," M.
                            O. 55 State St. Chicago, 111. AUTHORISED RULES OF THE SHAKER COMMUNITY. The religious basis of the Order must be
                            a foundation resting on the principle of righteousness, which principle is God. This should rule the life of the
                            individual for the protection of his own soul, for the peace of the family and as an evidence of his upright
                            standing before the world. Price, 10 cts.</p>
                    </div2>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>