<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1003" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><date value="18800301" TEIform="date">March 1880</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">49-72</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> MARCH, 1880. MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) G. A, LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, N. Y. Published by the United Societies.
                        OUR HOME AT HARVARD, MASS. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony "Go preach the Kingdom, of God! " ADDRESS ALL
                        COMMUNICATIONS TO " The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1880. The Shaker Vol. X. No. 3. 60
                        Cents Per AnnuM </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="49" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sowing and the tending the harvest" TEIform="index"/>THE SOWING AND THE TENDING THE HARVEST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. HAMPTON</byline><p TEIform="p"> " He that goeth forth and weepeth, bearing precious seed, shall doubtless come again with
                            rejoicing, bringing his sheaves with him." When about twelve years old I began to have a
                            dread of death — not merely when I happened casually to think of it, but I was for two years
                            haunted almost day and night with this hideous spectre, which to me at this time was
                            synonymous with total annihilation, as I had no faith whatever in the immortality of the
                            soul. In my fourteenth year I was so completely wrapped in the gloomy shrouds of despair,
                            that most of my time when alone was spent in tears, but not in prayer, for I neither knew
                            nor cared for any God. Not knowing how to obtain any relief, and almost insane with a
                            hopeless, secret sorrow, I consulted one of the ancient elders and sages of our institution,
                            to discover if there was any possible escape from the horrors of my situation, other than
                            suicide ; for I had fully made up my mind that this, my mental agony, was no longer
                            endurable. He proposed to me a sincere confession of all my sins as a commencement of a
                            process by which this terrible nightmare of fear and foreboding might be lifted from my
                            mind. I saw no relation whatever between the disease and the proposed cure ; for I had never
                            committed any sins worth naming, and I felt no conviction for what few I had committed.
                            However, I was convinced I must do something, and so confessed all my sins honestly, and was
                            for a short timli relieved from my awful gloom and sorrow. But it returned, and I bid
                            defiance to mortal power to remove it. But, as I turned into my fifteenth year, I all at
                            once blazed out into a perfect conflagration of passions, lusts, desires, appetites from the
                            lower strata of my being, which threatened to instantly burn up and sink into the lowest
                            hell of infamy and destruction, all my higher, purer instincts and aspirations. Accompanying
                            this state of mind was a most profound conviction for sin, and a sense of ruin, misery and
                            hell, so intense, that all my previous sorrow was a mere dust in the balance compared to it.
                            As soon as I perceived this declared war of the lower elements, I mustered all my higher and
                            holier energies to overcome and conquer these enemies of my eternal peace (for I felt they
                            were nothing less). This surely was a terrible time. I went down into the very bottom of the
                            Jordan, and scarcely ascended for a period of three years. A very great portion of this time
                            I was in prayers and page. - page. The Sowing and the Tending the Harvest, - 4!&gt; Queries and
                            Answers, ----- 65 Teachings or False Theology, Infidelity, and Radical Utterances, - - - - -
                            66 True Religion, - ----- 50 The Children's Grotto, 67 Unity of Faith, . ... - 51 Music:
                            Gilbert Motier, Marquis De Lafayette, - - 52 Crown of Grace, - - - - - 68 Among the Shakers
                            — III, - - - - 56 Home Topics,...... 69 Rest, --------58 Society Record, - - - - - ¦ - 70
                            Meezhahquod, ------ 59 Agricultural, ------ 70 Correspondence, ------ 61 Gems from
                            Contemporaries, - - - - 71 Editorial : " Puckered-Pursedness," 72 Maintenance of Shakerism,
                            62 Theological Tobacco, - - - - - 72 Editorial Notes, ------ 63 <pb n="50" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 50 THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. tears, and for about one whole year opened my mind nearly every day, and
                            for some weeks two or three times a day. But from the first moment of this conflict with
                            those lower energies of my nature, every vestige of my former, youthful, sorrows, fears and
                            agonies, fled away forever. Was there not then a congruity between the disease and the
                            method of cure proposed by the venerable sage and good elder? For many years I was obliged,
                            over and over, to re-enter the field of those conflicts and fight for my freedom from these
                            lower instincts (the very worst of all tyrants); but since I first commenced this war, I do
                            not recollect of having once yielded or compromised with my adversary. So much for
                        Sowing.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Teachings of false theology, infidelity and true religion" TEIform="index"/>TEACHINGS OF
                            FALSE THEOLOGY, INFIDELITY, AND TRUE RELIGION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p"> The mission of The Shaker Manifesto is first, to diagnose the present status of humanity,
                            physically, socially, morally, and religiously. 2. To suggest appropriate remedies for the
                            abnormal and diseased conditions of human society. 3. To set forth clearly, the distinction
                            between the good, natural or earthly man, and the good, spiritual or heavenly man. 4. To
                            teach the true standard of pure religion. 5. To bear that testimony from Heaven which shall
                            be a searcher of the hearts and tryer of the reins of human character and life. The Son of
                            God, as seen by St. John, was heard to say : " All the churches shall know that I am he who
                            searcheth the reins and hearts, and I will give unto every one according to their works."
                            But worldly ministers are employed in excusing the lives of men, in that religion consists
                            in believing that character avails nothing in the final awards of destiny ! Souls are lost
                            and saved (not from sin) but from sufferings by sin, through faith that Jesus Christ
                            suffered in their room and stead ! Thus mankind substitute conventional beliefs and
                            institutions for religion, and call" things by wrong names ; and at length,
                            conventionalities become impurities. So much wickedness and cruelty have been wrought under
                            the profession and name of Christianity, that the name '' Ghristian " is to millions a
                            reproach — a by-word of contempt. But, dominion over conscience is Antichrist, always and
                            anywhere, whether the result of the arm of national religion, law, force of custom,
                            conventional institution, theological dogmatism, creed, through individual sins or
                            blindness. In science, art, mechanics, mankind learn that the ultimatum of perfection is the
                            result of simples 1 The revelation of truth teaches the same thing in religion. Cease to be
                            the servants of sin by the cessation of the violations of convictions of righteous duty.
                            Elisha, the Prophet, taught a simple remedy for cure of palsy: "Go and wash seven times in
                            Jordan." The meaning of " Jordan " is "judgment." Thus was shown the cleansing of the
                            leprous soul, a soul diseased by sin— by washing, cleansing, coming many times to judgment —
                            confessing and repenting of sin. Benighted humanity deals in opposite extremes, both beyond
                            the bounds of truth, overdrawn, like a caricature. Thus theologians teach : " Three males as
                            God, of whom Jesus is one." Infidelity teaches : " No God hut Nature." True religion teaches
                            : " God a duality,— a Heavenly Father and Heavenly Mother — the creative powers of the
                            universe. Theology false: A Heaven beyond blue skies for an elected few. Infidelity : No
                            Heaven but earth, and the pleasures of sense. True religion : Heaven, the bliss of doing
                            good, and being good. Theology, false; Hell of eternal torments for those elected to
                            damnation, be their deeds good or evil. Infidelity: No hell for any sinners, here nor
                            hereafter, excepting the wary entrapments of fellow-man. True religion: Hell, inevitably
                            experienced sufferings; the results of violations of God's laws ; comprising sufferings
                            physical, mental and spiritual. Theology, false : Tortures of Catholic in <pb n="51" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 51 quisition for lack of belief in man-made creeds', a God-ordained
                            duty. Persecutions and tortures of Protestant inquisitions for faith in creeds opposite to
                            Protestant ideal truth. True religion : Freedom of conscience and blessings of peace and
                            salvation rendered unto all souls who will live the Christ life. Theology false: Belief in
                            the plenary inspiration of every word between the lids of the Bible, and similar approximate
                            ideas. Infidelity: No belief in any portion of the Bible, nor even in the existence of Jesus
                            Christ nor his disciples; the whole a myth. True religion : A recognition of a portion of
                            the Bible as a record of God's truth; a revelation from God, and a necessary guide to life ;
                            but many instructions and tolerations of the Bible adapted to one age of humanity, not
                            adapted to succeeding ages of progress. Portions of the biblical record, a history of human
                            weakness, wickedness and depravity much to be deplored. Theology false: Eesurrection of the
                            physical body of Jesus being the true resurrection of the Lord. Infidelity : No resurrection
                            of either body or soul ; but death, an eternal sleep. True religion: The Christian
                            resurrection, a raising of the soul from death (the fruit of sin) to life (the fruit of
                            righteousness), to obedience to God's laws, being life eternal. Theology false: Day of
                            judgment a time to come when the world shall be consumed with eternal fire ! Infidelity: No
                            day of judgment ever to occur. True religion: The day of judgment a period experienced by
                            any soul, when by the light of truth, transgressions of its laws are discovered by that soul
                            in its life's career, and it confesses those deeds of transgression to witnessing souls,
                            who, in like manner have confessed and repented, or are repenting of sin. The law of eternal
                            truth leads mankind to a life of benedictions, services to fellowman, sacrifices of self to
                            do God's will for the benefit of fellow-beings ; a holy com. munion with the pure, good and
                            wise /</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unity of faith" TEIform="index"/>UNITY OF FAITH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eads, Hervey L." TEIform="persName"/>HERVEY L. EADS</byline><p TEIform="p"> It is generally believed by the outside world that the Shakers, like their ecclesiastical
                            bodies, have a written creed which all must believe, and to which all must subscribe, who
                            apply for admission into our body. Herein I propose to disabuse the public mind in this
                            regard, by disclosing the fact that the Shakers have no written creed, being founded on
                            revelation; on this rock we propose to build and there remain. Nevertheless, there are some
                            things necessary to insure success to applicants, if it be proper to use the term things to
                            conditions. These are : First. They should have an inward awakening to enable them to sense
                            the " exceedingly sinfulness of sin." Second. They should have an internal desire to be
                            freed from it and to live a higher, purer and more angelic life than they find it possible
                            to do in the world. Third. They should, even if they are of the highest class, and among the
                            most learned of the lower world, be willing to be taught the way out of sin and into a holy
                            life. If their object in coming is to teach instead of being taught they had better not
                            apply, because the child spirit only will insure success. Fourth. It is necessary they
                            should believe that God is ; and that He is the new order of those who faithfully serve Him,
                            and that He is a God of order in all things and has the same established among men, and
                            which, when found, must be submitted to in order to come into harmony with Him. Fifth. They
                            should be willing to bring all the deeds and sins of their past lives to the light of this
                            order and be taught how to shun them in future. Sixth. None should ever apply merely for the
                            " loaves and fishes ;" all such are sure to fail. Seventh. They should be willing to "put
                            their hands to work and their heart to God." All who have gained these conditions are ripe
                            for the harvest and ready for a life and home in God's Zion, and may confidently expect to
                            be successful in working out their <pb n="52" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. own salvation.
                            All those who have not gained these conditions would do well to pause and not apply. It will
                            be asked: Are all within the gates in possession of these conditions? I answer, nay. Being
                            filled with love and sympathy, hope and charity for the down-trodden of our race, we have
                            admitted thousands while only the tens have been succsssful and made their "calling and
                            election sure." We have fully proved the truth of the Saviour's words, " Many are called,
                            but few are chosen." Had none been admitted only such as had the conditions named, we should
                            not have been forced to this sad confession. But I am asked : "Must culture and learning
                            become subordinate to, and be taught by, ignorance 1" Ans. Not by ignorance in spiritual
                            things. But, if this supposed ignorance has found the pearl for which the world, with all
                            its wisdom and learning, has sought in vain, then worldly learning and wisdom must be
                            content to take the lower seat " I thank Thee, Father, that Thou hast hid these things from
                            the wise and prudent and hast revealed them unto babes, even so Father, for so it seemed
                            good in Thy sight." Even when the conditions named are gained, we may still entertain shades
                            of theological dogma, and think variously of many things without detriment of union or
                            gospel travel. In the various educations there are many things imbedded in the intellectual
                            understanding which will take time to correct. Still, unity of faith is desirable in the
                            body, which, to attain, is worth laboring for ; to this end it is suggested to me by a very
                            intelligent Elder, that it would be well to explain more fully the difference between
                            tutelary deities and subordinate gods, than is now apparent to the common reader as set
                            forth in " Shaker Theology, " since their offices seem to be the same, and the existence of
                            one is denied. This I cheerfully do. Tutelary deities are believed to be attributal — that
                            they did not originate by generation in any lower world. This idea originated in heathen
                            lands thousands of years since. They had offices and names for more than 80,000 of them. It
                            arose from the belief that God was not omnipotent in being, and must of necessity have other
                            trustworthy deities to act when and where he could not himself be present. They supposed he
                            had a throne much 'larger than himself in the middle of his universe, on which he sat in
                            regal splendor, with a pleromac world around him filled with attributable deities to send
                            forth to distant planets. Others taught the doctrine that there were two Gods on the throne,
                            one male, the other female, and these deities were their offspring by generation ; hence
                            they worshipped the images of generation. All such as were thus brought into existence or
                            immediately created by God, were termed tutelary deities. God subordinate, or subordinate
                            gods, were persons and angels erroneously so styled, because they were God-appointed agents,
                            by and through whom He chose to enlighten the world. Such were Moses, Elijah, Christ and
                            others. Some otherwise enlightened minds of this day apply to God, condition, figure and
                            extension, properties of matter, thus denying his omnipresence and infinity only in an
                            elementary and diffusive way; that is to say, He is located somewhere in space, diffusing
                            his power as the sun does his light; but this idea is no improvement on the tutelaries, and
                            it will be no hindrance to the gospel travel of any soul to class them both as chimerical,
                            and let them go back to heathen land whence they sprang. So. Union, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gilbert Motier, Marquis de Lafayette, and his experience among the Shakers in 1793, or 1794" TEIform="index"/>GILBERT MOTIER, MARQUIS DE LAFAYETTE, AND HIS EXPERIENCE AMONG THE SHAKERS IN 1783, OR
                            1784</head><p TEIform="p"> The Marquis De Lafayette,- one of the most illustrious names of modern history, was born at
                            Chavaignac, in Auvergne, 1757, and commenced his career at the court of Louis XV, at the
                            period when hostilities were commencing between Britain and her American Colonies. At the
                            age of twenty, he left the presence of his bride, and, fitting out two vessels with arms and
                            provisions, sailed for Boston, was received by Washington and his army with acclamations,
                            and joining their rank as a volunteer, was wounded in his first action, near Phila52 <pb n="53" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 53 delphia, while he commanded the vanguard of
                            the patriot army at the capture of New York. On returning to France when peace was concluded
                            with the mother country, Lafayette found himself immensely popular, and he presently took
                            his seat with the notables convoked in 1787. In the course of his notorious and glorious
                            career in the governmental revolutions in France, during which the royal family twice owed
                            their preservation to his address and courage ; but by reverses of fortune, he was at length
                            captured by the Austrians and imprisoned at Olmutz; was released in 1797, and retired to
                            private life. In 1818 became a member of the Chamber of Deputies, and resuming his career as
                            an advocate of constitutional principles, had the satisfaction of seeing the dream of his
                            life realized in 1830, in France. In 1824 he revisited the United States, and was received
                            with great enthusiasm. But time, more capricious than he, allowed him to see the stone
                            hurled at the feet of his ideal, liberty, and he carried the saddest of all lessons with him
                            to eternity in 1834. Many believers in special providences have considered that the Marquis
                            De Lafayette, was one of the best mediums ever brought under natural inspiration. Before he
                            was twenty years of age he was appointed ill due form to hold rank in the French army. It
                            was at this period the American Colonies were struggling for independence. Prince William,
                            of England, was making a tour through France near where Lafayette's regiment was quartered,
                            and was guest to a French nobleman in that neighborhood and Lafayette was one of a select
                            number invited to dine with him. The loquacious English Prince commenced an unreserved
                            conversation respecting the American War. Perhaps none at that table had any definite
                            knowledge of the character of that struggle, nor the true object the Americans were
                            contending for; with Saxon frankness the Duke talked the whole matter out, without the least
                            duplicity or covering. There is no believer in inspiration in cause and effect but would
                            discern at a glance that his caution was controlled, his perception beclouded and his
                            descriptive powers excited by some higher presiding agency. He is reported to have been very
                            eloquent and candid, and to have represented the Americans as an oppressed people struggling
                            for liberty, though he seemed unconscious of what he was doing. Deep down in the soul of the
                            Marquis lay slumbering a noble patriotism, unbounded liberty, and universal love of his
                            race, and a disposition which would prompt him, when rightly inspired, to sacrifice treasure
                            and pour out his blood like water in defense of the rights of man. The story of the Prince
                            and the spirit which inspired it, thrilled the inexperienced soul of Lafayette, like holy
                            fire ; it awakened the budding powers of his manhood, and aroused the newer and greater
                            qualities of his being into action. In contemplating the man, to many he then seemed
                            quickened and transformed into a new being ; he seemed suddenly to have developed the wisdom
                            of the sage, and the courage and daring of a hero. He soon presented himself as the champion
                            to help crush out tyranny, that human freedom might be erected upon its ruins ; he seemed
                            moulded for the very age in which he lived ; his whole career in the new and old world, and
                            the part he took in both, proves it. Lafayette's first interview with General Washington
                            goes far to prove that he was a strong medium ; passing review under the severe inspection
                            of a master spirit of the same organization. With a board of officers he sat down to dine
                            with Washington, and before the hour had expired, by useful observation and deep impression,
                            his whole character was read, and read correctly by the great American Chief. Lafayette was
                            attracted to Washington at all times as to some guardian angel; he was unconsciously,
                            influenced by spirits which ministered to the father of his country. We introduce this
                            singular man in this manner, to claim that it was not possible for him to enter where any
                            kind of inspiration was agitating human beings, without being excited by it. Among the many
                            confidential labors and missions intrusted to Lafayette, he was sent from Albany to
                            negotiate with the Indian tribes, to take up the war hatchet for the Americans ; in his
                            intercourse with them <pb n="54" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 54 THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. he commanded their
                            veneration and enlisted many of the red warriors in defense of the colonies. It was while on
                            one of those missions that he called on the Shakers at Niskayuna, N. Y.. (now Watervliet).
                            It was an important period in the inspiring commencement of the latter day, a time when many
                            were flocking to Mother Ann Lee, and the Elders with her, to hear the gospel requirements
                            and tidings which brought salvation. A period when all became quickened by the power and
                            inspiration which attended the first witnesses of truth who first proclamed Christ's second
                            appearing. When the Marquis entered the neighborhood of Niskayuna, where the gathering to
                            Mother Ann Lee was fast progressing, he heard of their meetings, and in company with another
                            officer he called to visit them. Among the believers there were many who had been connected
                            with the army from the beginning of the war, some who hed joined Mother Ann's society
                            before, and some after Lafayette had entered the service of the army ; and as both officers
                            were in simple regimental dress, they were readily recognized. He entered, very quietly, the
                            little dwelling where they first held their meetings ; some were conversing, some passing in
                            and out, and some were under singular inspired operations ; among the most eccentric of this
                            class, were the outward manifestations of Abijah Wooster ; he, among many others of strong
                            minds, had investigated diligently, received faith correctly, and believing that Ann Lee was
                            inspired by higher spirits to declare to them the most self-sacrificing testimony and word
                            of God ever written, the power which attended her testimony had set them all on fire, and in
                            great commotion. According to the laws which control organizations it was utterly impossible
                            for Lafayette, with his singular powers, to enter a place with such surroundings, and not
                            feel the state of the spiritual atmosphere, and the electric current into which he had
                            entered. Lafayette was of a tall,manly,commanding form, and was the observed by many, and he
                            was silently and busily engaged in closely inspecting the strange scene before him ; true to
                            his mediumistic powers and instinct s where the most remarkable inspiration was, apparent,
                            there he was the soonest attracted. Abijah Wooster was at that time under perpetual
                            agitations, shaking, jerking, twisting in sudden convulsions. Seated on the back side of the
                            room, Lafayette passed directly through the crowd, and quietlyseated himself by his side,
                            and to him devoted his undivided attention. He did not seem attracted to the man but the
                            power that controlled and moved him; he looked steadily and watchfully upon him, and when
                            agitated and moved, would lay his hand upon the limbs of the subject thus agitated. By thus
                            closely observing him at all times, by laying on his hands much of the time, and continuing
                            his investigations persistently, it embarrassed Abijah greatly ; he said he felt Lafayette
                            to be a powerful spirit that brought him into great bondage ; wishing to break this
                            disagreeable spell and find relief from it, and the singular freedom thus taken with his
                            gifts and person, he said to Lafayette: " You seem desirous of obtaining this power ; " but
                            the only answer received was : "It is desirable!" By this time Abijah became so thoroughly
                            disconcerted that he suddenly arose and walked out of the door; Lafayette rose as suddenly
                            and followed him. Determined to make good his escape from him, he cast about in his mind to
                            determine what he should do next, and finally went down to the barn ; but his investigator
                            followed on and went to the barn also. The condition of the pursued was rendered more
                            awkward in every movement the pursuer continued to make ; and to make it appear to Lafayette
                            that he had business there, Abijah seized the broom and went to sweeping up the barn floor,
                            taking all the pains to clean and put the place in order that was necessary; but the
                            patience of Lafayette was not to be exhausted, for speechless and motionless he serenely
                            waited to see what the next move would be. Abijah now started for the house, but close on
                            his footsteps followed Lafayette, more faithful than a brother. Eesolved to escape at all
                            hazards, Abijah lifted a hatchway, and walked down into the cellar, still closely <pb n="55" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 55 followed by the man who was not to be shaken off for
                            trifles, who descended into the cellar also. The confusion of Abijah at this period of the
                            chase may be imagined, but not easily described, but he rallied, and resolved upon one more
                            effort. A rude ladder extended from the cellar to the room above ; this Abijah hastily
                            ascended, but as hastily was followed up by the unrelenting Lafayette. In all these moves,
                            turns and overturns, nothing like ridicule or levity was apparent in Lafayette, but a
                            settled determination to learn what influence or power controlled Abijah and caused upon him
                            such strange movements and commotion. When they returned to the room Mother Ann and some of
                            the elders were there, and by these Lafayette was soon drawn into conversation; and as they
                            soon became earnest in this, Abijah, thinking he had already obtained his share of the
                            entertainment seized a favorable moment to slip away. What followed after that he learned
                            from the Brethren and Sisters present at the interview. Lafayette inquired what the nature
                            of the religious movement among them was, that brought so many people together. Mother Ann
                            described to him the work that believers were entering into; that the kingdom of Christ was
                            gradually opening upon the world, and many were awakened to see their lost condition and
                            were coming to judgment ; that after passing through the work of cleansing the soul, by the
                            oral confession of all sin to the elders of the church, they received the spirit of Christ
                            and became inspired with the true light, and the power of salvation from sin. Lafayette
                            inquired to know why he could not share in this power as well as othersMother Ann, now under
                            inspiration, declared to him that his time had not come to share in this spirit. She seemed
                            to enter quite into his case, and informed him that a great work lay before him on the earth
                            plane, and that he would have to pass through a wide field of sufferings, before he could
                            ever receive the gospel of salvation. In after years he may possibly have called the words
                            of this singular prophetess to remembrance, when what was promised him under inspiration
                            became a great fact in his sorrowful life. It may often have came back to his meditation, as
                            he lay bound, for years, in the old dungeons of Olmutz and Magdeburgh. However, this may
                            have been in the bloody struggles of the French Revo. lution,or in his exile in foreign
                            lands, something of the kind was unquestionably reviewed in his recollection, when his
                            spirit took its flight from the noble earth-farm of the Marquis De Lafayette. Many yet
                            remember the startling intelligence that reached America of his sudden death. After his
                            decease was reported in Paris, the first packet that came to America brought the sad news;
                            but immediately minister ing spirits, at the time of Ms death, honored the Shakers with the
                            first reliable dispatches. The first night after his death, one of the brethren at New
                            Lebanon saw in vision Lafayette and many others near him, and from his own spirit learned
                            that he had passed into the regions of immortality. The Prophet Daniel's vision was no more
                            certain to him than this was to the more modern visionist. From the impression made, the
                            dreamer was so confident of the fact that when he arose with the morning, he stated, without
                            qualification, that Lafayette had gone to the spirit land. The statement made its
                            impression, the dream of course was remembered, the date recorded, and when the tidings
                            reached this continent, all was verified. Washington was born to break the strong chain
                            which bound the colonies to the old world ; Lafayette was led by that power which guides the
                            destiny of nations, to join hands with Washington, and pass through the first fiery
                            struggle, and be taught by his genius, and to drink deeply of his inspiration. Their real
                            labors lay in two hemispheres. Washington ever cherished the same tender recollections of
                            Layfayette that a father would for a beloved son. In the bloody struggle of the French
                            Revolution, the sympathy of Washington was the strongest power which supported the marquis,
                            and, while struggling through the gloomy years of prison-life, the toils he had shared and
                            the good he had done under the father of his country, were among his most sustaining
                            recollections. <pb n="56" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 56 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. After obtaining his liberty,
                            he still toiled on for the welfare of France, and died as he had lived, imitating the
                            example of the man he held dear, and who had long used all his influence to obtain his
                            liberation On the hard fought field of the American Revolution he formed a tender
                            acquaintance with the old patriots and heroes who gained for America her independence. When
                            his tried spirit was released from the fetters of mortality, his spirit instinctively turned
                            to his dearest friend Washington, and to his old associates in the army of revolutionary
                            notoriety in this hemisphere. When his stormy life was closed, and he was awakened to
                            realize his entrance into the abodes of the departed from earth, the first consolation he
                            sought was the sympathy and friendship of the noble patriots who first found a place in his
                            youthful affections. In this far-off nation were the dearest objects of his love, and here
                            he took his course. Inspiration teaches that many of these spirit friends were then in the
                            work of God in the spirit-land. At the head of these stood Washington, who, like a guardian
                            angel, stood ready to gather into the order of redemption all who had suffered and bled with
                            him in defense of the rights of man. It would seem certain that many of these early friends,
                            like ministering spirits, hovered over the dying couch to soothe the last agonies of the
                            noble French hero. No doubt they were anxious to conduct him to that resting-place where
                            they had found the treasures of immortality and eternal life ; and when his soul had broken
                            the fetters of clay, they tenderly conveyed him to their own resting-place. Under these
                            considerations, how singular appears to have been his first attractions to Mother Ann and
                            the Elders of the Shaker Church while he was a soldier in the army— a man of earth, and
                            destined to act as the Champion and Leader for long years, in some of the most thrilling
                            scenes in which man ever suffered ? How simple are Heaven's mysterious providences! That
                            such a man could be thus inspired and touched with hallowed fire, in the morning of life, in
                            his attraction to Believers in the mission of Christ Second Appearing, and to fix his
                            attention upon the great fact which was to secure his salvation when scenes of earth should
                            close upon him forever.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Among the Shakers: III" TEIform="index"/>AMONG THE SHAKERS: III</head><p TEIform="p"> There may be among the Shakers those who are common-place, peculiar, or bigoted, but there
                            are certainly some who are fine, intelligent men and women. I recall one pleasant-faced,
                            motherly woman, who took me in charge on my first visit, showed and explained things, at the
                            same time asking me questions about my family, and telling me her own history and experience
                            in a quiet, gentle and yet dignified manner. It was a real pleasure to look upon her face,
                            with its broad, full forehead and modest, gentle eyes. I used to watch her as she went round
                            with the others in meeting, and think what a saintly looking woman she was. Not a harsh
                            expression, I was told, had ever come from her while she had been there. She told me that
                            her husband had visited the Shakers with the intention of joining them, but he changed his
                            mind, while she learned to believe in them, and left him and joined them with his full
                            consent. When I spoke to her of their small number of converts she said with great fervor
                            and earnestness, that was nothing to her ; she would still be a Shaker if there were only
                            one more in the world, as the number did not alter the truth. There was another woman of a
                            different type, though no less sincere in her belief. She had married while young a man of
                            wealth and position in Boston; but afterward became intensely interested in Adventist
                            doctrines, and it was said had with others prepared herself for the expected second coming
                            of Christ upon a certain day. She subsequently learned of Shakerism, and became one of its
                            most zealous advoates. She tried in vain to convert her husband, and at length considered it
                            her duty to leave him, although she had at the time hree children, the youngest an infant.
                            She liad fully intended to take this infant with tier ; but on the day of her departure her
                                <pb n="57" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. husband utterly refused to allow her to do
                            so. This proved a great trial, yet she determined not to abandon her faith. But it was a
                            long time before she could get the baby's cries out of her mind. Night after night they were
                            ringing in her ears, but she reflected that it was in every way well taken care of. She
                            entered into her new faith with great ardor, and seemed to think it only natural that she
                            should sacrifice her own personal feelings upon the altar of her faith. She was ardent and
                            enthusiastic in spirit, an active mind, spoke often with spirit and earnestness in the
                            meetings, and wrote many articles in favor of Shaker life and principles. After about thirty
                            years' experience in a Shaker Community she displayed no regret, but seemed to have only a
                            consciousness of having acted her part and done her duty in this world, and was satisfied
                            with herself for having done it. She was young looking, sprightly and robust, and had
                            enjoyed much better health, she said, since she had lived according to her conscience than
                            previously. I have already mentioned the Elder of one of the Families as being distinguished
                            for his sociability, but his history deserves more special mention. He speaks of himself as
                            having been as a young man one of the wildest of the wild. He happened to be working at his
                            trade near a Shaker settlement, and often heard of them in various ways. He laughed at and
                            ridiculed them as much as any one could, never dreaming of ever becoming a believer in their
                            doctrines. He visited them occasionally out of curiosity, and was at length led into
                            discussion with an elderly woman of the Family, who talked to him very plainly, and
                            presented certain questions to him so forcibly and so different from what he expected that
                            he became convinced the Shakers had the truth. He joined them at twenty-five years of age,
                            with life all before him. He possessed a vigorous mind and body, and devoted himself heart
                            and soul to living up to all the requirements of the new faith. To him this was no child's
                            play. He was a man of strong passions and affections, and it was only by great power of will
                            and prolonged effort that he was able to subdue himself and conform to Shaker purity. When
                            we saw him at the age of seventyfive he was firm in the conviction that he had been called
                            upon to live such a life, and that if he had neglected to live so here he would have been
                            compelled under greater difficulties to live it hereafter. He was the head of a Family whose
                            duty it was to receive visitors, and he explained the Shaker theories to strangers, and took
                            the chief part as speaker at their public meetings. He was by no means a fine speaker, his
                            ideas being often roughly expressed; but he had the merit, in common with most Shakers, of
                            speaking to the point. A different kind of man altogether was one who held the position of
                            Trustee for the Society. He had been brought there by his parents when a child, with a
                            number of brothers and sisters. They were a delicate family, and a number of them died of
                            consumption. One brother left and engaged in business in a neighboring city, and the one of
                            whom I am speaking was the only one left among the Shakers. He was a tall, fine-looking man,
                            with delicate, refined and clear-cut features; a man of very few words, but when he spoke he
                            showed that he thought much, and his ideas proved him to be a man of good common sense,
                            without a particle of bigotry. He had so much gentleness of manner as to be almost womanly,
                            though never weak nor effeminate. He always showed a good deal of kindly regard for children
                            and for whatever required protection. It seemed impossible for anything or any one to suffer
                            at his hands; and yet at the same time he had such a quiet persistency in defending what he
                            thought right that he usually gained his object. His mind seemed to be progressive in every
                            thing, and he was in favor of any thing which would have modernized the Shakers and taken
                            them out of the ruts into which they had fallen. He favored the introduction of new
                            machinery and inventions, the formation of classes for higher education, etc., but he had to
                            work cautiously and quietly among people who look with suspicion upon novelties. He was
                            clearly in advance of his surroundings, though he was in harmony with the faith in its more
                            intelligent form. 57 <pb n="58" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 58 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Had he been in the
                            outside world there is no doubt but that he would have reached eminence and wealth. In fact
                            it is easy to imagine him the proprietor of large mills or workshops, with a flourishing and
                            wellordered community springing up around him, of whose interests and welfare he is as
                            careful as of his own. There were many others whom I should like to mention, but perhaps
                            these will serve to show that the Shakers are people of like desires, thoughts and feelings
                            with ourselves, and that it has been just as hard for them to sacrifice themselves as it
                            would be for any of us. We may think that they have no connection with ourselves, but in the
                            long run I think it will be found that they have largely influenced public sentiment in
                            America. Perhaps no person can live without in some degree changing and modifying the
                            circumstances of hundreds of others, and so the Shakers, though seldom obtruding themselves
                            upon public no. tice, have for the past hundred years been quietly changing or strengthening
                            public opinion in various ways, either directly or through the influence of others. The best
                            writers on political economy seem to be approaching very near Shaker doctrine in their views
                            on communism and the advancement of women. It may seem from the foregoing as though I were
                            in favor of Communism, but I think no one can have a greater aversion to Communistic and
                            Socialistic theories in general. There has seemed to me to be in them so much unsound and
                            unreasoning sophistry, that I scarcely had toleration enough to consider them at all. Had it
                            not been that I had met with some who were not gainers but losers by Communism, and who
                            lived it not for themselves but for the common good, I should not have thought a moment upon
                            it; and in trying to do the Shakers justice I am led to believe, so far as I can understand
                            the subject, that at the bottom of much that is repulsive, unnatural and inconsistent in
                            their system, there is a germ of truth, which in the far-off future may develop into
                            something which may justly be called Communism, but which will bear very little resemblance
                            to the Communism of to-day. All the enterprises for the promotion of the common good are
                            tendencies in this direction, such as many public institutions, the common-school
                            provisions, colonization, co-operation, and all those things which, based on the idea that
                            men are equal, tend to make them so. Many of the Socialists of to-day reject Christianity,
                            but there is nothing so Communistic in the highest sense as the Christian religion. All its
                            precepts and teachings are for the equalization and uniting of people all over the world,
                            and binding them together in one common interest. Heaven itself is pictured as a place where
                            all are made equal; where there are no rich, no poor, no weak or infirm, but where
                            disabilities of all kinds are removed, and the highest and broadest Communism prevails. And
                            it may be so that in future it will be possible to have a type of it here on earth; that
                            mankind may become so enlightened, and live so much in accordance with natural and moral
                            laws, that the fact of mind being more than matter and life being more than meat will.be
                            universally recognized; and that the presence of a human being in this world will be enough
                            to entitle him to all the earth affords!</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rest" TEIform="index"/>REST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brainard, Jane M." TEIform="persName"/>JANE M. BRAINARD</byline><p TEIform="p"> Looking around us we behold upon the face of creation an expression of harmonious rest,
                            suggestive of comfort and quiet, without conflict. All nature is subject to divine law, and
                            moves to immutable plans of the great Law Giver ; man only differing from other Deific
                            attributes through the power of free agency, which has been conferred upon him above all
                            other works of the Divine Architect. Hence we deem him, originally, the most perfect of all
                            God's handiwork. But per force of his free agency he has wandered from his divine origin,
                            and restlessness and dissatisfaction are the evident results. Not in mature minds only is
                            this unrest apparent, for we often see it in the tiny infant; it dawns with life and seems
                            to follow its course from the cradle to the grave ; and many come in and go out of existence
                            in this life without knowing the <pb n="59" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 59 blessing of
                            rest, sweet rest! But as law and precision govern the entire universe, man, with all his
                            obstinacy, must succumb to the natural law of his finite being, and in harmony with all
                            creation yield to the attractions of the stronger powers of light, and thus grow away from
                            darkness into the stronger elements of light. That light is stronger than darkness, is
                            evident to every intelligent mind, not only materially speaking, but spiritually, also ; and
                            by reason of this plain fact mankind have in many instances been caused to avoid dark ways
                            and places and have been drawn towards the light of a new life that would take them back to
                            God ; for the precious soul belongs to its Maker, and can never find justification in
                            material things beyond the use and not the abuse of the things of time. We know there are
                            causes for unrest to our bodies ; but if our minds are at peace with God these can easily be
                            borne. How many have wandered to and fro through earth's domain in pursuit of rest, but
                            finding it not, because their interior lives were at variance with the higher principles of
                            true Christianity. Artificial means may serve to allay the fiercer feelings of unrest for
                            the time being ; but these soon pass away leaving the soul that has become estranged from
                            its Creator like the troubled sea, that is constantly casting up mire and dirt. But, One has
                            said, " Come unto me all ye that are weary and heavy laden, and I will give you rest." This
                            is a beautiful invitation and I feel that it has reached my soul in the fullness of its true
                            meaning ; and any response shall be a practical devotion to the principles of true
                            Christianity. By so living I shall ever remain a participant in that heavenly rest which the
                            prophet said remained for the people of God. And while I feel an inward gratitude daily
                            welling up in my soul for the spiritual baptism I have received, I would not be selfish in
                            the possession of my heavenly treasures, nor unmindful of those without the pale of Christ's
                            kingdom, who perhaps if they knew the way and had the invitation would gladly enter the ark
                            of safety and act well the Christian's part. To all such I would say come and learn wisdom
                            and peace in the ways of righteousness, and share in the labors and blessings of the higher
                            life. The door of the kingdom is ever ajar ; only knock and it shall be opened unto you, and
                            you shall be made a welcome guest at the Lord's table, and fed with bread that perisheth not
                            in this ark of heavenly rest. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Meezhahquod: the millenium of the Indians" TEIform="index"/>MEEZHAHQUOD: The Millennium of
                            the Indians</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sproat, Granville, T." TEIform="persName"/>GRANVILLE T. SPROAT</byline><p TEIform="p"> Many of the north-western tribes of the American Indians cherish a belief in a coming
                            millennium—a day of universal peace and love—when the red men shall be gathered into one
                            common league of friendship and brotherhood—a perfect Indian community. The place of meeting
                            they call the " Long House," or " Keche Wahkiegun," and say that it will reach from one
                            great ocean to the other. This belief was very forcibly expressed in the presence of the
                            writer by Keche Behzeke, a chief of Chippewa nation in 1837. It was spoken in his own
                            wigwam, in a council of chiefs, in reply to the question, " What are the hopes of your
                            people for the future?" It was delivered in the Indian dialect, and abounded with beautiful
                            tropes and figures, so characteristic of the red men. We have endeavored to render the
                            thought, with many of the metaphors expressed, into English, in the piece before us, and
                            have chosen, as best adapted to the subject, the poetic diction. </p><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Long House shall reach to the Gates of the Sunset..." TEIform="index"/>The Long House shall reach to the Gates of the Sunset...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Keche Behzeka" TEIform="persName"/>Keche Behzeka</byline><p TEIform="p"> The Long House shall reach to the Gates of the Sunset; Its roof-tree shall measure from
                                sea unto sea; The door of the wigwam shall ever stand open, To welcome all souls to the
                                Home of the Free. The Great Spirit, from his fair home in the South Land, Shall smile on
                                his Red Children dwelling below ; He shall scatter us corn on the mountains and
                                valleys.* And by all the streams tender beanplants shall grow. <pb n="60" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 60
                                THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. O'er the fair Hunting Grounds, in the Land of our Fathers, The red
                                deer shall roam in the long summer hours; The moose and elk shall o'er broad prairies
                                wander, And Great Kesisf kiss all the birds and the flowers. Keche NodinJ shall dwell in
                                his cave in the North Land ; He shall chill us no more with his frost and his snow ; And
                                the sun-god shall look from his home in mid-heaven, And, singing and dancing, the river
                                shall flow. From the North to the South, on the Wall of the Sunrise, Shall hang a
                                Cloud-curtain all radiant with gold; No Pale Face shall lift it to steal on our
                                birth-right, No eye of the White Stranger look through its fold. No treacherous
                                Sea-Rover, with cruel Firewater, § Shall prowl round our wigwams, and bind us for slaves
                                ; No Death-poison slay all our women and children, While the rivers run red with the
                                blood of our Braves. Where the Big Water dwells, by the Doors of the Sunrise, Again
                                shall our white canoes onward speed; No Demon -boats || howl o'er the terrified waters,
                                With their big eyes of fire, and their thundering tread. On the rainbow of Souls,** on
                                the pathway of angels, From the Land of Immortals, where good spirits go, They shall
                                come back again to their homes in the forest, And walk, hand in hand, with their loved
                                ones below. We shall dwell all our lives in the Home of our Fathers, Where good spirits
                                talk with us all the day long; Our hearts will* be glad in the Wigwams of Feasting; Our
                                spirits be cheered with the dance and the song; No more shall we meet in the home of the
                                dying, To take the Last Smoke,ff and to send our Farewell, In the land where the Red Men
                                shall meet as true brothers, The land where the Great Spirit calls us to dwell. *(" He
                                shall scatter us corn, etc.") The Indians have this tradition. Many winters ago there
                                was a great famine among all the tribes that lived on the shores of Keche-gaming.
                                ("Great Lakes.) It was in the time of corn-planting. There was no rain for many moons.
                                The streams all dried up. and the moose, elk and deer fled from the Hunting Grounds, to
                                the country far north, for water. Many of the old men died of hunger, and the women and
                                children lived many days on the tender bark of the roots of trees. Then the great chief,
                                Manitogezhick (Sky Spirit), called for all the tribes to assemble and worship before the
                                Great Spirit. They ¦confessed their sins before him. They worshiped him all day and all
                                night in the dance. They worshiped him still another day. The longer they worshiped the
                                stronger they grew. The old men, women and children, who were left in the wigwams to
                                die, were brought into the Lodge of Worship. The worshipers laid their hands upon
                                them—they revived, arose and joined in the dance. Then, on the third day, the Great
                                Spirit opened his windows in the South, and poured out his rain upon them. It rained
                                many days. Corn sprang up in all the valleys, and ripened in a single month. Wild
                                berries covered the'plains. The moose, elk and deer returned. There was feasting and
                                rejoicing bef6re the Great Spirit. The Braves washed the war-paint from their faces, and
                                did not go to war any more. It was a time of peace— a foretaste of the Indian's
                                Millennium. i(Qreat Kesis, etc.") The Indian's name for the sun. It is thought, by some
                                of the tribes, to be the home of the Great Spirit, and from it he sends his cheering
                                rays, through the opening at the top of the wigwam, to gladden the hearts of his Red
                                Children, They love the sun ; for they say it gives them life and strength. When it is
                                under an eclipse, they^it in silence, in their wigwam?, and do not speak until it shows
                                its face again; when the whole camp is filled with rejoicing, and they salute one
                                another with these words, "Kaget, odo penasewo-g," etc. 11 Now are our hearts like the
                                birds; for the sun shines upon us once more." t(Keche Nodin, etc.") The Spirit of the
                                Wind. He is a very strong spirit, and the Indians fear him; and when caught out in a
                                storm on the lakes, they make him an offering by throwing some of their treasures into
                                the sea, where his children, the little Wind Spirits, stand ready to receive them. Their
                                exclamation on such occasions is—Kaget neerkahdisi! (Truly he is veryangry. §(" Cruel
                                Fire-ivater.") The Indians also call it '' Fire Broth "-rlshkndo Wahbn; also, '' Death
                                Poison." All the good Indians detest it; while the bad ones will part with all they
                                possess for a dram. They say it was brewed by Fire-Spirits, in a cavern beyond the Big
                                Waters, and always marks the coming of the Pale-Faces. (II"Demon-boat* howl," etc.) The
                                Indians called the first steamboats they saw "Demonboats." They thought they were
                                propelled by Machemenito, the great Evil Spirit, who carried them on his back ; and that
                                the flashing of the fires, as they approached their shores, by night, was the lightning
                                of his eyes, and the roaring of the steam was the thunder of his voice. **("The Rainbow
                                of Souls," etc.") Among some of the tribes, the rainbow is believed to mark the path on
                                which good spirits go to the Land of Souls; and on it they will return again to visit
                                the earth in the good time coining." ++("JLast Smoke," etc) Ksquah Opwahgon.— See "
                                Manifesto," July No., 1S79.</p></div3></div2><pb n="61" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Celibacy: its relation to longevity, and as an essential to divine life" TEIform="index"/>CELIBACY: ITS RELATION TO LONGEVITY, AND AS AN ESSENTIAL TO DIVINE LIFE.</head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, February 5, 1880. " TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.,
                                Feb. 5, 1880. </dateline><p TEIform="p">Much respected friend, Dr. J. Dixson— Your letter to our much loved brother, W. Offord,
                                was very acceptable, being suggestive of many letters of similar import. Therefore we
                                will answer you, as the representative of numerous inquirers. 1. " What are the effects
                                of abstinence from exercising the functions of generation?" Ans. Freedom from disease of
                                the generative functions. 2. " What does your century's experience of abstinence
                                contribute to physiological science ?" Ans. It contributes the above fact, freedom from
                                the diseases of the generative functions. 3. " What forms of disorder arise from such
                                abstinence ? " Ans. No specific form of disease is incident to the life we live. We
                                enjoy better health than those outside of us. 4. " How does it affect length of life ? "
                                Ans. Favorably. The author of this letter is nearly seventy-six years of age ; has lived
                                a Shaker life more than half of his days, and personally indorses the above answer in
                                all its bearings. Your negative inquiries I will attend to before I close. To
                                physiologists, philosophers, medical men and others, we say, form your theories
                                according to the facts presented, and we will abide the result. You are aware that in
                                the presentation of argument, there is a logical procedure. To meet the foregoing in an
                                orderly manner, we assume that man is in possession of and manifests a two-fold
                                emotional life. The lower, represented by the propensities ; the higher, by the
                                attributes of goodness, mercy, and aspirations Godward. In view of this assumption, your
                                questions may be summed in one inquiry: Can men and women live in the higher life, to
                                the exclusion of the exercise of the generative functions ? We take the affirmative of
                                this question, and it is for physiologists, philosophers, medical men and others to show
                                (not us) that the position taken is not tenable. When they do, we will meet them with
                                the experience of an hundred years; which, however, is barely a drop in the bucket
                                compared with the experience of past ages. Celibate institutions have flourished for
                                thousands of years in Thibet. The Brahmins of India can speak of their experience.
                                To-day, China and Japan have their celibate orders. Their existence in these stereotyped
                                civilizations is an inverted prophecy that celibacy has existed for untold ages in these
                                countries. The Theraputse of Egypt present their experience. The Essenes in Judea had
                                their celibate communities. The order of the Vestal Priestesses in ancient Rome lasted
                                about one thousand years. And the monastic orders of Europe down to the present day,
                                about two thousand years. And, strange to say, before Columbus touched the shores of
                                this Western land, Mexico and Peru had each their own civilizations, and celibacy was
                                found in, them both ! From every quarter of the globe we have convincing testimony, that
                                wherever man has made any progress beyond being a mere animal, the laws of the higher
                                life have broken forth in celibate institutions. First in history and foremost in the
                                field is Asia. Next in order is Africa. Europe responds for more than two thousand years
                                in similar manifestations. Ancient America adds her quota of experience to the
                                practicability of a virgin life. And lastly, the Shakers of modern America, in the
                                sunshine of physiological law, and in all the well-understood relationships of life, add
                                their mite of experience to the testimony of past ages, that a celibate life is not only
                                practicable, but also favorable to health and length of days. It is a condition
                                necessary to the fulfillment of their wants and desires as a peculiar people, and a
                                preliminary essential to their happiness, viz.: The manifestation and growth of the
                                divine life in their spirits. We believe the mission of Jesus Christ was to manifest to
                                humanity the diviner, the angelic life-; and its possibility, propriety, and excellence
                                as bearing directly upon the subject of heaven on earth. One of its conditions is virgin
                                purity, <pb n="62" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. as is lived by the people called
                                Shakers. Here arises the inquiry: Does such a life diminish or increase the awful
                                maladies which the generative man and woman are subject to ? Let us see: Diseases range
                                themselves under the two main divisions — sexual and nutritive functions. Under the
                                former head, there is a long list of the most horrible of diseases ! The life lived by
                                us at once emancipates the sexes from that frightful list. The next inquiry is: What is
                                the effect of a virgin life on its subjects ? The vital statistics of our Order show
                                that those who from youth and upward live a virgin life average greater length of years
                                than does the generative order. As regards diseases of the nutritive functions, the same
                                statistic proofs are applicable. Further, prospectively, we see, that an application of
                                hygienic law to all the departments of life will insure good health daily, and greater
                                length of years. This will flow naturally from our testimonies. First, we testify
                                against the " lusts of the flesh." Secondly, that eating and drinking should be for use
                                only. Hence alcoholic drinks are not used, neither is tobacco by the rising generation.
                                With those of advanced life, who come among us, the vile weed is hardly tolerated. Tea
                                and coffee in the long run are regarded by some as being injurious, being antagonistic
                                to bodily growth, and to the removal of effete matter from the system. The consumption
                                of animal food with us has greatly diminished ; and it is thought by many to stimulate
                                the lower organs of the brain, and that the angelic life can be more happily consummated
                                without it. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Frazer, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Frazer</byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Virtue of home love" TEIform="index"/>Virtue of Home Love</head><p TEIform="p">No man can safely go abroad that does not love to stay at home ; no man can safely speak
                                that does not willingly hold his tongue ; no man can safely govern, that would not
                                cheerfully become subject; no man can safely command, that has not truly learned to obey
                                ; and no man can safely rejoice, but he that has the testimony of a good conscience.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="a Kempis, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Thomas a Kempis</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Maintenance of Shakerism" TEIform="index"/> MAINTENANCE OF SHAKERISM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Can Shakerism be successfully maintained? or must it die for want of converts and
                                supporters ? These are serious questions, affecting the world at large, more seriously
                                than it does those who are its present advocates and earnest supporters. To those who
                                stoutly maintain its principles, in the face of all worldly opposition, there comes a
                                gain in salvation and redemption, which, while secured to these few, are really needed
                                to leaven the world at large, into superior manhood and womanhood. The faithful
                                supporters of the faith feel a security of heaven's future blessings by experiencing so
                                large an enjoyment of these at the present time. Should the institution die, it would
                                not seriously affect those who, having bartered away their worldly, unchristian lives,
                                for the gain of heavenly and eternal life, are already secured to their Christian
                                reward; but can the world at large spare the action of its testimony, the agitation of
                                its principles, which now, more than ever in the past, are working revolutions and
                                evolutions among governmental and churchal policies, to the end that new earths and new
                                heavens may be inaugurated ? Let the world bear witness to the unparalleled courage, and
                                hope and trust of a people, who, securing to themselves no earthly honors nor
                                emoluments; who, believing that their call to the support of principles known as
                                Shakerism was G-od's call and is to represent the salt of the earth"; who have trusted
                                unfailingly to Providence 62 <pb n="63" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 63 to send
                                laborers into their field, with " none to declare their generations " ; whose
                                companions, converts to a similar faith, have no inducements, but the fruits of the most
                                active self-denials, who cannot be man-made, but must be God-made, and who yet, for more
                                than a century, have neither known nor felt any such feeling as failure brings ; but
                                hold unflinchingly, theirunhoneyed, unworldly, unpopular testimony to invite "whosoever
                                will." Be it also known, that the Shakers are a sect, whose Church has no outer court,
                                but whose priests and people are brought to -the same square and plummet of communal
                                life, and this fashioned after the active cross and self-denial of Jesus, the Christ.
                                Resolving to do duty unfailingly; determined upon no retreat from its radical, Christian
                                cross — listening not to any worldly following to " come down from that Cross, and all
                                will believe on you"—but "glorifying in whatever shame " there may be in following the
                                exactness of Christ's life, the Shakers have no reason to anticipate any failure of
                                their institutions. For more than a century, their Church has stood with its indices
                                pointing to a life superior to a worldly life, and a constant reminder of the
                                life-example of the Master ; for this length of time it " has been the specie basis that
                                has upheld the paper theories " and hopes of communal and cooperative brotherhoods,
                                actively hinting at heavenly life on earth, and being more than ''the far-off echoes of
                                the Primitive Christian" Church " ; while its testimony for peace and peaceful
                                arbitrations have been heard, acknowledged, and acted upon by the nations. From which
                                considerations we conclude: Shakerism being the harvest of the world's good, its career
                                is quite in its infancy. Lean though its supporters often feel; oft though they suffer
                                the blight of disappointed hope and despondency; it is God's work, and we have only to
                                do duty and it will stand forever. Relying solely upon the resurrection of souls out of
                                themselves and selfishness; out from denominations which yield unsatisfactory returns ;
                                and who, casting about for a superior religion and life in the world, but not of the
                                world, let none repine nor worry about the continuance and maintenance of the Shaker
                                Church. To lose heart would be to lose hope in super-excellent humanity, and of God
                                working with humanity; for so long as there is an earnest of prayer, "Thy kingdom come,
                                thy will be done in earth, as it is in heaven," so long will the Shaker Church be
                                maintained in flourishing conditions, while its glorious principles will continue
                                actively to spread, and the fame of its founder and supporters will never be "unknown,
                                unhonored, nor unsung." vv</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What profiteth celibacy?" TEIform="index"/>What Profiteth Celibacy?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Elsewhere, our Brother D. Fraser gives answers to a candid inquirer upon the subject of
                                Celibacy. The answers will be found to be profitable reading. We opine, however, there
                                are vastly stronger reasons for living virgin, celibate lives, than because it tends to
                                better health, freedom from sexual diseases, and greatly to longevity. Our brother gives
                                the true ring at every inference that it is the <pb n="64" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 64 THE SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. condition necessary to grow successfully into the Divine life. Celibacy per
                                se—of itself merely—is unworthy of much commendation; and only as it is used for, and
                                becomes, the means or even one of the means by which the Divine life, the Christ life is
                                approached and attained unto, but little can be said in its "favor, but rather savors of
                                constrained selfishness. In the progress of individual Christianity it becomes and is
                                simply and positively a necessity. None is so Christian without it, not only, but is so
                                far from Christ practice, so far from being a Christian in this respect. We acknowledge,
                                all cannot be christians after this manner of Christ's example, so Jesus said, and so
                                our experience with some individuals proves. We are only sorry that this is so—that
                                indulgencies which ruin the chasteness of the Christ life are a necessity with some,
                                otherwise ardent strugglers after the Divine pattern. Yea, sorry are we, that the lower,
                                animal propensities should overcome the superior elements of the angel in humanity,
                                causing so many to be thus dissimilar to Christ. Connected with this subject, is the
                                fact that all religious denominations, those which marry, and those which do not, pay
                                the highest tributes of praise,singling out for especial worship and admiration, those
                                who have lived and died "celibates for the Kingdom of Heaven's sake." The lip service of
                                such praise is like very thin air; but the love of such a life, which leads individuals
                                to live it, because it was more like Christ's life, and because this life was most like
                                God's life, this is true praise—a genuine, worshipful adoration of God—in our lives.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lafayette" TEIform="index"/>Lafayette</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> We present in this number, some of the curious observations of Lafayette in earth life,
                                among the Shakers. Since his departure to the Spirit land, every society of the Shakers
                                has heen frequently visited and happily noticed by this exalted and noble soul, in the
                                most unmistakable manner. Very many anecdotes of the foremost men of our nation, past
                                and present, and their happy association with the Shakers, might be collated and
                                profitably presented to the public. Unworthy of notice and esteem, as many worldloving,
                                flesh-seeking, pleasure-hunting, so-called Christians, think the Shakers are, it is a
                                valuable thought to us, that the noblest men and women, of past and our own times, and
                                of our own and other countries, have considered it no condescension to seek and merit
                                our esteem, and they missing no opportunity to repay the favors.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian progress" TEIform="index"/>Christian Progress</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> To those who can recall the precepts of preaching and writing of only onequarter of a
                                century since, must be forcibly and happily impressed with the mighty strides which
                                pulpit and practical Christianity have made toward the teachings of the model Christian.
                                There is a greater love of Christ manifested to-day than ever before — manifested too,
                                not through adherence to technical, theological points, but in the acknowledgments so
                                often heard that Christ's life was and is best for Christians RomanCatholics were never
                                so stirred among themselves, that their best representatives should copy at least one
                                peculiar feature of Jesus and apostles—that of celibacy. Celibacy <pb n="65" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/>
                                THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 65 for greater righteousness' sake obtains greater respect and
                                encouragement among the purest thinkers of all denominations, Jewish, Catholic, and
                                Protestant alike, than ever before. The horrors of war are deprecated more than ever
                                everywhere; and the more peaceful methods of arbitration and non-resistance have assumed
                                possible and real engagement of the reflection of nations. The great Gladstone, of
                                England, has lately invited all ' Europe "to engage in a general disarmament! The rush
                                of the Communists, wild and unwise though it seems, has for its calmer meaning "Share
                                and share alike," something like Pentecostal days. We are living in grand times. The
                                millennium is approaching faster than we are apt to think that it is ; and where souls
                                are living as Christ did, and dying unto the world as Jesus did, the millennium has
                                already come, and come to stay.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We would call special attention to the article upon the Millennium among the Indians..." TEIform="index"/>We would call special attention to the article upon the Millennium among the Indians...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> We would call special attention to the article upon the Millennium among the Indians, as
                                written so sweetly in poetry by our talented Brother Sproat. It is known that the
                                spirits of Indians find access to their mortal brethren more easily than the majority of
                                others, not Indians. There appears, with their apparent ignorance, much oi their native
                                innocence; and there is ' much more native wisdom than people commonly know of; for much
                                o: which, profitable information we render thanks to G. T. Sproat.</p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We purpose being on hand with March Manifesto by..." TEIform="index"/>We purpose being on hand with March Manifesto by...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> We purpose being on hand with March Manifesto by Feb. 29th, th birthday of Mother Ann
                                Lee — th 36th anniversary!</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Queries and answers" TEIform="index"/>QUERIES AND ANSWERS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> 1. " Will you please give us the best and liortest definition of a Shaker life ?"
                                Certainly : A life that is pure, peaceable, unworldly and heavenly, like Fesus Christ's
                                life. 2. "Do you consider it necessary to become ascetics in order to be Christians?"
                                Only as Christ was an ascetic. 3. " In your opinion, must we live celibate ives, to be
                                followers of Jesus Christ ? " How can we follow where Jesus did lot lead ? 4. " Would
                                not 'the world become extinct if all should so live ? and is it desirable that such
                                should be the case ? " (1.) Certainly; if all should so live, population would cease.
                                (2.) To the « few " who " are able "'and willing so to live, the questions of
                                desirableness or undesirableness, declarative of generations, never occur as germane
                                considerations. 5. " Did not Jesus have great respect for the institution of marriage?"
                                As a worldly, civil institution, he did; so does every sensible person. As a Christian
                                practice, he did not, nor can his genuine followers. 6. " Did not Jesus advise the
                                selling of coats for the procuration of swords ? and what were these swords to he used
                                for? " It is said in scripture that he so advised. It is a safe, Christian rule to sell
                                as many coats, and procure as many swords with, the proceeds, as Jesus did, and only as
                                many, and to use the swords after thus obtaining them just as Jesus did. See ? 7. " Did
                                not Jesus show a spirit of physical violence and retaliation in driving out those who
                                were defiling the temple ? " It is said, in disapprobation of this chronicle,that "the
                                zeal for his Father's house had nearly " destroyed his Christian equanimity. Jesus could
                                sorrow for his mistakes. 8. " In 'Plain Talks,' you say the first requirement of
                                Shakerism is an honest con- <pb n="66" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 66 THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. fession of
                                one's sins. How is this following Jesus?" It is going down into the Jordan — judgment —
                                to some one representing a confessor, like John Baptist, and imitating Jesus by
                                rendering an account of the way you have lived, good, bad, or indifferent to your best
                                light and understanding. The confessions of Jesus to John made it apparent to the latter
                                that a better man than he stood before him ; hence John's remarks. Would to heaven it
                                might similarly be your case when making your confessions to some Shaker elder; and the
                                elder's response, " I have need rather to be baptized of thee." 9. " What advice would
                                you give me if I believed in Shaker doctrines of life and my wife did not ?" "Act your
                                faith." "Liberty of conscience" is guaranteed to every American citizen, in this living
                                faith, no less than in the belief of dead creeds, nor in the prosecution of selfish
                                indulgences under the civil con tract, called marriage. 10. " Could I engage in the
                                trial of Shakerism in any of the societies with the understanding that if I did not like
                                it, I could return to my present, married life with my family ? " We would be far from
                                advising any such proceeding. Shakerism is ruinous to marital felicities; and you could
                                not return to former, fleshly indulgences and selfish aggrandizements with the same
                                satisfaction, after tasting Shakerism, as before. Regrets that you ever heard of
                                Shakerism would ensue, if you should return to the habits of your worldly life ; or
                                remorseful reflections would follow, that you had recanted a better way of living. You
                                have heard of " the sow that was washed, returning to her wallowing in the mire" — this
                                means the return of a woman from Shakerism to her worldly life ; and " the dog that
                                returned to his vomit" — this would mean you, returning to eat again what you had thrown
                                out of your spiritual stomach as hurtful to you as a Christian. See? 11. " What social
                                permissions are granted the sexes among the Shakers ? Do or do not the rules of the
                                societies create a disrespect and coldness, the one toward the other?" Our founder, Ann
                                Lee, was a woman of great affection and love toward both males and females. Discerning
                                that "poor man, while under temptations to the flesh is always in danger," she carefully
                                removed from the practice of her children aught that would arouse the semblance of
                                passion. She demonstrated, as the Shakers now do, that there can be a warmer, purer
                                affection manifested by the sexes toward each other as gospel brethren and sisters,
                                subject to rules that forbid physical contact, than by the conjured worldly idea, that
                                there can be no love without sexual embraces of some kind. This love gets cold. Shaker
                                love " never grows old " nor cold, " but is new every day."</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Radical utterances" TEIform="index"/>RADICAL UTTERANCES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> There is some person connected with the Golden Rule, of Boston, Mass., that is,
                                apparently, trying to outrival The Shaker Manifesto in its radical utterances. Of course
                                it matters not who utters a truth, but that it is uttered opportunely, nevertheless we
                                would pay homage to the conscientious bravery that puts plain, unvarnished, yet simple
                                Christian facts where, and in a manner that professedly Christian folk must see and
                                think of them—apart from their moulded ehurch catechisms. Hear : When you hear a man,
                                who holds up his head in society, confess in public prayer that he is a poor, miserable
                                creature, unfit to live, you had better put your hand on to your pocket-book. A
                                specially interesting service once a month for the benefit of the heathen is a good
                                thing; but would it not be in the line of Christian duty to have a special service once
                                in a while for the young men who do not attend the churches, but are at home in the
                                drinking saloons ? <pb n="67" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. A religion that is
                                eloquent Friday night and active on the Sabbath, but is left at the family altar for
                                fear that it will be troublesome in the counting-room, will hardly convince shrewd men
                                of the world that it is worth their attention. The bread-and-butter gospel to a family
                                that are hungry will do more to lead them to love and trust God than a pocket full of
                                New Testaments. When Christianity gives as warm a hand, as pleasant a face, and makes
                                its places of worship as inviting as theatres, billiard halls and liquor saloons, there
                                will be less poverty and crime charged to rum, and more credit due religion. Virtue,
                                honesty, manliness do not need to be locked in a bank vault for security. A good
                                character cannot be stolen by day or night. If any man has a character that can be
                                stolen, the thief will get cheated.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mine" TEIform="index"/>MINE</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Whatever else you are, children, do not be selfish. We often hear, ringing
                                        out above the music of children's voices, the words, " That's mine!" and it
                                        startles us like a sharp clap of thunder when the sun is shining— it seems so
                                        little in keeping with the sunshine of childhood. Not long since, a mother,
                                        selecting clothes for a poor woman, brought to the parlor a pair of bright red
                                        stockings, beautiful, but too small for her little one. The child saw what it
                                        was her mother held, and sprang forward, saying, " You-won't give her those,
                                        mamma ? Those are mine ! " and the emphasis placed upon that one word " mine "
                                        opened to our gaze such a yawning pit of selfishness in that young girl's heart
                                        as made our own ache to contemplate. Don't be selfish, children. It is not
                                        really natural for any of us to be unselfish, but by a little care we can make a
                                        sort of second nature. That is, act generously and unselfishly so often that it
                                        grows to be almost natural for us to do so.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Brethren's advocate" TEIform="index"/>Brethren's Advocate.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boy and his conscience" TEIform="index"/>THE BOY AND HIS CONSCIENCE&gt;</head><p TEIform="p"> BOY. Over the fence is a garden fair — How I would love to be master there ! All that I
                                lack is a mere pretense, I could leap over the low white fence. CONSCIENCE. This is the
                                way that all crimes commence, Sin and sorrow over the fence. BOY. Over the fence I can
                                toss my ball, Then go in for it — that is all; Picking an apple up 'neath the tree,
                                Would not be really a theft, you see. CONSCIENCE. This is a falsehood, a weak pretense,
                                Sin and sorrow over the fence. BOY. Whose is the voice that speaks so plain? Twice have
                                I heard it, and not in vain. Never will I venture to look that way, Lest I should do as
                                I planned to-day. CONSCIENCE. This is the way that all crimes commence, Coveting that
                                which is over the fence.—SeL</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God sees me" TEIform="index"/>GOD SEES ME</head><p TEIform="p">I have heard of a little boy who was kept from committing a great sin remembering that
                                God could see him. He was tempted to take something that did not belong to him, but he
                                said : " Although nobody sees me, God sees me, and I fear I should never again be good.
                                I never could pray again to God; and what should I do when I come to die, and go away to
                                answer God? I would rather be poor always than steal."</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A missionary in Jamaica once asked a little negro in a missionary school..." TEIform="index"/>A missionary in Jamaica once asked a little negro in a missionary school...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> A missionary in Jamaica once asked a little negro in a missionary school, " Who are the
                                meek ?" The child answered, " Those who give soft answers to rough questions."</p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Girls can't throw stones" TEIform="index"/> Girls can't throw Stones</head><p TEIform="p"> .—They often try but fail. Why is it so? Physiology answers the question. The collar
                                bone in the anatomy of a female is several inches longer than that of a male, and is set
                                several degrees lower down. This long, crooked bone interferes with the free and full
                                action of the shoulder, and that's the reason why girl's can't throw stones. So it is ;
                                but they can do some other things, quite as important, and can do them better than the
                                boys ! —Enter-prise.</p></div3></div2><pb n="68" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Crown of grace" TEIform="index"/>CROWN OF GRACE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Martha J. Anderson</byline><p TEIform="p"> Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. 1. Purity, brightest of im 2. O! I behold thee a 3. Down through the
                            cycles of mortal graces, glorified angel, rolling ages, Star that il— Clothed in fair Saints
                            have exlumined the Savior's life crown, Gleaming afar through dark shadowy raiment unsullied
                            and white, Sent unto earth as a chosen etolled thee by emblems sublime, Virtue, the name for
                            which martyrs and places, Unto our spirits thy light cometh down. Shine in thy fulness our
                            vangel, Souls to redeem from temptation and blight. Holy of holies, the sages, Yielded all
                            claim to enjoyments of time Beautiful spirit! we lives to make blessed, Be the refiner of
                            every heart, Till in thy heart where thou reignest, Sacred the altar and quenchless the
                            fire, Every € covet thy blessing, Sanctify wholly our souls unto thee, Then in the <pb n="69" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 69 glory like Pleiades beaming, Heavenly gifts
                            sliall sweet influence impart, motion each motive and action, Rise like pure incense to
                            realms that are higher, light of God's countenance dwelling, We from the bondage of sin
                            shall be free.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A small piece of charcoal put into the pot with boiling cabbage..." TEIform="index"/>A small piece of charcoal put into the pot with boiling cabbage...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> A small piece of charcoal put into the pot with boiling cabbage removes the smell.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To make good starch..." TEIform="index"/>To make good starch...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> To make good starch, after you have boiled it, put a small piece of butter and a
                                teaspoonful of sugar in it, and the gloss is obtained.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In boiling meat..." TEIform="index"/>In boiling meat...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">In boiling meat for soup use cold water to extract the juices. If the meat is wanted for
                                itself alone, plunge into boiling water at once</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A smart girl on shipboard found out from the cook how to peel and slice onions..." TEIform="index"/>A smart girl on shipboard found out from the cook how to peel and slice onions...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> A smart girl on shipboard found out from the cook how to peel and slice onions without
                                crying over them. Very simple : Just hold them under water during the operation.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To remove ink stains..." TEIform="index"/>To remove ink stains...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> To remove ink spots from any white fabric, throw salt and pepper over it in abundance,
                                and all traces of ink will disappear. Soak the stained parts in milk, and the stains
                                will be removed. Either way will work like magic.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Experiments have been made" TEIform="index"/>Experiments have been made
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Experiments have been made in Italy with borax as a preservative for butter " It has
                                been found," says the Italian minister of agriculture, " by recent trials at the
                                agricultural station, that the addition of eight per cent borax to the salt, preserved
                                the butter in its natural fine flavor for three months, although exposed to the air.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lumps in starch or gravy" TEIform="index"/>Lumps in Starch or Gravy</head><p TEIform="p"> .—How true it is that, if wo observe and remember, we can learn something of every one
                                we meet. A few days ago I learned from the poorest housekeeper I know something new
                                tome— that salt added to the flour before the water, on stirring paste for starch or
                                gravy, would prevent the flour from forming into lumps. Of course I used to salt both
                                gravy and starch, but I never observed the good results of adding the salt first.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Remedy for ear-ache" TEIform="index"/>Remedy for Ear-ache</head><p TEIform="p"> .—The Journal of ¦Health gives the following: There is scarcely any ache to which
                                children are subject so hard to bear and difficult to cure as the ear-ache. But there is
                                a remedy never known to fail. Take a bit of cotton batting, put upon it a pinch of black
                                pepper, gather it up and tie it, dip it in sweet oil, and insert into the ear. Put a
                                flannel bandage over the head to keep it warm. It will give immediate relief.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The secret of protecting furs..." TEIform="index"/>The secret of protecting furs...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> The secret of protecting furs and woolen garments from the depredations of the moth is
                                very simple. In the first place, see that the article you are putting away is thoroughly
                                clean. Remove all spots of grease and dirt, and brush all dust from the gathers and
                                folds. Take your furs out-doors and beat them thoroughly with a small rod, going over a
                                small part of the surface at a time, till the whole have been beaten. Then seal each
                                article up in double folds of newspaper, pasting so closely that neither air nor insect
                                can get in. This is a better way than any we know of, not excepting camphor, tobacco,
                                pepper, and other pungent preventives which are commonly used.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What luster Goldwin adds to the plain name of Smith..." TEIform="index"/>What luster Goldwin adds to the plain name of Smith...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">What luster Goldwin adds to the plain name of Smith. He has lately said, " If Jonathan
                            Edwards found the truth it is very remarkable, since he never sought it for a moment."—Am.
                            Soc</p></div2><pb n="70" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society items" TEIform="index"/>SOCIETY ITEMS</head><p TEIform="p"> " There is no death," we happily record.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Canterbury, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">is buying potatoes, having lost most of its crop by the rot. The slippery season has
                                worked terribly with some of the saints here. Received from Benj. H. Smith, $12.00. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">That was quite a severe loss of the North Family, to have a val uable team of horses
                                disappear beneath the ice of their beautiful lake. We sympathize.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">The experiment of heating buildings with hot water is being made at this place, and witli
                                apparently the grandest success. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Richard Van Deusen has discovered a remedy, and sure preventive against the attacks of
                                borers upon fruit trees. It is cheap, and so easily applied, that there ought to be a
                                great demand for it. He may be addressed on the subject at Shaker Station, Conn. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South Union, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>South. Union, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p"> Elder H. L. Eads learned by sad experience that he is not "the boy of yore," but 73
                                years of age, when jumping from a railroad train, ere it had fully stopped at his home,
                                he was thrown with such violence as to break some of his ribs, and otherwise injure him.</p><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rankin, William" TEIform="index"/>William Rankin
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Since ready for press we have received intelligence of the decease of Wm. Rankin, at
                                    this Society, on the 25th ult., aged 76. </p></div4></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, Ohio.</head><p TEIform="p">Elder S. W. Ball we learn has been transferred to the Society at Whitewater, O. Wherever
                                he goes, he has our unbounded respect. He is that man of whom that lovely saint, Joving
                                sister, and loved-by-everybody-Eldress, Elizabeth Fanonce said: " With all his faults,
                                lie's as good as God ! " </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, New York" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">The Central Ministry arrived at this place February 11. Thousands upon thousands will
                                hereafter miss the beautiful and shade-affording willows which adorned the entrance to
                                the Church Family. They are no more. It is proposed to introduce an immense circular saw
                                for lumbering purposes, with a proportionate waterwheel in the " Great Red Mill." This
                                looks enterprising. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/> Union Village, O-</head><p TEIform="p"> Received of Chas. Massey, $20.00; Chas. Clapp, $4.15.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hancock, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Hancock, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> Received of Thomas Damon, $5.00; of I. R. Lawson, $25.00. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Received of Benj. Gates, $70.50.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Agricultural</head><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Broom-corn seed" TEIform="index"/>Broom-Corn Seed</head><p TEIform="p">.— An exchange states that the seed of broom-corn, which has hitherto been considered
                                useless except for planting, and an inferior article of food for cattle, has been
                                discovered to be valuable as a breadstuff. It was first used as a substitute for wheat
                                in 1870 and 1871, but, like many other good things, was lost sight of, and its
                                manufacture was never carried to success, and never became even particularly known until
                                about three years ago. The yield of flour is about one-half in place of two-thirds from
                                wheat. The bran is also as valuable as wheat bran as a food for animals. The flour
                                cannot be told from wheat flour, and the bread, cake, etc., is delicate, inviting and
                                delicious, and easily digested. The yield of broom-corn seed is also enormous, a single
                                spear often producing a pint of seed, and the yield has reached five hundred bushels to
                                the acre, while it is safe to estimate the average at one hundred bushels.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Covered yards for cattle" TEIform="index"/>Covered Yards for Cattle</head><p TEIform="p"> .— American farmers for the most part have yet to learn the value of a covered yard for
                                their stock. There are many days in the year when cattle could be turned into such a
                                yard, that would otherwise be condemned on account of the weather to stand all day in
                                the stable. The roof would prevent all waste of manure from washing, and would make the
                                yard so cleanly and "comfortable that the animals could lie down. In this country, where
                                wood is cheap and almost every man sufficiently handy to be his own carpenter, we are
                                convinced that farmers have only to see the advantages of such yards to adopt them at
                                once.</p></div3><pb n="71" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gardener's secret" TEIform="index"/>A Gardener's Secret</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Peter Henderson, the veteran gardener, made a very significant statement
                                        before the convention of nurserymen and florists. This statement embodies the'
                                        remarkable fact that if garden seeds, when planted in the spring, are firmly
                                        pressed, when under the earth, by the ball of the foot at the time the gardeners
                                        are putting them into the ground, they will invariably grow, drought or not
                                        drought; and what is still more important, they will spring up earlier and grow
                                        faster and mature better than any of their kind which have not been subjected to
                                        this discipline. The same rule of pressure, he says, holds true in regard to
                                        transplanting trees, shrubs and plants. This is an item of great practical value
                                        to many of our people, and especially to those who live in the suburbs.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Cleveland herald" TEIform="index"/>Cleveland Herald.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Travellers say that the Chinese..." TEIform="index"/>Travellers say that the Chinese...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Travellers say that the Chinese' have a method of preserving grapes so as to have them
                                at hand during the entire year, by cutting a circular piece out of a ripe pumpkin, or
                                gourd, making an aperture large enough to admit the hand. The interior is then
                                completely cleaned out, the ripe grapes are then placed inside, and the cover replaced
                                and pressed in firmly. The pumpkins are then kept in a cool place, and the grapes will
                                be found to retain their freshness for a very long time.</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to measure the height of trees" TEIform="index"/>How to Measure the Height of Trees</head><p TEIform="p"> —When a tree stands so that the shadow can be measured, its height can be readily
                                ascertained as follows : Set a stick upright — let it be perpendicular by the plumb
                                line. Measure the length of the shadow of the stick. As the length of its shadow is to
                                the height of the stick, so is the length of the shadow of a tree to its height. For
                                instance : If the stick is four feet above the ground, and its shadow is six feet in
                                length, and the shadow of the tree is ninety feet, its height will be sixty feet. 6 : 4
                                : : 90 : 60. In other words, multiply the length of the shadow of the tree by the length
                                of the stick, and divide by the length of the shadow of the stick</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gems from contemporaries" TEIform="index"/>GEMS FROM CONTEMPORARIES</head><p TEIform="p"> The strengthening of principle is better than a great deal of frothy emotion. The secret of
                            walking in the light is in keeping aloof from tarnished appearances. To be a follower of
                            Christ is to live as Christ lived ; to be a Christian is to be like Christ. The trumpet of
                            fame will sooner or later do us all the justice we need, without giving the blast with our
                            own breath. A colored preacher, commenting on the passage, ' Be ye therefore wise as
                            serpents and harmless as doves," said that the mixture should be made in the proportion of a
                            pound of dove to an ounce of serpent. How many theological wars would have been averted if
                            the Christian charity of Mr. Emerson's latest word to preachers had prevailed : " Always put
                            the best interpretation on a tenet." A good many Christians pray that the world may be
                            converted, and then sit down and wait for God to answer their prayers. But if they are
                            farmers, they never pray that God will plough their corn fields, and then get up on the
                            fence and wait to see the dirt fly.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wishing" TEIform="index"/>WISHING. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Saxe" TEIform="persName">Saxe.</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> I wish that friends were always true, And motives always pure ; I wish the good were not as
                            few, I wish the bad were fewer; I wish that persons ne'er forgot To heed their pious
                            teaching; I wish that practicing was not So different from preaching. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lesson of life" TEIform="index"/>The Lesson of Life</head><p TEIform="p"> Charles Kingsley's farewell to a child is the great lesson of life for us all: My gentle
                            child, I have no song to give you; No lark could pipe to skies so dull and gray ; Yet, ere
                            we part, one lesson I can leave you For every day. Be good, dear child, and let who will be
                            clever; Do noble things, not dream them, all day long ; And so make life, death, and that
                            vast forever, One grand, sweet song.</p></div2><pb n="72" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Puckered-pursedness" TEIform="index"/>PUCKERED-PURSEDNESS</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A quaint minister once prayed that the church might be delivered from "
                                    puckeredpursedness." He meant that his desire was that the purses of his people
                                    would not be kept so tightly closed that the money could not get out from them to go
                                    on the errands of the Lord. The church at large needs to be delivered from this
                                    evil. Some money does come, but the purses of Christians are still too closely
                                    puckered. Open them wider, brethren ! If the purse is full, let the gift be large.
                                    If the purse be scantily filled, nevertheless let the outcome be proportionate.
                                    Purses are filling up all over the. land. May they not be kept puckered when the
                                    claims of a perishing world are presented to Christian thought.— 0. In American
                                    Messenger.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="American messenger" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Theological tobacco" TEIform="index"/>THEOLOGICAL TOBACCO</head><p TEIform="p"> . The wise Golden Rule thoughtfully says : " We are glad that at last the cause of poor
                            Freeman's insanity, by which his child was murdered, is discovered. By the testimony of a
                            neighbor, it was not bad theology but tobacco." Apropos of which we present the following: A
                            SUSPICIOUS LOOKING ANGEL. Dominie H. was one of the old-times' circuit riders, whose rough
                            exterior and somewhat non-society ways often obscured his real goodness of heart. One day he
                            was caught in a shower in Illinois, and, going to a rude cabin near by, he knocked at the
                            door. A sharp-looking old dame answered his summons. He asked for shelter. " I don't know
                            you," she replied, suspiciously. " Remember the Scriptures," said the dominie. " Be not
                            forgetful to entertain strangers, for thereby some have entertained angels unawares.' " "
                            You needn't say that," quickly returned the other; " no angel would come down here with a
                            big quid of tobacco in his mouth ! " She shut the door in his face, leaving the good man to
                            the mercy of the rain and his own reflections. A Turkish Belief.— " The Turks," says a
                            correspondent of the Observer, writing from their midst, " are believers in the second
                            advent of Christ. It is a common remark among them now that the prophetic indications of His
                            coming, as given in their books, are being manifested. These signs are general distress and
                            suffering, disorder, war, rebellion, the decline of the true faith, general corruption,
                            oppression, etc. He is to descend at Damascus, become a genuine Moslem, and during the forty
                            years of His earthly career He is to secure great prosperity, and peace shall be so complete
                            as to extend even to the lower orders of creation, as described in Isaiah. The advent of
                            Christ is to be succeeded by other wonders in rapid succession, and then the end of the
                            world is to come. This is the belief of all orthodox Mohammedans, and considering the
                            belief, it is not strange that the devout among them are looking for the end of the world.
                            During no period of their recent history have the signs above mentioned been so fully
                            realized as at present." It will usually be found that those who are grossly vicious in
                            manhood dropped a seed of vice in the morning of life ; that the fallen youth who was
                            religiously trained and has become corrupt, broke off his connection with the virtuous ways
                            just where he did a very wicked thing in boyhood. Here is a fact to be pondered. The oldest
                            man in the prison could not say that childhood and youth had no connection with his present
                            condition. Perhaps he could point to the very day and hour when he decided his present
                            character. Sel. Has any one permitted himself to make use of injurious expressions
                            respecting you? Reply to him by blessings. Does he treat you ill? Be patient. Does he
                            reproach you? Is the reproach just ? If it be, condemn yourself; if not, it is but a breath
                            of air. Flattery could not really impart a merit to you if you have it not, nor calumny give
                            you faults that you do not actually possess. Does he tax you with ignorance ? In showng
                            yourself angry you justify the charge. Does he persecute you ? Think of Jesus Hirist. Can
                            you ever suffer as he has suffered 1—St. Basil the Great.</p></div2><!--
                    <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>