<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1007" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><date value="18800701" TEIform="date">July 1880</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">145-168</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
	                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p>The Shaker JULY, 1880, 60 Cents Per Annum Vol. X. No. 7. MANIFESTO. G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, N. Y. Published by
                        the United Societies. OUR HOME AT SHIRLEY "And they shall turn to you for a testimony: '' ''Go preach the Kingdom of
                        God!" ADDRESS ALL COMMUNICATIONS TO " The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N. D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1880.</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p> [Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>--><pb n="145" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><!--                    <div2 type="none">
                        <p>CONTENTS. page. page. " Look at Home,"  145 Jewish Testimony of Christ, ... 159 CUMHERED ABOUT MUCH
                            SERVING, - - - 145 TEACHINGS OP THE TaLMU.), - 159 The Order of Shakers, a Priesthood, not a Sect, 145 Greeds,
                            - ]60 Prentissiana, - - - - - - 147 The Religions of the Head and Heart, - - 161 Is, Shakerism the
                            Millennium ? - - - 147 I Time's Changes, - - - - - 161 Reply, - - - - - - - 148 ] England's Wicked Wars, - - - -
                            162 What Matter, -149 Spiritualism One Hundred Tears Ago, - - 163 Infidel Sophistry Rebuked, - 150 Sad
                            Facts,  163 It may be your turn next, - - - 153 Grand Thoughts from Contemporaries, - - 164 Editorial :
                            Honesty, - 165 The Good Time Come, - - - - 154 Music: A Monstrous Hypocrisy, ... 154. The True Shepherd's
                            Voice - - - - 166 Editorial Notes, - - - - - - 155 The Modern Church's Invitation, - - 167 The Children's
                            Grotto, - - - - 156 i Danielites, - - - - - - - 167 Society Record, - 157 j Sanitary Thoughts, - 167
                            Book Table, - 157 The Theologian and General —Which is Right, 168 Agricultural, - 158 Josh Billings'
                            Philosophy, - - - - 168 </p>
                    </div2>--><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Look at home" TEIform="index"/> LOOK AT HOME</head><p TEIform="p"> Should you feel inclined to censure Faults you may in others view, • Ask your own heart, ere
                            you venture, If that has not failing, too. Let not friendly vows be broken, Rather strive a
                            friend to gain ; Many a word in anger spoken Finds its passage back again. Do not, then, in
                            idle pleasure, Trine with a brother's fame; Guard it as a valued treasure, Sacred as your
                            own good name. Do not form opinions blindly, Hastiness to trouble tends ; Those of whom
                            we've thought unkindly Oft become our warmest friends. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cumbered about much serving" TEIform="index"/> CUMBERED ABOUT MUCH SERVING.</head><p TEIform="p">Christ never asks of us such busy labor As leaves no time for resting at his feet ; The
                            waiting attitude of expectation He oft-times counts a service most complete. He sometimes
                            wants our ear —- our rapt attention — That he some sweetest secret may impart; 'Tis always
                            in the time of deepest silence That heart finds deepest fellowship with heart. We sometimes
                            wonder why our Lord doth place us Within a sphere so narrow, so obscure, That nothing we
                            call work can find an entrance ; There's only room to suffer — to endure. Well, God loves
                            patience ! Souls that dwell in stillness, Doing the little things or renting quite, May
                            justas perfectly fulfill their mission, Be just as useful in the Father's sight, As they who
                            grapple with some giant evil, Clearing a path that every eye may see ! Our Saviour cares for
                            cheerful acquiescence, Rather than for a busy ministry. And yet he does love service, where
                            'tis given By grateful love that clothes itself in deed; But work that's done beneath the
                            scourge of duty, Be sure to such he gives but little heed. Then seek to please him,
                            whatsoe'er he bids thee! Whether to do, to suffer, to lie still! 'Twill matter little by
                            what path he led us If in it all we sought to do his will! </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Order of Shakers, a priesthood, not a sect" TEIform="index"/> THE ORDER OF SHAKERS, A
                            PRIESTHOOD, NOT A SECT. DANIEL FRAZER.</head><p TEIform="p">Every act of this priesthood should represent a divine motive, and be outwardly illustrative
                            of hygienic and moral law. How much the spirits in prison (those who have done wrong to
                            themselves and to <pb n="146" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/>the neighbors) need help as such a priesthood can
                            render, I am not prepared to say. But if there is another planet in all the wide beyond,
                            whose inhabitants present so seething a mass of physiological and moral impurity as ours
                            does, I would send every soul of them, the dyspepsia, the cholera, the small-pox or the itch
                            ; and carry them all off, or leave them so busy scratching themselves, as to utterly
                            preclude the possibility of scratching any thing out of their neighbors. The thoughts of
                            many indwellers of clay do not, practically, extend much beyond their own mole-hill. Those
                            who see the ages as they roll, their thoughts are more dignified. They see that the time
                            allotted, and all the troubles assigned to man, are but brief, educational opportunities,
                            preparatory to a life of higher aims, and nobler purposes. And that there will be those who
                            will rise into the higher life, and being clothed with a divine humanity, form a priesthood,
                            whose presence will say: ''Peace, be still, ye elements of human trouble." At first, it will
                            be traduced; but the never-dying afflatus flowing through them, from the " Throne of Eternal
                            Brightness," will, in succeeding generations, call forth forms of love, beauty, peace and
                            good will. Even the hems of their garments will be curative ; and the sweetness of their
                            spirits will catalyze into harmony, even devils. Chemists know that there are substances
                            that by mere contact arrest decomposition. And again, there are substances, which, when pat
                            in contact with another certain substance, will change its chemical character, and yet
                            themselves remain unchanged and undiminished. That divinely vitalized beings possess a
                            corresponding power I have not the smallest doubt ; indeed, I have the most undoubted
                            assurance that all such, whether in or out of the body, possess that power. Jesus Christ
                            expressed the same idea : " Ye are the salt of the earth ;" but if the salt loses its
                            ability to cure by contact, it will be thrown out to be trodden under foot. The salt of
                            Judea was a very poor article, and had to be kept under certain conditions to be worth any
                            thing. Hence this figure was exceedingly appropriate to all his disciples : " Watch and
                            pray," lest ye lose your power. No doubt Jesus often retired to pray that he might be able
                            to keep from evil those whom the Father had given Him. If society can be so far cured, as to
                            do justice to all its members in the matter of giving an equal chance for a start, and a run
                            in the race of life, and give over killing one another, it will be satisfactory as a
                            beginning. Musing on the state of humanity, my thoughts have run thus : Is it possible, will
                            the time ever come when society will rise above its own history — cease to repeat itself ?
                            Have the common forces of our nature, which in all ages with unerring exactitude, have given
                            the same radical features to all modifications of human society, the power to do otherwise
                            than they have done ? The response is, " history will continue to repeat itself, till a
                            superior force within and without will, to the troubled elements of our lower life, say, "
                            Peace be still." At present, society is wisely let alone, to discover and solve her own
                            problems. Evils will certainly increase, for it is their nature to reproduce, incarnate, and
                            make themselves felt. Should a few of the spirits of what are called the dark ages, visit
                            us, and compare notes, they would declare that our civilization is all alive with troubles.
                            Hence, I have been for some years inclining to the opinion, that the time is already on the
                            wing, when Shaker institutions will become a necessity in the earth. Our Order is not
                            exclusively for those who are its members ; but also others — to be a priesthood to them —
                            to change humanity into peace; to assist in introducing the crowning civilization of the
                            ages; and finally help to wind up the terrestrial destiny of man; thus fulfilling the
                            prophetic sentiment of Berkley: "Westward the course of empire takes its way, The first four
                            acts already past; The fifth will end the drama with the day — Time's noblest offering is
                            the last." </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shallow men believe in luck and circumstance..." TEIform="index"/>Shallow men believe in luck and circumstance...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Shallow men believe in luck and circumstance ; strong men believe in cause and effect.</p></div2><pb n="147" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prentissiana" TEIform="index"/>PRENTISSIANA</head><p TEIform="p"> THEOLOGY BOILED DOWN. " Let us make man" of our birthright inheritance the germ of the
                            Eternal Duad ; let us make man, male and female, in the likeness of God. The germ, our
                            highest, holiest aspiration, must germinate and be diligently nurtured by holding the lower
                            law influences in subordination to the germ. Our knowledge of God and of all thereunto
                            appertaining, is and will be in proportion to the growth of the germ. RELIGION VS. SCIENCE.
                            To primordial man, religion and science are antipodes. As, by slow and toilsome processes,
                            humanity revolves, religion and science meet and embrace each other. Bigot and infidel, with
                            expanded views of God and humanity — of God in humanity— meet, and like kindred drops,
                            mingle into one. The day dawns ; the day star is rising ; darkness shall flee away. Love
                            must govern the world. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Is Shareism the Millenium?" TEIform="index"/>IS SHAKERISM THE MILLENNIUM?</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Brethren, Lomas, Myrick, Dibble, Evans, and all other writers in the sparkling Manifesto
                            : "All ye who have the hope of the millennium, please answer me through the Manifesto some
                            questions which I will now ask you ; not in a captious spirit, but in the name of reason,
                            and all that is good, great and holy. 1. Is it possible for Shakerism to redeem the world
                            and bring the millennium in any general sense, so that order, harmony, peace, prosperity,
                            common property, and all the concomitants of brotherly love shall prevail throughout the
                            whole world ? Are you the Christ or do we look for another ? If it is not possible for
                            communism to exist for any length of time outside of the doctrine and practice of celibacy,
                            and if Shakerism is indebted for its existence more to the training and tutorage of the
                            young and unconverted taken in from the outside world, than from those who flow into it
                            through growth in grace or compulsions of the holy spirit; and if with both sources of
                            supply, you are constantly dwindling through death and desertion, are we, wellwishers to the
                            race, who are constantly praying " Thy kingdom come," to look for the whole millennium to
                            come through you ? If so, what cheer ? If not, are we to look to some generative order of
                            communism to multiply and replenish the world with a better stock of human beings who shall
                            hate war and contention, and so fulfill the prophecy of beating the sword into plough shares
                            ? Again : If there is any communism extant or yet to be developed that will bring the
                            millennium, will not that be the one that shall maintain it ? And if so, won't it have to be
                            generative, self-sustaining, etc.? Are not you Shakers to be considered the forerunners of
                            the true order rather than the order itself ? The John Baptists that shall precede the real
                            Clmst ? Is the generative act necessarily unholy any more than the act of eating—seeing that
                            both acts are in and of themselves selfish, and therefore liable to perversion ? Are not all
                            our faculties selfish in their action, each in its own sphere of activity ? ... Does not
                            even benevolence seek its own gratification, and sometimes meet restraint ? Is it not
                            possible for the people of Oneida to be just as sincere, and as much inspired by all that is
                            good and great, as you are ? If they take the wild horse of amativeness, so essential to the
                            life of men, and yet so destructive sometimes, and lasso him down to the halter, and there
                            bridle and harness and train him into the divine (?) works of a scientific propagation, to
                            the production of a more noble, human fruit age, are they not doing the noblest work
                            possible to conceive of? And is not that even in the eyes of the God of all life and purity,
                            a holier thing to do than to catch and mutilate him, and thereby compel him to live without
                            the hope of reproduction — the loss of parentage — the love of offspring, one of the most
                            unselfish, or rather one of the most selfish, and therefore the <pb n="148" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/>most
                            happifying elements of the human soul? Yours, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hamilton, D. H." TEIform="persName"/>D. H. Hamilton.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reply" TEIform="index"/> REPLY</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">1. Relative to the question: " Can Shakers inaugurate the millennial dispensation as a
                            universal phase of human evolution and experience ? " Our interrogator appears to anticipate
                            that only one class of laborers, one kind of labor, and that of earthly type, is necessary
                            to introduce the millennium demonstrably as though the jeweler should combine the task of
                            miner, assayer, goldsmith and diamondsetter, or, as though the gospel minister should be
                            taxed with the duties of civilization, including the clearing of land, agriculture, common
                            school education, jurisprudence, political economy, sociology, and all the evolutions and
                            minutiae of science; the handicrafts of art, the developments of the mental capacity,
                            through literature, and the investigations of philosophy ! The biblical patriarch Jacob, in
                            his dream of human evolution, saw a ladder reaching from earth to Heaven, representing steps
                            of progress for human development ; there must necessarily be laborers adapted and devoted
                            to each step. Before the human family can be. adapted to the millennial phase of life, it
                            must first be elevated to the true order of the earthly life, the Adamic, at least they must
                            accept, philosophically, and, until called, by perception and conviction, to a higher life,
                            practically, the righteousness of the Noachian epoch. There are workers in the field of
                            nature, striving to bring the human family into this righteousness, preparatory to a higher
                            state of progress and development into the spiritual sphere —the millennial dispensation—
                            the introduction of the Kingdom of Heaven upon earth. To those who feel a call of God, and
                            are prepared to enter upon the'labors of a millennial, spiritual, heavenly life, the doors
                            are open, and all such are prepared for and invited to come into the the courts of the inner
                            temple — the millennium ; none others can recognize its advent, therefore it never can be
                            instantaneously universal. The Kingdom of Christ, pre-eminently, is not an earthly, bnt a
                            heavenly inheritance: "My kingdom is not of this world," said Jesus Christ. It has its
                            existence in souls who are willing to rise out of and dwell above the mere animal,
                            passional, generative plane of life; these, few or many, constitute the Christ revealed to
                            earth's inhabitants in the present time; these inaugurate the millennium; and, though
                            mankind look long and anxiously, they will never see any other, 2. Of Communism, as of
                            individualism, there are two orders —earthly and heavenly. The first is obtained by a
                            joining of individual, self interest, for a mutual gain to self, of all parties composing
                            the community, but subject to division at the pleasure of the individual, each withdrawing
                            his individual portion of the gain, at any desirable opportunity, The consecration of
                            selfish gain to the individual, as to the communeyro tern., on some plan of organization, is
                            the only successful scheme upon which a mere earthly — worldly communism can succeed. On the
                            contrary, a consecration of life's labors, interests, entire treasures and gains,
                            indivisible and inviolate, to the service of God, and to the promulgation of the Gospel of
                            Christ, and the dispensation of its charities, constitutes a communism of the heavenly
                            order, which is but the outward manifestation of the internal relation ; and this alone is
                            the communism of the millennium. A growth or development of humanity toward its attainment
                            will ever be gradual like the rising of the sun ; it never can be instantaneous and
                            evanescent, like the lightning flash, or the bursting of a meteor; all scriptural
                            misinterpretations to the contrary notwithstanding. 3. "What Cheer toward the Millennium ? "
                            Why the fact, that in each and every human being there is an angelic nature, which, in its
                            evolution, yearns for this phase of development. If the forerunner be so difficult to attain
                            what would the reality be ? Add to this the universal unrest and transitions of professors
                            of religion of all denominations, multitudes going from one de- <pb n="149" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. 149 nomination to another, and from that to spiritualism ; from that to
                            infidelity, and from this again to spiritualism. 4. To the reforms of the generative order
                            mankind are to look for the salvation of mankind from those debasing and dissoluting habits
                            and diseases that threaten the destruction of the human race from the face of the earth, and
                            to the subsequent reproductions of this reformed humanity for a conservation of the race
                            from oblivion. Generation peoples the earth plane ; but it is a death to the generative,
                            worldly life — regeneration — that people the heavens ! " He that saveth his life "—(the
                            generative, selfish worldly life-) "shall lose it — (the heavenly life), " but he that
                            loseth his life— (the worldly generative, fleshly life) " for my sake and the Gospel's,
                            shall find it" !— (the new regenerated life) " unto life eternal "— Christ ! 5. The Shaker
                            church is by no means the " forerunner of the true Order, rather than the order itself." The
                            "forerunner" to which our querist refers, is the reform of generation and worldly society.
                            If the forerunner be so difficult to attain, what would the reality be ? The Shaker
                            organization is the order of the millennium itself, ' like a grain of mustard seed," which
                            is to grow unto a tree so that " in its branches shall rest fowl of every wing." It is the "
                            harvest of the world." 6. Concerning " the holiness of the generative act," as our querist
                            expresses it: That alone is holy which is wholly and entirely devoted and consecrated to a
                            Godly use, for that is the meaning of holiness. Were it possible for generation to be
                            divested of all selfishness and lust — performed agreeably to the laws of God in nature, it
                            would be in its sphere and place, but would not, and could not elevate man above the
                            perfected, earthly, animal plane. The angel in man—his soul's evolution and development must
                            still be pending. The " training of the wild horse of amativeness " is a goodly and
                            important work of reform for the earthly Adamic man, and those engaged therein, sincerely
                            and honestly, may be inspired by spirits in the generative life ; but as the physical body
                            is inferior to the soul, even as the casket is inferior to the jewel it contains ; as the
                            sowing, though proper in its time and place, is less glorious than the harvest, so the
                            earthly millennium, or the state of reformed, earthly, animal nature and life, must always
                            be a lower plane condition than the inheritance in that " kingdom which is not of this
                            world." 7. The spiritual " emasculations '' which fit souls for the Kingdom of God are never
                            " compulsory," nor do they unsex the subject, except in relation to those elements that are
                            earthly, sensual and devilish ! " In Christ there is neither male nor female " generatively;
                            but regeneratively there is both male and female in all the tenderness, loveableness and
                            affection of the angels of God, and they will be the progenitors of a spiritual off-spring
                            to fill the Heavens for multitude. " Neither let the eunuch say, behold, lama dry tree."
                            "For more are the children of the desolate than the married wife, saith the Lord."—Isa. lvi,
                            3, and liv, 1. Shakers, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What matter" TEIform="index"/>WHAT MATTER</head><p TEIform="p">What matter, friend, though you and I May sow, and others gather ? We build, and others
                            occupy, Each laboring for the other. What though we toil from sun to sun, And men forget to
                            flatter The noblest work our hands have done — If God approve, what matter? What matter
                            though we sow in tears, And crops fail at the reaping; What though the fruit of patient
                            years Fast perish in our keeping ; Upon our hoarded treasure, floods Arise and tempests
                            gather — If faith beholds beyond the clouds A clear sky, what matter? What matter though our
                            castles fall, And disappear while building ; Though strange handwriting on the wall Flame
                            out amid the gilding ; Though every idol of the heart The hand of death may shatter ; Though
                            hopes decay and friends depart— If heaven be ours, what matter ? " </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="From time immemorial it has been..." TEIform="index"/>From time immemorial it has been...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">From time immemorial it has been, and still is, the folly of the world to crucify its
                            Saviours, and deify its destroyers."</p></div2><pb n="150" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Infidel sophistry repuked" TEIform="index"/>INFIDEL SOPHISTRY REBUKED</head><p TEIform="p"> " The fool hath said in Ids heart there is no God "—Psalm 53, 1. Friend : — It seems there
                            were plenty of infidels in the days of the Psalmist, as he complains often and mournfully of
                            being perplexed by the taunting question: "Where is thy God ? " I had thought I would not
                            trouble you further, until I saw Underwood's argument, which he used in the Scranton debate.
                            Yours and his being so far short of sound reason, and so misleading, I have concluded to
                            briefly notice them. You think I have " not made a point for Shaker celibacy." I admit the
                            impossibility of making a favorable point for any who are swallowed up in sexual animalism,
                            as most of the world now are. They are like moles working away under ground, and know
                            nothing of the bright sunshine above them. My first duty to you is not to make a point for
                            celibacy, but to convince you of an immortal part and immortal life ; failing in this, I
                            know, so far as you are concerned, all my efforts will be labor lost ; but I trust it may
                            save others from being drawn into the maelstrom in which you seem to be engulfed. I think
                            you honest, but lacking in education. This is strikingly manifest in your asserting that the
                            thinking being within you is merely a portion of your body, though you afterward contradict
                            this by saying your thinking being was not in a tub-mixture. You say that " thought is the
                            result of certain organic combinations of matter and molecular action." If these molecules
                            were not in the tub-mixture, whence came they? You are very correct in saying the power of
                            thought was not in the tub-mixture of which your body is composed, because in its formation
                            no other matter was added, but there was a thinking power added which was not in the tub of
                            matter. If you had known that it was the uniform testimony of all the great philosophers and
                            deep thinkers that ever lived, that thought was the attribute of spirit, but not of matter,
                            your cool, self-assuring positivity would have yielded to a modest doubt respecting the
                            truth of your position in saying dogmatically, that " thought is merely a movement of the
                            molecules of the brain." Now, remember these atoms were in the tub-mixture—why did they not
                            think then ? Did a mere change of position give them the power of thought ? Do these
                            molecules move upward to have high thoughts, and downward to have low thoughts, and backward
                            to think wrong, and forward to think right ? Further, do the molecules act of themselves, or
                            is there some other power which causes them to think ? Were you a logician, I would call you
                            back to a reconsideration of most of your postulates, which are as defective as the one
                            under consideration. Does your intelligence and knowledge increase by the tumbling together
                            of a thimbleful of molecules? Are the little corpuscles or atoms of matter which form the
                            molecules independent in their actions when they take a notion to think ? When fpassion
                            demands and your judgment objects, saying no, on which side are the molecules ? Are they
                            both objecting and agreeing, saying, " I will not consent consented ? " Or is there not a
                            judge within to approve or condemn, besides the passions or atoms? What is .it that causes
                            compunction ? Is it the liver, stomach, lungs or heart, or is it a little phosphorous or
                            electricity ? You surely can now see that your position is untenable. You confess this much
                            by saying, " It is true mind was not in the tub-mixture." You acknowledge you have a mind.
                            Whence came it? I pass over all your hads and ifs as containing nothing germane to the
                            subject of mind, as you now cannot fail to see the dilemma in which you have placed
                            yourself. You say, ".If there is an existence superior to man I am ready to believe. If you
                            or any person will give me a single proof of it." I gave you proof a posteriori, which is
                            the most sure and correct mode of reasoning, but it seems you did not comprehend it. I will
                            try to make it more clear before I get through You say, "I am not too proud to be
                            converted." Will you compel me to think you are too dull ? You say, " I feel accountable to
                            myself." Which part of you is it that feels accountable to some other part ? What part? Now
                            look at it: Is it not the animal material part that is accountable to <pb n="151" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE SHAKES MANIFESTO. 151 the mental or spiritual being within ? Or do tlie eyes feel
                            accountable to the ears ? How must we understand you, if it is not the outer self that is
                            accountable to the inner self. You cannot help seeing and knowing that matter cannot be
                            accountable to matter;hence you have acknowledged your spiritual being in saying you are
                            accountable to yourself. Again, you are mistaken in saying that animals think as we do. The
                            difference is this : The former act without deliberation or reason, being governed by the
                            laws of instinct. All they learn from man is from the external, while man deliberates,
                            reasons and learns almost wholly from within, by the operation of the infinite mind on his
                            intellect and higher consciousness; from this source comes his increased intelligence, while
                            animals progress not. The magpie builds her nest now just as the first magpie did. Fixed
                            laws govern all but men, who alone is a progressive creature. You say you want proof. Are
                            these evidences insufficient ? But you believe particles of matter think, without a particle
                            of proof. Of this, proof is impossible in any direction—a posteriori or a priori. Still you
                            believe this easily, while you ." fight shy " of all evidence going to prove mental, soul or
                            spiritual existence. You should strive to be con sistent. Now please stand up while I again
                            give you my proofs of a higher existence than man. Listen attentively, a priori reasoning is
                            from cause to effect, while a posteriori reasoning is from effect to cause. In either case
                            the judgments must be palpable and indisputable or the reasoning will be vain. Assertion is
                            at no time reason. Yours is incumbered with too many of these. First, let me question you.
                            Will you agree that no effect can equal the cause ? Yes. Is man, as we find him, body and
                            mind, an effect ? Yes ; he did not cause his existence. Then if he did not cause liis
                            existence, that cause was greater than man? Yes. Now, is there any thing in the arcanum of
                            nature greater than man ? No. Well, then, it logically follows beyond cavil that there is an
                            intelligent cause of his existence above and distinct from nature. I call that cause by the
                            name God; you may call it by what name you please. Still unsatisfied, you ask me, did not
                            man arise out of nature ? Answer—His body is of nature ; his mind of God. If it did arise
                            the course of the rising was God. You can now be seated. Was not the Psalmist right in
                            saying " The fool sayeth in his heart there is no God 1" I now with you stop abruptly, as I
                            wish to show up the sophistry of Brother Underwood's reasoning. He and Evans, his
                            antagonist, both seem drifted out to sea without chart or compass. Persons who both affirm
                            and deny the same thing of a proposition vitiate their whole line of argument. This is more
                            particularly the case with Underwood than with his opponent. He starts well by the
                            enunciation of a Spencerian truth—" All change is due to an absolute self-existent
                            substance, the nature of which is inscrutable." He could not mean matter, for matter is not
                            inscrutable. He must have reference to Spencer's and Tyndall's unknowable force or power
                            behind nature, which we call God. But he goes on and affirms that " matter and force are not
                            two separate entities, but are simply two aspects of the same thing." This postulate
                            violates the canon of logic which demands that " every proposition which is not self-evident
                            be analyzed and reduced to its simplest elements, and made clear before the synthetic
                            process begins." Both of these gentlemen frequently violate this, with other canons of logic
                            in their arguments, which render them reliable. Now if matter and force are only different
                            aspects of the same thing-—he must mean matter at rest and matter in motion—hence we have no
                            use for the term "force," but herein is involved a contradiction; for he has told us that
                            all change in matter was due to an inscrutable substance in nature which must be different
                            from matter. His adding, " No force without matter—no matter without force,"' is, according
                            to his own definition, simply saying, no matter without matter. But he blunders along, as
                            one false position requires another false position to sustain it. Not recognizing mind
                            force, he goes on to affirm that " intelligence is a form of force." Thus runs his logic:
                            First sumption — Force is an aspect of matter. <pb n="152" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 152 THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. Second sumption — Intelligence is a form of force. Ergo—Intelligence is a form of
                            the aspect of matter. Such logic for a teacher ! But any thing to deny an intelligent power
                            above nature. Now, Underwood, please stand up till I question you. First—-What kind of
                            matter is force ? Answer—I said it was an aspect of matter. Well, then, it is an appearance
                            of matter ; that is, matter and force are two appearances of the same thing! Well, then, if
                            matter is rough or smooth, or black or white, it is different aspects of the same thing.
                            Then intelligence is a form of the same thing. When an otherwise intelligent mind is driven
                            to such a corner in defending the no-God idea one cannot help exclaiming that the Psalmist
                            spoke a high truth when he said, '' The fool sayeth in his heart there is no God." Now let
                            us return to the " inscrutable substance " that causes all change in matter. I ask, Is that
                            inscrutable substance intelligent? Yes. Is the matter which it changes intelligent ? ]STo.
                            Well then that inscrutable substance is not matter. It follows then that nature or matter is
                            subordinate to this changing power which you call cause, and we call God. So then confess
                            that God exists, seeing your arguments establish the fact, contrary to what you intended.
                            Now it is evident and not to be disputed that this infinite intelligent force operates on
                            the mind and consciousness of man, increasing his knowledge and giving mind power, and this
                            power which fills immensity we most properly call God. This conclusion, it seems to me, is
                            irresistible. Again you say, " Mind is disappearing." How ? It is reappearing much faster
                            than it is disappearing. Please tell me what mind is, as you acknowledge a distinction
                            between it and matter '? Is it conditioned or unconditioned, an extended or unextended
                            substance? Answer—Well, I hardly know; to be honest, I cannot tell. Can pou? Certainly. It
                            is the spirit entity that inhabits your clay house. Yon ask: Can this be demonstrated ?
                            Certainly. Matter we have agreed cannot think Mind thinks within you, therefore it is a
                            distinct entity from matter. This entity we call spirit. To concede, as we do, that mind is
                            greater than matter, and then say it was the product of nature, would be making the effect
                            greater than the cause, which is impossible ; and as this cannot be, it follows that a
                            greater cause than either nature or man gave mind to him ; as said, this cause we call God.
                            There is no escaping this conclusion. Again, Underwood says, after portraying the evils that
                            are in the world : Infinite power could remove evil. Infinite goodness would do it, but evil
                            exists; then there is a lack of either goodness or power, therefore an infinite God can not
                            exist." Thus he supposes he has proved the nonexistence of God to a demonstration. But the
                            sophistry is easily exposed. It is simply saying that if God does not remove or retain what
                            I think should be removed or retained, then there is no God. Ignorant presumption ! As
                            though his finite sense of right and wrong, good and evil, should be the rule for the
                            infinite mind of the universe ! All evil originates with man, who, in order to progression,
                            is created with free agency. If he could not deviate from the breath of goodness he could no
                            more progress than a block of wood or stone. If all mankind would so govern themselves as to
                            be moved only by the attribute of goodness there would be no suffering in any quarter of the
                            globe. Why did he not say at once, if God is good and all powerfnl, why did He not make me a
                            perfect and good man ? Why did He not make me God, equal in goodness with Himself ? And why
                            does He allow me to stump my toe, or cheat my neighbor, or go astray in any thing ? If He
                            does not do all this, but leaves me to take care of myself, then " an infinite God cannot
                            exist." Is it not the fool that sayeth in his heart '' there is no God ? " The Fetish who
                            bows down before the orb of day in worshipful veneration, with his mind extended beyond to
                            the Author and Cause of the luminary, acts with much more sense and wisdom than the learned
                            infidel who denies the existence of such cause. Let it be noted that I am not contending for
                            an anthropomorphic Deity, not for one who would require a hole like the Mammoth Cave for an
                            entrance, nor for the pantheist's personal infinite — a personal infinite is a
                            contradiction—a personal infin- <pb n="153" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/>ity is impossible. The pantheist is as
                            sense. ess as the atheist, and much more so than he theist who gives a human form to the
                            Deity. He mistakes the shadow for the sustance. And while he can easily perceive that his
                            finite mind is distinct from the mat, 'tel' of his body, he is inconsistent and foolish
                            enough to affirm that the shadow is a component part of the infinite mind, when he denies
                            the same of his own mind and body! It is no more the case with the infinite mind than his
                            own shadow is a part of his body; but thus the pantheist lives all his life in a
                            contradiction. Could he look upon all 'matter as a mere shadow, which it is, when compared
                            with mind, his difficulties would all be removed. For when this fieeting [shadow passes from
                            us, and the soul is free. it is not then a world of matter we shall live in, but a world of
                            mind, for matter is no more obstruction to spirit movement than a shadow is to our bodily
                            movement. Then we shall i have exchanged the shadow for the substance. Whoever claimsthat a
                            part of the infinite mind is insensate matter is as insane as the man who would say his nose
                            or great toe was a part of the finite intelligent Ego within him, or that the spittle from
                            his mouth had been a part of his soul which he was now spitting out! If we know, as I
                            contend we do, and as I have demonstrated, that we have a spirit entity or Ego within us,
                            which is distinct from the matter of our body, we may then know that the universal over-soul
                            or Ego of the universe, the infinite mind, is distinct from matter, and by law directs and
                            governs it, as he, by our finite spirit, directs us. It is not rational nor sensible to
                            declare that matter is a part of the infinite mind because we cannot see how infinity can be
                            infinity without including the shadow with the substance. I repeat, matter cannot be a part
                            of the infinite mind any more than our fingers and toes can be a part of the finite mind.
                            The two are distinct, matter is ever changing, but the infinite mind is changeless, always
                            existing from everlasting and always perfect. It is said by a late writer, that the Bible
                            teaches a personal God. It also teaches an infinite God. The personal God is simply a person
                            through and by whom the attributes of Deity are most conspicuously manifested to the world.
                            This is "God manifest in the flesh," and it is, then, both safe and our duty to look to this
                            light and obey it, because he will never see the infinite wholeness, neither in time nor
                            eternity. The finite will never comprehend the infinite. Among all who ever walked on this
                            planet, Christ was the person who manifested the greatest fulness of the attributes of Deity
                            - was the first to call him Father. He was the manifestation of God to the world. '1'0 Him,
                            then, we may safely look, and if the infinite mind has through and by Him established an
                            order whereby we may likewise be brought into the same harmony and relation to God that He
                            attained to, then we should look to that order, and blend with it. Any other course is
                            senseless and suicidal.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eads, H. L." TEIform="persName"/>H. L. Eads</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It may be your turn next" TEIform="index"/>IT MAY BE YOUR TURN NEXT. </head><p TEIform="p">Judge not too harshly, oh, my friend I Of him your fellow man, But draw the veil of charity
                            About him if you can. He once was called an honest man, Before some trial vexed - He stepped
                            from out the narrow way - It may be your turn next. Fainting- upon the great highway A
                            suffering soul doth lie ; Go staunch his wounds and quench his thirst, Nor pass him idly by.
                            God will not brook the swift excuse, The thoughtless vain pretext, A fellow-mortal bites the
                            dust- It may be your turn next. You heard, one day, a single word Against a person's name;
                            Oh, bear it not from door to door 'I'o further hurt his fame. If you're the. man you claim
                            to be, Remember then, the text, '1'0 " Speak no evil," true or false It may be your turn
                            next. The world is bad enough, we own, And may need still more light; Yet, with true love to
                            all, may be Help in the cause of Hight'. Lift up the sinful and the weak, The soul by care
                            perplexed, Well knowing that to drink the gall, It may be your turn next, </p></div2><pb n="154" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial.</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good time come" TEIform="index"/>THE GOOD TIME COME. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Never before did" the good time coming" appear so near as now. It is even at our doors -
                                it has entered the tabernacle of human hearts - and we see eye to eye as never before,
                                that the life of Ghrist is the only genuine Ohristianity. Creeds, which have hindered
                                the dawn of this religious liberty - to think and to know this great truth - are at a
                                very great discount, almost on a par with the chaff of the most bigoted sectarianism.
                                Accepting the life of the great Ohristian founder as the main and only important feature
                                of the Ohristian religion, the worse than superstitious error of " Jesus dying on Oal
                                vary for the sins of the people," will be dispelled. He died for us, truly, but He died
                                unto a worldly, fleshly, sinful nature, long before His sufferings upon the triangular
                                erection. He died in defense of principles which must be accepted and lived in order to
                                be a Ohristian. He was crucified unto physical death, rather than prove unfaithful to
                                His conscientious dictates - the will of His Father. In the death of Jesus, we learn the
                                important lesson of dying in defense of the right, rather than to live contrary to the
                                will of God. Herein was the only good determined by His cruel death. But in that
                                beautiful life - that loving, peaceable, unretaliating, unselfish and virgin-pure life -
                                herein was and is the essence and spirit of His mission - herein we have an elder
                                brother, a noble, leading exampler of how we must live to he Ohristians, His disciples,
                                His follow- ers, N ow is the good time all who espouse this truth, knowledge, "'Tis not
                                the wide phylactery, Nor stubborn fast, nor stated prayers That make us saints; we judge
                                It tree By what it bears. And when a man can live apart From works, on theologic trust,
                                I know the blood about his heart Is dryas dust." 'I'he religious institutions, the world
                                over, demand fruits as evidences of our beliefs, and the correctness of our, creeds is
                                determined by the quality, purity and unselfishness of our lives as illustrated in every
                                day behavior. With this demand active, the world is growing better; in fact was never,
                                nearly so good before. The good time has come, and reason and the religion of common,
                                good sense, prevails over the unchristian creeds which ignored the brilliant efficacy of
                                living Christ's life, while they clunr/l.th unfruitful hopes to a useless and cruel
                                death. Life, the life of Christ, has conquered death,' and never in the future, can
                                error spread its direful influences upon the religions feelings of the people, that they
                                ever more will choose death rather than life. For this good time come, so actually and
                                extensively, let us all be truly grateful. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Monstrous Hypocrisy" TEIform="index"/>A MONSTROUS HYPOCRISY. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">It is pretty generalJt u nderstood that Shaker testimony is diametrically opposed to the
                                mingling of churchal affairs with state matters. As evidence of our good faith in this
                                desirable and necessary opposition, we have ever declined to enter political arenas, ,
                                or to express by our votes any prefer-. ences for political aspirants; or to ao-. cept
                                proffered political positions with<pb n="155" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 155 their
                                honors and emoluments. We believe, with Jesus, in rendering unto worldly governments
                                their dues; and in being ever more faithful to keep God's tributes,tdue from us,
                                separate and uncontaminated from the policies of state. Hence, we are opposed to the
                                thousands of military post chaplains, chaplains of legislative bodies, and chaplains of
                                regiments in the Burgess or national guard. We have a Christian testimony against, and
                                horror of, any chaplain who professes Jesus Christ, who yet believes in war,
                                retaliation, the maiming of human lives or the spilling of human blood under any
                                circumstances. Under Judaism such detestable officials and disgraceful cormorants, under
                                pay of the devil and perverted treasuries, might with some reasonable excuses occupy;
                                but a minister occupying a position where duty compels the dispensations of the New
                                Testament, in which the forgiveness of sins and love of enemies is so abundantly taught,
                                yet who suborn themselves for lucre to the teaching of forgiveness of enemies, but not
                                until after they have killed them, is a most disgraceful hypocrisy! Gen. Schofield, at
                                West Point, lately bore valuable evidence against such frauds as military chaplains,
                                when he disclaimed that they ever taught any "such foolishness as unretaliation!" " The
                                New Testament teaches such a doctrine," retorted the General, " but we teach no such
                                foolishness here ! " and this is true with the entire state governments the world over.
                                We therefore enter a loud, living and eternal protest against such abominable hypocrites
                                as chaplains, who, under Christian colors, plead excuses for, or who encourage war. Tell
                                ns not our protests are in vain; for the good, true, and best sense of the entire people
                                are with us, and will yet effectually rid the country of such Jesuitical hypocrisy. It
                                is a most disgraceful perversion of the high calling of a Christian minister to mingle
                                his voice as such, where common sense teaches the hypocrisy and sacrilege of his
                                prayers. We plead with governments of state to dismiss all such, and in the interim of
                                such action by the government, we invite every such chaplain professing Christ, to
                                immediately resign.</p></div3><div3 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial Notes</head><div4 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Providential workings" TEIform="index"/>Providential workings
                                </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">EDITORIAL NOTES. PROVIDENTIAL WORKINGS. Only a few years since, and there went up
                                    from all over the lands, the dreadful howls and disturbing commotions of religious
                                    controversies. Nothing engendered more bitterness of feeling nor reprehensible
                                    vituperation. To-day men love their fellows too well, to quarrel with them over
                                    matters about which each has the right to enjoy freedom of opinion and conscience,
                                    so long as no infringement occurs upon the civil or religious rights of others. And
                                    yet this grand change from bitterly waged, religious (?) crusades, to peaceful,
                                    golden-ruled courtesy, has come, and come to stay. Ask men "how all this has
                                    happened?" " What has been the cause of the great, good change ? " None can give a
                                    definite answer, commensurate to the occasion. But we know that the " powers of the
                                    world to come " have been busy — the angels are nearer to-day <pb n="156" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/>
                                    156 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. than ever, and the time being ripe for their labor, "the
                                    day-star has arisen, the morning dawns; the sun, in full meridian splendor, will
                                    certainly appear. Let us work with the angels. Said the good man: " My Father
                                    worketh hitherto ; and I work."</p></div4><div4 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit of our July number" TEIform="index"/>Spirit of our July number
                                </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> THE SPIRIT OF OUR JULY NUMBER. By a careful perusal of our present issue it will
                                    appear to the candid reader fruitful with hope and confidence in our loving
                                    parentage, Father and Mother God, and the continued growth of love to our fellow
                                    beings. The cogent and liberal feelings exhibited by our brethren are worthy of
                                    notice. Although Elder Eads is determined the infidels shall have a God, yet he is
                                    very kind hearted about his compulsions we know. Eead Bright's and Beecher's
                                    remarks. Consider the tribute to Jesus paid by our liberal brethren, the Hebrews ;
                                    and the "Teachings of The Talmud." In " Creeds" we find exhibited a very pretty
                                    spirit; and we get some important lessons from "Religions of Head and Heart." The
                                    epitome of •'The Wisdom of Contemporaries" will give all more love, and better
                                    opinion of mankind's leaders of thought. Don't fail to learn "The True Shepherd's
                                    Voice," and sing it with us on second Sunday in July. We have endeavored to present
                                    a good number. The verdict we leave with our intelligent readers.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bishop Bedell says that..." TEIform="index"/>Bishop Bedell says that...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Bishop Bedell says that, if ministers would only speak the trath in funeral sermons, the
                                demand for such discourses would be rapidly diminished. It would be a bold man who
                                should undertake the experiment.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto.</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Virgin tree" TEIform="index"/>THE VIRGIN THEE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sproat, Granville T." TEIform="persName"/>Granville T. Sproat.</byline><p TEIform="p">Among the north-western tribes of American Indians, I once witnessed a very interesting
                                ceremony, called " WahMskah Metig" or the "Test of the Virgin Tree." It was in the month
                                of May, which the Indians call the " moon of flowers," that this festival was
                                celebrated. The place selected was a beautiful plain, in the center of which was a large
                                tree, called, in honor of the occasion, the " Virgin Tree." This tree was decorated with
                                wreaths of pure, white flowers, woven, on the morning of the festival, by the maidens of
                                the tribe. On the morning of the day, all the village band assembled and seated
                                themselves around the tree, while the maidens of the tribe danced around it in quick and
                                uniform succession, singing the song of the White Spirits, which may be translated thus
                                : " I bear a gift of purity ; I bear a gift from White Spirits to me ; I bear a gift
                                from the Virgin Tree." While singing this song, the maiden reached forth her hand and
                                touched the tree, and taking from it a wreath of white flowers, placed it on her head.
                                She then turned to the assembly and waited for a response from them, which was this; "It
                                is yours! it is yours! the gift of the White Spirit is yours !" If any one in the
                                assembly failed to respond to these words, he was called forth, questioned, and then
                                made to confront the maiden and bear witness to her want of chastity. If this could be
                                proved, she was stripped of her crown of white flowers, and expelled from the band of
                                Vestals; nor could she be admitted, until after several months of fasting and
                                purification, among the band of worshipers that worshiped in the Great Open Lodge of
                                Worship, before the Great Spirit. Come to the Virgin Tree ! Ye Vestals, one and all !
                                Come, for pure spirits from the skies Are sending forth their call. <pb n="157" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 157 " Come forth ! come forth ! " they cry, "And join the
                                Heaven-crowned throng ! Come, let your hearts and voices join, And sing the Vestal
                                song." Come to the Virgin Tree! The place is holy ground, Here peace, and joy, and
                                gentle love From heavenly spheres are found. No darkness gathers here — Light beams from
                                worlds above ; Pure are the spirits waiting here To bless us with their love. Come to
                                the Virgin Tree ! Let no unhallowed feet Approach this tree of purity Where Heavenly
                                spirits meet! Let no base, wanton fires Burn in the Vestal's breast, Upon whose
                                consecrated brow The sacred crown shall rest! Come to the Virgin Tree ! Around it,
                                bending down, The radiant ones draw near to bless The Vestals, with their crown. They
                                bless from spheres above, The crown of purity ; Oh ! with what love they gather here,
                                Around the Virgin Tree ! Canaa, N. Y..</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record.</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>PASSED TO THE BETTER LAND.</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bates, Martha Phelps" TEIform="index"/>Martha Phelps Bates
                                </head><p TEIform="p"/></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sizer, Daniel" TEIform="index"/>Daniel Sizer
                                </head><p TEIform="p"/></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall, Helen H." TEIform="index"/>Helen H. Hall
                                </head><p TEIform="p"/></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Foltz, John" TEIform="index"/>John Foltz
                                </head><p TEIform="p"/></div4><div4 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><p TEIform="p">From Shakers, N. Y , May 31, Martha Pfielps Bates, aged 77 years. From Canaan, N. Y.,
                                    June 6, Dantel Sizer, aged 76. From Harvard, Mass., June 12, Helen H. Hall, aged 24
                                    From Union Village, O., June 13, John Foltz, aged 65 years. The Central Ministry
                                    leave Mt. Lebanon for an extended visit to Eastern Societies, on Aug. 11.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We cannot make men unworldly..." TEIform="index"/>We cannot make men unworldly...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">We cannot make men unworldly by crying down their daily work as of no
                                        spiritual importance, and contrasting it with " religious " duties. What they
                                        need is the presence of Christian motives, to act in every thing for the glory
                                        of God, and whatever they do, " do it heartily as unto the Lord." Under the
                                        inspiration of this motive, a man may be just as religious in managing a
                                        railroad, in planting crops, or in making brooms, as in preaching and praying.
                                        Indeed, all honest work, done with Christian motives, is a sort of prayer, and
                                        is an essential means of grace.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Methodist" TEIform="index"/>— The Methodist.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Table.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="History of England" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Science in story" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Golden days" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">" MORE AND MORE " Still come pouring from the press of I. K. Funk &amp; Co., Nos. 10
                                and 12 Dey street, New York. Continued volumes of Knight's unequaled History of England,
                                at only 30 cents a volume. Besides, these enterprising publishers are doing a most
                                commendable work of reissuing, with new type, some of the most valuable books ever
                                published in both the old and new world, and at fabulously low prices. We urge our
                                readers to send, with our compliments and get a catalogue of the books and rates already
                                issned, and judge if what we have heretofore said respecting the above firm is not true.
                                '' SCIENCE IN STORY." This is the title of a profusely illustrated volume, intended to
                                teach youth and children correct physiological truths. The story connects a mischievous
                                monkey with a household, where a doctor's page is taking some excellent lessons upon the
                                human frame, causes and effects of health and disease, etc., and one is tempted to laugh
                                and grow fat while unconsciously getting most desirable information upon health matters.
                                Moreover, it is a safe book to put into the hands of young people, inspiring in them a
                                desire to shun bad habits, the necessity of medicine, and to keep the liring temple
                                healthful and clean. It is issued in five small books, or the same combined in one large
                                volume. By The Murray Hill Pub. Co. , New York city. Parents would do well to get a
                                sample book. The Golden Days is a weekly paper printed in Philadelphia, Pa., by the
                                publisher of " Saturday Night," and is carefully prepared for boys' and girls'
                                recreation and information. Unlike the majority of periodicals issued specially for
                                young people, it is remarkably free from foolishness and food to excite the already too
                                wide awake passions, and while interesting the young mind, is ingeniously weaving a web
                                of useful facts, figures and information, to be <pb n="158" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 158 THE SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. highly appreciated after many days." The religious feelings are fostered in a
                                proper department, while " Uncle Will " seems to have an unfathomable fund of knowledge
                                in scientific facts to impart. The paper must be popular, and will do much good,
                                displacing much trashy literature so frequently falling into youthful hands and heads.
                                It is fully illustrated. John Everson, Publisher, Philadelphia, Pa.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Agricultural.</head><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Connecticut Dairyman, who has been experimenting..." TEIform="index"/>A Connecticut Dairyman, who has been experimenting...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A Connecticut Dairyman, who has been experimenting with turnips as food for cows, thinks
                                they are worth twenty-five cents a bushel. There was no saving in the amount of hay
                                consumed, but they increased the flow of milk, and were an aid to the digestion of hay
                                and other dry fodder. European experimenters have come to the same conclusion.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to estimate crops per acre" TEIform="index"/>How to estimate crops per acre
                            </head><p TEIform="p">How to Estimate Crops per Acre.— Place together four light sticks, measuring exactly a
                                foot square inside, and with this measure walk into the field and select a spot of fair
                                average yield, and lower the frame square over as many heads as it will en-' close, and
                                shell out the heads thus inclosed carefully, and weigh the grain. It is fair to presume
                                that the produce will be the 43,560th part of an acre's produce. To prove it, go through
                                the field and make ten or twenty similar calculations, and estimate by the mean of the
                                whole number of results. It will certainly enable a farmer to make a closer calculation
                                of what a field can produce than he can by guessing.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Box measures" TEIform="index"/>Box measures
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Box Measures. ¦— Farmers and market gardeners will find a series of box measures very
                                useful; and they will readily be made by any one who understands the two foot rule, and
                                can handle the saw and the hammer. A box 16 by 16 1-3 inches square, and 8 inches deep,
                                will contain a bushel, or 2150.4 cubic inches, each inch in depth holding one gallon. A
                                box 24 by 11 1-5 inches square, and 8 inches deep, will also contain a bushel, or 2150.4
                                cubic inches, each inch in depth holding one gallon. A box 12 by 11 1-5 inches square,
                                and 8 inches deep, will contain half a bushel, or 1075.2 cubic inches, each inch in
                                depth holding half a gallon. A box 8 by 8 1-4 inches square, and 8 inches deep, will
                                contain half a peck, or 298.8 cubic inches. The gallon dry measure. A box 4 by 4 inches
                                square, and 4 1-5 inches deep, will contain one quart, or 67.2 cubic inches.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Revised table of weights" TEIform="index"/>Revised table of weights
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Revised Table of Weights. Apples, dry......... 22 lbs. per bushel. Barley..............
                                58 " Beans............. 60 " Beef................200 " per barrel. • " ................
                                303 " per tierce. Blue Grass Seed..... 14 " per bushel. Buckwheat.......... 48 " "
                                Bran___............ 20 " Castor Beans........ 46 " " Clover Seed.......... 60 " "
                                Coal...............2240 " per ton. Coal................ 80 " per bushel. Corn
                                shelled......... 56 " Corn on the ear...... 70 " " Fish................ 200 " per
                                barrel. Flaxseed............ 56 " per bushel. Flour............... 196 " per barrel.
                                Hemp Seed.......... 44 " per bushel. Lucerne............. 60 " " Millet...............
                                48 " Oats................ 32 " Onions.............. 52 " Peaches............. 32 "
                                Pears............... 60 " Pork................ 200 " per barrel. Potatoes............ 60
                                " per bushel. Rye................ 56 " Salt, fine............ 55 280 Salt,
                                coarse.......... 320 .......... 50 Salt, sacks........... 14 Timothy Seed....... 45
                                Wheat............. 60 per barrel. per bushel, per sack, per bushel. The weight, by law,
                                of a few of the articles named, to a bushel is not uniform in all the States, and,
                                therefore, may vary slightly from the above in some places. It is customary in measuring
                                coal, potatoes and like articles to " heap " the bushel, as it is called, and, in that
                                case, five even pecks are about equal to one " heaped bushel."</p></div3></div2><pb n="159" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jewish testimony of christ" TEIform="index"/>JEWISH TESTIMONY OF CHRIST.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The late Mr. Noah, a Jew and a distinguished editor, of New York city, said: "
                                    Jesus preached at all times, and in all places, in and out of' the temple, with an
                                    eloquence such as no man has since possessed. Jesus was free from fanaticism ; His
                                    was a quiet, subduing, retiring faith. " He mingled with the poor, communed with the
                                    wretched, ayoidedthe rich, and rebuked the vain-glorious. He sincerely believed His
                                    mission, courted no one; was pointed and severe in His denunciations. These are not
                                    the characteristics of an imposter ; but, admitting that we give a different
                                    interpretation to His mission, when one hundred and fifty millions believe in His
                                    divinity, and we see around us abundant evidence of the happiness, good faith, mild
                                    government and liberal feelings which spring from His religion, what right has any
                                    one to call Him an imposter 1 — that religion which is calculated to make mankind
                                    happy cannot be a false one." Dr. Raphael, a profound scholar and eloquent Rabbi,
                                    whose name was one of the most familiar in religious circles some thirty years
                                    since, speaks in a similar strain: " If you are desirous of knowing the opinion of a
                                    Jew, ay, of a teacher in Israel, re specting the proceedings against and the
                                    condemnation of the Master from Nazareth, I do not hesitate to tell you that I do
                                    not by any means feel bound to identify myself, or my brethren in faith, with those
                                    proceedings or to uphold that condemnation ; I, as a Jew, do say that it appears to
                                    me Jesus became the victim of fanaticism combined with jealousy and lust of power in
                                    Jewish hierarchs, even as in later years Huss and Jerome of Prague, Latimer and
                                    Ridley, became the victims of fanaticism combined with jealousy and lust of power in
                                    Christian hierarchs ; and while I and the Jews of the present day protest against
                                    being identified with the zealots who were concerned in the proceedings against
                                    Jesus of Nazareth, we are far from reviling His character or deriding His precepts,
                                    which are for the most part those of Moses and the prophets." The Jewish nation was
                                    the chosen people of God, and though " He opened the door of faith to the Gentiles,
                                    that the Gentiles should be fellow heirs and of the same body and partakers of this
                                    promise in Christ by the Gospel," nevertheless, it cannot be denied that the promise
                                    was first given to the Jews. When prominent teachers in Israel give such testimony
                                    as we have quoted, it makes us feel as though the time were near at hand when the
                                    ancient people of God, which kept its faith for so many centuries, will be brought
                                    under the banner of the Cross, and there shall be but one fold and one Shepherd. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Frank Leslie's Sunday Magazine" TEIform="index"/>— Frank Leslie's Sunday
                                Maga</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Teachings of the Talmud" TEIform="index"/>TEACHINGS OF THE TALMUD.</head><p TEIform="p"> This supremacy of reason even in matters of faith is well set forth in one of the most
                            remarkable legends contained in the Talmud. It is to be found in Baba Metziah (59): " An
                            important question of doctrine as to pure and impure things was being discussed in the
                            presence of Ilabbi Bliezer the Great. All his arguments urged in favor of the views he
                            entertained had been answered ; he could find no reply. He was silenced but not convinced.
                            Suddenly his eye caught a plant that was growing in a corner. ' That I am in the right,' he
                            indignantly exclaimed, ' and that my views are in accordance with our law, let yonder plant
                            be witness.' Scarce had he spoken the words, when the plant, tearing its roots from the
                            earth, moved across to the opposite side ! ' What means this marvel ? ' cried the Rabbins
                            together. ' What has this prodigy to do with the question we are now debating?' 'Well,
                            then,' resumed Eliezer, ' let the brook which is now running downward demonstrate the truth
                            of my decision.' hnmediately the stream of water turned and commenced to flow upward toward
                            its source! " ' What,' cried the Rabbins, ' does this brook running upward or flowing
                            downward prove as to the purity or otherwise of what we are now discussing 1' ' Then,'
                            exclaimed Rabbi Eliezer, ' let the walls of this chain- <pb n="160" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 160 THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. ber be my witness to testify for me.' Straightway the walls bent them and
                            threatened to overwhelm the whole of the assembled doctors. Uprose Joshua, the son of
                            Chananyah ; ' 0 ye walls,' he cried, ' what have ye to do with the interpretation of the
                            holy law?' Awed by the voice of the great Rabbin, the walls recovered their former position.
                            ' If all this be unavailing,' said Rabbi Eliezer, ' let the voice of God decide!'
                            Immediately a bath kol — a heavenly voice — was heard saying,' Cease your contradictions ;
                            Eliezer the son of Hyrcanus is right.' Uprose again the blacksmith Joshua, president of the
                            Beth-Din, protesting against this mysterious voice. ' Reason," he angrily exclaimed, ' is
                            not concealed in the skies. It has been sent down on earth -—there conferred upon man. To
                            man's intellect pertains the interpretation and knowledge of the law. To the majority of the
                            sages alone belongs henceforth the authority to decide all questions of doctrine.' " The
                            lesson conveyed in this remarkable legend is that which underlies the entire Talmud.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Creeds" TEIform="index"/>CREEDS.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New Jerusalem Messenger" TEIform="index"/>[New Jerusalem Messenger.]</bibl><quote TEIform="quote">When we consider that the creeds to which men are asked to subscribe are, for the
                                    most part, the dogmas of an old theology, which nobody now understands, or believes
                                    as formerly, it is not strange nor unreasonable that there should be a strong
                                    feeling of opposition or prejudice against them. The denominations of the Old
                                    Church, many of them, have for some time been drifting away from their old moorings
                                    ; they seem to be as it were afloat upon a sea of uncertainty ; scarcely any two
                                    think alike who undertake to think at all, and it might be impossible to frame new
                                    creeds which half a dozen men of them would acknowledge. So far then as creeds tend
                                    to fetter the mind, and stand in the way of progress, instead of aiding it, they are
                                    certainly worse than useless. And it seems useless to talk of creeds, for those who
                                    do not know what they believe. Still it remains a fact, that all religion is founded
                                    upon the acknowledgment of some truth, or of something which is supposed to be
                                    truth, concerning Divine things. And the expression of this acknowledgment, in a
                                    written form, constitutes a creed. Every one then, who has any religion, or any
                                    religious belief, has something or other which may be called a creed, though it may
                                    not be written, and though it may not be even very distinctly conceived in his own
                                    mind. The New Church having an authoritative and rational revelation of the doctrine
                                    of spiritual truth, has wherewith to form a full and intelligible creed, because it
                                    has, in this revelation, the means of obtaining a clear and distinct faith in the
                                    great objects of Christian belief, and above all, in the Lord himself. But not only
                                    is the Old Church, to a great extent, in the uncertain and unsettled condition of
                                    belief of which I have spoken, but there is, if I mistake not, a considerably large
                                    class among them who seem to be quite satisfied to remain in this condition. They do
                                    not appear to be interested to know the truth of spiritual things, beyond the barest
                                    outlines of Christian doctrine. They say, perhaps, it is of little consequence what
                                    a man believes, if he only lives well. They think, possibly, it is of little
                                    consequence who or what the Lord is, provided only He saves us. There is probably
                                    quite a generally pTe vailing impression that it is impossible to arrive at any
                                    certain knowledge and understanding of spiritual things. It is scarcely at all seen
                                    that a man's life is according to what he believes, that is, the real belief of his
                                    heart. Some say, the Bible is a sufficient creed. But experience must sooner or
                                    later convince every intelligent student and investigator of religious truth, of
                                    what Swedenborg says, that the Bible cannot be understood without doctrine. It
                                    becomes necessary to search the scriptures in order to understand what it is which
                                    they really testify concerning the Lord and eternal life. It is possible to draw
                                    from them creeds the most various and contradictory in their character. This may,
                                    perhaps, be imagined to be a defect in the Bible ; but it results, in reality, from
                                    the Divinely perfect adaptation of it to all states and conditions of humanity to
                                    those who <pb n="161" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. 1G1 are able to bear but a
                                    very little of the light of truth, as well as to those who can bear much; to them
                                    who can see no further than the most outward appearances of truth, as well as to
                                    those who are internal men ; and so that they may find in it much or little of
                                    truth, or none at all, according to their love of truth for its own sake. Thus it
                                    compels no one. but leads and guides all who are willing to be led. The case is
                                    similar with the book of Inspiration to that of the book of Nature. Both present at
                                    the first view much to attract our attention and' admiration, but also much which
                                    does not appear what it really is. Both need to be carefully studied and understood.
                                    Both teach us of the unsearchable wisdom of the Creator, but only they find the
                                    instructiQn who are willing to learn. The Bible has, heretofore, been understood for
                                    the most part only literally and believed blindly, and upon authority. Now the
                                    number is fast growing smaller who are willing to believe it in this way. Men wish
                                    to know what its claims really are, and what it means before they will believe. This
                                    is but reasonable. But where, except in the writings of the New Church, can these
                                    desires be gratified ? There they certainly can be.</quote></cit></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., D. H." TEIform="persName"/>D. H. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religions of the head and heart" TEIform="index"/> THE RELIGIONS OF THE HEAD AND HEART.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Although man's reason is the inlet to his affections, there are many things that
                                    enter the former that do not reach the latter. There is a religion of the head, and
                                    one of the heart, and in many respects there is a vast difference between them. The
                                    religion of the head consists in a number of ideas which have so engaged the
                                    attention as to assume before the mind undue proportions, so that their apprehension
                                    is held to be all sufficient. They are the man's hope of salvation. If he is
                                    indifferent as to the interests of the general cause, and fails to give of his means
                                    to its support as he is able ; if he neglects to assemble with the people of God for
                                    prayer and confer•ence ; if he neglects secret prayer; if he indulges in habits that
                                    are at variance with the spirit of the gospel ; if he fails to "abstain from all
                                    appearance of evil,'' the fact that he still retains his faith in these ideas is
                                    heralded as evidence that all is well with him. His religion is wholly one of faith
                                    without works. "This man's religion is vain." His ideas may be all true, but they
                                    are of no benefit to him. His theory of redemption may be correct, but it is a
                                    redemption that does not embrace him. He "holds the truth in unrighteousness." While
                                    he complacently believes himself to be on the road to glory he is on the road to
                                    ruin. The religion of the heart consists in a belief in, and conformity to the
                                    gospel of Christ as a whole—theoretical, experimental and practical. ' The theory,
                                    having been intellectually apprehended, has descended to the affections, and lifted
                                    them off things below, and set them on things above, thus giving experience; while
                                    the stream, rising in the heart, flows out into the life, carrying a blessing
                                    wherever it goes. This is " pure and undefiled religion." It seeks to know the truth
                                    for the sanctification which the truth brings. It loves the cause for its worth, and
                                    is jealous for its prosperity, for which it is not slow to make sacrifices. It
                                    carries its possessor to the closet, to the prayer-meeting, to the various duties
                                    and crosses of his sphere, with willing feet. It is kind, courteous, and " behaveth
                                    itself not unseemly." It is not easily daunted, but overcomes by the grace of God.
                                    It ever keeps the goal in view, and presses toward it. It will bring its possessor
                                    to the joys of the Eternal world. Reader, which of these two religions is yours ?</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Domestic Journal" TEIform="index"/> — Domestic Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Time's changes" TEIform="index"/> TIME'S CHANGES.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">It is wonderful to contemplate that while ten thousand Jews hover about captive
                                    Jerusalem, and millions more look wishfully Zionward, the Rothschilds—Jews— can
                                    count up their $3,400,000,000, and to-day the two Prime Ministers of Great Britain
                                    and France, Benjamin Disraeli and Jules Simon, are both Jews. Jews the bankers of
                                    Europe's kings — Jews the premiers of <pb n="162" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 162 THE SHAKER
                                    MANIFESTO. seventy millions of civilized people. All this, too, where a century ago
                                    the poor Jews were hunted from nation to nation like wild beasts. How this once
                                    despised people are marching to the front in riches and honor! And the two powerful
                                    premiers named, it is said, are keeping a sharp eye on old Jerusalem, with a view of
                                    getting possession. Meanwhile a railroad stretches over a part of the Holy Land; the
                                    scream of the iron horse echoes among the hills and valleys where the old prophet
                                    long ago uttered his prediction of a chariot that in the great preparation day of
                                    the Lord would run like lightning. There are also two hundred and fifty Protestant
                                    churches worshiping among the sacred hills, and sever; hundred and sixty children in
                                    the Sunday-schools of Palestine ring out the very hymns and songs that our children
                                    know and sing in this land. Think, too, that on Mount Zion, where stood the holy
                                    house, there has within a few months past been placed that thing of wonder, the
                                    modern printing press, and it is sending out books descriptive of that famous
                                    country. The clank of Zion's first printing press over the old abodes of David and
                                    Solomon ! O, shade of the wise man, is there nothing new under the sun ? Are there
                                    not signs?</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Church Union" TEIform="index"/>— Church Union.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="England's wicked wars" TEIform="index"/> ENGLAND'S WICKED WARS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bright, John" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">What John Biiight Thinks of the Conflicts in Afghanistan and Zululand. Extracts from John
                            Bright's recent Speech in Birmingham. We now come to another question, and that is the
                            question of the habit which the people of this country have had for a long time past, and
                            especially just lately, of entering into savage and cruel wars. I believe all wars are
                            savage and cruel ; but I mean harsh and cruel wars on uncivilized or half-civilized men.
                            When 1 read of transactions of that kind something always puts to me this question : What is
                            it that makes, if any thing makes, this needless and terrible slaughter different in its
                            nature from those transactions which we call murder? We call one set of transactions war,
                            which has a totally different sound to what we term murder, and we do not appear to inquire
                            when thousands are guilty what it was that brought it on, and why it was that we should
                            inflict that terrible slaughter, while we are all excited to the last degree if some
                            individual, by the vindictive act of somebody else, is put to death, and that act is called
                            murder. Take the wars with the Zulus and the Afghans. We know we have had excuses made for
                            them, and excuses which were not justified by the facts — excuses that the Zulus attacked
                            Natal, which is absolutely and notoriously and entirely false. We have had statements with
                            regard to the Afghans very much of the same character, that they were going to throw their
                            influence with another and a northern power, and that they insulted outrageously the envoy
                            sent to negotiate with them — all of which I believe there is not a particle of foundation
                            for. These are excuses offered by persons who commit crimes in order that they may say these
                            acts were not crimes, but necessary acts of statesmanship. Well, at most, in regard to
                            either of these powers, the case was one of suspicion, but suspicion which the most
                            experienced persons said there was no ground for. But is it right upon mere suspicion, that
                            a country like this •should send, in the one case 20,000 and in the other 40,000 troops to
                            invade the territories and put to death not less than 20,000 men engaged in the defense of
                            their own country, which, in our case, we consider honorable and needful ? * * * We may be
                            quite sure that in some shape if we, the people of England, tolerate the bloody and
                            sanguinary crimes which are committed in our country's name, if they are so committed, and
                            we do not remonstrate and condemn, we shall have no acacquittal at the tribunal by which the
                            actions, not of individuals only, but of nations and peoples, are finally judged. Now that
                            is my view. Perhaps I have spoken too strongly, and perhaps with a warmth and an earnestness
                            which some of you may think unnecessary. [Cries of "No, no."] I believe it is not possible
                            to too strongly condemn a policy by which the' hard-earned treasure of our people is wasted,
                                <pb n="163" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 163 by which the blood of our people and
                            those we are to call our foes, is shed. To-day is the anniversary of the battle of Isandula.
                            I do not know how many lives were sacrificed in it, but there were 1,500 lives lost on the
                            British side, namely, officers, soldiers and native troops — and I know not how many of the
                            Zulus were slaughtered in a war which has never been proved to be necessary. Sad day! Can
                            any one show us the justification for the action we then took, of the compensation we have
                            received for the enormous and incalculable loss of life in that one day's war? Well, in
                            Afghanistan — a country as large as France, and as mountainous as Switzerland — our troops
                            are engaged in slaughtering and hanging the natives of the villages, and women and children
                            are turned out into the frost and the snow of this inclement season, and this is done at the
                            command of a government professing to be wiser and more Christian and more humane than those
                            with whom our troops are contending. I say let us abandon our pretensions ; let us claim no
                            longer to be Christians; let us go back to the heathen times while we adhere to the heathen
                            practices. Let us no longer, as I see some of the leading men of this country have within
                            the past few weeks, at the opening of churches and the laying of the foundation of churches,
                            join in a mere regard for the Christian religion. I say, take down at any rate the Ten
                            Commandments inside your churches and say no longer you believe in or read the Sermon on the
                            Mount. Abandon your Christian pretenses or else your savage and heathen practices.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritualism one hundred years ago" TEIform="index"/> SPIRITUALISM ONE HUNDRED YEARS AGO.</head><p TEIform="p"> The Merrimac Valley Visitor (Newburyport, Mass.) contained in its issue of April 10th a
                            lengthy article upon Shakerism, in which it is stated that for upwards of one hundred years
                            what is now known as Modern Spiritualism was familiar to that people. The manifestations
                            were prevalent during the times of Ann Lee, who was born in Manchester, England, in 1736,
                            and came to this country in 1774, "driven by persecutions and instructed by revelations,"
                            and continued until 1837, when, from that time until 1848, they appeared more frequently and
                            with greater power. " It came upon them by songs and music in the air; it seized upon little
                            girls at their amusements and whirled them around the room, prostrated them on the floor,
                            and threw them into trances. Soon they began to talk, narrate what they saw in the spiritual
                            realms, sing hymns unwritten, set to music that mortal eyes had never seen. They had the
                            gift of tongues; also the gift of discernment, so they could read the characters of those
                            they had not before met." It is fortunate for the world that these things subsequently
                            occurred outside of that community, for they considered that the people of earth were in a
                            totally unprepared state for what they (the Shakers) were experiencing. Having held this
                            view of the case for more than a century, it is quite probable we should have been debarred
                            from communion with our spirit-friends up to this time, and whether we should ever be
                            granted the privilege would depend altogether upon whether — according to Shaker
                            judgment-—-we were sufficiently prepared for it. But the invisibles were not to be kept
                            back, and so they rapped at Rochester and sought an interview with the people of earth.
                            These old-time Shaker manifestations prove to us, what the history of all past ages confirms
                            as truth, that evidences of spiritpresence and power are not new, not characteristic of our
                            times alone, but as old as history itself. B. OF L.</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sad facts" TEIform="index"/> SAD FACTS.</head><p TEIform="p"> It is a sad fact to contemplate, that in the works of Messrs. Krupp, at Essen, Prussia, 300
                            cannon of the largest caliber are turned out every month; that 15,000 have been made in two
                            years. The European governments use them for the mutual destruction of their subjects, and
                            appear always ready to begin this destruction when they can find a pretext. * * * The worst
                            of it is, that for the supply of armies the best men are required, the flower of the nation,
                            while the cripples and old men are left at home for the propagation and improvement (?) of
                            the human species.</p></div2><pb n="164" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>GRAND THOUGHTS FROM CONTEMPORARIES.</head><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="That every good was diminished..." TEIform="index"/>That every good was diminished...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> That every good was diminished in proportion as the evils of the war were multiplied no
                                one can deny.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="That the immorality and brutality of the present..." TEIform="index"/>That the immorality and brutality of the present...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> That the immorality and brutality of the present times are largely — we will not say
                                wholly — the results of the war, no observing man, it seems to us, can deny.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We reap as we sow" TEIform="index"/> WE REAP AS WE SOW.</head><p TEIform="p">Plant blessings, and blessings will bloom ; Plant hate, and hate will grow ; You can sow
                                to-day — to-morrow shall bring The blossom, that proves what sort of a thing Is the
                                seed, the seed that you sow.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unselfish and noble acts..." TEIform="index"/>Unselfish and noble acts...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Unselfish and noble acts are the most radiant epochs in the biography of souls. When
                                wrought in earliest youth, they lie in the memory of age like the coral islands green
                                and sunny, amid the melancholy waste of ocean.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>— Dr. Thomas.</byline></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Are you doing any thing to publish..." TEIform="index"/>Are you doing any thing to publish...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Are you doing any thing to publish and scatter Gospel tracts ? A tract which costs a
                                penny may save a soul. And tracts can be multiplied by millions if means are fur nished
                                to pay their trifling cost. Some can write tracts, others can publish them economically,
                                others can pay for them ; others still can distribute them judiciously, and so all can
                                be helpers in the work, and sharers in the blessing.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To be a Christian is not..." TEIform="index"/>To be a Christian is not...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To be a Christian is not to believe that Moses wrote the Pentateuch or John the Book of
                                Revelation ; it is to be a follower of Jesus Christ. The purely literary opinion
                                respecting the authorship of an ancient book has no moral character ; but the judgment
                                that appreciates and reveres a noble life and the j udgment that either disregards or
                                disdains a noble life has a moral character. There is no better test of manhood than
                                this : the appreciation of the nobility of divine manhood in another.— The Christian
                                Union.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christianity is discussed by a learned Turk..." TEIform="index"/>Christianity is discussed by a learned Turk...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Christianity is discussed by a learned Turk in Blackwood for January in a manner that
                                does not reflect favorably upon believers. The gentleman admits the superiority of the
                                moral teachings of Jesus, but affirms that his professed followers have perverted and
                                degraded those teachings to a degree unparalleled in other religions, so that the
                                nations in semi-barbarous ignorance are corrupted by contact with modern Christendom
                                which he calls anti-Christendom, since its real God is mammon: " Among Roman Catholics
                                the reign of mammon is tempered by a lust of spiritual and temporal povver. Among Greek
                                Christians it is tempered by a lust of race aggrandizement. Among Protestants mammon is
                                supreme." But he allows that there are noble exceptions, and that some are struggling to
                                practice the higher virtues of Christianity.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Speak the truth in love" TEIform="index"/>Speak the truth in love
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Speak the Truth in Love.— Do not advocate a holy life in a scolding and unsanc tified
                                tone. Don't press men to seek perfect peace as if you were driving reluctant animals
                                before you. Don't talk in funeral tones about it, and urge as if the grave was yawning
                                under your feet. It is the high birthright of every child of God to be like Him. You are
                                not in the happiest condition to set it forth unless the " candle of the Lord " shines
                                brightly upon your own heart and face. It is a Beulah land where heavenly gales fan the
                                earth, and the fruits of Paradise invite the taste. Encourage the people of God to go up
                                and possess it. Tell them they are well able to do so, although the Anakim may still
                                remain in the land. It is a good thing to carry into the pulpit with you one of the
                                clusters of grapes native to this " enchanted ground." There is nothing so impressive
                                and subduing as a real, loving, glowing, melting heart-experience. Let this be seen, and
                                the milk and honey and the fruit of that region will be greatly coveted.— Zion's
                            Herald.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Christian Union says..." TEIform="index"/>The Christian Union says...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> The Christian Union says: Moreover, this belief in Jesus is not in the least dependent
                                on literary belief in the authorship of the four Gospels. A. few years ago a Hindoo
                                merchant, coming from his native village in the interior on a trading expedition, picked
                                up a copy of the New Testament as a curiosity and carried it back to his home. He
                                commenced reading it; was struck by the simple beauty of Christ's teaching and life;
                                read it to his neighbors ; <pb n="165" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> they shared his ,admiration; by common
                                consent they adopted it as their standard by which to live. The man died; the village
                                held on to the book, and came to be known in all the district as the Village with the
                                Book. When, later, a Christian missionary came to the place, he found the village in
                                spirit and character essentially Christian. Neither the Hindoo apostle nor any of his
                                disciples knew any thing about the literary question. When Christ lived, when and by
                                whom his life was written, they neither knew nor cared. The life was there before them;
                                it was worthy to be followed; and they followed it. To be a Christian is not to believe
                                that Moses wrote the Pentateuch or John the Book of Revelation; it is to be a follower
                                of Jesus Christ </p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Honesty" TEIform="index"/>HONESTY.</head><p TEIform="p"> HENRY WARD BEECHER talks to his con-gregation thus thoughtfully and fearlessly: I think the
                            great crying danger in our day is lying and dishonesty. Some folks think it is heterodoxy
                            with reference to the doc-trines of the Atonement and of the punish-ment of the wicked; but
                            I think it is lying and dishonesty. I hold that unless this church can maintain a gospel
                            that shall bring itself to bear on these subjects you will be eaten up by dry rot. I hold
                            that the influence of the individual members of this church, and the influence of this
                            church collectively, ought to take care of the taxa-tion question of Brooklyn. There is very
                            great dishonesty in the matter of taxation. There is widespread selfishness and lying and
                            dishonesty on the part of property-holders who are unwilling to take their share of the
                            burden of government. There is all manner of secretiveness and duplicity practiced by men in
                            this matter - and that even among professors of religion, and church members and officers of
                            churches-that they may get rid of paying their por-tion of the tax for the support of the
                            com-monwealth; and it is a shame. I am in favor of taxing churches and ministers. I am in
                            favor of taxing every thing, right through the whole community, except the State's own
                            institutions and institutions of charity. 'l'here is no reason in the world why a minister
                            with a salary like mine should not be taxed as much as if he were a bank president; and
                            there is no reason in the world why this church should not be taxed in its property. It is
                            said that it is working for the welfare of the whole com-munity, and that it makes good
                            citizenship. So it does; and every honest storekeeper and mechanic does the same thing; and
                            every well-regulated church is doing what every other well-regulated institution is doing in
                            the community. And I hold that there should be witnesses springing up in Christian churches,
                            among Christians every where, in favor of honesty in rendering an account of property, and
                            in favor of men paying their taxes willingly and gladly; for many men are sneaks in this
                            matter. Multitudes of men there are, worth their millions, who scarcely pay their mills.
                            That fact begets ill feeling; and outside classes say, "Here are these rich men who go into
                            the churches and bear each other out in dis-honesty, and smear over that dishonesty by
                            hypocritical religion; and we have to pay the heavy debts." It makes disintegrating
                            prejudices throughout the community; and I say that it is the duty of Christian men in
                            churches to see to it that a gospel is preached in every pulpit that will make men love the
                            truth, and make them honest - honest toward the State, honest toward corporations, honest
                            toward all classes - for honesty in transactions on the part of a great commercial nation
                            like our own is John Baptist to the Gospel. I think that the counterfeiter and the thief may
                            be converted; but I do not believe that a man in whose blood runs secret dishonesty and
                            hypocrisy can be converted without these things coming to the surface and being repented of
                            by him. Religion is not morality; but there is no religion without morality. Dirt is not
                            wheat; but there is no wheat that has not dirt under it; and there must be morality in
                            public sentiment; and I do not know where we shall get it unless it comes out of our
                            churches; and this church, that never has been second in any good word or work, ought not to
                            be second in exerting a purgative and healing influence on the community in this matter of
                            honesty.</p></div2><pb n="166" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True sheperd's voice" TEIform="index"/> THE TRUE SHEPHERD'S VOICE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Collins, Elvah F." TEIform="persName"/>ELVAH F. COLLINS,</byline><p TEIform="p"> MT. LEBANON, N.Y. 1. Hear the sweet voice of the Shepherd of Israel, Calling the lost sheep
                            home- 2. Flee ye in haste from the darkness now deep'ning, Ere he doth turn away; 3. Limped,
                            the silvery streams that are winding, Thro' verdant pastures broad- Home to the fold of his
                            love and tenderness, No more in sin to roam. And in the wilds of a fruitless wilderness,
                            Blighted your hopes decay. Gardens, where flowers of immortal pu-ri-ty, Send forth their
                            breath to God. Wander no more on desolate mountains, Nor o'er the desert barren and drear,
                            Wander no more on desolate mountains, Nor o'er the desert barren and drear, Wander no more
                            on desolate mountains, Nor o'er the desert barren and drear, Heed ye the tones that are
                            pleading in mercy, Come to my fold my blessing to share. Hear ye the voice of the Shepherd
                            of Israel, Come to my fold I'll gather you near. Heed ye the voice that so sweetly is
                            calling, Come to my fold, in love draw ye near.</p></div2><pb n="167" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Modern church's invitation" TEIform="index"/> THE MODERN CHURCH'S INVITATION.</head><p TEIform="p">Come hither sinners for advice. Not, however, without price, We need you if you are well
                            heeled To labor in our harvest field. But if you have an empty purse And are not able to
                            disburse, We do not want vou in our fold-The only key to which is gold. Don't tell us of the
                            Lord's reply When the rich man did apply, That he must sell all that he had So that the
                            naked might be clad. Our Saviour's was a different case, He needed no costly meeting place,
                            For His poor and simple band Needed no churches large and grand. But how shall our temples
                            rise Until their steeples reach the skies? To build them needs wealth untold, So if you join
                            you mnst have gold. According to your worth in gold Shall be your welcome to our fold, If
                            you your thousands count by tens Most hearty shall be our amens. But if you are poor we'll
                            pass you by, Our motto, "no poor man need apply," We've nothing further now to say Only,
                            that for you we shall pray. </p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Danielites" TEIform="index"/>DANIELITES.</head><p TEIform="p"> The latest sect in England is that of the Danielites. It had its rise in 1876, and its
                            founder was T. W. Richardson, a student of medicine and a vegetarian. The organiza-tion has
                            a form of initiation, degrees, badges, scarfs and all the paraphernalia of a secret society.
                            The person who desires to become a member takes a solemn vow to abstain entirely from fish,
                            flesh and fowl, from spirituous and malt liquors, from snuff and tobacco. When this promise
                            has been taken and a solemn pledge of secrecy given, the candidate is ushered into the
                            "garden," which is the Danielite name for lodge. The head of each garden is called the chief
                            gar-dener. The sect has no theological system. A member may believe what he chooses, so long
                            as he affirms the existence of a Supreme Being and maintains a vegetable diet. The
                            initiation fee is two shillings. It is said that the order has many adherents and is
                            spreading in England.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sanitary thoughts" TEIform="index"/>SANITARY THOUGHTS.</head><p TEIform="p"> ONE of the chief offices of a good nurse is to think for her patient. An invalid should
                            never be teased with the exertion of making a decision. "THE person who keeps the outside of
                            the neck covered with heavy wraps, has the in-side covered very frequently with what is
                            popuLarly known as a hard cold." ThE Secretary of the Liverpool Vegeta-rian Society states
                            that he has walked 500 miles in 15 days - an averago of 35 miles per day - on a diet of
                            nothing but raw fruit and this without unusual fatigue or bodily strain. DR. Nichols
                            suggests that the reason fruits do not digest well when eaten after flesh, is because the
                            gastric juice secreted to act on the meat will not act well on the fruit. Perhaps on this
                            account the better way is to eat fruit before meals rather than a dessert. A medical man
                            discoursing upon sleep, makes this remark: "One man may do with a little less sleep than
                            another; but as a general rule, if you want a clerk, a lieutenant, a lawer, a physician, a
                            legislator, a judge, a president, or a pastor, do not trust your interests to any man who
                            does not take all the average eight good solid hours of sleep out of the twenty-four.
                            Whatever may be his reason for it, if he does not give himself that, he will snap some time
                            just when you want him to be strong." THE world wants more sunshine in its disposition, in
                            its business, in its charities, in its theology. For ten thousand of the aches and pains,
                            and irritation of men and women, we recommend sunshine. It soothes better than morphine. It
                            stimulates better than champagne. It is the best plaster for a wound. The good Samaritan
                            poured out into the fallen traveler's gash more of this than of oil. Florence Nig-htingale
                            used it on the Crimean battle-fields. Take it into all the alleys, on board all the ships,
                            by all the sick beds. Not a phial full, not a cup full, but a soul full. ]t is good for
                            spleen, for liver complaint, for neuralgia, for rheu-matism, for failing fortunes, for
                            melancholy. - </p><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Faith and works" TEIform="index"/>Faith and Works.</bibl></div2><pb n="168" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Theologian and General- which is right" TEIform="index"/>THE THEOLOGIAN AND GENERAL-WHICH
                            IS RIGHT?</head><p TEIform="p"> In looking over a morning daily, while riding from Omaha to Kearney, we came across a
                            selection from the New York Observer, written by Dr. Prime, in which the question is asked:
                            "Must a man have the devil in him to make a good soldier? The Doctor, in speaking of the
                            late General Hooker, says: " In Angust last I spent a Sabbath among the White Mountains, at
                            the Profile House, with General Hooker. He spoke to me of his mother, and of the religious
                            instruc-tion she gave him, and he was not able to say that he had lived up to the lessons of
                            his childhood. "But the truth is," he said, "a man can-not be good and be a fighting man. He
                            must have the devil in him. To kill one another, men must have their blood up, and then they
                            are just like devils. Now, there's General -," naming one of the generals of the last war,
                            "he is too good a man to command an army; when two armies come in collision he is afraid
                            some one will get hurt; he can't bear to have blood shed; he's a good man, very good,
                            everybody loves him, but he has not enough of the devil to be a good general." I sought to
                            take another view of the sub-ject, and argued that many splendid gener-als had been men of
                            high moral and relig-ious character, who pursued the profession of arms as a duty to their
                            country, regarding war as a necessary evil and the last resort of government. " Very true,"
                            he said, "but when it comes to fighting, all the devil that is in a man nust come out." How
                            foolish it seems in men who profess to be expositors of the humble and peace-able doctrines
                            of Jesus to try to make fight-ing men believe that they are actuated by a Christian spirit.
                            No matteer how willing they may be to accept such doctrines their own good judgment tells
                            them better. The Spirit of Christ cannot prompt the slaying of his brother, and when General
                            Hooker says the fighting man must have the devil in him he manifests a better knowledge of
                            theology than Dr. Prime, who through flat-tery tried to make him believe that Christ will do
                            the devil's work. Xo wonder men are inclined to infidelity.-</p><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Primitive Christian" TEIform="index"/>Primitive Chris-tian.</bibl></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Josh Billings' philosophy" TEIform="index"/>JOSH BILLINGS' PHILOSOPHY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Billings, Josh" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Thare iz a good deal in a name: vinegar sounds sour to me, so duz honey sound sweet.
                            Philosophy iz a self-sakraficing virtue; most of it iz spent on our nabors, but little on
                            ourselfs. Yung man, satisfy yurself, and the world in dne time are sure to giv yu all the
                            praze yu deserve. Thare may be people who never make enny blunders or mistakes (or think
                            they don't), the best we kan say for them iz pain-fully korrect. Too mutch larning and too
                            little wisdum iz making the whole world mad; the mis-take iz az old as the farce enackted in
                            the garden ov Eden. There iz a great deal more virtew and happiness in the world than we are
                            aware ov; menny ov us hav it in our possesshun without knowing it. Opinyuns rule mankind,
                            and yet two-thirds of all the opinyuns afloat are like foot balls; the man who kan kik them
                            the highest iz the best fello Musik iz not only a plezant power, but it iz one ov the
                            cheapest ones too; enny per-son who haz genius enuff to turn a grind-stone kan understand a
                            fiddle. The man who laffs and nods hiz hed, and sez, " Yes,jess so," to every thing yu say,
                            iz one of the hardest men in the world to git onto the bak ov sixty day paper. It seems
                            rather tuff, and quite ridikilus, that a man who haz honestly earned fame kan't git it until
                            after he iz ded, and then haz to take it in second-rate poetry on hiz tume stun. There seems
                            to be two kinds of wisdom; one a llIan gits from studdying only the bad side ov human natur,
                            the other from stud-dying both the good and bad side, and then striking a helthy average.
                        </p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>