<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0404" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><date value="18740401" TEIform="date">April 1874</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">25-32</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="25" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- <p>Vol. IV. No. 4. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY, T^tt^ty Cents Mt. Lebanon, Ool. Co. N. Y.. April, 1874r. PER annum</p>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ann and Emanuel" TEIform="index"/>ANN AND EMANUEL</head><p TEIform="p">Were both transcendently important persons, as individuals. Far more so as representatives.
                            In Algebra, a, as unit, may represent the whole genus of sheep. Thus it is in the
                            Revelations. Its Angels, Trumpets, Seals. Books — written within and without — Vials,
                            Plagues, Horses and other Beasts. And the symbols, whether of things animate, or inanimate,
                            do invariably stand for quantities, Powers, Ages, Empires, Orders, Nations, Systems, as they
                            operate, succeeding each other and dance in the great kaleidoscope of civil and religious
                            history of the human race, from the beginning, to the end of time. This algebraic idea is
                            the key to unlock the Revelations. But the lock itself, that has fastened them up and hidden
                            them from human ken, is the actual number, measure, weight and value — the meaning of each
                            character, type or figure, in this great sum on the chessboard of civil and eclesiastical
                            mundane human history. As the learned, skillful anatomist, like Agassiz, who, finding one
                            perfect bone of an extinct, or unknown quadruped, constructs therefrom, the whole system, or
                            framework of the hitherto unknown animal — So it is with the chief of all mysteries — the
                            Revelations. Having (bund, with certainty —admitting not a doubt— one great central event,
                            therein described, all else falls naturally into line — " Bone cometh to bone," and each
                            socket is filled. We have one grand whole. Ann Lee. and Emanuel Swedenborg inaugurated Eras
                            too marked and prominent to be missed, or mistaken for any thing else than what they are.
                            Swedenborg personified the Angel of Spiritualism. Ann personified the reaping, or Harvesting
                            Angel. The Angel, that should harvest the whole earth. The Female Messiah, with her John the
                            Baptist forerunner, to ripen and prepare the harvest for the Reaper. Rev. 14; 14. " I
                            looked, and behold a white cloud, and upon the cloud one sat, like unto the Son of man,
                            having, on her head, a golden crown, and in her hand a sharp sickle. And then came an Angel
                            out of the Temple, which is in Heaven — Church in the Spirit world — He, also, having a
                            sharp sickle. And another Angel came out from the altar that is in the Temple, who had power
                            over fire, saying, to that Angel, Thrust in thy sharp sickle and gather the cluster, the
                            ripe fruit of the vine of the earth-Church." Thus the earthly order is reaped. And the
                            Heavenly order will be reaped also; being saved so as by fire. If the righteous scarcely be
                            saved, where shall the ungodly and sinner appear? SWEEDENBORG ANGEL — SPIRITUALISM. " I saw
                            an Angel come down from Heaven, having great power, and the earth was lightened with his
                            glory." Rev. 18 ; 1. The preceding Angel to this was Babylon — Christendom in its dotage — "
                            Mystery, Babylon the great—the mother of Harlots, and abominations of the earth."
                            "Horns"—Rational powers, grow out of her, that hate her absurd mysteries—"make her desolate
                            and naked — eat her flesh and burn her with fire." Thus they cook and live upon her. They
                            solve her mysteries, and resolve them into no sense. They expose the abominations of holy
                            and unholy wars. Holy Inquisitions, and Holy Alliances, with their consecrated wafers and
                            candles — their diping and their sprinkling, as a sign of a sign — a shadow of a shadow —
                            with their sips of wine and bits of bread, to be eaten with the flesh of the man Jesus, and
                            washed down with his blood. Holy Christian cannibalism — Doctrine of Devils. Theoretically
                            and practically, a horrible and bloody theology. Under its blighting influence, the few
                            monopolize the life elements, while the many are forced into the bowels of the earth, to
                            delve in mines, or into hurtful factories, or noxious manu- factories, on the earth's bosom.
                            The creators and their creations, being alike the subject of ungodly speculation.
                            Spiritualism is destroying those who destroy the earth. Co-operation and communism wait upon
                            her footsteps. Hear the New York Tribune : "SPIRITUAL" PHENOMENA. We present this morning an
                            abstract of a remarkable article in the London Quarterly Journal of Science. The writer of
                            the article is Mr. William Crookes, editor of the periodical in which it appears, and a
                            chemist and physicist of high reputation. He has devoted several years to a careful
                            scientific investigation of the so-called phenomena of Spiritualism, as presented especially
                            by Mr. D. D. Home and Miss Kate Fox, and he writes of them in the calm critical manner that
                            we should naturally look for in a man of his character and calling. That the result of his
                            inquiries will create a lively discussion we can hardly doubt. For Mr. Crookes, though he
                            shows none of the symptoms of religious enthusiasm, feels bound to admit the reality of the
                            mysterious phenomena which took place scores and hundreds of times in his own rooms, in
                            broad daylight, under conditions of his own choosing, and under the careful scrutiny of
                            scientific unbelievers. When a man of his stamp tells us that he has seen Mr. Home floating
                            in the air, and goblets, card-plates, dinner tables, and other solid objects dancing through
                            space, as if the laws of gravity had been repealed; when he describes a "self-luminous cloud
                            "that plucked a heliotrope blossom and carried it to a lady; when he tells us of nebulous
                            and ghostly hands that shaped them- selves out of nothing before his very eyes, and rested
                            unresisting in his grasp till they gradually dissolved into impalpable vapor,— we cannot
                            help listening to him with a certain sort of amazed respect. For we must acknowledge that he
                            firmly believes his own statements, and that he is not a person to be deceived by any common
                            trickery. He emphatically rejects two explanations which are often advanced: one, that the
                            mediums are jugglers; the other, that the observers are insane people or fools. Whether
                            there is some unknown physical or intellectual force which can do all these wonders in ways
                            not yet understood, whether the dead return to visit us, or devils come to deceive, Mr.
                            Crookes promises to debate hereafter. Going back a few short years, when Prof. Farraday, who
                            preceded Crookes, was the Angel of Science in the Isle of the Ocean, the Mistress of the
                            seas. What a change, a most marvellous change ! Farraday, clothing himself with contempt, as
                            with a garment, denied all the facts upon which Spiritualism, as a science, sought to
                            procure a page in the British Encyclopaedia, a niche in the temple of English fame.
                            Farraday, to his neverending shame, refused, in the name of Science, to investigate the
                            claims of Spiritualism. But its facts—the basis of all science — have prevailed; Prof.
                            Crookes has investigated, and glory will rest upon his name, while Wisdom is justified of
                            her children — the Shakers — who, following their intuition, led by their prevision, and
                            inspired by a Divine Revelation, worshipped the new-born babe, while yet in the manger of
                            public doubt, as to whether it was a quadruped or a human, and helped to nurse it into a
                            vigorous manhood.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Theological treasury" TEIform="index"/>THEOLOGICAL TREASURY</head><p TEIform="p">DEATH—LIFE. —O— That there is a necessity for sacrifice, that atonement with God may be
                            vouchsafed to souls, is a principle underlying the true Church of God. The spirit of the
                            atonement is a right one. The popular rendering is assuredly false. The important features
                            of nearly every denomination, from the Roman Catholic to the Second Advent, may claim the
                            right to be adjudged correct, as pointing, at least, to the spirit of truth. But nearly all
                            of these varied prominent doctrines among sects, are so encumbered by Babylonian rubbish,
                            that long years have, and may elapse, ere the full light of truth will dispel the clouds
                            that obscure the perfect day. Under the guidance of the Christ, Jesus died for sinners —that
                            Jesus might more perfectly live — and that tinners might live like unto Jesus. The central
                            idea of this truth teaches all, that Jesus more really lived for F. W. EVANS, Editoii. <pb n="26" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 26 8HAKEE A-ISTD sinners, than that he died for them ; though he did
                            both —died first, then lived. His body was hung to the triangular erection, which, while it
                            teaches us that Jesus was " true to the last," has no reference to his real death for
                            sinners. The same death remains on earth in sinners' behalf; and the same life of saving
                            power is as extant to-day as ever was incarnated in Jesus, and illustrated by him for suf-
                            fering humanity's sake. Wherein was the sacrifice? Wherein the atonement? "He that seeks to
                            save his life shall lose life." Jesus died for sinners — true ; and thus he illustrated, how
                            each must die ; he not, by any means, relieving us from the necessity of the same death —
                            death unto every unchristian word and work. " He died, that others might live ;" most
                            assuredly — thus teaching in his own person, that by their dying as he died, unto the world,
                            the flesh and devil, they might live and reign with him as Christians ! " The blood of the
                            Lamb," being interpreted, means " the life of Jesus Christ;" and whichever term we use, we
                            will conclude that our sins are atoned for, when we shall have confessed them, and repented
                            of the same by their entire renunciation — " ceasing to do evil, and learning to do well!"
                            If we will live the life of Jesus, his Mood will be efficacious for our cleansing. How truly
                            we can sing with our Wesleyan friends, the sentiments of their little song: "Must Jesus bear
                            the cross alone, And all the world go free ? Nay, there's a cross for every one, And there's
                            a cross for me 1" But when we hear the honeyed tongue of the serpent, interspersing among
                            sacred song: "Jesus paid It all, All the debt T owe, Nothing, neither great nor small,
                            Kemains for me to do." We pronounce these and similar sentiments, the second greatest lie of
                            the devil, the first being, " Thou shalt not surely die !" Amid the early Christians, one
                            general feature became beautifully prominent — all conformed their lives to the life of
                            Jesus. And this practice led to the organization of the Pentecostal Church. Had the
                            followers of Jesus left him to bear their cross, and be disciplined in their stead, while
                            they followed their unbridled lusts and selfish inclinations, then would the records fail of
                            being the hallowed pages which many of them now are. Jesus called men from their nets — some
                            were married, some not; he dissolved the marital relations of the disciples, and united them
                            in the superior relations of unlusting spiritual brethren and sisters. (Why have the
                            Churches, professedly Christian, reversed this rule ?) " Follow me," said Jesus; " die unto
                            the world, live the Christ-life — die as I die, live as I live, and even as I am
                            resurrected, so ye shall become the children of the same resurrection. Are ye rich in purse?
                            Ye shall be privileged to bless others equally with yourself. Are you poor ? the Gospel will
                            be equally magnified, inasmuch as it elevates your condition to an equality with the
                            formerly wealthy. Were you warlike ? You need be so no longer ; for the Gospel will show you
                            the folly of such perversion, and give you power to live above resentment. I am the way, the
                            truth and the life. Seek this way, learn this truth, and live this life, and ye shall have
                            treasure in heaven." Such we believe to be the living testimony preached and practiced by
                            his self-denying followers. And no precious Mood will produce these results. The
                            sin-forsaking " life " of Jesus alone will do it. The " blood " that made Jesus what he was
                            is equally operative and powerful to-day. But, whoever waits for Jesus to take the medi-
                            cine by which they will find redemption, waits in vain, and saves a life that would, by its
                            loss, secure this truth, and live this life, and ye shall have treasure in heaven." Such we
                            believe to be the living testimony preached and practiced by his self-denying followers. And
                            no precious Mood will produce these results. The sin-forsaking " life " of Jesus alone will
                            do it. The " blood " that made Jesus what he was is equally operative and powerful to-day.
                            But, whoever waits for Jesus to take the medi- cine by which they will find redemption,
                            waits in vain, and saves a life that would, by its loss, secure to them the virgin life that
                            peoples the heavens!</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>Elder G. A. Lomas, Watervliet, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Redeeming work" TEIform="index"/>REDEEMING WORK</head><p TEIform="p">" Let this mind or disposition be in you, which was in Jesus." Make yourself of no
                            reputation. Take the form of a servant. Subdue pride, ambition, carnal desires, and the love
                            of pleasure. Perform plain duties as they lie before you. To know the Truth, as it concerns
                            ourselves, each one of us, and to practice it; in this consists salvation. Not waiting to do
                            some great deed to manifest our devotion to God; but performing little duties, daily acts of
                            kindness, marking our steps every hour with wisdom. Having found the pearl of great price,
                            go and sell all and buy it. That which affects my peace of mind, my temper, my health, my
                            present and future happiness, most vitally concerns me. To regulate my life according to the
                            demands of the Gospel, this is my life-work. And to this end we must possess the Christ-like
                            disposition, conquer opposing obstacles that would impede or hinder; crucify the flesh,
                            overcome the world; subordinating every purpose, every wish, every thought and desire, to
                            the chief object of personal redemption from a depraved nature, and a wicked world. What a
                            noble undertaking ! What a work lies before us ! A labor sufficient to fill the vast
                            capacities of the soul, sufficient to employ every moment, to fill every hope for the
                            future, to engross the mind, and abstract it from sordid objects; a salvation to be worked
                            out with fear and trembling. Who would desire to prolong mere life, in order to live and die
                            as the animal ? Who would desire to live, rendering our whole being subservient to slavish,
                            sensual and selfish wants ; and neglecting the concerns of the spiritual and immortal
                            nature? What aids we have by the way, as we journey on in the redeeming march! We have both
                            while we wake and when we sleep, the ministrations of good angels, of redeemed spirits, to
                            assist us. We have the blessed example of saintly characters, here upon earth, to encourage,
                            and the consciousness of duty performed, to cheer us. " Take my yoke upon you, and learn of
                            me, for 1 am meek and lowly." We must habitually cultivate the graces of meekness and
                            humility, for an important element in redemption is true humility. In our experience come
                            many chastisements, to lower our pride and implant within us the seeds of humbleness of
                            heart. To succeed, this work must be continued and carried out according to principles of
                            truth, with fixed views, and a resolute purpose and will. The heart is the citadel which
                            must be rendered impregnable against assault. Though trials often reach us, Though troubles
                            be our lot, Yet every thing should teach us, Our hearts should falter not.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="MacRae, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Thomas MacRae, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Approximate new earth" TEIform="index"/>APPROXIMATE NEW EARTH</head><p TEIform="p">Extract from report of Overseer of the Poor in Vineland, N. J., 1869 : "With a population of
                            ten thousand, no citizen of Vineland, has, for the period of six months, required relief at
                            the hands of the Overseer of the Poor, and our poor expenses are a mere trifle. " During the
                            entire year there has been but one indictment, and that a trifling one. " We have no need of
                            a lire department. We have no debt. Our taxes are only one per cent on valuation. "The
                            police expenses are seventy-five dollars a year." Well done for Vineland. Let other Towns
                            emulate Vineland in this respect. We may then hopefully look for the time when there will be
                            no poor, no police, no indictments — except by conscience — no doctors, no lawyers, no
                            sickness, death, nor pain. In place thereof, industry, co-operation, and one perpetual in-
                            heritance in the new earth of the meek.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/>Elijah Myrick</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Probation" TEIform="index"/>PROBATION</head><p TEIform="p">That the eternal destiny of all souls is decided at death is a doctine of Christendom. Who-
                            ever advances the idea of probation, beyond the grave, is supposed to be on the verge of
                            scepticism or spiritualism. We have no controversy with other people's religion, even if we
                            disagree in theology. Our God is rational, possessing all the attributes of tender parents
                            —father and mother. All intelligent beings were designed for a purpose, best known to them
                            who, for aught we know, have sufficient power and skill to humble the mightiest man, and
                            bring the most stubborn woman to simple obedience. The Eternal Parents' mercy is not limited
                            to a few, nor to time allotted here. All souls must and will have opportunity to hear and
                            obey the truth. There is manifest incongruity in the idea that persons of equal goodness,
                            virtue and sincerity, who, for want of faith, or because of what others please to term
                            heresy, are devoted to eternal misery, while their believing companions, although polluted
                            with crime, may, through the merits of Jesus, enter the mansions of eternal brightness and
                            ecstatic bliss. Millions never hear the sound of the Gospel in this life. Other millions are
                            so constituted that obedience to gospel principles is, under earthly conditions, impossible.
                            Judged by their fruits, not all who profess faith in the atonement are qualified for that
                            heaven where no unclean thing can enter. In every intelligent being there is a germ of
                            divinity, whose aspiration for angel food will, in some of the worlds, become too strong for
                            resistance. Entering the spirit world, men and women are still in possession of their former
                            faculties and affections, with all the depravity incurred by indulgence. They have left only
                            the bodily organs behind. All grades and conditions exist in the next world. Naught but
                            indomitable compliance with our holiest aspirations can change the moral status of the soul
                            in this, nor in any world. They, who neglect selfdiscipline, must inevitably realize the
                            degradation of such neglect. Those who are obedient to their holiest aspirings are drawing
                            nearer to the fountain of good. Many, who in this world, fared sumptuously every day,
                            pampering every desire, will, on entering the next world, meet with bitter disappointment.
                            No miraculous salvation through the merits of another will transport them to heaven, a place
                            where what each one loves is good for all, and all possess it. Their appetites and passions,
                            intensified by gratifica tion, are upon them — minus the means of gratification. On the
                            other hand, many, who like the publican, or poor Lazarus, feel unworthy of the crumbs of
                            God's mercy, will stand high in the scale of virtue, prepared for the work of gaining power
                            and victory over every evil propensity by a daily cross. This work must be performed by
                            every soul before complete happiness is attained.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, Chauncy" TEIform="persName"/>Chauncy Dibble, Watervliet, N. Y.</byline></div2><pb n="27" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers: Spirit manifestations - among them prior to their going to the world" TEIform="index"/>Shakers: Spirit manifestations - among them prior to their going to the world
                        </head><p TEIform="p">[From the Weekly Herald, Cleveland, O.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">SHAKERS. SPIRIT MANIFESTATIONS — AMONG THEM PRIOR TO THEIR GOING TO THE WORLD. "
                                    We speak that we do know, and testify that we have seen." John 3; 11. " Write the
                                    things which thou hast seen, and the things which are, and the things which shall be
                                    hereafter." Rev. 1 ; 19. Friends Editors Herald:—Agreeably to your request, we write
                                    to give you and your readers a brief statement of facts, which we have been an eye
                                    and ear witness to, of those "spirit manifestations " which took place in our midst
                                    some years prior to their going to the world. And this we do the more readily,
                                    knowing that the Cleveland Herald is the oldest paper published in Cleveland, and if
                                    we mistake not, has the largest circulation of any in Northern Ohio. 'It was in the
                                    year 1838, in the latter part of summer, some young sisters were walking together on
                                    the bank of the creek, not far from the hemlock grove, west of what is called the
                                    Mill Family, where they heard some beautiful singing, which seemed to be in the air
                                    just above their heads. They were taken by surprise, listened with admiration, and
                                    then hastened home to report the phenomena. Some of them afterwards were chosen
                                    mediums for the "spirits." We had been informed, by letter, that there was a
                                    marvelous work going on in some of the eastern societies, particularly at Mt.
                                    Lebanon, New York, and Watervliet, near Albany. And when it reached us in the West
                                    we should all know it, and we did know it; in the progress of the work, every
                                    individual, from the least to the greatest, did know that there was a
                                    heart-searching God in Israel, who ruled in the armies of Heaven, and will yet rule
                                    among the inhabitants of earth. It commenced among the little girls in thechiidren's
                                    order, who were assembled in an upper room, the doors being shut, holding a meeting
                                    by themselves, when the invisibles began to make themselves known. It was on the
                                    Sabbath Day, while engaged in our usual exercises, that a messenger came in and
                                    informed the Elders, in great haste, that there was something uncommon going on in
                                    the girls' department. The Elders brought our meeting to a close as soon as
                                    circumstances would admit, and went over to witness the singular and strange
                                    phenomena. When we entered the apartment we saw that the girls were under the
                                    influence of a power not their own — they were hurried round the room, back and
                                    forth as swiftly as if driven by the wind —and no one could stop them. If any
                                    attempts were made in that direction, it was found impossible, showing conclusively
                                    that they were under a controlling influence that was irresistible. Suddenly they
                                    were prostrated upon the floor, apparently unconscious of what was going on around
                                    them. With their eyes closed, muscles strained, joints stiff, they were taken up and
                                    laid upon beds, mattrasses, etc. They then began holding converse with their
                                    guardian spirits, and others, some of whom they once knew in the form, making
                                    graceful motions with their hands —talking audibly, so all in the room could hear
                                    and understand, and form some idea of their whereabouts in the spiritual realms they
                                    were exploring in the land of souls. This was only the beginning of a series of "
                                    spirit manifestations," the most remarkable we ever expected to witness on the
                                    earth. One prominent feature of these manifestations was the gift of songs, hymns
                                    and anthems, new, heavenly and melodious. The first inspired song we ever heard from
                                    the "spirit world," with words attached, was the following, sung by one of the young
                                    sisters, while in vision, with great power and demonstration of the spirit, called
                                    by the invisible " THE SONG OF A HERALD." " Prepare, O ye faithful To fight the good
                                    fight, Sing, O ye redeemed, Who walk in the light. Come low, O ye haughty, Come
                                    down, and repent. Disperse, O ye naughty, Who will not relent. For Mother is coming,
                                    Oh hear the glad sound, To comfort her children Wherever they're found, AVith jewels
                                    and robes of fine linen To clothe the afflicted withal." Given by inspiration, at
                                    North Union, August, 1838, ten years prior to the " Eochester Kappings."
                                    EXPLANATION. We wish it distinctly and explicity understood that when the term
                                    Mother is used in any of our sacred writings, the highest sense in which we use that
                                    term carries us to the Deity, of which Mother Ann Lee was a representative of the
                                    eternal Mother principle in the Godhead, as the first born daughter of God, as Jesus
                                    Christ was a representative of the eternal Father principle in the God- head, as the
                                    first born son of God, both of whom were divinely inspired. Are we not too prone to
                                    make gods of subordinates, and finalities of Unites ? Ann Lee taught her followers
                                    to worship God manifested in man, woman, or child. Not the creature. Not persons,
                                    but principles; persons must pass away, but principles, never I This may conflict
                                    with our education and the doctrine of the Trinity, but it does not conflict with
                                    Moses, nor Joshua, nor Genesis, nor Geology — science —nor with good common sense.
                                    St. Paul declared, (if he did not understand it,) when he said, " for the invisible
                                    things of Him from the creation of the world are clearly seen, being understood by
                                    the things that are made, even His eternal power and Godhead, so that they are
                                    'without excuse." Romans 1; 20. According to Moses, among the first things which God
                                    made was man: "And God said, Let us make man in our image, after our likeness; and
                                    let them have dominion," etc., Them in the plural, includ- ing the woman—the mother
                                    principle—not him— man alone—nor father alone. "Let us," i. e., Father and Mother
                                    principle in the God-head. "So God created man in his own image ; in the image of
                                    God created he him; male and female created he them," etc. (Genesis 1;26, 27.) Is it
                                    not singularly strange that commentators of the last two thousand years, or nearly,
                                    have failed to recognize this great principle of Mother in the God-head, as well as
                                    Father, when it was impossible for one to exist without the other? The other, is
                                    always implied. On what principle, then, have we, in the past, excluded the Mother
                                    from the God-head and substituted something else, that has no analogy in the
                                    universe? when there is nothing more clearly taught in holy writ, and is now being
                                    revealed through babes and sucklings. But to our subject —no more digression. Next
                                    followed the little boys in the line of visions and revelations. But, before we take
                                    our leave of the girls, we will relate one incident which we saw exhibited, which
                                    may have a good effect on those in earth life. The gifts continued increasing among
                                    the children. Among these were the gift of tongues, visiting the different cities in
                                    the "spirit world," holding converse with the indwellers thereof, some of whom they
                                    once knew in the body. And in going to these cities they were accompanied by their
                                    guardian angels, and appeared to be flying, using their hands and arms for wings,
                                    moving with as much velocity as the wings of a bird. All of a sudden they stopped,
                                    and the following questions and answers were uttered through their vocal organism:
                                    Question—What city is this ? Answer-" The City of Delight." Question—Who live here?
                                    Answer—The colored population. Question—Can we go in and see them ? Answer—
                                    Certainly. For this purpose you were conducted here. They were admitted, their
                                    countenances changed. Question—Who are all these ? Answer— They are those who were
                                    once slaves in the United States. Question—Who are those behind them ? Answer—They
                                    are those who were once slaveholders. Question—What are they doing here ? Answer
                                    —Serving the slaves as the slaves served them while in the earth life. God is just;
                                    all wrongs have to be righted. Question—Who are those in the corner? Answer—They are
                                    those slaveholders who were unmerciful, and abused their slaves in the world, and
                                    are too proud to comply with the conditions ? Question—What were the conditions ?
                                    Answer—To make confession and ask forgiveness of the slaves, and right their wrongs,
                                    and this they are too proud to do. Question—What will be done with them? Answer—When
                                    their time expires they will be taken away and cast out, and will have to suffer
                                    until they repent, for all wrongs must be righted, either in the form or among the
                                    disembodied spirits, before souls can be happy. And when the girls came out of
                                    vision, they would relate the same things, which corresponded with what they had
                                    previously talked out. Now, we will leave the girls for the present and go into the
                                    boys' department. Here we find them holding meetings by themselves, under the safe
                                    guidance of their care-takers, going in vision, some boys and some girls, for the
                                    work had progressed so as to reach adults, and all were called im- mediately into
                                    the work, whose physical organizations would possibly admit of mediumship. The
                                    peculiar gift at this time, was in visiting the different cities in the " spirit
                                    world," and in renewing acquaintances with many of their departed friends and
                                    relatives, who were the blissful and happy residents therein. But before we go any
                                    further, we will let our mediums describe the first city they come to after crossing
                                    the river. Question—What city is this ? Answer—The Blue city. Quest ion—Who lives
                                    here ? Answer—The Indians. Question—What Indians? Answer—The American Indians.
                                    Question—Why are they the first city we come to in the spirit land, on the plane,
                                    and most accessible? Anuwer—Because the Indians lived more in accordance with the
                                    law of nature, in their earth life, according to their knowledge, and were the most
                                    abused class by the whites, except the slaves, and many of them now are in advance
                                    of the whites in "spirituality," and are the most powerful ministering spirits sent
                                    forth to minister to those who shall be heirs of salvation. At another time these
                                    same mediums, fifteen in number, of both sexes, were sitting on benches in the
                                    meeting-house, saw a band of Indian spirits coming from the " Blue City " in the
                                    spirit world, to unite with them in their worship, said, " They are coming, and as
                                    soon as the spirits entered the door they entered the mediums, which moved them from
                                    their seats as quick as lightning, Then followed the Indian songs and dances, and
                                    speaking in the Indian tongue, which was wholly unintelligible to us except by
                                    spiritual interpreters. It is said the white man first gave the Indian rum ; in
                                    exchange the Indian gave the white man tobacco. Both of which are a curse to
                                    civilization. Which was the aggressor ? If the Indians are allowed to smoke tobacco
                                    in the " spirit land," (which is doubted) is it any wonder that their city is called
                                    the '¦ Blue City ? " Now, Editors of the Herald, if your readers would like to know
                                    any thing more about these things, of which we have only begun to give a brief
                                    sketch, we would recommend them to take the Shaker and SJiakeress, a neat little
                                    Monthly, published at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., edited by Elder F. W. Evans, and Elderess
                                    A. Doolittle. It teaches the equality of the sexes, etc., only 50 cents per annum.
                                    We like it for the following reasons : 1. We like it because it is the Shakers'
                                    missionary to the world. 2. We like it because it teaches the science of a higher
                                    life. 3. We like it because its columns are enriched by original articles from some
                                    of their ablest writers of both sex, drawn from experience, and a " community of
                                    ideas." 4. We like it because of the music on the last! page of each number, which
                                    is worth more than the subscription price of the paper. As the sound of sweet music
                                    dies away in the distance, so is the passing away of friends we Jove.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Weekly herald (Cleveland, Ohio)" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>James S. Prescott, Agent for the Shaker and Shakeress.
                            Cleveland, Ohio, P. O. Box 262.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For book-worms to think of" TEIform="index"/>FOR BOOK-WORMS TO THINK OF</head><p TEIform="p">To form a correct estimate of books and of what should be our relations to them, we must
                            recognize the fact that a book, no matter what its outward form or subject, represents, in
                            its spiritual character and magnetism, the life of the person who wrote it. In reading it we
                            are dealing with the same personal force and character as we should be if we were in actual
                            contact and conversation with the living author. The conditions and perils of fellowship are
                            substantially the same. Reading a book is like forming a personal acquaintance. Wise men are
                            careful about giving themselves up to fellowship with a stranger. Ought they to be less
                            careful in coming into fellowship with a book ? If salvation and damnation are the results
                            of fellowship, and if books are mediums of fellowship, it would be well to inquire whether
                            in this age of universal book-making and reading, men and women are not in greater danger of
                            losing their souls by this kind of fellowship, than by all others together?</p></div2><pb n="28" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prussian letter" TEIform="index"/>A PRUSSIAN LETTER</head><p TEIform="p">My Dear Sister : Your letter of the 9th of December, came into my hands on the last day of
                            the old year. I felt glad and thankful to hear once more from you, and I readily comply with
                            your desire to learn how I am getting on, in body and soul, in my new Shaker-home. Nearly
                            all the remedies employed here for bodily ailments are, outdoor work, plain vegetable food,
                            unbolted wheat-meal bread, and fruit. I am glad to be out of the reach of allopathic
                            treatment, which, nine times out of ten, brings ordinary diseases to a fatal end. Only by
                            giving nature a fall chance to work out her own salvation, without counteracting, impeding,
                            poisonous drugs and unnatural obstructions, is she enabled to bring things to a good end. A
                            full water and hygienic treatment is certainly superior to all other remedial processes. In
                            this respect there is yet room for improvement amongst us. I should wish to see, in every
                            family, a brother and sister, who were well instructed in hygienic and hydropathic
                            principles. The " Laws of Life " I want to see read in every Shaker family. By these means,
                            much weakness and disease might be cured in a short time. I learn more and more to
                            understand, that a faithful fulfilling of the regularly repeating duties and labors of daily
                            life, is one of the surest conditions of contentment and inner peace. Your report of the
                            members of our family, I have read with sympathy. But I see there so many unfortunate,
                            stunted, crippled, and abnormal states and conditions of life, as well in a physical as in a
                            moral point of view, that the Shakers condemning and rejecting, from religious principles,
                            all natural generative family life, as well as the sexual relations that create it, appears
                            to me less hard and extreme. I place the Shaker's life higher, by twothirds, than the
                            average family and social relations in the outside world. Their constant striving after
                            moral and spiritual culture and developments: their holding on to purity and chastity ; by
                            laboring in self-denial, for spiritual life, for unselfish, disinterested, activity and
                            industry, each one seeking the good of the whole ; puts them on a higher plane than those
                            who seek to gratify exclusively their own self, and who search for happines in material and
                            sensual directions. Even in our Shaker rudimental state of development, the grosser vices,
                            which ruin and empester human society in all its classes, do not exist amongst us. Tobacco
                            and spirituous liquors, which transform at least one-third of the human race into physical
                            and moral cripples; sexual incontinence, inside and outside of family life, which destroys
                            and ruins another third of the race ; pauperism and material misery; all this is not known
                            amongst us. But instead thereof, a moderate degree of comfort, with frugality and industry,
                            and a morally clean and pure atmosphere, reigns throughout. I think such a state includes
                            blessings which can hardly be estimated high enough. My sincere sympathy and co-operation is
                            sure to our leaders, in the three families of our order, for the progress which has been
                            made in our physical life, in regard to diet, that forms the basis for future moral and
                            spiritual growth. " Onward " is written on our standard ; and the next object to be attained
                            unto, is the sacrifice of super-fine flour. It will meet with many a short sighted pre-
                            judice, and have to struggle against stubborn opposition. The flesh meat has quite disap-
                            peared from our family table, but this I would hardly call a progress, if it were not
                            followed by the further step of giving up entirely the use of super-fine flour, and taking
                            in its place the coarse, unbolted meal. I have for some time eaten no other, and I feel much
                            the better of it. Some time ago, we had the coarse, unbolted rye bread on our table, as we
                            eat it in Germany, where it forms the staple food for the Prussian army, and of many of the
                            laboring classes ; and I felt, by the use of it, an increase of strength and vital animation
                            of fifty per cent. Fine rye flour paste is only fit to be eaten by individuals who
                            contemplate suicide. If this change, of using the coarse meal of all the sorts of grains,
                            was introduced throughout the families of believers, it would bring about a great many other
                            changes ; and not only put away weakness and disease, to a large extent, but also transform
                            our whole conditions of labor and farming. Half the quantity of grain we now use would be
                            sufficient for sustaining the family, and hard labor would, in consequence, be diminished
                            considerably. We would not need so much hired help then, and that would lighten the burden
                            of the sisters and diminish our expenses, as well as lessening the dangers to our young
                            people, by removing them from low and vulgar influences. More leisure for culture and
                            refinement, in music and mental exercise, would be gained. Whoever are able to free
                            themselves of false habits and silly prejudices, will recognize and admit, that the way we
                            now select and prepare our food, is not perfect, nor free from objections. Should we try to
                            change the constituents of the atmospheric air for our breathing, we would not act any more
                            senseless than we do, by sifting out any part of the grain we use. It is an indirect
                            abnegation of God and His divine wisdom, as creator of nature and of all organic life, that
                            furnishes, in vegetable organisms, and especially in the seeds of some of them, the proper
                            nutriment for producing and maintaining the higher life. In the kernal of grain there are
                            two constituents, the inside non-nitrogenous starch, the outside nitrogenous; the whole
                            enclosed by the husk or hull. If it were possible to separate half of the white of eggs, and
                            let the germ of the young chickens be developed out of the remainder, we should produce just
                            such a scrofulous, unfinished breed of chickens, as is now the young human raised upon
                            super-fine flour; either directly or indirectly by their mother's milk. An immense amount of
                            human misery, too large to be perceived at once, would disappear, if these simple,
                            unrefutable truths could be recognized, reduced to use, and the conditions of physical life
                            be transformed according to them. People are disposed to think that such a change, as is
                            here indicated, when first brought before them, an extraordinary sacrifice and privation ;
                            but that is a mistake. It is just the contrary. There is a perfect analogy between the
                            change from an unrighteous to a righteous life. A person accustomed to indulgence in vain
                            worldly pleasures; in sensuous revelry and debauch, will find the change to a sober, frugal,
                            industrious, pure and chaste life, a sacrifice hard to bear. The regular duties of daily
                            life will appear monotonous ; existence, insipid and without charm. But before long a gentle
                            calm will steal over the mind ; a feeling of peace and quiet contentment take the place of
                            gnawing restlessness and dissatisfaction with self and others. The turbulent waters of the
                            soul will become smooth and clear, and the rays of divine love will enter like sunbeams. An
                            organism, accustomed to be under the constant influence of stimulants and narcotics, will,
                            at first, find good wholesome food and drink insipid, and without relish to the digestive
                            apparatus, weakened and sickly by improper nutriment, the coarse food will be too rough and
                            hard ; but, by persistence in using it, this will soon change. A healthy, vigorous condition
                            of the bodily organs, will enable them to do their work properly ; and the preparations of
                            coarse meal and fruits, will afford to the refined and quickened perception of the nerves, a
                            gustatory enjoyment greater than ever before. Only in this way man will reach that blessed
                            condition to make his body a place in which a divine spirit can dwell. When we have purified
                            and refined our physical systems, noble, loving feelings and thoughts will enter our heart
                            and mind, with out our being conscious of it ; just as surely as a crude, wet, swampish
                            soil, that was only able to produce lower vegetable organisms, will, by draining, tilling,
                            letting sunlight and air penetrate it, have higher forms of plant life germinate, and be
                            finally able to bring forth grain and fruit. We must never forget that God is Love, and that
                            means, happiness is insured to his creatures as a condition of their existence. In this way
                            alone we shall attain the blessed state of liberty, which every soul longs for, and which
                            Spinoza defines thus, " to do, by our own will and impulse, the will of God, that is to be
                            one with God." I hope, my dear sister, you have kept alive, and have not got choked by this
                            shower-bath of wisdom, that I have poured down upon you, but that you may profit by it and
                            be happy. Yours affectionately,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Assmann, Julius" TEIform="persName"/>Julius Assmann, Cannan, Feb. 25,1874</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watchman" TEIform="index"/>WATCHMAN</head><p TEIform="p">Tell us, watchman, what of the night ? Has the hour of midnight passed ? do stars shine out;
                            or, is it all dark, dark, darkness? Or, do you see the signs of the coming day beginning to
                            appear ? Tell us, for we have work to do, and with the first signs of the day we would be
                            astir! 0, Seeker! yet a little while and the day shall come, bright and beautiful, for the
                            sky is already aglow with beams of morning light, such as tell of a glorious day ! Wrong,
                            injustice, tyranny, superstition, avarice, falsehood, with all their attending followers,
                            who, through the long, dark night, have tramped the streets of the great earth with polluted
                            feet and violent hands, leaving misery in their wake — these are already trembling for their
                            deeds, which testify against them, and one by one they are being banished from the face of
                            the earth ; and men and women are speaking without fear, undaunted by the darkness; they are
                            rising up in judgment against the wrongs of night, and, as the day dawns, they are running
                            to and fro, asking each other anxiously, " Where shall we go to wash ourselves clean; to
                            clothe ourselves; to find employment for our hands and feet, fit for the light of the
                            noonday ? " And they who have not bowed the knee to the powers of night, nor sacrificed on
                            her altars, shall point them to the running stream, to the garments bright, to the work of
                            the day, that the Kingdoms of this world may become the Kingdoms of our Lord, and His
                            knowledge cover the earth as the waters cover the sea.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Thomas Smith, Cannan, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="worldnews" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Terror of the Inquisition gone" TEIform="index"/>The Terror of the Inquisition Gone</head><p TEIform="p">The Inquisitorial halls of Rome have rung lately with words that contrast marvelously with
                            the entreaties, cries and groans which they have heard in other days. Father Grassi, the
                            priest who was recently converted at Rome, has appeared before the Tribunal of the Holy
                            Inquisition, and in the course of an exultant justification of his course, he uttered the
                            following words, which must have burned into the very hearts of some of the priests present.
                            "In this room, to-day, I come to bear witness to the truth, and you no longer have the power
                            to touch a hair of my head; you have lost all authority; the work of God has commenced; and
                            soon these walls, these chambers, these instruments of torture and this tribunal will be
                            ground like so much dust under our feet. Now listen to what God has promised to do here in
                            Uoine against the enemies of his church. Here is the infallible order that God sends to the
                            Roman believers: 'The God of Peace will soon grind Satan under his feet.' Do you not tremble
                            at these words of the Lord? Is it not Satan who has imposed and directed so many judgments,
                            so many tortures, so many butcheries and massacres in these very rooms? But already Satan
                            begins to be conquered; the torch of the dog of the Inquisition is forever extinguished, the
                            breath of God has blown upon it, and from this time forth it can never more be ignited."</p></div2><pb n="29" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: a parable" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: A PARABLE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">Once upon a time there lived a good patriarch, who had the great misfortune to have a large
                            family of decidedly bad children; yet somehow these children were not legitimate at all;
                            they were owned by a kind of prosy ; and although, to some minds, how this thing could be is
                            a paradox, yet in tracing their lineage to its origin, as nearly as we can, we find that not
                            one of them ever had a mother. And indeed the great Primogenitor, to whom they claimed
                            relationship, in reality, never had but one child, and that was a beloved son, who was as
                            old as Ids father, and dwelt in his bosom, which, we will suppose, signified his love and
                            entire confidence. He was also as good and perfect as his father, and kept his injunctions,
                            and did always those things which pleased him. But the other adopted, accidental, or inci-
                            dental children, were disobedient, heady, highminded and rebellious, daily doing those
                            things that displeased their good father. He gave them lessons which they would not heed,
                            and he pleaded with them, and sent messengers to warn them, but they would persist in doing
                            as they pleased. At length he decided that forbearance toward them had ceased to be a
                            virtue, and his patience became so exhausted, that he was angry with them every day; and he
                            finally concluded to destroy them all. The good son, who had been safely ensconced in his
                            father's bosom, happened to be in a more calm and considerate frame of mind, and he looked
                            upon those wicked children with tenderness and compassion, for he saw many good traits of
                            character in them, which he thought would be better saved than destroyed, and determined to
                            appease his father's anger. So he said, " Now my ever adorable father, I pray you listen to
                            me, and do not carry your design into effect! I offer myself a willing sacrifice, a
                            propitiation for their grievous wrongs. It is but just that they should die, and justice
                            must be satisfied ! And now, all I ask is, let mercy rule and exonerate them, and 1 "will
                            die in their stead! And the following shall be an everlasting bond, or covenant, between you
                            and me : You shall give all these children into my charge, and I will stand as mediator
                            between you and them, and I will give my blood to seal this covenant; and I will become a
                            'palladium, to the whole family, and they shall trust in me, and whatsoever they ask of you,
                            they shall ask in my name. And this covenant shall endure through all coming ages; and
                            should the children multiply and become as numerous as the sands upon the sea shore, it
                            shall remain the same. Yon shall accept my life as the ransom for all their past, present
                            and future violations of just and righteous laws ; provided they will believe that I am able
                            and willing to forgive them as often as they transgress ; and that there is sufficient
                            efficacy in my blood to wash away even the very stains of sin. The great and good father was
                            well pleased with the generous offer of his wise and humane son, and he joyfully accepted
                            him as a sacriSHA.KEHES8 fice in lieu of punishing and condemning any of the rest: and that,
                            on account of the rightousness, sufferings and death of his innocent and only son, he would
                            absolve all the guilty ones. Now, all that remains to be done is, since it has been decided
                            that sin is the unavoidable concomitant of human life, to confess in some closet or secret
                            place that they have broken their father's laws and done many wrong deeds, and ask for one
                            drop of the atoning blood, and all is right ! Who, we would ask, can help admiring such a
                            benevolent character? Is it not worthy of all praise ? say the popular theologians through
                            the orthodox churches. Jesus Christ, through John of the Apocalypse, said, " Behold, i come
                            quickly, and my reward is with me, to give to every man according as his toork shall be.
                            Which shall we accept ? We offer a simple remedy for some of the ills of humanity ; it is
                            not a compound of condi ments, nor mineral substances, but of good common sense. Keep the
                            hands employed in some useful avocation, the feet dry and warm, head cool, body clean, and
                            the stomach supplied with plain, healthful food, taken at suitable intervals ; keep good
                            hours, and remember that night is the time to sleep and rest; store the mind with good
                            mental food, carefully avoiding every kind of trashy and unclean literature, that would
                            serve to act upon and stimulate the animal passions ; keep the thotights pure; and do
                            precisely " unto others as ye would that they should do unto you;" then you will make
                            progress toward a healthy soul and body.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Innocence" TEIform="index"/>INNOCENCE</head><p TEIform="p">O innocence, tliou spirit bright, Thy pathway we have found! And, guided by thy angel hand,
                            We'll tread thy holy ground. We look with joy upon thy face, That hath no cloud or shade ;
                            And pray thy voice may yet be heard Through every rank and grade. When shall we see thy
                            temple fair, Adorned with souls in white, Who drink from thy eternal springs, With chaste
                            and sweet delight. In them false honor is dethron'd, With all its glittering train; By them
                            the tyrant's chain is rent, And truth has pow'r to reign. In Truth is found simplicity, And
                            liberty combin'd, And whosoe'er will seek for her The tree of life will find. She leads
                            through virtue's flowery path, To wisdom's quiet vale, And crowns with lasting life the
                            soul, Whose courage does not fail.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Maynard, Betsey" TEIform="persName"/>Betsey Maynard, Harvard, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gentleness" TEIform="index"/>GENTLENESS</head><p TEIform="p">" Thy gentleness hath made me great," said the Psalmist, in oive -of his inspirational
                            moments. Wrhose gentleness ? God's gentleness ; the Wisdom and Love elements from the Father
                            and Mother in Deity ; but more particularly of the AfAther, who (in speaking of her own
                            MaterniTt^ and Eternity), said^ " Hear, for I will speak of excellent things ; counsel is
                            mine and sound wisdom. When He (God) appointed the foundations of the earth, then I was by
                            Him, as one brought up with Him ; and I was His delight, rejoicing always before Him." And
                            Jesus, who was called the " Lamb of God," a name so typical of gentleness, how mild was he
                            in his intercourse with all with whom he came in contact, holding in reserve the indignation
                            that his pure spirit must often times have felt at the glaring wrongs around him. 29 Once,
                            at the desecration of the temple when there was a grievous departure from Law and Gospel,
                            such a letting down of principle to the greed of worldly gain, he gave vent to the deep
                            feelings of his heart, and cast out the money-changers, and sellers of doves, and overthrew
                            their tables. He felt that the temple of God was defiled; and that they were seeking to
                            supplant the blessed ministers of purity and love. That rebuke administered through the
                            medium of the " small cords," probably made them feel more like a company of thievish
                            transgressors, than like honorable merchants. But the Spirit of Truth, with which he was
                            baptized, being "quick and powerful" to discern the true from the false, was constrained, at
                            times, to exclaim in the ears of his hearers," Ye adulterous generation ! " " generation of
                            vipers I" etc. But gentleness of spirit, as the rule, marked his course of life. Some recent
                            writers have sought to prove that Hie good Jesus was at fault, because he abjured the
                            relationships which belong to the natural plane of life, for the spiritual and heavenly
                            relationship of the kingdom of heaven; they say, " What we want of our teachers, is not
                            abdication, but conquest." They urge that Christianity, as taught by his professed
                            followers, has erred in the same way. But we ask, what is Christianity worth, if it does not
                            affect a change of life and character ? " The Law made nothing perfect," for the reason that
                            it was " weak through the flesh," and those very permissions which some of our modern
                            writers are urging as essential; nor did it bring deliverance to a groaning world; nor did
                            the philosophers and sages who preceded Jesus Christ, or who were contempora- neous with
                            him, give such relief. The earth still remained unredeemed with sin and misery predominant,
                            and goodness the exception. Christ, with his self-denial as the terms of discipleship, and
                            call to follow him in a daily cross, taught the purity and holiness required, when he said,
                            " Be ye perfect even as your Father who is in Heaven is perfect." He then taught a degree of
                            self-renunciation beyond what had previously been required; and not only taught it but lived
                            it. Evidently he gladly would have gathered his disciples around him, and formed a nucleus
                            of a community, if he did not positively require it of them at that time. It would seem that
                            a part of the twelve were unprepared for a communion of interest; and the truths of that day
                            were so far in advance of the travel of its receivers, that Jesus spoke to them in parables,
                            and said : that all could not receive his teachings as a whole, but, " whosoever is able let
                            him receive it." The Pentecostal baptism, for a time, made those who believed, of one'heart
                            and mind, and then they had all things in common ; but they were only " a kind of first
                            fruits," and were not able to carry out the principles to perfection. Persecution, and the
                            worldly spirit within, and from without, overcame and scattered them, and all who did not
                            wish to be disturbed in their worldly life and possessions, doubtless breathed easier when
                            those who were turning" things " upside down" were divided and scattered, or gathered to the
                            spiritland. In those days, there was a high mark set upon virginity, those who were " holy
                            in body and spirit," saw the luster and charm thrown around the character of the Virgin <pb n="30" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 3O Mary, and many others since, who have suffered every indignity, and
                            even loss of life itself, rather than violate the law of Chastity. How marked was the
                            description of John the Revelator, concerning the Church of the future, which would be
                            composed exclusively of undefiled virgins. The world has had Convents and Nunneries to
                            represent the devotees to the principle of Virginity ; but never until recently, has the
                            world been permitted to see the fruits of the teaching and example of Jesus, when carried to
                            their ultimates. Through the inspiration vouchsafed to an uneducated woman, who belonged to
                            a society that believed in the solemn ministry of silence, and inward waiting upon the Lord,
                            have the principles of the first Christian Church been revived, which were nearly swept away
                            during the dark agea. Her inspiration was professedly from the Saviour, who conversed with
                            her as with a friend, and enlightened her as to the cause of the degradation and misery of
                            humanity, and the means by which Eden could be restored to more than its primitive glory,
                            which would be effected by 7'e-generation instead of generation. And now, by the continued
                            living influx of Divine revelation from the Spirit-world, by which the Second Christian
                            Church is vitalized, and through the power of the Dual Order in the highest heavens, a new
                            spiritual Household is formed, under the supervision of a representative father and mother;
                            and sons and daughters are brought forth, who become brethren and sisters in Christ; and,
                            although in the world, and performing all needful duties pertaining to the earth life, are
                            not 0/ the world. The old heavens are now passing away in confusion, the religions of the
                            world having proved themselves inadequate to supply the soul needs of humanity ; and a new
                            heaven is appearing. The new earUi is also beginning to appear, in which physical reforms
                            are working for the elevation of man and woman relating to the physiological and generative
                            life ; that a new and a better race may be brought forth to occupy and recreate the earth.
                            But let not that class decry and seek to destroy those who follow the Lamb, and who sing the
                            new song of victory over the " beast and his image," —the earthly and sensual nature; for,
                            without the new heaven, where would be the ministration of light and heat, which is to
                            vitalize the new earth, and inspire in the heroic struggle for a nobler and more harmonious
                            race ? They must advance both together, and move on toward the goal of complete redemption.
                            The one must act upon the other, like " The wheel within a wheel," which the Prophet saw in
                            vision. The motion and force of the whole is dependent upon each, and neither can say that
                            the other is unnecessary. The happiness and redemption of the race is the object in view;
                            and, if that can be accomplished by the denial of the generative instincts, in those who "
                            are able," and who feel the necessity of thus doing, that they may form a connecting link in
                            the chain of progress, and be joined to those who are more elevated, and thereby improve the
                            race, can it be a matter of regret, or an occasion of fear, that " the world will run out,"
                            when it is so evidently exhausting itself by excesses, and by wars, pestilence, and
                            famine,—the consequence of physical and generative sins? The system which Jesus came to
                            teach, never having been fully put in practice, can it be truthfully said, that Christianity
                            has proved a failure ? " The whole creation has groaned, being in pain, waiting for the
                            manifestation of the Christ in the second part of his manhood, or for the second Eve, that '
                            the sons and daughters of God' might appear. ' The Comforter' was to come —' Christ in his
                            glory.'" " The woman is the glory of the man." The Church of the past has been onesided, and
                            as unproductive of good results as any house would be without a mother, and with nought but
                            a combination of three male principles. This, however, was not a part of Christ's teaching:
                            for none could be more tender and charitable toward woman, than he was, nor more
                            appreciative, as her unbounded love to him would show; which constrained her to be last at
                            the cross, and earliest at the grave. When " all are one in Christ Jesus, neither male nor
                            female," but all take part in the various industries, and branches of government, according
                            to their ability, neither being independent of the other, but supporting a pure brotherly
                            and sisterly relation, in the innocence of little children; where the labor, toil, and
                            energies of all, are freely given for the benefit of all; who will say that the " kingdom of
                            heaven is not pretty well advanced on earth ? In this spirit of consecration, men or women
                            may " buy as though they possessed not, and use this world as not abusing it;" for all is
                            ours; not mine, and thine. When souls in this manner give cheerfully of time and talent to
                            the public good, sacrificing their natural desires and loves, which would lead them to the
                            pursuit of beauty in nature and art, and instead, turn their steps to the bedside of age and
                            weakness, to minister care, food, and comfort, or to bestow the mother love upon the
                            orphaned and lonely ones of earth, can we not feel that this self-renuncia- tion is one in
                            whicli the "man of sorrows" would sympathize ? And will he not claim such, as his true sons
                            and daughters, who are thus striving to grow more and more into his likeness ? Can they not
                            say with the Psalmist, " Thy gentleness hath made me great ?"— great in self-abasement, that
                            the good may be exalted; and in self-denial, that the heroism of the Chief of self-deniers
                            may be ours ? for he possessed the same nature that we possess, yet relinquished all for the
                            higher life, and became a pattern for others to follow, and practically showed that " He
                            that ruleth his own spirit is greater than he that taketh a city;" and those who gain this
                            victory, and are attracted to, and vitalized by, the "Women clothed with the sun"—truth and
                            light— " ha ring a crown of twelve stars upon her head," representatives of the twelve
                            Christian virtues, do really " partake of the waters of life ;" for they have dug deep to
                            find them. Happy are they who have heard the voice of the heavenly Bridegroom and Bride, who
                            are calling for wise virgins to appear in clean and white raiment, to grace the marriage
                            supper: for the " Bride hath made herself ready ;" and let them be sure to supply their
                            lamps with oil, that neither the darkness of the way, nor the length of the journey, may
                            dishearten them. Some have come in, and their sorrow has been turned into rejoicing, and
                            their souls have been cheered with music and dancing. And the " Spirit and the Bride "
                            continue to say " come," and the children of Zion repeat the invitation : O come, all ye
                            wand'ring and motherless ones, Whose cup of affliction with mis'ry o'erruns ; Come, strip
                            off your garments of sin and of shame, And bathe in our fountains, ye blind and ye lame, For
                            nothing is sweeter in heaven or earth, Than love from the Mother who gives the soul birth ;
                            The Mother, blest Mother, who taught us the way To enter the mansions of heaven's bright
                            day.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. Webster, Harvard, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Testimony of an aged sister" TEIform="index"/>TESTIMONY OF AN AGED SISTER</head><p TEIform="p">I AM now eighty years of age, and it is about thirty-nine years since I united with the Be-
                            lievers in Christ's Second Appearing; and I feel a strong desire before I am gathered to my
                            fathers and mothers, who have passed on before me to the spirit land, to say a word to the
                            stranger, and to the young of Zion's fold, concerning that faith by which I was called to
                            come out from a world of sin, to embrace the Gospel work, which contained the power of
                            salvation, and which has been, to me, the " Pearl of great price." When I was fifteen years
                            of age, I united with the Baptist Church, and continued with them many years, striving to
                            find a power that would satisfy my heart's desire, and redeem my soul unto God, who gave it.
                            At the age of thirty-seven, I trembled to find, that 1 was yet a sinner in the sight of God,
                            and a wanderer from Him. I united with the Presbyterians, and strovo to renew my zeal, and
                            work righteousness, and live more to my own justification, and to God's acceptance. I
                            continued in this soul" struggle seven years, but could not find food sufficient to sustain
                            the spiritual part; for my soul hungered and thirsted after the bread and waters of life,
                            and demanded a greater supply than I could obtain. At this time of need I read some of the
                            publications of Believers (commonly called Shakers), and was led to investigate their doc-
                            trine, which, at that time, seemed strange to me. At length I visited the society at
                            Canterbury, N. H., and spent four days there, and then returned to my home. In about one
                            year from that time, revisited the people at the same place, where I was kindly received and
                            entertained. No pains were spared to enlighten my understanding, by giving me such
                            information as I required ; and I had an opportunity of judging of their principles by the
                            fruits brought forth. I perceived that a true Christian life and character must be based
                            upon self-denial and the cross, which crucifies the carnal mind, and all selfishness ; and
                            brings souls into a oneness of heart and life, and enforces the golden rule. Each ray of new
                            light that shone into my soul, warmed and gave life to my immortal spirit; and I became
                            satisfied that it was the true way of God, and that it would bring life and salvation, if I
                            would be obedient. My understanding was enlightened to see the cause of my loss from God;
                            and that if I would become a true follower of Christ, the lower animal nature in me must be
                            mortified and subdued. I resolved to prove the work, by being obedient to my convictions,
                            and find a life in God, though it should be at the expense of every self-pleasing desire;
                            remembering Christ's words, " Forsake all and follow Me." Circumstances rendered it more
                            convenient for me to unite with the Society of Shakers in Enfield, SHA.KER _A.ND <pb n="31" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKERESS. 31 Conn. I did so sincerely, according to my best understanding,
                            and placed my all upon the altar of j ustice and truth; and by so doing, new and increasing
                            light, joy and love beamed into my soul, yielding a satisfaction which I had long sought,
                            but could not find, and I am now satisfied that true peace of mind and rest to the soul
                            cannot be obtained except by a full sacrifice of the worldly life, through watching and
                            prayer. I have never regretted the choice that I made, nor had one desire to return to my
                            former mode of life. And now, at the age of four score years, I feel to raise my heart and
                            voice in praise and thanksgiving to God, for the great salvation that I have found; and with
                            my feeble hand I pen these few lines, hoping thereby to benefit some of my fellow creatures
                            who are now, as I once was, wandering in darkness and sin. My prayer is that all such souls
                            may find resurrection life in Christ, which alone will insure happiness in this world, and
                            eternal bliss in the world to come.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wright, Mary C." TEIform="persName"/>Mary C. Wright, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Eldress A.:" TEIform="index"/>Dear Eldress A.:</head><p TEIform="p">I would show my appreciation of your beautiful description in February No. of Sister
                            Margaret's departure to her spirit home, by returning thanks. I read the account with deep
                            interest, and was edified and strengthened by the inspiring expressions which fell from the
                            lips of our dear Gospel sister, as her spirit was about to take its upward flight to the
                            unseen world. Her example in life and death is worthy to be imitated by every one who "
                            names the name of Christ," and professes to love the truth. Without purity of heart, we are
                            not practical Christians ; and true " love is the seal of discipleship," and will so remain
                            ; and only through self-denial, and the same cross which Jesus bore, can any soul " be
                            crucified unto the world, with all its affections and lusts." Such is the faith implanted in
                            my heart; and by it I am resolved to live and die. I would have my life all pure and
                            righteous; and my latest breathings like sweet Margaret's, drawn out in prayer for Zion's
                            prosperity ; and, that her inmates may be filled with love and peace, and songs of rejoicing
                            and praise. Do we not see how death may be swallowed up in victory, and the grave robbed of
                            its terrors by a sinless life, while the spirit rises in triumph over all inferior things ?
                            Those who thus live, do not die when they pass out of the material form ; by throwing off
                            the grosser part, life becomes intensified — quickened — and we often feel a power, and
                            sweet influence emanating from them, which give peace and rest to our spirits, while engaged
                            in the arduous duties of the earth life. They become as guardian Angels to those whom they
                            have left on the shores of time; and they often gather to the circles in the Eden home on
                            earth, which, through consecrated labor, themselves have helped to create ; and they
                            continue to strive to enhance its beauty, and to adorn all its walks ; and they delight to
                            encourage and uplift each struggling soul, and to guide the young in the beautiful path of
                            innocence, which leads to peace. How safe we feel while confiding in such holy watchers, to
                            protect and guard the little flock. Now, my dear mother, I want to say to you, that Sister
                            Margaret is not gone far from your embraces ; she is still your own, and her spirit lingers
                            to bless and to cheer. And, since leaving the clay tenement, her spirit is happy and free in
                            the society of the good and pure, in the Church of God on earth, and in heaven. Death to
                            her, is but a birth into the higher life with enlarged powers of action. And, I feel to
                            rejoice with her, that the messenger of life (not death) hath opened the door of liberty,
                            and set her spirit free from the frail body, which it was her lot to inhabit. I feel renewed
                            courage and strength, to press on in the gospel work ; and I will toil patiently and wait
                            until the time shall come for me to be gathered to my heavenly home; and I hope to be found
                            worthy to dwell with the shining saints in glory. I pledge myself to be with you in the
                            progress of truth, now and forever. In bonds of Christian love and affection.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Julia" TEIform="persName"/>Julia Johnson, West Pittsfield, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Woman's sphere" TEIform="index"/>WOMAN'S SPHERE</head><p TEIform="p">"The eyes may brighten, and lips may smile, And the heart with anguish be torn the while."
                            For woman (generous toiler) Can bury sorrows deep Till oft, in cloister'd moments, 'lone,
                            She finds them but to weep. And yet her grief must silent be, Her burden she must bear, Till
                            truth can fetter error strong, And heed her time-bound prayer. She was not form'd for man to
                            rule With firm relentless hand ; She was not form'd a chattel slave, To be at his command;
                            She was not form'd to be the means ¦ Of bearing down a name Unto an offspring cursed,
                            debased, That cause her spirit shame. She feels her rights, but she is bound By those whom
                            passions hold; She knows her claims to earth and heav'n, For this her heart is bold. She
                            presses through the flood of thought, Sarcasm, scorn, and ire ; She holds her way undaunted,
                            firm, Enrobed in Love's attire. She knows, when Reason, Justice pure, Shall place within
                            each heart Those living truths which guard the soul, Then slavery will depart, And Freedom
                            can her course pursue, Sustain her glorious cause, While Wisdom helps to form anew The
                            Father's broken laws. Then priest, or priestcraft, ne'er can stay Equality, or right; But
                            man shall own and bless the cause Which gave to earth new light: And, through her powers for
                            good and right, Life's burdens shall decrease ; While 'neath her influence, chaste and pure,
                            Disease and crime shall cease. Through her shall gleam the golden light, And inspiration
                            true Shall touch with love the soul of man, His life for God renew. And then, as one,
                            they'll toil in peace, And seeds celestial sow ; While heav'n and earth the chorus swell,—
                            God reigns with man beloiv!</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Byrdsall, Charlotte" TEIform="persName"/>Charlotte Byrdsall, Mt. Lebanon.</byline></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is argued that woman is not in servitude..." TEIform="index"/>It is argued that woman is not in servitude...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is argued that woman is not in servitude, because she voluntarily places herself in cer-
                            tain positions, and chooses her own condition; therefore, to her it is not bondage, but
                            freedom. We would ask, Are not the organic laws of the land, and the usages of society, such
                            as compel some women to accept conditions that would otherwise be repugnant to their
                            feelings ? Before American chattel slavery was abolished, its abettors claimed that
                            thousands of the negro slaves did not desire emancipation; that they so loved their masters,
                            under whom they served, that they could not be induced to leave them, and accept of freedom.
                            Freedom for woman has a deeper and broader signification than is generally supposed. There
                            are gleamings of light upon the subject; but as yet, many who think they have advanced
                            ideas, and understand the matter well, will find, as light and truth increase, that their
                            present views are undefined and chaotic. That woman is measurably a willing slave, while she
                            panders to fashion, and yields herself, without constraint to libidinous desires, and seeks
                            to satiate sensual passions in herself, or in others, we will not deny. We pray that a
                            divine power may descend from the heavens, that will open the eyes of those who are
                            spiritually blind, and shake both priests and people, and awaken them to a consciousness of
                            the real conditions and needs of humanity at the present time.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editress" TEIform="persName"/>Editress</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Songs" TEIform="index"/>SONGS</head><p TEIform="p">The peculiar gift of song that is given to Believers in Christ's Second Appearing, is
                            beautiful, and highly prized by them. The breathings of the soul in measured strains of
                            melody, filled with inspirational power from the interior spheres, is like balm to the
                            spirit. The first founders of the Second Christian Church, Mother Ann, and her co-laborers,
                            father William and father James, were very much blest with the gift of new and inspira-
                            tional songs. The Christ-Spirit that baptized them, seemed to say, " Sing unto the Lord a
                            new song; and chant no more the melodies which properly belong to the old heavens ; for
                            behold the time has come for old things to pass away, and all things to become new in the
                            coming New Dispensation. The songs of Zion shall be filled with prayer and praise ever
                            changing and constantly affording new food to supply the soul's needs through all the
                            progressive stages of the travel and growth of Believers." Thus far, we have confined
                            ourselves to vocal music, and spiritual inspirational songs have been given, until they may
                            be numbered by thousands. They are simple in style, but are peculiarly adapted to the
                            religious feelings, and they touch the harmonic chords in the human soul, and lift it into
                            the Divine element. Hitherto, we have not aimed so much to be scientific, as to be spiritual
                            in our singing. And many who have given their attention to the mere science of music have
                            criticised us ; while others, more spiritual, say, if you can have but the one, it is better
                            to retain the spirit and essence, than to have the science without them. But as we claim
                            that God is the Source of all true science, we may with safety cultivate our voices, and
                            work with the inspirational powers toward perfection in music, as in all other things ; for
                            the more refined and harmonious we become in worship, the more beautiful shall we appear in
                            the sight of Angels, and the more acceptable will our offerings be. Then, dear Gospel
                            friends, let us strive to correct our faults, while we cherish the gift of new and inspired
                            songs as a rich ministration from Angels and departed friends.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dodgson, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna Dodgson, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Power of prayer" TEIform="index"/>POWER OF PRAYER</head><p TEIform="p">By a young Shaker Sister fifteen years of age. Prayer is the desire of the heart, the breath
                            of the soul. The humblest petition which flows from a sincere heart is more acceptable and
                            effectual than the most eloquent words that may pass the lips without sincerity and true
                            simplicity. Prayer is essential to a true life ; for it is a shield. Jesus said, " Watch and
                            pray lest ye enter into temptation." God looks at the heart. He does not measure prayer by
                            the quantity of words uttered, nor take into account the eloquence of those words. David
                            said : " If I regard iniquity in my heart, the Lord will not hear me. The thoughts of the
                            wicked are an abomination unto the Lord; and He knoweth them afar off; but He heareth the
                            prayer of the righteous." The prayer of faith is powerful, as many have proved who have
                            asked Divine assistance in times of trouble and affliction. Jesus said: "'Use not vain
                            repetitions as the heathen do, who think they shall be heard for their much speaking." If we
                            have faith in God — possess childlike simplicity-^are contrite in spirit, and ask with a
                            confiding trust, we shall receive; and shall find the promise true : " If we knock it will
                            be opened unto us."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Midgley, Eliza" TEIform="persName"/>Eliza Midgley, Enfield, ^.</byline></div2><pb n="32" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Labor of life" TEIform="index"/>LABOR OF LIFE</head><p TEIform="p">Andante. -0 1. Dream not a way life's golden hours In realms of transient bliss; And tarry
                            not in pleasure's bow'rs, In quest of hap2. Fair fields in God's own heritage Invite to
                            nobler aims, The stronger powers of good engage Through virtue's ho3. The chambers of thy
                            soul expand, And stretch thy tents abroad, Clasp Labor in Religion's hand, And aid the work
                            piness. ly claims, of God; "ffov there the syren sings her song, The wand'rer to decoy,
                            There subtle charms like magnet strong, Allure but to destroy. Awake! for glorious themes to
                            strive, Above earth's sordid pelf, In broad philanthrophy to thrive, Beyond the sphere of
                            self. Till the millennial day shall shine Unto earth's distant bound; Till perfect love, and
                            peace divine, Abiding place have found.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lamentation" TEIform="index"/>LAMENTATION</head><p TEIform="p">A wild cry arises from memory's haunt, From depths of conditions of woe! Where children of
                            darkness, of sorrow and want, No ease for their sufferings know. There is cursing, and
                            wailing, and anguish of heart, A writhing in torment and pain ! O why this injustice ? what
                            aid will impart The pow'r that will freedom obtain ? This cruel oppression that crushes the
                            poor, And gives to the wealthy their weal, This un-christian spirit turns from the door, -
                            The needy to starve, or to steal. 'Tis asked, " is it true that the houseless descend To
                            join with the ruinous train, Whose brief lives of vice in infamy end, And this for some
                            slight paltry gain ? " 'Tis true, ah, too true, we are forced to reply, Fair virtue to
                            mammon doth bow, For gaunt destitution is still waiting nigh, To stamp with starvation the
                            brow. We look for the soul — that is buried from sight, And dross is piled up in its place ;
                            Like gold in the ore, 'tis obscured from the sight, But little of it we can trace. Yea, the
                            " seed bud of beauty " is withered and crushed By storms of adversity's hour, And the small
                            voice within is stifled and hushed By passions strong pleading for pow'r. But ye who can
                            shake from the rough, iron hand, The chain of oppression so cold, Go, unbind the weak and
                            the poor of the land ; Be fearless, undaunted, and bold. 'Tis God fires your purpose, ye
                            noble and brave, And angels inspire you still on ! For truth, that's almighty and able to
                            save, Is seen in the work you have done. No more be ye faint at the sight of distress,
                            Dismay'd at recitals of woe, Which now from the lips of the suffering press, Whose hearts
                            only bitterness know. For happier days we are gifted to see Dawn o'er this sin-blighted race
                            ; When men in a brotherhood equal shall be, And poverty find not a place ; When the standard
                            of purity higher is raised, And the blind are enabled to see That only through holiness God
                            can be praised, And only the truth maketh free.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leavenworth, Elvah" TEIform="persName"/>Elvah Leavenworth, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If I were suddenly asked to give a proof..." TEIform="index"/>If I were suddenly asked to give a proof...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">If I were suddenly asked to give a proof of the goodness of God to us, I think I should say
                            that it is most manifested in the exquisite difference He has made between the souls of
                            women and men, so as to create the possibility of the most charming companionships that the
                            mind of man can imagine.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Helps, Arthur" TEIform="persName"/>Arthur Helps</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Of such is the kingdom of Heaven" TEIform="index"/>OF SUCH IS THE KINGDOM OF HEAVEN</head><p TEIform="p">Words, O, how full of meaning, uttered by lips so mild, revealing a pure undefiled heaven to
                            man ! Not the heaven the haughty priesthood preach of, in fanes where the wealthy and
                            fashionable meet one day in seven. Those devotees of fashion, may proudly kneel in cushioned
                            pews — read from gilded books long liturgies—but, their practices are such, as tend to
                            impoverish the nation, and foster crime. Their church steeples may point heavenward ; but,
                            while their church communicants, are so fraught with avarice, and have so little
                            righteousness that they will not feed the poor with bread ; God's Angels will not recognize
                            them ; their heaven is too gross. God will not own a hireling priesthood who are pampered
                            with every rare luxury,while the orphan, and widow, hardly obtain scanty fare. There is no
                            such enslavement for the meek and lowly born, in the heavenly city, whose streets are paved
                            with gold. Truth's grand fruition, that will bring to earth the heavenly prize, will be a
                            baptism which will sweep away all priestly superstition, and establish brotherhood. If earth
                            shall ever roses bear, Where thorns are wont to grow, The idlers must do their share Of
                            labor here below. Come, come ye Angel forces, From your Eden realms above ; And dry up sin's
                            foul sources, By the reign of Peace and love. From the upper spheres of Wisdom, Come spirits
                            pure and bright, To herald in a kingdom, To bless the world with light. Bright vision, when
                            we see thee come, All souls shall childlike be ; And earth shall be the happy home Of
                            Christ's community.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Crittenden, S." TEIform="persName"/>S. Crittenden, New Haven</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Richter's dream" TEIform="index"/>RICHTER'S DREAM</head><p TEIform="p">I DO not know that I can conclude this number better than by quoting Richter's dream, in
                            which he shows the feebleness of man's imagination in the presence of the infinite wonders
                            of the universe. It is translated by De Quincey : " God called up from dreams a man into the
                            vestibule of Heaven," saying, "Come thou hither and see the glories of My Kingdom," and to
                            the angels that stood around His throne He said: " Take him! Strip from him his robes of
                            flesh, cleanse his vision, and put a new breath into his nostrils; only touch not with any
                            change his human heart, the heart that weeps and trembles." It was done, and with a mighty
                            angel for his guide the man stood ready for his infinite voyage; and from the terraces of
                            Heaven, without sound or farewell, on a sudden they swept into infinite space. Sometimes,
                            with the solemn flight of angel wings, they passed through the horrors of darkness, through
                            wildernesses of death that divide the worlds of life; sometimes, they passed over thresholds
                            that were quickening under prophetic motions from God; then, from beyond distances that are
                            counted only in Heaven, light dawned as through a shapeless film; by unutterable pace they
                            passed a light — a light, by unutterable pace passed them. In a moment the blaze of suns was
                            upon them — in a moment the rush of planets was around them. Then came eternities of
                            twilight that revealed, but were not revealed. On the right hand and on the left towered
                            gigantic constellations, that by self-repetitions and answers from afar; that by
                            counter-positions, built up triumphal gateways whose archways, whose architraves,
                            horizontal, upright, raised and rose at altitude of spans that seemed ghostly from
                            infinitude. Without measure were the architraves, beyond memory the gates, past number, the
                            archways. Within were stars that scaled eternities around ; above was below, and below was
                            above, to man stripped of gravitating body. Depth was swallowed up in height insur-
                            mountable; height in depth unfathomable. On a sudden, as thus they rode from infinity to
                            infinity; on a sudden, as thus they tilted over abyssmal worlds, a mighty cry arose that
                            systems more mysterious, that worlds more billowy, other lights, other depths, were coming,
                            were nearing, were at hand. Then the man sighed and stopped, shuddered and wept. His
                            overladen heart uttered itself in tears, and he said: "' Angel, I will go no farther, for
                            the spirit of man acheth with this infinity. Insufferable is the glory of God. Let me lie
                            down, and hide me in the grave from the persecution of the Infinite, for end I see there is
                            none." And from all the listening stars that shone around there issued a choral voice: " The
                            man speaks truly. End is there none, that ever yet we heard of." "End is there none?" the
                            angel solemnly demanded; "Is there indeed no end, and is this the sorrow that kills you?"
                            But no voice answered, that he might answer himself. Then the angel threw up his glorious
                            hands to the heaven of heavens, saying, " End is there none to the Universe of God! Lo!
                            also, is there no beginning!" The more and the greater are life's difficulties, the more
                            honorable it is to carry off the victory. Man may be disappointed in his greatest hopes in
                            life, without, on that account, becoming unhappy.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Offord, William" TEIform="index"/>William Offord
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Offord, William" TEIform="persName">William Offord</persName>, aged 71, Mt. Lebanon, Febru-
                                ary 11, 1874.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Williams, Matilda" TEIform="index"/>Eldress Matilda Williams
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Williams, Matilda" TEIform="persName">Eldress Matilda Williams</persName>, aged 63,
                                Watervliet, Ohio, January 29,18T4.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bundy, Elizabeth" TEIform="index"/>Elizabeth Bundy
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Bundy, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName">Elizabeth Bundy</persName>, aged 30, Pleasant Hill,
                                Ky., February, 1874.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>