<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm1710" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">23</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">17</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><date value="18871001" TEIform="date">October 1887</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">217-240</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="17" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
<pb id="p1"/>
OCTOBER.
THE
MANIFESTO.
Published by the United Societies,
"Every plant which my heavenly Father hath not pknted shall be rooted
up."- -Matt, xv., 13,
Canterbury, N. H.
1887.

<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
The Gospel Testimony, No. 19.
Kespect Yourself,
True Love,                - -
Theology,              ...
Universal Love,
A Star from Heaven,
Storm at Sea,                                 Battles of Shaking-,
An Exemplary Life,
Letter- -H. Wormhout
Living Faith,             Notes- -The Teacher,
Pork as Food,
Farewell Meetings,
Wonderful Miracles,
Music- -Sweet Peace,
Crown of Creation,
Truth,
Ninety Barrels a day,
Kind Words,
Books & Papers,        Salvation Army,
The Old Story,
Deaths,                 ...
217
219
223
225
22S
230
232
233
234
236
237
23&
239
240
NEW HOME SEWING MACHINE C. ORANGE.MASS:
CHICAGO _ 30 UNION SQUARE.N.Y-   DALLAS,

Send     10 cents
and    receive   &
CHEAP Reading.
back numbers of THE HOME COMPANION, no two alike, filled with good
reading  for  all homes.           Address,
The Home Companion.
Troy, N. H.
SHORT HINTS
- - - - -ON- - - -SOCIAL ETIQUETTE,
Compiled from the latest and best worfcs
on the subject by "Aunt Matilda.'"
PBICE, 40 cents.
 book should be in every
 family desirous of knowing "the proper thing to do.'7
We all desire to behave properly and to know what is the best
school of manners. What shall
we teach our children, that they
may go out into the world well
bred men and women?
"SHORT HINTS" contains
the answer and will be mailed
to any address, postage prepaid on receipt of price.
SPECIAL
Until further notice we will
mail each of our friends a copy
of the above valuable book
gratis and free of postage, if
they will mail us 15 wrappers
of Dobbins' Electric Soap.
By folding up the wrappers
as you would a newspaper, the
postage will only be 2cts.
Always put your full name
and address on the out side of
the bundle and write the word
"Etiquette" also, and then we
will know who sends it.
I. L. CRAGIN & Co.,
PHILADELPHIA,
<pb n="" id="p"/>
Vol. XVII.
OCTOBER,  1887.
No.  10. --><pb n="217" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the elders, William Lee and James Whittaker no. 19" TEIform="index"/> The Gospel Testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the Elders, William Lee and James Whittaker.
                            No. 19.</head><p TEIform="p"> Published expressly for the several Communities of Believers in 1816. Re-written by Henry C.
                            Blinn. General Instruction for Believers. Mother Ann often renewed the promises of God and
                            of Jesus Christ, to those who were faithful to take up their crosses against the sins of the
                            world. She often said, "Fear not little flock, for it is your Heavenly Father's good
                            pleasure to give you the kingdom." If you are faithful to take up your crosses against all
                            that ii evil and follow Christ in the regeneration, you will receive an hundred fold now .in
                            time, houses and lands, Brethren and Sisters, Fathers and Mothers and children, and in the
                            world to come, eternal life. Blessed shalt thou be when thou comest in, and blessed shalt
                            thou "be when thou goest out." Blessed shall be ttoy basket and thy store. To a company of
                            young Believers she said:- -You should love one another, and never have one hard or unkind
                            feeling toward any one. You should live together every day, as though it was the last day
                            you should live in this world. Never forget one another, and never forget that you have been
                            blest with a privilege among Believers. On your return home be diligent with your hands, for
                            godliness does not lead to idleness. When you are at work, doing your duty in the gift of
                            God, the wicked one can have no power over you, because there is no room for temptation.
                            "Children should obey their parents, for this is right." You should come to the requirement
                            of the law. Christ did not come to destroy the law, but to fulfill it, and you should do the
                            same. Arm yourselves with meekness and patience. If you improve in one talent, God will give
                            you more. Be obedient. This is the way to find salvation. I have taught you the way of God ;
                            you must keep it. I am but one, I do ray work and you must do your work. When I have
                            finished my work I can help you no more. I wish you knew your day and privilege. You have a
                            privilege that many souls have desired and could not obtain. If you take up your crosses
                            while you have power to please yourselves, you offer to God the first fruits. Such souls
                                will<pb n="218" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> receive that honor and crown of glory which other souls can
                            never obtain. All souls will have a privilege of this gospel, either in this world or in the
                            world of spirits. You have your day now ; you can travel out of your loss by obedience, by
                            taking up the same cross that Jesus took up. Those who bear the cross in this life, and
                            faithfully endure to the end, will be brighter and more glorious than the angels. They will
                            be kings and priests unto God. Mother and the Elders always manifested great care and
                            interest for the children and youth, and often counseled the parents conceraing their
                            children. They took pleasure in speaking to the children of Believers, and teaching them to
                            be obedient to their parents. Little children are nearer to the kingdom of God than those
                            more advanced in years. Jesus took little children in his arms and blessed them and said,
                            .Suffer little children to come unto me, and forbid them not, for of such is the kingdom of
                            heaven. Little children are simple and innocent and should be brought up in that manner. If
                            they were brought up to be simple and obedient, they would receive good as easily as they
                            would evil. God created the soul pure and iunocent, and when souls shall be redeemed from
                            their loss, they will be restored to God and will be pure and innocent. Little children were
                            instructed to kneel and to pray before partaking of their meals. Keep your children neat and
                            clean, and they will be blest with the gifts of God. Never call them bad names. Let your
                            conversation before them be as becomes godliness. You should not talk about that which will
                            excite their minds to evil. Set before them a godly example, as becomes the gospel of
                            Christ. In the condemnation of sin, Mother Ann exercised a remarkable power, while at the
                            same time great charity was manifested toward those poor souls who were blinded by the sins
                            of the world. At times her spirit seemed like flames of fire, and her words penetrated to
                            the heart. hove God, love the way of God: love the gospel. God feeds the hungry with good
                            things, but the rich he sends away empty. If you are not fed, it is wherein you do not
                            hunger and thirst after righteousness. Those who do shall be filled. You may be deceived as
                            others have been. They think they have enough, and so do you, and at the same time you have
                            no victory over sin. Two of the Brethren were unjustly accused and wronged by a merchant of
                            Albany, and they threatened to prosecute him. Mother Ann said to them. You should not touch
                            the law. He that takes the sword shall perish by the sword. If you take the law you will
                            lose the gift of God. Trust in God. What! build the things that God will destroy? Woe to the
                            lawyers ! They take away the key of knowledge. Trust in God; He will deliver his people. Go
                            in faith and God will deliver you. Bear this in mind.- -The law shall go forth from Zion and
                            the word of the Lord from Jerusalem. Trust ia that law and God will deliver you. All have
                            the nature of sin. AH are lost in that nature which was received from your fore-fathers. You
                            were born in it; have been brought up in it and still persist to bring up your children in
                            it. Your teachers never taught you a<pb n="219" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> better way. They taught you as
                            they lived. I know there are souls here that will receive the gospel. Now it is presented to
                            you, and if you obey it, and take up your crosses against all sin you will find a victory.
                            You ought to let your light shine that others may see your good works, your faith and
                            repentance, that they may take knowledge of the way of God. To a company that came from a
                            great distance. Mother Ann said, Why do you come from such a distance, spending your time
                            and money, to see me while you judge me in your hearts as no better than a witch? You that
                            are guilty of this, should come forward and humbly confess it to God. Three of the company
                            came forward and confessed that they were guilty of the charge. You are required to go and
                            keep the way of God, and not return to your former sins. The labors of the people of God
                            will not be lost, but will be a savor of life unto life or of death unto death to all souls.
                            Will you stand by me and be a witness for God? Let the word of God take deep root within.
                            Plough up the fallow ground of the heart. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Respect yourself" TEIform="index"/>RESPECT YOURSELF.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fitts, Ednah E." TEIform="persName"/>EDNAH E. FITTS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> In the words spoken or the acts performed, "Let not thy left hand know what thy right hand
                            doeth." Jesus understood the natural inclination to covet the approval or shun the censure
                            of friends, or even foes, who may witness our conduct. Opinion is not a safe criterion by
                            which to decide the right and wrong in our lives. Is not every person blest with reason, a
                            responsible being and as such will he not alone become answerable for his righteousness or
                            unrighteousness? An eye-witness may sanction, may even applaud our deeds, but the question
                            is ; Can we respect ourselves in the motive which prompts the action ? Respect Yourself. We
                            consider these two words as the key to an honorable, Christian life. Every child or youth
                            who can be impressed or persuaded to adopt them as their guides in all the walks and talks
                            of immature years, will lay a sure foundation for a virtuous life. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True love" TEIform="index"/> TRUE LOVE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, Amelia J." TEIform="persName"/> AMELIA J. CALVER. </byline><p TEIform="p">When the sky is cloudless and we pursue our journey in sunshine, with buoyant hopes and a
                            glad heart, we sigh not though much of the love we feel from others, is manifested in a bow
                            of recognition as we pass. But when the storm beats down upon us, and blinding sleet
                            obscures the way, ah! then how our hearts long for the love which opens the door, and with a
                            hearty welcome, calls us in, to share the hospitality of the glowing fireside. Mt. Lebanon,
                            N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Treatise on theology no. 1" TEIform="index"/> A TREATISE ON THEOLOGY. No. 1.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/> F. W. EVANS. </byline><p TEIform="p">Our sources of the knowledge of gospel faith and doctrines are, first, revelation ; second,
                            the records of revelation- - the scriptures; and third, facts- -the<pb n="220" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/>
                            subject matter of revelation aud of its records. 2. Adam, when in Eden, was in the midst of
                            an external world of facts, of which he was the observer, exponent and interpreter. He also
                            soon found that he was intimately connected with an interior (or invisible) world of facts,
                            equally as real and substantial as those of the external. That interior world contained its
                            own observers and exponents of its facts. 3. These were Adam's derivative creators, and
                            interpreting agents and instructors, who revealed to him and his posterity a knowledge of
                            the facts of their world and their significance to the race of mankind upon earth. 4. Adam
                            and his immediate descendants possessed no scriptures. During the first dispensation,
                            observation and revelation were the basis of their enacted laws and of their principles of
                            action. The external and internal worlds, and man's civil and religious systems formed from,
                            and in reference to those worlds, constituted the first heaven and the first earth. 5. There
                            were fixed constitutional laws in man, and in the worlds of which he was the offspring, that
                            could not be infringed with impunity; " Dying, thou shalt begin and continue to die," was
                            the penalty of their violation. 6. The free agency of man, in either good or evil, in the
                            first dispensation, was limited to the natural and spiritual worlds in which it operated.
                            Their boundaries could not be passed by man in his normal condition. 7. An historian records
                            past facts; a prophet, future facts. The latter was thus formed : An angel from the second
                            heaven (the one above that in which the man lived) descended to and opened the interior of a
                            man or woman, and then communicated to him or her those things that already existed (in an
                            embryo state) in that heaven; which things would be incarnated on earth, in that or some
                            succeeding dispensation. 8. To the angel, such things were equally matters of fact as were
                            those recorded by the historian to man. Man, for evil, could not ascend above the stars
                            (lights,) or sons of God in his own heaven. 9. The first three heavens were the creative or
                            generative heavens, from whence the propagation aud increase of the human race primarily
                            proceeded. The rulers in those heavens had the especial charge of the process of creative
                            generation, in the order of election, or line of the Messiahs and prophets pertaining to
                            each dispensation. 10. It should be understood that the creation of man was not completed,
                            but only begun, in Adam ; and that creation continued to progress, conjoined to propagation,
                            until it culminated in the man, Jesus, and then in the woman, Ann Lee. 11. The fulness of
                            the first dispensation was attained through the line of righteous souls, ending in Abraham,
                            who walked in the truth, and possessed a heart devoted to the service of God. To him the
                            second heaven was opened ; and a messenger from thence, who had superintended Abraham's
                            creative generation (as the angel Gabriel did that of Jesus) saluted him, and became his
                            guardian spirit- -to him. God. This spirit anointed or baptized him into the second heaven ;
                            and thus Abraham became the Lord's Christ, or Messiah, of the second dispensation. And,
                                through<pb n="221" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> obedience, he began to create a new heaven and a new earth,
                            wherein dwelt the righteousness of the second dispensation. 12. The faith of Abraham
                            evidently was not in any records or Scriptures of the first dispensation. But his trust, his
                            faith and his dependence were placed primarily in the revelations to him from the second
                            heaven, through that spiritual being who had charge of him, and whom he called God. 13.
                            Moses was his descendant and successor ; and he was ministered unto from the same source,
                            and by the same spirit; he walked by the same rule and minded the same authority. His
                            quotations from and reference to Scriptures of the preceding dispensation are few indeed.
                            But the records of his own deductions and laws, drawn from the two worlds of facts, by
                            observation and revelation, (including the Scripture records) are somewhat extensive ; and
                            to them men ought to pay far more practical respect than they now do. 14. From that period,
                            those who came into the second dispensation exercised their free agency therein. They could
                            only obey the laws of the second heaven and earth, and be blessed by them; or, by violating
                            them, they could corrupt themselves. But they could not go beyond their own order, to
                            prevent or defile the third heaven ; that was beyond their reach and power, and beyond the
                            influences of the fall; and could only be entered through obedience to its truths, and by
                            fulfilling the laws of the two preceding heavens and earths. 15. Jesus came of the line of
                            the righteous of the second dispensation, as Abraham did of the first; and, like him, was
                            perfected in his order, as a natural earthly man- -the finished scholar of the Mosaic
                            schoolmaster. At his birth, he possessed a good physical organization, his creative
                            generation haviug been superinduced by the angels of the third heaven. 16. These were they
                            who, at his birth, sarig glory to God, good will peace to man. They also attended to his
                            education, from his childhood upwards ; even as did the angels of the first heavens- -Adam's
                            creators- -educate him. Yet they infringed not his free agency. At the age of thirty, he had
                            attained to the full measure of a perfect Jew; and he also became a prophet, and was
                            continually inspired by the angels of his own heaven- -the third. This prepared him to be
                            reached by an angel of the fourth heaven. 17. And when the spirit of Elias, through John the
                            Baptist, came preaching repentance unto Moses, and the people came confessing their sins
                            committed under the law and against it; which sins had excluded them from the camp, and John
                            baptized them into it again, among the rest came Jesus, to open his mind and confess to John
                            ; and John found that Jesus had kept the law as neither himself nor any of the people had
                            done. For, as no one of them could convict him of wilful sin, so neither could Joha, who
                            then affirmed that Jesus, rather than himself, was the most proper person to be priest to
                            hear confession and do the baptizing. 18. An angel from the fourth heaven immediately
                            descended upon Jesus, anointed him with the oil of gladness above his fellows, and begat him
                            into that heaven, which was a " heaven of heavens," as the great jubilee was a Sabbath of
                                Sabbaths.<pb n="222" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/>19. The first effect of the ministrations from this new
                            fountain of truth was, to teach Jesus that, inasmuch as he had hitherto kept himself from
                            all fleshly defilements, which were condemned by Moses, he must now take up his cross daily
                            against the generative life of nature itself, in even its most innocent and lamblike state.
                            He was taught that, from the beginning, it had been destined to be "slain from the
                            foundation of the world," and that, a he had been faithful in resisting the temptations
                            arising from the cravings of the fallen nature he inherited (on his mother's side) from Adam
                            (though, in the line of the Messiahs, the least perverted of the human family.) he must
                            thenceforth resist unto death the temptations, drawings and attractions of the earthly
                            generative sexual nature, which, by virtue of his manhood, he possessed, and which he had
                            inherited incorrupt on his paternal side. 20. The end- -the harvest then commenced in him ;
                            and the lust of generation would be effectually destroyed ; for the life of generation
                            itself, and the life of the generative relation of the sexes, were to be slain- -destroyed
                            and burnt up by the fire of the fourth heaven. 2.1. Jesus was the only individual in that
                            day who was begotten by a spirit of the fourth (the Christ) or resurrection heaven ; and he
                            continued his travail until he was born thereiuto ; and there he remained, isolated and
                            alone from the human race. This was that " far country" that the king, in the parable, went
                            to. This was "the heaven" which the apostle said must receive him, "until the restitution of
                            all things that God had spoken by the mouth of all his holy prophets since the world began
                            ;" that is until the second appearing of Christ: which of necessity must be the time of the
                            begetting (and travail for the new birth) of a female, as this alone would prepare a
                            helpmeet, a bride, that the marriage ol the Lamb might be consummated. 22. This female the
                            earth produced under the action and guidance of the same third-heaven angels that brought
                            forth Jesus. They now operated, not upon the physical elements merely, as in the ease of
                            Jesus, but upon the moral, the intellectual and the spiritual; and in an especial manner in
                            the line of the witnesses. The Jews betrothed children as soon as they were born ; but
                            marriage itself was not consummated until the parties were of suitable age. 24. One
                            important principle of interpreting Scripture is this : Those travailing in the third
                            dispensation, and heaven and earth, which are still generative, could not know or see, or
                            even prophecy, except "only in part," of the things pertaining to the fourth dispensation
                            audits heaven. 25. The duality of God ; the existence, nature and duality of Christ; the
                            plurality of churches, and of Holy Spirits- -the anointing- -from them ; together with the
                            all-important subject of a spiritual pareutage, and the begetting and travail towards the
                            new birth into the fourth heaven, or resurrection state, were to the apostles, and all other
                            Jewish Christians, as to Nicodemus, an incomprehensible mystery, which they, as
                            Christianized, generative men and women, could not understand ; as by themselves was fully
                            and freely acknowledged, saying, "It doth not yet pppear what we shall be. "</p></div2><pb n="223" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Universal love" TEIform="index"/> UNIVERSAL LOVE.</head><p TEIform="p"> O God, my God, thy love for me Is love for all humanity. Without respect, thy tender care Is
                            for thy children everywhere; And as we grow in godly grace, All that is thine we too
                            embrace, And like the Savior in His call, Show love and kindness unto all. Canterbury, N. H.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/> M. W. </byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There fell a star from heaven" TEIform="index"/>THERE FELL A STAR FROM HEAVEN
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, J. L. D." TEIform="persName"/>J. L. D. SMITH.
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> I saw a falling star Shoot
                                    downward from the sky- - The heavenly glories far- - The gleaming radiance die. A
                                    starry path of light, A darkened way before, Down sinking in the night- - Its time
                                    of beauty o'er! Alas ! for falling star, Light fading on its track; No glory from
                                    afar Will call the wanderer back. I saw a human soul Made in God's image bright,
                                    Spurning his wise control, Turn downward from the light. It missed the golden gate ;
                                    It did not run its race; Yet, groping now, too late, Its pathway would retrace. Alas
                                    ! for human soul, Were not a Helper given, The while the ages roll, To lead thee
                                    back to heaven ! </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Storm at sea" TEIform="index"/>THE STORM AT SEA
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M'Carrell, Carrie V." TEIform="persName"/>CARRIE V. M'CARRELL
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Dark is the night o'er Galilee- - A night
                                    of storms upon the sea- - Lone in their boat the Master's band " Toil hard in rowing
                                    to the land. " He lingers praying on the height. No earthly succor find they near;
                                    The strong arms lose their sturdy might, The strong hearts sink in helpless fear;
                                    Then from white lips a prayer is pressed, There is a calm- -the storm's at rest- -
                                    And walking o'er the angry wave, The Master cometh- -them to save. Beyond thy shore,
                                    0 Galilee, Still shines that pathway o'er the sea; Storm-beaten, faint and sunk in
                                    fear, We call and find the Savior near- - Yet walking o'er the angry wave, While
                                    grief and doubt our weak hearts fill Yet reaching out His arm to save, Yet softly
                                    calling, " Peace, be still. " </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="The Catholic" TEIform="index"/> The Catholic.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Battles of shaking no. 1" TEIform="index"/> "BATTLES OF SHAKING." No. 1.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>ALONZO G. HOLLISTER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Jesus foretold that immediately preceding "the sign of the Son of man, coming in the clouds
                            of heaven, (these clouds being religious assemblies of people,) that the powers of the
                            heavens would be shaken. What are these "- -powers" but the traditionated doctrines and
                            systems of religion in which men for many generations, have been taught to place their hope
                            and trust for future happiness? Systems whose false foundations of arbitrary and partial
                            election, vicarious atonement, imputed righteousness, and justification by faith without
                            works, doctrines prove them to be of the class to which Jesus referred when he said "lie
                            that heareth these savings cf mine and doeth them not, shall be likened to a foolish man who
                            built his house upon the sand. And when the winds (of the spirit) blew, and the rains (of
                            truth) descended, and the floods (of Divine light) beat against that house, it fell," Matt,
                            vii., 26, because of its false and treacherous foundation, and a superstructure of like
                                ma-<pb n="224" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> terial, cemented with sin. Rev. xviii., 5. It was a mighty
                            revolution or shaking which began with the preaching of Jesus Christ, and after abolishing
                            the Jewish ritual and national polity, continued to the overthrow of the powers and
                            institutions of heathendom in Europe, and also in large parts of Asia and Africa. But then
                            the mountains and islands of human power and defense, were only moved out of their places as
                            foretold in Rev. vi., 12-14. The power of Imperial Rome was divided, ravaged, and overturned
                            by hordes of barbarians. Heathen rites and customs were labeled Christian, and the
                            conquerors after joining the church, compelled their brother barbarians to profess the same,
                            or peril their lives by refusing. Heretics, who stocd for freedom of conscience, were
                            destroyed out of the laud as history shows, by fire and sword, or by more dreadful tortures,
                            until a corrupt church which had risen up in all the high places and defenses of the
                            displaced order, could say in its heart, " I sit as a queen, and shall never know sorrow nor
                            widowhood/' But its power was greatly shaken by that famous division called the Reformation,
                            which was a premonitory symptom of her end. " For every house and every kingdom divided
                            against itself, cannot stand, but is brought to desolation." Another shaking is foretold in
                            chap. xvi., 18, in which "Every island fled away and the mountains were not found."
                            Arbitrary governments and military defenses, all these must go. The writer of Hebrews
                            referring to the voice which shook the earth at the promulgation of the law from Sinai,
                            says, ''But now He hath promised saying, Yet once more I shake not the earth only, but also
                            heaven. This yet once mort, signifies the removing of those things that are shaken as of
                            things that are made, that the things which cannot be shaken, may remain." Behold now this
                            shaking the earth, in the shaking governments of the earthy man. In the year 1787, in which
                            the witnesses of Christ's second appearing ascended from the earthly into the communal order
                            of the heavenly societies, began the "great earthquake" Rev. xi., 13, called the French
                            Revolution which shook the nations of Europe, changed long standing customs and usages, and
                            broke the continuity of the ancient regime. In Feb. 1848, a tremor ran through the kingdoms
                            of Europe, like the shock of an earthquake. A number of ruling monarchs abdicated their
                            thrones, or fled as from an invisible avenger, to die in private life. The king of France
                            did the latter. Kingly power or autocratism has been weakening ever since, and the power ot
                            the people has been rising. And the shaking continues, uncovering the roots of despotic rule
                            in civil society by arraigning at the bar of enlightened reason, all monopolies protected by
                            human enactment, also feudal tenures of land, which have enabled the strong and scheming to
                            grasp irresponsible power, and with iron hand to lay unbearable burdens on the defenseless,
                            and to compel the sweat of the poverty stricken laborer to pile up wealth for their masters
                            to waste in luxury, extravagance, unbridled license and idle ease. These things being tested
                            in the judgment, are found wanting in all the elements which make for righteousness,
                            justice, and equity, and are utterly an-<pb n="225" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> tagonistic to harmony,
                            happiness, and the peace of the millennial reign. Near the same date, began the "Rochester
                            spirit knockings," the dawn of "modern spiritualism," which is shaking the strongholds of
                            denominational creeds and distinctions, or " powers of the heavens" in the religious world,
                            to their lowest foundations, strongly seconded by the rationalistic tendency of the human
                            mind, freed from the domination of a false ecclesiasticism. The light now coming into the
                            world through this channel is making a mighty shaking in church opinions and beliefs
                            relating to the future state, the conditions of souls hereafter, and the causes which
                            produce those conditions. The knowledge is gaining ground that life is continuous- -that for
                            the ascending, progressive soul, there is no appreciable interruption of consciousness-
                            -that the dissolution of the mortal body, introduces no one to an arbitrary and miraculous
                            change of life, nature, or disposition, let his belief be whatever it may, but that the same
                            general laws of growth and development by voluntary action, preside over the manifestations
                            of character after, as before the change to invisibility- -that the will for a season at
                            least, is as free there as here, and that changes of state are wrought by voluntary action
                            upon motives which appeal to the will or to the understanding, or to both. "Increased
                            knowledge" is proving many doctrines of the churches to be the invention of blind guides,
                            false alike to truth, to reason, and to revelation. Among these is the doctrine of no
                            repentance nor change of character by change of motives and conduct after death- -the
                            physical resurrection of the mortal body- -the miraculous transformation of sinners into
                            saints by faith without works, that sinners can be saved from the penalties of sin by giving
                            money ; or by submitting to a priest, and being sprinkled with holy water, or what is the
                            same, by joining a church and performing certain ceremonies called sacraments ; or by
                            imputing to the sinner, the good deeds of some one else ; or by anything short of genuine
                            repentance and the utter forsaking of all sinful desires and practices. What are some of the
                            things that cannot be shaken ? Ans. The absolute and immutable distinction between moral
                            good and moral evil, as pertaining to human conduct. Also Justice, Equity, Righteousness,
                            Integrity to truth and honesty, Benevolence, fair dealing, Love to God, and Fraternal
                            brother and sisterhood. These things are being established aud more and more extended,
                            notwithstanding the apparent increase of materialism, which depresses the spiritual and
                            exalts the beastly elements of human nature. Many, having discovered that much which has
                            been taught for immutable truth in the name of religion, is unworthy of credit, have lost
                            confidence in everything called religion, and have turned to war upon it, striking blindly
                            and beating the air, because they do not discriminate between the true and the false ;
                            between what is of the earth and what is of God, but exulting in their release from
                            unreasonable fears, and the restraints of discipline, they war as fiercely against "the
                            Lamb," manifest in a divine spiritualism, as against ignorance, superstition, and false
                            ecclesiasticism. Nevertheless, as "God has put it into their hearts to fulfill his will,"
                            their ha-<pb n="226" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> tred to a church which professes to be espoused to Christ
                            while really wedded to the world, and pandering to all the perverted passions and
                            propensities of the cai'nal mind, helps - -n the shaking of those things which cannot abide
                            the test of emancipated and illuminated reason. The TRUE INWARDNESS OF ALL GENUINE religion,
                            is supreme love to God, and its correlative, love to man as his offspring, the fruits of
                            which are manifest in its votaries, and need never be mistaken. Many hearts possess this
                            love in a less or greater degree, both without and within church organizations. Probably
                            there are some in e^ery denomination who are better than the system they advocate, for
                            systems accounted religious, which embrace the corrupt life and practices of the world with
                            its mixture of evil and good, do encourage the propagation of evil in the seed, on one hand,
                            while attempting od the other to hold its grosser manifestations in check. But souls
                            actuated by the love of God, will not be prevented by denominational or sectarian bias, from
                            free and friendly interchange and mutual understanding. True religion a'ppeals to the love
                            of God, or to love for the truth in which He is manifest, and to love fraternal. False
                            religion appeals to fear and says in theory and practice, if not in so many words, "Save
                            your soul from an avenging God aud from everlasting hell by joining the church and paying
                            its dues. Do not rely upon your own good works for salvation, but upon the merits, or the
                            blood of Christ. Nor think it possible to live without sin in this world ; but avo*d public
                            scandal, and condemn every one that refuses your currency. Though ';idol shepherds who feed
                            themselves and not the flock." cry "Witchcraft! Delusion! Sorcery ! Doctrine of Devils !" a
                            few earnest watchers see in the " knockings" a sign that "the marriage of the Lamb has
                            come," heaven is open to man as it never was before, and "Christ stands at the door and
                            knocks," to call souls to the feast. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Exemplary life the best preaching" TEIform="index"/> An Exemplary Life the best Preaching.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Preter, Charles Julius" TEIform="persName"/>CHARLES JULIUS PRETER. </byline><p TEIform="p"> A seemingly well to do, cultured, and intelligent man, in company with two females, visited
                            us one day, purposely to find out if the Shakers did live up to their profession of living a
                            pure and holy life. They were greatly pleased with all that they saw, and admitted, that^
                            Believers came nearer to the example and life of Jesus, than any people, sect, or
                            denomination, they knew of. They declared that they were disgusted with all the preaching in
                            the world, they did look at it as vanity, priestcraft, and folly. The gentleman of the party
                            said, "Obey the golden rule, and the two great commandments, and live up to the fifty-eighth
                            chapter of Isaiah, and you will sure and certainly be saved and kindly received into the
                            spirit spheres. This made quite a sensation in our Family, and caused us to examine those
                            texts in the Scripture by ourselves. The golden rule is, " Whatsoever ye would that men
                            should do to you, do ye even so to them, for this is the law and the prophets." Matt, vii.,
                            12. The two great commandments are, "Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart,
                            and with all thy soul, and<pb n="227" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> with all thy mind," this is the first and
                            treat commandment, and the second is like unto it, "Thou shalt love thy neighbor as thyself,
                            on these two commandments hang all the law and the prophets." Matt, xxii., 37. The
                            fifty-eighth chapter of Isaiah reads thus, "Is it such a fast that I have chosen ? a day for
                            a man to afflict his soul ? is it to bow down his head as a bulrush, and to spread sackcloth
                            and ashes under him? wilt thou call this a fast, and an acceptable day to the Lord ? Is not
                            this the fast that I have chosen? to loose the bands of wickedness, to undo the heavy
                            burdens, and to let the oppressed go free, t nd that ye break every yoke ? Is it not to deal
                            thy bread to the hungry, and that thou bring the poor that are cast out to thy house? When
                            thou seest the naked, that thou cover him, and that thou hide not thyself from thy own
                            flesh? Then shall thy light break forth as the morning, and thine health shall spring forth
                            speedily ; and thy righteousness shall go before thee; the glory of the Lord shall be thy
                            reward. Then shalt thou call and the Lord shall answer, thou shalt cry, and he shall say,
                            Here I am." In these few texts are comprehended the true meaning and purport of all the
                            scriptures. "If a man say I love God, and hateth his brother, he is a li-ir, for he that
                            loveth not his brother whom he haih seen, how can he love God whom he hath not seen ?" 1
                            John, iv., 20. And how can any one love his neighbor, or his brother as himself, except on
                            the strictest principles of equity and equality, justice and righteousness? All who
                            constitute the true church of Christ live in a community as Brethren and Sisters, where all
                            fare alike, and where those who stand in front are showing by their works, 1hat they bear
                            the greatest cross of self-denial ; Jesus said unto his disciples, "If any man will come
                            after me let him deny himself, and take up his cross, and follow me." Matt, xvi., 24.
                            Self-denial is the first thing our Savior requires, the next a cross to bear, by living a
                            pure, chaste, and holy virgin life, and then "follow me," to live just as he did. The
                            mission of Jesus was, "On earth peace, and good will toward men." Luke, ii., 14. "Blessed
                            are the peacemakers, for they shall be called the children of God." Matt, v., 9. "All they
                            that take the sword shall perish with the sword." Matt, xxvi., 52. Our Savior set us an
                            example of meekness and humility, of charity and love. "Take my yoke upon you, and learn of
                            me ; for I am meek and lowly in heart and ye shall find rest unto your souls." Matt, xi.,
                            29. "Bre'hren if a man be overtaken with a fault, ye which are spiritual, restore such an
                            one in the spirit of meekness." Gal. vi., 1. The advice given by Mother Ann was, " Never
                            speak to, or reprove any one, while under excitement or in a passion." "In meekness
                            instructing those that oppose themselves." 2 Tim. xi., 25. A good Believer will never give
                            any one a harsh or unkind word, but will remember always the advice of our Savior, "Love
                            your enemies, bless them that curse you, do good to them that hate you, and pray for them
                            which despitefully use you and persecute you, that you may be the children of your Father in
                            heaven ; for he maketh his sun to rise on the evil and the good, and sendeth rain on the
                            just and unjust." Matt, v., 44. "By this shall<pb n="228" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/>all men know that ye are
                            my disciples, if ye have love one to another." John, xiii., 35. Believers who are now
                            established more than one-hundred years io this country, have given evidence to all men,
                            that they are the children of the Prince of Peace, for they have always been opposed to all
                            wars and fightings, they would rather suffer death, than be compelled to kill, or even to
                            injure, wound, or hurt any one of their fellow men. There are but a few denominations of
                            Christians outside of our Order who follow our principles in this respect, such as the
                            Quakers, Dunkers, Menonites etc., who have our blessings and sympathies on that account. But
                            what do we behold among the rest of the self-styled Christian nations in the world,
                            Catholics, as well as Protestants? Not less than eighteen million soldiers are enrolled,
                            drilled and armed, liable to be ordered out, to butcher one another among those who call
                            themselves civilized in Europe alone aside of those in other continents and divisions of the
                            earth. A person's life is far more safe in Constautinople, Smyrna, or Cairo, than in New
                            York, Paris, or London. What awful crimes are committed to these (christian ?) cities ! Are
                            not the large Mahometan cities far ahead of them in regard to common decency and morality ?
                            There is not a single house of illfame, nor places where intoxicating drinks are sold, to be
                            found in all the moslem cities. The Turkish police would severely punish them, if such were
                            to be found. Are any so blind, as not to perceive the difference between the peaceful
                            followers of the meek and lowly Prince of Peace, and the murderous followers of Cain, who
                            are seeking to imbrue their hands in their brethren's blood? As true believers in Christ's
                            second appearing, let us give evidence to the world by our exemplary lives, by living
                            strictly chaste, righteously, godly, and soberly, by practicing every virtue, and good work,
                            to be honest, kindly treating all men, to abstain from all filthy, vicious habits,
                            intoxicating drinks, and tobacco, but above all things labor for charity, which is the bond
                            of perfection, so that those outside of our order, when they see our good works, may praise
                            God in the day of their visitation. Union Village, Ohio. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear elder Avery: I presume you received..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Dear elder Avery: I presume you received...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Holland, Schiedam, July 1887" TEIform="index"/> Schiedam, Holland, July, 1887.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Elder Avery :- -I presume you received the postal card which I sent some weeks ago, and
                            wherein I gave my consent to the publishing of the letter as you desired. I have read all
                            the books which you had the goodness to send, and I must say I can fully agree with many of
                            the views of the United Society, however strange they may appear to many "orthodox"
                            Protestants. How much more comforting is your doctrine of the Fatherhood and Motherhood of
                            God than that of most Christians ! I must confess I could never love the Calvinistic God,
                            who, "just for the fun of the thing," cau condemn millions of people to hell without even
                            giving them the chance of getting to heaven. The tenderness of a divine Mother is wanting in
                            popular theology, and I think that is the reason why, in the Roman and Greek churches such a
                            prominent place is given to the holy virgin mother of Jesus. I admire the biography of
                            Mother Ann's life very much. I have no doubt that she was a<pb n="229" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> most
                            remarkable woman, full of faith and possessing the spirit, of Christ. Yowr doctrine in
                            regard to an intermediate state after this life appears to me most reasonable and in perfect
                            agreement with the justice of God. It is an undeniable fact that all are not in this life
                            judged according to their works, therefore there must be some place where it is done. It
                            would also be the height of injustice to condemn whole nations for not believing in Christ,
                            who have never had an opportunity to hear about Him. I sappose one of the points in your
                            belief least liked by the opponents of Shakerism must be confession of sin to members of the
                            ministry. Some will say it is "popish" but if that is a valid reason, they should drop the
                            other "ordinances" as well, because they are also observed in the Roman Catholic church.
                            Others will not hear anything about human mediators between God and man. But permit me to
                            ask, why then have they ministers at all, if they can administer their own sacraments, such
                            as baptism and the Lord's Supper? And if, according to their belief, they require ordained
                            ministers to administer the said ordinances in order to obtain some spiritual grace or
                            blessing, how then can they consistently object to confession. and absolutism pronounced by
                            members of the ministry of the church. Some will say :- -You Shakers have no true ministry,
                            because not ordained by us. But do not the Greek and Roman churches say this very thing to
                            all Protestants on the face of the earth ? The resurrection of our carnal bodieis another
                            point in which I have never had a strong faith. I could never see the beauty nor the utility
                            of the dogma. I may here remark that Job xix., 26, is translated ; zal ik nit myn vleesh God
                            aanschouwen, in the I)utch- -State Bible, which is in English literally as follows : "Shall
                            I out of my flesh God behold." In regard to our Lord Jesus receiving the divine or Christ
                            spirit at his baptism, what can be more scriptural and rational ? How could Jesus receive
                            anything from God that He did not possess before, if, as the orthodox assert, He was both
                            God and man from his birth ? Jesus could not have received the Holy Spirit before his
                            baptism, at least in such a special mauner, for then there would have been nothing more to
                            add at his baptism in order to complete his divine mission. I notice from the books which
                            you sent that the worship of the United Society is entirely different from that in vogue
                            among other denominations, and that dancing forms an important part in it. It cannot be
                            denied that it has Holy Scripture in its favor, but it seems to me that if Shakers do not
                            care about what the world says iu regard to a virgin life, the intermediate state, living in
                            communities, concession of sin, they might employ other adjuncts of worship as well. I refer
                            to the use of lights, incense, special robes for the ministry during divine service,
                            flowers, etc. Not for the glory of man, but for God's praise, could you not then say with
                            the Psalmist: "I have loved O Lord the beauty of Thy house and the place where Thy glory
                            dwelleth." Because in some churches they use these things iu the service of human beings, it
                            does not follow that they are wrong, when employed for God's service only. I am glad you do
                            not make a sort of paper god out of the Bible. I don't be-<pb n="230" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> lieve aa
                            open Bible only, is a salve for every religious or moral wound. What authority have those
                            for their opinion who say we are not to believe anything unless it is foun d in so many
                            words between the covers of the book, and why are we to believe that God confines Himself to
                            this book only. The Bible is a book of historical events, more especially of God's people or
                            church, and since they have not ceased to exist, it seems to me the Bible will not be
                            complete until the last of God's people have been received into heaven. Therefore I see no
                            reason why the life and revelations of Mother Ann Lee and her companions should not form as
                            much a part of the New Testament, as the history of our Lord Jesus Christ and his immediate
                            followers. There are many other points to which I could have referred, but it would make my
                            letter too long. Neither have I mentioned any texts of Holy Scripture which go to prove your
                            faith, since they are better known to you than to me. I hope, dear Elder, I have made myself
                            understood, for I am but a sorry scribe. My letters are generally few and far between.
                            Permit me again to express my thanks for your kindness, and I remain, with my best wishes
                            faithfully and most respectfully yours, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wormhout, H." TEIform="persName"/>H. Wormhout.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Living faith" TEIform="index"/> LIVING FAITH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/> CATHARINE ALLEN.</byline><p TEIform="p"> " As the ancients of the city pass away, Who will keep the testimony burning bright? Who
                            will hold the Virgin Standard snowy white Like the saints who've gone before us in our day?"
                            It seems to me there has never been a time in the history of Believers, when these weighty
                            questions should have recurred so often for serious consideration, as during the past few
                            years, when, through all the Societies, from Maine to Kentucky, the Reaper of souls has
                            removed from our ranks so many of the brave and true, who have borne a heavy burden amid the
                            noonday heat of Zion's trial, and on her watch-towers have faithfully kept their vigils
                            through the weary hours of night, when in the guise of pretended progress, the enemy has
                            sought entrance at every gate, to under miue the beautiful temple, whose corner stone is
                            Virgin Purity. All of those who first embraced the Gospel have long since been gathered
                            home, and those who received the flame of the testimony immediately from them are following
                            in quick succession. Still we are blest with a faithful remnant, whose lives are a glory on
                            the earth, and a continual song of praise to God ; and they look to those whom they have
                            nurtured with the milk of the Word, to gather and perpetuate with increase, that living
                            testimony of truth, which has been to them nearer and dearer than life itself. The present
                            depletion of our ranks is not the least cause of discouragement, fear or doubt, to those
                            whose faith is rooted in eternal principles, and in that gift of divine revelation in which
                            this Gospel was established, and in which alone it can be maintained. It certainly is not
                            the product of human wisdom, and neither can human agency subvert or destroy it. That power
                            which creates is able to sustain. Never shall those flames of truth be extinguished, which
                            have been kindled in the hearts of humanity, by those burning coals God drops from his
                            altars above. God has always had his witnesses;- -a peculiar people,<pb n="231" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/>
                            separate from the world, who have in their day and dispensation been as a type or
                            foreshadowing of the Kingdom of Heaven. With the founding of the American Government, and
                            correlated thereto, was established the " Shaker " Order,- -the Millennial Church, the
                            beginning of the kt new earth and new heaven." Both these civil and religious systems were
                            in advance of any that had preceded them and as good as the people were then prepared to
                            accept; and although not in themselves perfect, yet they comprehended those principles of
                            eternal progress, which if left free to adapt themselves to the ever expanding needs of
                            humanity, will render them acceptable, and equal to the demands and highest aspirations of
                            future ages. Herein is grounded our faith and hope ; and here rests our responsibility ;
                            that while we look well to our foundations, and keep every stone iu place that has been iaid
                            by our predecessors, we must reach forward for their ministrations, a new influx from the
                            Christ heavens whose baptisms shall enable us to carry forward the work which they so nobly
                            began. An olden prophet spake of a time wheb " the light of the sun shall be seven-fold as
                            the light of seven days, in the day that the Lord bindeth up the breach of his people, and
                            healeth the stroke of their wounds,"- -a beautiful type of the consummation of the Gospel
                            work, when the "' seven seals" shall have been opened and the 'b seven thunders" shall have
                            uttered their voices, through those by whom progressive degrees of truth shall be revealed.
                            Those echoings that have come down to us through the long corridors of time, speak not only
                            of geological epochs, or of the successive changes through which all human organizations,
                            politically and socially considered have passed ; but they teach us that above and
                            encircling all, are spiritual cycles, which are marked by the onward course of that orb of
                            celestial radiance which has ever operated on mankind to develop and uplift. These cycles
                            have their seasons whicli follow each other successively, as those of earth ; and as surely
                            as the gushing life of Spring, and the golden wealth of harvests are wrapped in the cold
                            bosom of Wiuter, so during the long period of spiritual inertia that has brooded over
                            humanity, vital forces have been concentrating, which ere long will burst forth over a more
                            enlightened and progressed people than have ever before been the subjects of a deep
                            religious revival, the ripest fruit of which will be reaped from the earth, and gathered
                            into spiritual communities of the resurrection life. The intelligences of the spirit world
                            have been acting as missionaries upou the inhabitants of earth to prepare them therefore,
                            and I really believe that as those pass from us who have been faithful in the work of their
                            day, that instead of leaving Ziou weaker, her strength is increased thereby. They still
                            live, and, united to stroug ministers, return and seek to inspire those who inherit the
                            fruition of their labors, with fuller consecration and devotion to the Cause, and to bestow
                            that power of deep conviction for sin, which shall prepare us for a permaneut increase. Let
                            us welcome the lightning's flash, and the voice of a Second Thunder now rolling th;ough the
                            Heavens. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sorrow has its useful lessons" TEIform="index"/>Sorrow has its useful lessons
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Sorrow has its useful lessons.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., A. I." TEIform="persName"/>- -A. I. B.</byline></div2><pb n="232" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES. </head><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> THE MANIFESTO. OCTOBER, OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published at Shaker
                                Village Mer. Co., N. H. All articles for publication should be addressed to Henry C.
                                Blinn, and all letters on financial business to A. Y. Cochran. TERMS. One copy per year,
                                postage paid, " " six months, " Send for specimen copy, free. .75 .40 </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Teacher" TEIform="index"/> THE TEACHER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Whatever else may be brought forward as a religious subject upon which to write or to
                                speak, men have never gone beyond the plain and simple expressions that were uttered by
                                the voice of Jesus. He may have been learned or unlearned, he may have been thoroughly
                                acquainted with the devious ways of man, or he may have been ignorant of some of the
                                lowest strata of society. Whatever may have been his position in the world, he was
                                emphatically the friend of poor men, and his words and the influence of his spiritual
                                life has remained with them more fully than with any other class. From the Edenic age to
                                the present, the life of man has claimed more or less attention. Teachers of all kinds
                                hava each in their turn exercised a moulding influence, and consequently man's journey
                                has been as varied as are the figures in the kaleidoscope. That, however, which
                                interests us the most, at this time, is his moral education, and on this subject the
                                Bible affords us much satisfactory information. The Mosaic institution was of great
                                value to man. It obliged him to learn lessons of morality and to practice a commendable
                                degree of self-denial. His food and clothes came under the direction of the law. Indeed,
                                the food of man has always been a subject of discussion and at times, has taken
                                precedence of all others. It has been accepted by many that in the diviue plan it was to
                                be of the fruits of the earth. The controversy has led to states of mind that has
                                brought forth hatred, jealousy, evil speaking, bloodshed and war. Whether right or wrong
                                in this, there is one thing quite certain, man as found to-day, is a variable creature
                                and accommodates himself to the surroundings in a most wonderful manner. His long march
                                of thousands of years, has been one of singular interest in which may be found almost
                                every shade of humanity, and equally as well every shade of religious belief that could
                                originate in the mind. From among the multitude of nations has arisen the Hebrew, and
                                that nation has published a higher code of morality than the others, has sung more
                                beautiful songs, and has left on record a class of writings that after these thousands
                                of years has a world-wide circulation. Out of this nation has arisen a man, a teacher of
                                righteousness, a son of God. Obscure in his parentage, he followed the trade of a
                                carpenter with his father till he had reached the age when a Jew was permitted, by the
                                law, to act as a public teacher. His mission was that of repentance and a preparation
                                for the kingdom of G-od. Those who had sinned against the law 1887.<pb n="233" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> which God gave for the protection of man were exhorted to repent acd make due
                                confession of their wrongs, while all who had walked in crooked ways were urged to make
                                strait paths for their Lord, and for themselves. Through his influence, as a friend to
                                the poor, and as a good physician to the afflicted, several persons accepted him as a
                                Divine Teacher, who had brought to them, "Glad Tidings." The gospel of "good news" was
                                one of wonderful simplicity. Every thing that he said was within the comprehension of a
                                child. Live peacefully with each other, said he, that you may be called the children of
                                God. Be anxious to do right that other people by seeing your good works may learn of you
                                to love God. Jesus taught a great many useful lessons by the flowers of the field, the
                                birds of the air and by the noticing of little children. To follow the great Teacher of
                                .righteousness, we have only to live in peace, keep the heart pure, and - -,|ir life
                                unspotted from the world. He wrote mo creed, established no system of theology and was
                                not a founder of any dogmatic constraint upon the mind. The kingdom of God was a theme
                                upon which he constantly dwelt. " Thy kingdom come," was his prayerful petition and it
                                was to come in the hearts of his faithful followers. In obedience to his commandments
                                they were to receive this great, good and heavenly kingdom. It was not to come to them
                                by personal observation but by living as he lived, meek, merciful, pure in heart, and by
                                hungering and thirsting after righteousness. This state forms the church of God as
                                described by the Apostle,- -a glorious church, not having spot or wrinkle or any such
                                thing, but it should be holy and without blemish. Eph. v., 27. That such a harmonized
                                and purified company of the sons and daughters of Adam, may even at some future day be
                                found in the service of God, worshiping in the beauty of holiness and spiritually
                                bearing xhe beautiful name of sons and daughters of God, is one of the encouraging
                                promises that enlivens our joy and makes us strong and determined to bear more
                                faithfully the cross of Christ, and to say our last farewell to the relations of the
                                world. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary. </head><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pork as food" TEIform="index"/>PORK AS FOOD
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> The Two Parasitic Evils Developed in the Tissues op Hogs. The
                                        prejudice against the flesh of swine as human food is as old as history. If it
                                        has any foundation in nature besides the filthy manner in which the hog is
                                        generally kept, it is because the hog is more subject to disease, or at least to
                                        a certain class of diseases, than other domestic animals. Its omnivorous
                                        appetite makes it liable to certain diseases from which the exclusively
                                        vegetable-eating animals are comparatively, if not entirely, exempt. The two
                                        evils most complained of are tapeworm and trichina- -both parasitic. Both of
                                        these are developed in the animal tissues, and it is very doubtful if ttiey ever
                                        afflict animals that do not eat animal food, or in some way get animal products
                                        into their stomachs and intestinal canals. The tape-worm, when encysted in the
                                        tissues of the hog, has the name of measles- - though wholly unlike measles in
                                        the human species- -the pork containing these encysted worms is known as
                                        ''measly pork." When taken into the human stomach, they are liable to develop
                                        there in the form of the loath-<pb n="234" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> some creature known as
                                        tape-worm. This is not necessarily fatal, but very annoying. In modern tim^s, it
                                        is successfully removed by the skillful physician without pain or injury to the
                                        patient. Trichina is a parasite much more to be dreaded even than the tape-worm.
                                        It is liable to infect the human system in such numbers as not only to be very
                                        painful, but fatal, and we believe there is no known remedy. It is encysted in
                                        the flesh of the animal, in a dormant state, like the tapeworm. When the
                                        trichina enters the human stomach, it attaches itself to the mucous membrane and
                                        there awakens to all the activity of breeding thousands, if not millions, of its
                                        kind. These young trichina at once start out to find a place in which to encyst
                                        themselves for a dormant rest and await a resurrection by having the flesh in
                                        which they are imbedded eaten by seme animal, brute or human, when they will
                                        repeat the roll of their progenitors. It is when passing from the stomach and
                                        intestines to the muscles that the trichina give f-uch pain, and frequently
                                        cause death. Pushing their way through the tissues, they cause great irritation
                                        and inflammation, resulting in death when the effects become unendurable. While
                                        in this active state of migration, seeking a home, they are as liable to be
                                        found in one class of tissues as in another. Hence, lard that has not been
                                        exposed to a heat of at least 212 degrees Fahrenheit, is just as likely to
                                        contain them, if the animal was killed when the trichina were in a state of
                                        activity, as in any other part or product of the hog. The only way to avoid the
                                        evil and suffering from tape-worms and trichina is to either wholly abstain from
                                        eating pork, or to be sure that it is thoroughly cooked so as to destroy the
                                        vitality of the encysted parasite. The muscle of the hog makes exceedingly
                                        palatable food, and many enjoy eating the fat. In spite of all the terrors and
                                        drawbacks, pork is a common and popular article of food. So long as animal flesh
                                        continues to be eaten by man, we presume pork will be eaten. As there is no cure
                                        for one of the diseases imparted by it, the safety of the public health demands
                                        that hogs be kept in a cleanly manner, fed only vegetable food and such animal
                                        products as belong to the dairy, and that the meat- -of all kinds, as for that
                                        matter- -shall be sufficiently cooked to destroy all animal life. Nothing less
                                        than subjecting every particle of it to a heat of at least 212 degrees will do
                                        it.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="National livestock journal" TEIform="index"/>National Live-Stock Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dr. Peebles and elder Evans in Glasgow" TEIform="index"/> DR. PEEBLES AND ELDER EVANS IN
                            GLASGOW. Farewell Meetings.</head><p TEIform="p"> We have had quite a time of rejoicing in Glasgow, having been privileged to see much of
                            those estimable men, Dr. Peebles and Elder Evans. It is not necessary that we agree
                            intellectually on all points to appreciate their moral and spiritual worth. Had we as a body
                            been at one with Shakerism we could not have loved the Elder more than we did. More than one
                            felt that here was not only a moral force, but a man of ideas, and so we have all been
                            stirred in a measure by the sweet simplicity, the naturalness and purity of the man.
                            Altogether a striking figure is Elder Frederick with his large fund of common sense,
                            throwing light on ancient errors, thrashing the absurdities of the churches, and trying to
                            work out the problem of a community in which righteousness will reign. To get at the better
                            way is the object and aim of all re^rmers, and the Shakers are surely entitled to the credit
                            of doing something to help the world to get at a higher truth than has yet been reached.
                            Hepworth Dixon, in his "New America," published over twenty years since, seemed to be much
                            attracted to Elder Frederick and the people. "The people," he says, "are like their village
                            ; soft in speech, demure in bearing, gentle in face ; a people seeming to be at peace not
                            only with themselves but with nature and with heaven." And again, "after spending a few days
                            among them, seeing them at their meals, and at their prayers, in their private amusements,
                            and in their household work, I found myself thinking that if any chance were to throw me
                            down, and I were sick in spirit, broken in health, there would be few female faces next
                            after my own wife and kin that would be pleasanter to see about my bed. Life appears to move
                            on Mount Lebanon in an easy kind of rhythm; order, tern-<pb n="235" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> perance,
                            frugality, worship, everyone seems busy, everyone tranquil." We may not comprehend Shaker
                            theology, cannot make much out of the Second Advent, some of us may not be so certain of the
                            first advent, but we can admit to the full that it is a sweet picture, which not only
                            Hepworth Dixon but so many other workers have drawn of their life, in marked contrast to
                            what is got out of the gas-lighted and gas-inspiring Christianity we are triumphant in. John
                            Ruskm forcibly says : "You might sooner get lightning out of incense smoke than true action
                            or passion out of your modern English religion." The Shakers have undoubtedly made a road on
                            which we can travel a long way; they have given us many lessons as to life culture, given us
                            many seeds of future life for our little garden. Men might go leagues to listen to such a
                            man as Elder Evans, and come back well paid. One feels that the realization of heaven on
                            eartli looks a bit nearer than ever it did before, and that it does not belong to dreamland,
                            but is practical and present. " Measured against the millions of Christian people in the
                            United States, six or seven thousand Shakers may appear of small ac count; and this would be
                            truth if the strength of spiritual and moral forces could be told in figures, but one man
                            with ideas may be worth a parliament or armv," says Dixon. The greatest, work is one which
                            the world does not talk about, does not even see. The Shakers soar above the level of all
                            common vices and temptations, and from the height of their unselfish virtue offer to the
                            worn and wearied spirit a gift of peace and a place of rest. Dr. Peebles, by his books,
                            which like sacks of corn are carried from land to land to be sown and bear their manifold
                            fruit, was closely known to all of us. It is a great thing even once in a lifetime to come
                            into contact with such men, to be cheered and comforted in your wayfaring, and get filled
                            with new vigor and new faith. Dr. Peebles is certainly a representative man amongst
                            Spiritualists. He is read and admired in every quarter of the world, and seems to be growing
                            in the esteem of spiritual worthies. With much poetic feeling his keen eye sees mines of
                            wisdom not quarried before, and brings a power of unsummed gold to light. Called iconoclast
                            by one school of thinkers, Christian by another, he seems neither, but he is undoubtedly a
                            man whose mind and conscience, heart and soul are all well developed. The striking
                            characteristic of the man as of his books is his warm affectionate nature. The affections,
                            after all. take the lead of the spiritual powers. Men trust the heart more than the head.
                            Dr. Peebles breathes a spirit of love to all mankind, has an affection transcending family
                            and kin, which has gone beyond all private friendship, overleaped the barriers .'f land and
                            people, and got to human kind. In every man who loves a true life, the affections grow
                            continually, and a sure belief in immortality idealizes and embellishes our daily life. Born
                            to a large estate of spiritual wealth, Dr. Peebles makes the most faithful use of his
                            opportunities, and however widely we might differ from such a man, no one could call him
                            narrow-minded, sectarian or bigoted. On Sunday last our hall was open for the first time at
                            a holiday season, but the desire to hear our visitors was ?n great that we had quite large
                            audiences. Each of the speakers did real service to us, quickening the feelings, imparting
                            ideas, seeking to supply pure religion to common life At the evening meeting, Mr. J. C.
                            Macdonald, from Manchester, presided, and gave forth some pie sing thoughts previous to
                            introducing the speakers. On Thursday last a farewell soiree was held in honor of our
                            visitors, Mr. James Robertson, president, in the chair. Again wms the dry ground watered
                            with the eloquence of Dr. Peebles and the homely teachings of the elder. Dr. Peebles said
                            that the books which he had written were as nothing compared to the books which were yet in
                            his head, and which never could find full expression. The elder said his theology did not
                            recognize the Bible as the word of G' d, that Jesus was not the Christ, and that the Gcd of
                            Israel was not the God of the Universe. Songs and readings were rendered by Mr. J. Bowman,
                            Mr. E. E. Barker, Mr. John Robertson, Miss Griffin, &amp;c, while short addresses were
                            delivered by Mr. David Anderson, Mr. Gavin Findlay, Mr, John Griffin, Capt. Fash Mr. McNish,
                            &amp;c. A<pb n="236" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/>nicely bound copy of Burn's poems amongst other gifts,
                            was presented to each of the guests. It would make too long a paragraph to report all that
                            was said or done, and words would but faintly echo the sweet feeling that prevailed.
                            Everyone felt deep regret at parting with the friends, who seemed much affected at the
                            warmth of their reception. Yesterday, Friday July 22, quite a large crowd followed them on
                            board the steamer " State of Georgia," to say farewell to the kindly hearts and attractive
                            souls who had blended us together so closely. A strong wish was expressed that it might be
                            our lot to meet them yet again in the form. All were deeply moved when the time came to say
                            the last final words. When Dr. Peebles' new book on "Spiritualism, Past, Present and Future"
                            comes out, we feel that it will be brave and good, and that it will quicken the progress of
                            mankind. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Robertson, James" TEIform="persName"/>Jas. Robertson. Glasgow, July 23, 1887.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wonderful miracles at Ste. Anne de beaupre" TEIform="index"/>
                            WONDERFUL MIRACLES AT STE. ANNE DE BEAUPRE.
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Oxley, J. M." TEIform="persName"/>J. M. OXLEY.
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">  It is not my purpose to
                                    enter into any discussion as to the credibility of miracles, whether wrought at Ste.
                                    Anne de Beaupre, or by one of the innumerable host of faithhealers that nowadays
                                    would fain persuade us to throw physic and physicians to the dogs. In 1662, as Abbe
                                    Casgrain tells us, a young man named Nicolas Drouin, from the parish of Chateau
                                    Richer, who was tormented with a very grievious form of epilepsy, obtained complete
                                    and permanent relief, as the result of a nine days' mass, at Ste. Anne. Two years
                                    later, one Marguerite Bird, whose leg had been badly broken, on being carried to the
                                    sacred spot, was there made whole and strong again. Blie Godin, brought almost to
                                    the grave with an incurable dropsy, while re* ceiving the eucharist felt his
                                    sickness depar from him, and sprang up shouting, "I am healed." The following
                                    incident I have upon the testimony of one of the most intelligent and well-informed
                                    French Canadians I have ever met, who witnessed it with his own eyes, and related it
                                    to me : Three years ago a well-todo farmer, living about ten miles above Quebec, who
                                    had been dumb but not deaf, from his birth, determined to try if Ste. Anne would
                                    vouchsafe him relief. Accordingly, bare-footed, bare-headed, coatless and fasting,
                                    he walked the entire distance to her shrine. Fainting, but full of faith, he wrote
                                    out ids confession upon the slate he always carried, attended mass, received the
                                    communion, and then lay down to rest. Next morning he was one of the first at the
                                    cotrmunion service. The church was crowded with reverent worshipers. Suddenly the
                                    service was broken in upon by a strange, half-articulate shout that startled every
                                    one. All eyes were turned toward the spot whence it came, and there, with
                                    countenance whose exultant brightness transcended all expression, stood the mute, a
                                    mute no longer, giving vent to his emotions in joyful ejaculations that filled the
                                    edifice. Thenceforward he spoke freely, and, with tears streaming down his cheeks,
                                    said to my informant: "Ah, Sir, won't my boys be glad to hear my voice! " With these
                                    and a hundred like marvels to kindle and sustain their faith, one can readily
                                    conceive with what sincerity the myriad pilgrims, scorning the logic of
                                    unimpressionable rationalism, chant their canticles in honor of their patron saint. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Cosmopolitan" TEIform="index"/>In the August Cosmopolitan. </bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keep thy garments pure..." TEIform="index"/>Keep thy garments pure...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Keep thy garments pure. Weed thy own garden with diligence. Sow and cultivate for a worthy
                            harvest; that thou mayest reap with joy the fruits of thy labors.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., M. E." TEIform="persName"/>M. E. H. </byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Though the mills of God grind slowly..." TEIform="index"/>Though the mills of God grind slowly...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> "Though the mills of God grind slowly, yet they grind exceeding small; Though with patience
                            He stands waiting, with exactness grinds He all."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Von Logan" TEIform="persName"/>Von Logan.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If you will not hear reason..." TEIform="index"/>If you will not hear reason...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> If you will not hear reason she will surely rap your knuckles.</p></div2><pb n="237" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sweet peace" TEIform="index"/> SWEET PEACE.</head><p TEIform="p"> MT. LEBANON, N. Y. 1. Come sweet peace and consolation Sovereign 2. Come sweet peace, thou
                            art prevailing, Surely 3. Come sweet peace, thou God-like spirit, Thou art 4. Come sweet
                            peace and fill my bosom, Let all of eternal thou hast gained the humble meek and jarring
                            sounds be rest, Bless thy children's habitation, Come and reign among the just, palm, Bitter
                            envy, strife and railing, Flee before the peaceful Lamb, mild. Who can clearly show thy
                            merit? Thou art Heaven's lovely child, mute, Let the 01 ive spread and blossom Fill us with
                            the heav'nly fruit. Come sweet peace and march before us Bind us in thy golden chain Come
                            sweet peace and take possession, Bear the sceptre in thy hand. Come sweet peace thou art the
                            bearer Of pure love and charity Come sweet peace and banish ever, All contention, war and
                            strife, While we join the heavenly chorus "Peace on earth, good will to man." Feast the
                            nations with thy blessings Eide triumphant thro' the land. Every feature, every gesture,
                            Shows that heaven's found in thee. Join us as a band forever To the blooming tree of
                        life.</p></div2><pb n="238" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Crown of creation" TEIform="index"/>THE CROWN OF CREATION
                        </head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by Elder Chancy Dibble.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Mr. Trumbull, editor of the Sunday School Times, is one of
                                    the ablest religious writers in the country, and not at all one of the sort of men
                                    who would be inclined by nature to over-estimate the position assigned to woman in
                                    the economy of revelation. The following words from his paper, being part of a reply
                                    to a correspondent, who claims that woman is morally superior to man now, and,
                                    therefore, must have been created so, are, therefore, all the more remarkable, and
                                    will be read with special interest: Woman was the crowning act of God's creative
                                    work. It is not to be supposed that God's climax of creation was morally inferior to
                                    that which preceded the climax. Even in fallen humanity, woman's moral nature is
                                    stronger than man's ; and it is in her greater moral power that woman is still a
                                    helper to man in the direction of his chiefest need Woman is fittingly characterized
                                    by the Apostle Peter (I. Pet. iii., 7) as "the weaker vessel," but the weaker vessel
                                    can contain the larger treasure of moral power; and man is told to render honor to
                                    woman for her moral dignity. It would have been sheer folly on Satan's part to test
                                    his strength on one of feebler moral power, while one of greater moral force was
                                    left uncontaminated, and capable of resisting a similar temptation. Satan's victory
                                    would have been incomplete, if, indeed, his failure had not been wrought by his
                                    leaving the real stronghold unassailed by him. But because the conflict was a moral
                                    one, Satan made the issue at humanity's moral centre. And it required adroitness and
                                    persistency on Satan's part to carry the moral citadel. That carried, Satan's
                                    victory so far was achieved. The woman, as the moral superior, having been led
                                    astray, man, morally the weaker one, was sure to follow. It took a fallen angel's
                                    fullest strength to lead a pure woman to ruin. A fallen woman's simple invitation
                                    was sufficient for man's overthrow. He waited for no arguments to convince a
                                    reluctant will. The order of the curse seems to furnish added proof of the greater
                                    moral responsibility, through the greater moral power, of woman The heaviest curse
                                    came on the tempter, who planned the ruin of the new race. Then came the punishment
                                    of the one who ought to have resisted evil, but who yielded to it. Last of all came
                                    a milder sentence on the weaker victim of evil. Woman had not been content with her
                                    moral superiority in the human race. She had aspired to "be as God," and her sin was
                                    a result of a disobedient action in the direction of that aspiration. As a
                                    punishment, woman was put in a certain subjection to man. It is in explanation of
                                    this subjection that Paul (I. Tim. ii., 11-14) says : "For ....Adam was not beguiled
                                    [he had no struggle of temptation] but the woman being beguiled hath fallen into
                                    transgression." Poor weak Adam was an easy victim, when the support of Eve's moral
                                    force was taken away from him. She, as the moral superior, was chiefly responsible
                                    for the transgression, an.'1 must accept the larger consequences of her larger
                                    responsibility. And now, as before the fall, the woman is morally superior to man.
                                    She seems by her very natnre to be more like God than is man. She turns more readily
                                    than man toward God. And she wins man to, and inspires man in, the loving service of
                                    God. God would not be God in man's conception, if there were no suggestion of the
                                    woman nature in God. Hence it is that while God says He pities his wayward children
                                    as a human father pities his children, God goes far beyond the thought of pity, when
                                    He declares of his loving tenderness towards his penitent child, "As one whom his
                                    mother comforteth, so will I comfort you." Ay! woman was foremost in the likeness of
                                    God before sin entered into this world; and she is foremost in the likeness of God
                                    now that sin is in all the world. And as it is true that by woman sin came to the
                                    race of man, so it is true that by woman there came a Savior to the race of man. And
                                    man has reason still to honor the larger moral treasure which he sees enclosed in
                                    the weaker vessel submitted to his loving charge; reason to honor woman, as woman
                                    for what she has been, and for what she is. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="NY weekly witness" TEIform="index"/>N. Y. Weekly Witness.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="239" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth" TEIform="index"/> TRUTH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Marion" TEIform="persName"/> MARION JOHNSON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> What is truth ? This is a query which has often been propounded since the days of Pilate,
                            but to which the mass of mankind, even if they wait for an answer, which Pilate did not,
                            seem to pay very little attention to it, evidently preferring not to be aroused from the
                            slumberous apathy which enshrouds them which the truth would effectually do were its
                            enlightening rays once suffered to find a lodgment in their hearts. Truth is that divine and
                            eternal principle, originating in the realms of everlasting light, which will ever stand in
                            direct opposition to all darkness and deceit, evasion or subterfuge. Only the most open
                            candor and sincerity and ingenuousness will meet its requirements. Jesus said, *- - 1 am the
                            truth," and a careful study of his recorded life, reveals to us, that Me embodied and
                            personified all truth in his lovely character, and as such was to us a worthy pattern and
                            exemplar. Again, He promised his disciples, that He would send the Comforter to them, even
                            the spirit of truth who would lead them into all truth. They were no doubt blinded, as are
                            the masses now, by the false traditions and superstitions in which they had been educated.
                            They could not perceive the truths which He preached and lived, in their excellence and
                            purity. When their eyes were opened by the pewer of truth, they found that they had been
                            cherishing false and mistaken ' ideas which vanished before its irradiating light. Truth is
                            eternally progressive, and as we advance in our spiritual travel step - - by step nearer to
                            the great Source and I Fountain of all truth, new unfoldings and developments of this divine
                            principle are continually opening to our inner vision drawing closer and closer the line of
                            demarkation between the false and the true ; showing us in an ever increasing light, the
                            duty we owe to God and to each other. It reveals truth in its majesty, as it ever beckons us
                            on to those glorious heights whereou it sits eternally enthroned. "Ye shall know the truth
                            and the truth shall make you free ;"- -that is and must of necessity be its mission, but how
                            is this freedom to be accomplished ? As the warm and life-giving light of truth enters the
                            soul, it loosens the fetters of false reasoning and erroneous opinions which a blind bigotry
                            have forged ; vivifying the spirit into newness of life, leaving it free to soar above all
                            that would bind or limit its capacity ; bringing into subjection every lawless passion and
                            propensity of the unsubdued heart which would hinder its upward progress, and prevent it
                            from expanding and developing into all truth. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ninety barrels a day" TEIform="index"/>Ninety Barrels a Day
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> There is a distillery in Massachusetts, "the largest rum
                                    distillery in the world, " so says an eye-witness to the following account, and "
                                    the amount manufactured averages 90 barrels a day, some for home consumption, but
                                    the greater part for export to the coast of Africa. The barrels contain 43 galions,
                                    and the internal revenue tax is 90 cents per gallon- -$38.70 a barrel. For 90
                                    barrels, a day's work, the treasury of the United States is enriched $3,483, minus
                                    the cost of the services of revenue wa.tchmen. That the government shall not be
                                    defrauded a farthing of the ungodly gain, or one drop of the fire water may not be
                                    lost, government padlocks are<pb n="240" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/>placed upon the rum reservoirs,
                                    guarded and opened daily for measurement, by internal revenue officers. " Ninety
                                    barrels a day! Can any one follow one day's proceeds of this infamous business, and
                                    trace its awful cui se trailing over the homes of men? Go where it will, it goes as
                                    a eurse. And the nation's revenue stamp is but the stain of blood money.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="W. C. T. U. bulletin" TEIform="index"/>W. C T. U. Bulletin.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/> KIND WORDS. </head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The truths of our beautiful gospel..." TEIform="index"/>
                                The truths of our beautiful gospel...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Ohio, White Water" TEIform="index"/> White Water, Ohio.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> The truths of our beautiful gospel are receiving more than common attention. We send our
                                best love to all who are connected with the publishmg of our little missionary- - the
                                Manifesto.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ball, Stephen" TEIform="persName"/>Stephen Ball. </byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers
                        </head><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>Phrenological Journal and
                                Science of Health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plague and peril of monopoly" TEIform="index"/>Plague and Peril of Monopoly</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Popular religions" TEIform="index"/>Popular religions</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Grammar school" TEIform="index"/>Grammar School</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health. Sept. Contents : Count Lyof N. Tolstoi;
                                Know Thyself; Natives of North America, No. 2. A Noble English House; Reciprocal
                                Influence of Mind and Body; Centennial of the National Constitution ; A Girl's Problem;
                                Handwriting and Character ; Notes from a Teacher's Diary; A Post Fourth of July Oration;
                                Palpitation of the Heart; Health Papers, etc., etc. Fowler &amp; Wells Co. 775
                                Broadway, N. Y. Hall's Journal of Health. Sept. Contents; Amusements; 111 Health from
                                over Eating; A Natural Healer; Laws of Health; Spirit Likeness; The Spirit Form;
                                Libraries of the World; Starving the Teeth; Children and Pet Animals; Liability of
                                Physicians; Clothes that Kill; A Triumph for Pasteur; Heloise, etc., etc. Office 206
                                Broadway, N. Y. The Plague and Pebil of Monopoly. A Lecture on Labor, Laborers and
                                Employers; by Parker Pillsbury, of Concord, N. H. Price 15 cts. "Under our present
                                corruptions in the government, our heartless and hypocritical modes and forms of
                                religion and worship, and our false and foolish construction of the social order, we may
                                expect, we must see, strikes, tramps, paupers, idiots, lunatics and criminals in number
                                and character more appalling than were ever known before." The Popular Religions, and
                                what shall be instead, by Parker Pillsbury. Price 10 cts. This little work of twenty-six
                                pages, is certainly well worth the careful perusal of every one who is interested to
                                know more about the " Popular Religions" of the day. The age of the author and his many
                                years of active experience in the cause of humanity, allows him to speak with authority
                                upon this and kindred subjects. Grammar School. A Monthly Magazine of Instructive
                                Reading for Young People. The Interstate Publishing Co. 30 Franklin Street, Boston,
                                Mass. The Sept. No. of the above work has a table of Contents that would interest almost
                                any pupil. The articles are all beautifully illustrated, which adds so much more
                                pleasure to the story. Price $ 1. per yr.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Salvation army has opened a lively..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Salvation army has opened a lively...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> The "Salvation Army" has opened a lively fire against our wicked capital. The infidels
                            marched out against them with their h..l..h blasphemy, and the clergy stood afar off and
                            drew their sacerdotal robes around them, looking on with holy horror. The police prohibited
                            them marching the streets, as this is a city of order; but not mindful of opposition, they
                            continued their attack, talking to about five hundred persons every night, which is as much
                            as their present hall can accommodate. I talked with the captain, and he said that in a
                            short time they should commence at a different point, in a hall about the same size. He is
                            hopeful of gaining a glorious victory for the Lord. Though I do not agree with them as to
                            their terms of pardon, yet I devoutly wish and hope that they may do a great deal of good by
                            arousing those who feel secure in the citadel of sin. Copenhagen, July 14. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mikkelson, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. Mikkelson.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Old story" TEIform="index"/> THE OLD STORY.</head><p TEIform="p"> 'Tis the old, old story ; one man will read His lesson of toil in the sky, While another is
                            blind to the present need, But sees with the spirit's eye. [mill, You may grind their souls
                            in the seli-same You may bind them, heart and brow; But the poet will follow the rainbow
                            still, And his brother will follow the plow. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="O'Reilly, John Boyle" TEIform="persName"/>John Boyle O'Reilly.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths. </head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Champlain, Polly" TEIform="index"/>Polly Champlain</head><p TEIform="p"> Polly Champlain, at White Water, Ohio, Aug. 15, 1887. Age 90 yrs. 4 mo. and 14 A mother
                                in the gospel. Was gathered to the Society in 1823 and has ever been a faithful and
                                devoted sister.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., S." TEIform="persName"/> S. B.</byline></div3></div2><pb n="241" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><!--  
THE MANIFESTO.
Absolutory Pure.
This powder never varies. A marvel of
purity, strength and wholcsomeness. More
economical than the ordinary kinds, and
cannot be sold in competition with the multitude of low test, short weight, alum or phosphate powders. Sold only in cans. Royal
Baking Powder Co., 106 Wall-st., N. Y.
MEDAL  MACHINES.
XTSW TOSS STATS A&EICULXU2AL WOBES
1st. Premiums at all Competitive   Trials
Railway, Chain andL- -r- -rHor*- - - -*- - - - - -*era, Xlsr- -*hers and Cleaners. Thr -sli- - -r&, Shaken, Clover Unllern, Feed Cutter- -, Wheel Hone Waken, Home Pitchforks, Shingle IVlachineH. Htruw Preserving- Bye Threshers, Portaltle Mteani-Eii- -finei. Cider and Wine Mills and Presses,
JDog- and Pony Powers, Disc Harrows
A Springy Tooth   Harrow*.     " Robinson's Hay Press, of four sizes- Will
work as easy with one horse, as
others with two. Made with Steel
Gearing which can not be broken."
WHEELER & MELICK Co.,
Send stamp for Circular an 1 leport of Centennial
trial.
_____   and BOARD Guaranteed
3 i oung Men or Ladies in each  wuiitry,
and  highest commission paid (often $l-iO
a month )    WE**'   II- - - -BOK   alrei dy  on
TIDAL WAVE fTrS-PTlUr ^VTTMFT? 5.
OF;SUCCESS  ihSS    Tf w J- - JJJii J^S>
in North and South America, at the Ice-Bound
Poles, over the lands of rhcMidnight Sun, under the
Equator, through the Dark Continent, MiuougUv Old
Temples of India, in th<- Flowery Kingdoms i f China
and Japan, amid the ruins of Incas, Aztecs n '1 Zcn , within Canons, Clif Building*, mid Gardens of
the Gods, on ihe. Isles of the Sea, and in all parts of
the ^lobe. 300 engravings, L,,w Pric. (Juick Sale*.
S nd for Circular. P, W. Ziegler, & Co., 720 Chestnut St. Philadelphia) Pa,
A REAL NECESSITY.
We presume there is hardly a lady to be
found in our broad land who, if she does not
already possess a sewing machine expects
some day to become the owner of one.
But after the mind has been fully made up
to purchase one of these indispensable articles, the question arises as to what kind of a
machine to buy.
Tt should be so simply constructed that the
most inexperienced can successfully operate
it. The other points mainly to he considered, and which are the most desirable, are
durability, rapidity, capacity for work, ease
of operation, regularity of moti >n, uniformity of tension, and silence while in operation.
The "Light-Running New Home" fills
the above requirements, and is said to coinbine the good points of all sewing machines
with the addition of many new improvements and labor-saving devices.
The price is no higher than that of other
machines, and every lady who is the happy
possessor of one may rest assured she.has
indeed a treasure.    See advertisement.
Any person who wants paying work as local or traveling agent for warranted nursery
stock should apply at once to James E.
Whitney, Nurseryman, Rochester, N. Y.
No experience is necessary, and complete
outfit is furnished free. Steady work the
year round and all stock warranted to be in
good condition.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
HIE     M IMFt.STO.
The Cosmopolitan
The handsomest, most entertaining, low price,
illustrated family magazine in the world.
($2.50 per year, with a $2.25 premium
free.) Sixty-four beautifully printed pages in
each number, filled with short stories, sketches,
travels, adventures, bright and brief scientific
and literary articles, by distinguished American
and foreign writers, such as Julian Hawthorne,
Harriet Prescott Spofford, George Parsons
Lathrop, Louise Chandler Moulton, T. Macdonald Oxley, Ella Wheeler Wilcox, H. H.
Boyesen, Catherine Owen, Rev. R. Heber
Newton, Alphonse Daudet, Paul Heyse, Count
Tolstoi, Th. Dostoivsky, William Westall and
many others. Also entertaining JtJVElVIIjE
and invaluable HOUSEHOLD departments.
One or more illustrated articles and several fullpage engravings in every number.
A Shannon   Letter and
Bill File or a Shannon
Sheet-Music Binder
Free   to   every
Subscriber.
These premiums sell
everywhere for $2.25
each. The File is the most
perfect device ever invented for the preservation and
classification (alphabetically and according to date)
of all letters, bills, etc.
Any paper can be referred
to, taken out and put back
without disturbing the
others. With the Binder
one can insert or lake out
any piece of music without
disturbing any other sheet.
Get SAMPLE COPY at NEWS STAND or
send 20 Cents to publishers.
A&ENTS WANTED. BIS COMMISSIONS PAID.
Schlicht & Field Co., Rochester, N.Y,
THE   ALTRUIST
Is a m >ntuly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, antl devoted to common property,
united labor, Community homes, and equal
rig'its to nil. It i* published by the Mutual
Aid C immunity, whose members all live sind
work together, and hold all their property in
common, all the men and women having
equal rights in electing officers and deciding
all business affairs by their majority vote50 cents a year; specimen copy free. Address A. Longley, Editor, 213 N. 8th st.,
St. Louis, Mo.
MAYNARD & NOYES,
MANUFACTURERS   OF
SLACK WRITING INK.
Boston Mass.
The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy, devoted to a correct method of living and a scientific and successful system of treating the
sick without the use of drugs. The number
bef ;re us is full of good and wise sayings
and must be a welcome messenger in the
homes where it is sent. Persons not particularly find of taking drugs will be much interested in learning how to heal the sick by
the aid of nature's law. Dr. T. V. Gifford,
Kokomo, Ind.
Messenger of Peace.
This is one among a goodly list of papers,
thnt is always a welcome Messenger It is
published by the "Peace Association of
Friends in'America." Whatever maybe said
in justification of the Biblical history of war, it
is quite too late, at this date, to attempt to
harmonize the teachings of the Lord Jesus,
with the barbarous deeds that are committed
by contending armies. The Messenger inculcates a peaceful spirit, and teaches that the
tini^ is coming when the nations shall learn
war no more. It is published at New Vienna
Ohio, at fifty cents per year.
After Forty years'
experience in th- -
preparation of more
than One Hundred
Thousand applications for patents in
the United States und Foreign countries, the publishers of the Scientific
American continue to act as solicitors
for patents, caveats, trade-marks, copy- -mh^bh rights, etc., for the United States, and
to obtain patents in Canada, England, France,
Germany, and all other countries Their experience is unequaled and their facilities are unsur- -
passed.
Drawings and specifications prepared and filed
in the Patent Office on short notice. Terms very
reasonable. No charge for examination of models
or drawings    Advice by mail free
Patents obtained through Munn&Co.arenoticed
Jnthe SCIENTIFIC AJttERICAN, which has
the largest circulation and is the most influential
newspaper of its kind published in the world.
The advantages of such a notice every patentee
understands.
This large and splendidly illustrated newspaper
is published WEEKLiY at $3.00 a year, and is
admitted to be the best paper devoted to science,
mechanics, inventions, engineering works, and
other departments of industrial progress, published in any country. It contains the names of
all patentees and title of every invention patented
each week. Try it four months for one dollar.
Sold by all newsdealers.
If you have an invention to patent write t*
Munn & Co., publishers of Scientific American,
861 Broadway, New York.
Handbook about patents mailed free.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
 --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>