<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2701" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">27</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18970101" TEIform="date">January 1897</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-16</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="27" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                    <pb id="p1"/>
    				<div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]<pb id="p2"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    <pb n="1" id="p3"/>
                    <div2 type=
                        <p>THE MANIFESTO PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. VOL. XXVII. Blessed is he that cometh in the name of the
                            Lord."—St. Luke,"—xiii., 35. East Canterbury, N. H., 1897.</p>
                    </div2>
                    <pb n="2" id="p4"/>
--><pb n="3" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="January" TEIform="index"/>JANUARY</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Martha J. Anderson</byline><p TEIform="p">Out of the tempest, storm and sleet, Comes the New Year calm and sweet; With crystal air, and
                            sky so blue, And mountain tipped with golden hue; For the sun has bared his gleaming breast,
                            Like a shining shield o'er the hills' white crest; And the virgin snow, like a quiet shroud,
                            Outvies the white-winged fleeting cloud, As o'er the earth like a mantle spread It covers
                            the germs of the sleeping dead. Ah! spring will reveal the life it holds, 'Neath the
                            sparkling sneet of its many folds; And the cloud that floats in the azure sky Will empty its
                            blessing by and by. But the day moves on so calm and still, There is scarcely a sound from
                            vale or hill, Save the crack of the teamster's whip I hear As the woodman's loaded sled
                            draws near ; Or lowing of cattle housed and warm, Far better sheltered from cold and storm
                            Than many of earth's dejected poor Who ask for succor without our door. JANUARY, 1897. <pb n="4" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. This day's delights my heart beguiles, With its outer
                            glow and its inner smiles ; For home abounds with blessings meet, For thankful heart or
                            wayward feet. And just as the placid day declines, Full many a thought my soul defines, And
                            many a new resolve is made To turn from paths where feet have strayed, And walk in the ways
                            of love and peace, That life may be blest in the year's increase. Then the seasons all will
                            hallowed be, As the holy bond of unity Binds heart to heart with friendship warm, That lives
                            through sunshine, cold and storm; That bears through trials, doubts and fears, And
                            strengthens with increasing years. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Less are blest of the better" TEIform="index"/>THE LESS ARE BLEST OF THE BETTER</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>Oliver C. Hampton</byline><p TEIform="p">THE great law running through the universe, by which the Less (or weaker and less
                            experienced,) are blest of the Better (or stronger, and more experienced;) and which
                            comprehends in its restful embrace the vast and sublime Order of Parent-hood, seems to me to
                            contain the surest foundation for the salvation of all souls. Viewing it in this way, I am
                            resolved to stand on this foundation and practically look to the same, for my peace and
                            well-being here and hereafter. Even supposing I may reach a period hereafter in my
                            experience, wherein I shall feel the direct force of no lawexternal to myself; still I shall
                            know that through the power of an intangible attraction, of this same great law, I am calmly
                            and securely held in its preserving embrace. Tho I walk through the valley of the shadow of
                            death, I will fear no evil; for thy rod and thy staff, (my Father and my Mother—the Paternal
                            Parent-hood,) they comfort me. This spiritual law, incarnated in Jesus and Ann, descends to
                            any and all their followers, who are, or may be at any time called to care for, and watch
                            over in a parental capacity, the members of Christ's Body, the Church of his establishing
                            long ago, so that the sublime scripture prophecy sung by the rapt Isaiah in the days of
                            yore, is literally fulfilled to all intents and purposes viz., and a man shall be as an
                            hiding place from the wind, and a covert from the tempest; as rivers of water in a dry
                            place, as the shadow of a great rock in a weary land. I believe that the theory above
                            indicated, is the process of evolution, by 4 <pb n="5" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 5 which man
                            is brought into the spiritual or new birth; and there is no other name given under heaven,
                            whereby we may be saved. It is evident from the character of the Apostolic Church that this
                            is the process Jesus resorted to in its formation and establishment. And being bound up in
                            the same bundle of life, why should not we thus help one another to the blessings of Eternal
                            life ? It is foolish for any to hope to enter Heaven alone, leaving his fellow beings behind
                            for he shall never attain to perfect felicity while one individual remains outside. This
                            entire independence of one man above another, is nothing but egotistic nonsense. Suppose
                            there was no other individual on the earth but himself? Where then would his enjoyment of
                            existence come from? Where would his thousand blessings, both temporal and spiritual come
                            from ? Where then would sympathy with his sorrows and agonies come from? Alas! They would
                            come from where? Man would be but a lonely iceberg, careering through the Arctic solitudes
                            of his own hideous selfishness. The constant cry of these enlightened spiritual and
                            metaphysical reformers is, "You must not depend on anything but your own majestic self, and
                            the infinitesimal portion of the Eternal God that is incarnated in you." There is surely no
                            principle of organization in this theory—no plan whereby the talents of each may be made to
                            accrue to the greatest blessing and advantage of all. It is foolishness to say, that an
                            individual out from under the control of his natural parents, is therefore literally
                            independent of any of his fellow beings ; directly or remotely;—for the government of his
                            country immediately fathers and mothers him. And the great Father and Mother of universal
                            goodness is back of the government. And as I am convinced, that it is through the
                            instrumentality of this great principle of organization, that we are to reach the highest
                            states of happiness and perfection:—and as I am convinced that this actually is the great
                            wheel of all evolution ; I am resolved to live thereby, and go on from degree to degree,
                            until I reach the haven of eternal rest. Union Village, O.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Remarks of Mother Lucy Wright, no. 4" TEIform="index"/>REMARKS OF MOTHER LUCY WRIGHT. NO. 4</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wright, Lucy" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">OUR union is our strength. We can not find protection without keeping a gospel union with the
                            church of Christ. Faithfulness in every temporal and spiritual duty will hold us in gospel
                            union. It would be better to suffer a great deal of inconvenience, than to have disunion.
                            When I received the gospel call, I received faith and knew that I had walked in forbidden
                            paths. I had no spiritual goodness to recommend me, <pb n="6" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 6 THE MANIFESTO. and
                            I was led to confess my sins to God; and I did it of choice. I esteemed my call too great to
                            live in the ways of evil. I was young, at that time, but I have traveled from degree to
                            degree, till I now claim the relationship of a good Believer. You have often heard of the
                            vineyard of Christ, and every good Believer has a part in this vineyard. Indeed, every one
                            has a vineyard of his own to keep in order. All noxious weeds must be destroyed, that the
                            good plants may be protected. I pray that all may be faithful in this spiritual work and not
                            allow anything to pass unfmisht. Remember the honest-hearted and obedient will receive a
                            full blessing. Mother Lucy seemed to be imprest that these would be her last words to the
                            Believers in Lebanon, and as she closed her remarks, extended to them a special blessing. On
                            January 10, 1821, she returned to the Society at Watervliet, where she remained till her
                            death. Mother Lucy still lives, and her testimony in favor of gospel union, and for
                            righteousness and peace can never die away. Mother Lucy exercised great love in her
                            ministrations and spoke so simply that even the children could understand her words. At one
                            time Mother remarked,—"Remember that heaven is order, and that order is heavenly. Our orders
                            are our walls of defense, and our gospel protection. I am thankful for my faith, as faith is
                            a gift of God. Keep your faith ; keep your union. It is more valuable than all earthly
                            things. We should be very careful how we speak to each other. Speak kindly and lovingly, in
                            the simplicity of the gospel, and neither give nor take offense." The End.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine, November 1896" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me. Nov. 1896</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Henry;—I write to tell you of my visit to Alfred in the days of Indian
                                Summer, from the 24th to the 31st of October. By the Portland and Rochester train we
                                were brought directly over land in plain sight of the village, around the east side of
                                the beautiful Massabesic Lake, to Alfred Corner, two miles from our destination. Here we
                                were met by Br. Frank Libby and Eldresses Harriet Goodwin and Eliza R. Smith, with a
                                carriage to take us home. It was a lovely ride along the lake-side; the autumnal foliage
                                decking the forests as far as the eye could see, amid slight zephyrs, the thought of
                                which was just sufficient to fan away all earthly cares. In the society of those we
                                love, how quickly time passes. We soon arrived at the Office. Here we find Sister
                                Lucinda Taylor waiting to receive us, and by her kindness, and that of those with her,
                                all our needs were anticipated and ministered unto. <pb n="7" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 7
                                And now a thought of the sudden change—a week in which to rest from the cares and
                                burdens incident to the home life that, during the past season, from the rush of
                                business, was almost overpowering. Instead of caring for others all are striving to care
                                for you. Upon the Sabbath we met for divine service. Prominent in the assembly were our
                                venerable Elders, Joshua Bussell and Hiram Tarbox, in spirit firm as the hills, bearing
                                the same testimony that we have often heard from them in the days that are past, both
                                here and in our home at New Gloucester. Beloved and consecrated ones, your spiritual
                                children will reap in joy what you have sown in tears. I can not tell you of all the
                                joys of those days, for space will not permit, but I will speak of the willow trees that
                                I went to see one afternoon. They grew by the side of the old road over which Father
                                James Whittaker came when he visited Alfred in the year 1785. He, and the Elders with
                                him, stuck the withes that they had driven their horses with, into the ground. They took
                                root and grew to be these great trees, nearly three feet in diameter. The one that
                                Father James set has fallen, and from the side of the trunk three or four large willows
                                are growing. These will be succeeded by others. The root will not die out, and as the
                                willow trees grow on and on, the seeds of eternal truth which Father James planted in
                                this place will also grow. Those principles will never die. These were my thoughts as I
                                stood upon the log of the fallen willow on that lovely afternoon. In the cemetery we saw
                                the names of the fathers and mothers who gave themselves with all they had, to found
                                this home for those who would follow in their footsteps and live the high and pure life
                                required of the sons and daughters of God. The final consecration was made when the
                                Society was" organized in the year 1793. Here they spent the remainder of their lives,
                                living together as brothers and sisters, sharing equally in every temporal blessing. I
                                noticed the names John Barnes, Elisha Pote, Rebecca Hodgdon and many others. Names to be
                                remembered in all coming time by those who tread the strait and narrow path which they
                                marked out. Their lives were not in vain. "The stone that smote the image became a great
                                mountain and filled the whole earth." I returned to my home at Sabbathday Lake, on
                                Saturday, the 31st. Elder Henry Green, of the Alfred Society, came also and we had the
                                blessing of his presence over the Sabbath, and a number of days following. The young
                                receive encouragement and the weak in faith are strengthened by his steadfast spirit. .
                                As I have in mind, at this time, the home at Alfred, "Beautiful for situation," and also
                                the home at Sabbathday Lake, I exclaim, with the Prophet, "How goodly are thy tents, O
                                Jacob, and thy tabernacles, O Israel! As the valleys are they spread forth, as gardens
                                by the river's side, as the trees of lignaloes which the Lord hath planted, and as cedar
                                trees beside the waters."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mace, Aurelia G." TEIform="persName"/>Aurelia G. Mace</byline></div3></div2><pb n="8" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Chapter on life-boats" TEIform="index"/>A CHAPTER ON LIFE-BOATS</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Baxter, George" TEIform="persName"/>George Baxter</byline><p TEIform="p">UPON the intellectual sea of life, there floats more than three hundred and fifty life-boats,
                            or in other words, denominations of religionists, each claiming to be able to "rescue the
                            perishing." To go aboard each craft, and learn the means by which they expect to reach their
                            highest ideal of righteousness, would be extremely interesting to the seeker after
                            knowledge. By a close inspection of one of these Life-boats we find the inscription, "The
                            Mormon Boat of Safety." Studying its theology, we learn that one Joseph Smith unearthed
                            golden tablets, upon which he claimed were written the "Laws of God." Many accepted these as
                            their guide upon the sea of life. With "church before state," and "extreme exclusiveness
                            from the world," for several years the Mormon Life-boat floated along serenely. Accumulating
                            wealth and many members, these were added to its goodly crew, but after a season, a
                            whirlpool of moral indignation swept over it, and cleansed it from the mire of greed and
                            sensuality, with which it had become tarnished. Mormonism, to-day, floats a more respectable
                            boat, by having come in collision with purer forces. So much for the "oars of endeavor," the
                            moral energy, which remains active, until the cargo of error, of injustice and inequality is
                            thrown overboard. Many of these life-boats are of magnificent structure, inviting the
                            respect and admiration of both he old and the young. Among these we find the "Spiritualist's
                            Boat," made of the strong timbers of truth. Intercommunion of the two worlds, which
                            interlacement of union has helped to lessen the power of creeds and dogmas of the dark ages.
                            This enlightenment, descended upon the Spiritualists, by means of an older life-boat, known
                            as the "Shaker-order." This boat was nearly eighteen hundred years in being constructed, so
                            vast was the bulk of truth with which it was freighted; It now floats upon the ocean of
                            life, casting out its lines of salvation to all souls tossing upon the crest of the sea,
                            while the Captain joyously sings,— "When God is for us, what the storm! What power his law
                            withstands? It is trusting in these laws that inspires the soul with courage to toil on, and
                            weary not in well-doing. Many of us know what it has cost us to become, and remain, what we
                            are. Yet a little while, and through the mists of enshrouding darkness has gleamed the stars
                            of bright promise and waking gladness, thus anchoring our faith still firmer in the grand
                            truth,— "Tho frail the barque, and fierce the gale, Unseen, the Pilot's hand, Yet, as thy
                            day, so comes thy strength To reach the promised land." <pb n="9" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                            . 9 Well may every soul who has reached this "promised land' of spiritual and moral
                            development testify of the blessedness and soul fullness realized by coming into harmony
                            with the Captain of the life-boat, whose compass points on war i and upward toward that
                            realm where purity, love and justice rule, an I where righteousness abounds. Enfield, N.
                        11.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Source of perfection" TEIform="index"/>THE SOURCE OF PERFECTION</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Hallett, Henry" TEIform="persName"/>Henry Hallett</byline><p TEIform="p">DO we not believe that the Great God and Father of all, whose love created this humanity of
                            ours; who regards each member of this fallen race as a son ; who has implanted in the heart
                            of man his own great love of perfection, is in the tend /rest sympathy with the yearning
                            after perfection, and has come to the rescue of his fallen children? It was his will, the
                            good pleasure of his will, to bring many sons unto glory; to fulfill this desire for
                            perfection; to bestow upon each soul the gift that should enable him to attain completeness
                            in the life of the individual, and of Society, by practicing self-denial and living a life
                            of Christ. H s body, inhabited by the Eternal Spirit, that shows man where and how he may
                            attain that perfection for which he had so earnestly, so long, and so in- effectually cried
                            out and striven. And, as the Epislie to the Hebrews tells us, it is in the Sou, the perfect
                            God, and the perfect Man,—that man can only find his perfection—a perfection, inorever,
                            which, as we see it in Jesus Christ, is not only the possession of an Eternal holiness and
                            completeness as God—not a flawless, unblemisht human sinlessness, but the perfection of a
                            manhood brought to its maturity through the experience of a discipline which was learned in
                            a school of suffering. The Captain, the Author of our salvation, was made perfect through
                            suffering. As he himself more than once said,—Thus it is written, and thus it behooved the
                            Christ to suffer and to enter into his Glory. That sinless human nature of his was brought
                            to its maturity, trained to become perfect and complete in will, experience and affection by
                            enduring and submitting to all humiliation, learning obedience by the things that he
                            suffered; and so he, for himself, was perfected, rising to height after height of spiritual
                            progress in patience, meekness, submission of will, until he was crowned with all
                            perfection. This, not for himself alone, but that his followers might see their pattern,
                            might through him receive that grace and power that should bring them to the glory of
                            perfection. Is there one reader who longs for perfection and is conscious of the
                            incompleteness of human life as it is, who realizes how full the great mass of humanity is
                            of evil—physical, moral, social, spiritual—and who yearns to reach a high ideal in the home,
                            and in his own soul; who longs to stretch <pb n="10" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 10 THE MANIFESTO. out a
                            helping hand to raise others ? Let him turn away from the impotent, isolated efforts of the
                            mere natural man; from the disappointing and conflicting struggles of self-constituted
                            reformers; from the philosophies of the worldly wise, and the fantastic experiments of
                            enthusiasts, to the one divine1 ly-given means of perfection. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ministration" TEIform="index"/>MINISTRATION</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Martha J. Anderson</byline><p TEIform="p">Part of the whole I find myself to be, Living and loving for all human kind, Rising in
                            strength the lower self to bind, Heir to the hope of immortality, Glad in the truth that
                            blesses and makes free. Soul currents leap the bound of sensuous mind, Pure ministrations
                            holy service find, Unfolding life of true divinity. Yet thought vibrations on their mission
                            sent, Have power to bless or curse in their intent, Uplift, or downward draw to sin and
                            pain, Make free, or stronger hold the captive's chain. Be mine the heart where hallowed
                            thoughts shall tent, From whence sweet messages of good are sent. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">iN this number we have adopted Rule 1st of the Simplified Spelling as recommended by the
                            Philological Society of London and the American Philological Association, also by the
                            Spelling Reform Association, and as found in the Standard Dictionary. Rule 1st. Change final
                            ed to t when so pronounced as in abashed (abasht) wished (wisht) etc. Retain final ed when
                            the e affects a preceding sound.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Better to suffer wrong than to do wrong...." TEIform="index"/>"Better to suffer wrong than to do wrong....
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"Better to suffer wrong than to do wrong." Deliver my soul from hardness of heart; from
                            bitterness of feeling toward others, however wrongfully they may judge me. All judge
                            according to the evidence given and the conception taken of the evidence, and causes may be
                            obscured from the sight of individuals so that effects may not be estimated aright, but time
                            will make manifest all things, and all wrongs will be righted.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Bushnell, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>Elder Richard Bushnell</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer is a strong and loving companion..." TEIform="index"/>Prayer is a strong and loving companion...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Prayer is a strong and loving companion who guides us gently and safely up the hill-side of
                            life's troubles to the broad plateau of true pleasure at the top.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="McGinnis, W. C." TEIform="persName"/> W. C. McGinnis</byline></div2><pb n="11" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Manifesto. January, 1897. Office of Publication" TEIform="index"/>THE MANIFESTO.
                            JANUARY, 1897. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION.</head><p TEIform="p">The Manifesto is publisht by the "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month,
                            and is the only work issued regularly by the Shakes Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain
                            and simple statement of the religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of
                            righteousness. Address all communications toHenry C. Blinnn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N.
                            H. TERMS. One copy one year, postage paid. .50</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. November. Thermometer. Rain. Snow. 1895. 39.93 3.75in.
                                3in. 1896. 42.67 2.125" 4" Highest Temp, during this mo. 64. above 0. Lowest " " " " 14
                                " " Number of rainy days " " 5 " snowy " " " 2 " clear " " " 13 "cloudy" " " 10 V. G.
                                Reed. Dec. 1896. Cold weather and frost has sealed up the tilling of the soil so that
                                the major part of the work has to be done under shelter. Cutting and drawing wood for
                                fuel, and journeying to exchange goods and fruit for money are the chief requisitions
                                for out-of-door work. As Florida contains a part of our family interest and members; for
                                want of home incidents that are perfected enough to be put in print, I will supply the
                                deficiency with a sketch of proceeding in the Olive Branch Florida. Spiritually they are
                                making progress by some ingathering, and some more in anticipation. One man additional,
                                John T. Roberts. He will occupy the Peterson House and he expects quite a number to
                                follow him. There are some others in anticipation. In temporalities their success is
                                markt. They have set and are setting 63 guava bushes. 125 good peach trees. Banana
                                promising. 100 peach to set. 40 orange trees. 6 grape fruit trees. 10 Japan per- simmon.
                                Henry has set out some grape and scuppernong vines, the latter to cover an arbor 70ft.
                                long by 10ft. wide. One third acre of rice 5ft. tall. An addition has been added to the
                                house, 15x16 ft. and two stories high. The rooms are suitable for angels to dwell in.
                                "Our bouse is the color of old gold." So say they.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reed, Calvin G." TEIform="persName"/>Calvin G. Reed</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North family" TEIform="index"/>North Family</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1896. Our proud old earth has successfully wheeled itself through the zodiacal signs
                                of 1896 and does not seem to be discouraged at beginning another round. Some say that we
                                live on the outside of it, some that we live on the inside, and some that there is no
                                such thing as matter at all. However true or false these may be, the fact that we are
                                here is self-evident. The work of seed-time and harvest has been faithfully performed by
                                willing hands, and the husbandman may well look with satisfaction on the year's rich
                                store and thank God for the golden fruits, the early and the latter rain. Our apple crop
                                has been enormous; 3,000 bushels of choice pickt fruit, besides hundreds of bushels of
                                windfalls. Labor on the farm, in the shop and barn is progressing along the lines of the
                                Brethrens' necessity, and the Sisters are doing their best to keep the house in order
                                according to sisterly devotion. <pb n="12" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 12 THE MANIFESTO. On the evening
                                of Dec. 4th we had a magnificent Auioral display; at first the sky grew dull and gray,
                                then a pink glow spread over it from which issued an army of emerald flames which heaved
                                and trembled for a moment like frightened ghosts, then marcht majestically across the
                                sky to make room for others. At their approach the very stars turned pale with surprise
                                at so grand a phenomenon. That the Editor, and all the dear ones of the faith in New
                                Hampshire and everywhere that our Communal homes are establisht may have a prosperous
                                and a happy New Year, is the wish of all the members of our household, sent to you on
                                the wires of love and union.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vinneo, Cora C." TEIform="persName"/>Cora C. Vinneo</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1896. By the time these Notes appear we will have past the festive seasons of
                                Christmas and New Year. It is fitting that they should be seasons of rejoicing,
                                especially to the little folks, for the one whose name and birth we celebrate, said
                                "Suffer little children to come unto me for of such is the kingdom of heaven." Our
                                Thanksgiving Day was observed by meeting in our home chapel. The theme of the service
                                was that we realize the causes for our thanksgiving, by comparison with those who were
                                needy and in bonds, and to pray that they may also be the recipients of those blessings
                                which they need. We cast in our mite of appreciation and thankfulness to those in whose
                                care The Manifesto is placed for its excellent typographical appearance and for the
                                testimony of truth that has been manifest in its contributions. When we see the enormous
                                amount of literature that is being placed before the reading public on every subject
                                that can possibly interest them; the organizations that are supported by the free
                                contributions of members who are largely of the working class; realizing the necessity
                                of keeping before the public their manifestos, many of them publisht weekly, our prayer
                                is that our Manifesto may fulfill its mission and that it may be sustained in advocating
                                the truth of higher life. To all the readers of The Manifesto we send greetings, wishing
                                them a Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>Hamilton DeGraw</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant Hill, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hill, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1898. Beloved Gospel Kindred;—It is with kindly greetings that I go on my mission of
                                love to greet the dear friends of our Communal home. My whole soul is interested in the
                                peace and prosperity of God's people, who have consecrated their lives in honest
                                endeavor for the good of humanity. Those who follow the spirit of Christ, in making a
                                full sacrifice of all selfish relations, will be endowed with that love and charity,
                                that will go far toward the saving of the world. It is now a lovely Sabbath morning and
                                my spirit goes out to meet those dear souls, with whom it was my privilege to walk in
                                "Wisdom's ways of pleasantness," before they past on, to enter the Father's house of
                                many mansions. With what trusting love my whole life, became a part of their life, and
                                their wisdom and loving kindness inspired me with a confidence that time can never
                                change. Through faith, even at an early age, I made the gospel my choice, and became
                                fully assured that it was the power of God unto salvation. With age came experience and
                                I with many others still enjoy an unshaken faith in the fundamental principles of the
                                gospel of Christ. O that trusting love that forms a tie; Too strong to break, too pure
                                to die.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rupe, Nancy L." TEIform="persName"/>Nancy L. Rupe</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1896. A happy and a prosperous New Year to all the readers of The Manifesto. We are
                                pleased to chronicle that we had <pb n="13" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MAN1FES W. 13 the honor of
                                entertaining our esteemed fellow-laborer, Elder Calvin G. Reed, of Mt. Lebanon. He was
                                our guest for several days during the month of November and long will the occasion be
                                remembered, for like the vaulted heavens with its myriad of stars, were the discourses
                                delivered by him in our Sabbath and Thanksgiving services, rich in expression and soul
                                goodness. He went among us as a minister of light and good cheer. We have also had the
                                pleasure of entertaining several members of the Christian Endeavor Society of East
                                Lebanon, and through the kindness of our friend Mrs. Jennie Paddleford, listened to an
                                interesting report of their New Hampshire State Convention, held at Portsmouth, N. H. In
                                compliance with the Governor's suggestion, we devoted November 26th to the giving of
                                thanks for past and present blessings. In the evening we enjoyed a pleasant and
                                profitable season, in which the literary and musical ability of the younger members had
                                the effect to cheer and edify the minds of all present. Freighted with blessings has
                                been the past year, prompting us to be wisely diligent in following the example of the
                                arisen Christ, with "hands at work and hearts to God," endeavor to entwine about the
                                lives of others, laurel wreaths of love, bedewed with Heaven's spirit of purity.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Baxter, George" TEIform="persName"/>George Baxter</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury, N. H</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1896. "Time without end." There need not be so much anxiety about the time, as about
                                the use that we make of the time. Faithful in duty toward God and man, will inevitably
                                bring the reward of "Well done." We have past our "Thanksgiving;" enjoyed our religious
                                service; sat in the seat of the gastronomer and are now anticipating the coming
                                Christmas. Winter is with us but as yet, no snow and but little ice. The singing birds
                                have all gone to their southern homes, but we still have left to us the blackest of
                                Crows, the beautiful Blue Jay, the incessant chatter of a Sparrow and the social, little
                                Chickadee. For all of these we give special thanks.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Blinn</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bangor, Maine, October 4, 1896" TEIform="index"/>BANGOR, ME. OCT.4, 1896</head><p TEIform="p">Elder Henry;—With much interest I have read youf article in the Oct. Manifesto, "Life in the
                            Light." To me it has the right ring to it. How true the saying, "How very little is known
                            correctly concerning us or our Community." This is a very sad confession to make af- ter
                            being in existence for over one hundred years. It goes to show the lack of the true Christ
                            spirit and the disobedience to his injunction, "Go preach the gospel to every creature." You
                            have been praying for nearly fifty years for an increase, for a tidal wave to flow to you
                            from the outside world to fill up your scattered and broken ranks, and why has not your
                            prayer been answered? The reason is very apparent as God never helps only those that help
                            themselves. You have prayed and trusted in God to do the rest, instead of going to work to
                            have your prayers answered. Prayers amount to nothing without works, any more than faith
                            does. When all the Societies combined, go to work in earnest with all sincerity to spread
                            the gospel light of true salvation to the world, then that prophesy will come to pass, "They
                            will flow to you like doves to the windows." If each Society had done no more than I have
                            done for the last twenty years by putting their literature before the world, they would be
                            much better known to-day than they are. I have been a subscriber to your little gospel
                            messenger ever since its first issue and have bought many extras; have put a wrapper and a
                            stamp on them and on all my subscription numbers, and have sent them out to do missionary
                            work, without money or price, because I had an interest in the cause, believing it to be the
                            only true way of salvation. <pb n="14" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 14 THE MANIFESTO. If all the Societies had
                            been less absorbed in the root of all evil, and more interested in the spread of the light
                            of gospel truth, there would not be that dearth there is among them now. The only way for
                            the Shakers to be better known, is for them to flood the world with their literature without
                            money or price, "Cast thy bread upon the waters, and thou .shalt find it after many days."
                            Let all the Societies contribute what each can afford, more or less, for a missionary
                            purpose, do your part to put the gospel light before the world and leave the rest with the
                            Heavenly Host. My desire is, th it the Shakers would wake up to this most important matter
                            and go to work in real earnest. Now seems to be the time to sow the good seed. I will do
                            what little I can in my humble way to this end. Let all the true servants of the Lord, let
                            their light shine into the darkness of error. Where light penetrates, darkness disappears,
                            passes away into the eternal light. Yours Fraternally,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Emery, Simon" TEIform="persName"/>Simon Emery</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the memory of our brother William Thrasher" TEIform="index"/>To the Memory of our Brother
                            WILLIAM THRASHER</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="DeGraw, Genevieve" TEIform="persName"/>Genevieve DeGraw</byline><p TEIform="p">uAnd in every work that he began in the service of the house of God, and in the law, and in
                            the commandments, to seek his God, he did it with all his heart and prospered." —2 Chron.,
                            xxxi,, 21, And the doors of heaven swung open A soul past thro' to stay, Freed from the
                            snares and cares of earth And freed from mortal clay, And that soul found a joy holy A peace
                            which the angels know For his life was pure, good and true While he journeyed here below.
                            And the angels came down to bless him His deeds they gladly record And now they come
                            commissioned To pilot him back to his Lord. They sing him the glad song of welcome As he
                            enters the mansions above. Well done Oh! thou faithful good servant Enter thou in the joy of
                            God's love. Tis the day of thy grand coronation Go, wear the bright crown you have won, Go,
                            dwell with the ransomed in glory Rejoice now your work here is done. Rejoice and be glad it
                            is wisdom That dust unto dust must return, Unhampered the soul may the better The soul's
                            needed lessons there learn, We count it not death but awakening This wonderful transfer from
                            earth A passing from shadow to substance To treasures of immortal worth, Our life there
                            shall be restful action With friends who have gone on before Who know of that beautiful
                            country And dwell on its "Evergreen Shores." Our brother has there found a haven, A home by
                            angel hands made, In vision we clearly behold him In garments of splendor arrayed. "And thus
                            this man died leaving his death for an example of a noble courage, and a memorial of virtue,
                            not only unto young men but unto all his nation."-2 Mac, vi, 31. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The heart that is emptied of evil imaginings finds no pleasure in stirring up strife" TEIform="index"/>
                            The heart that is emptied of evil imaginings finds no pleasure in stirring up strife
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The heart that is emptied of evil imaginings finds no pleasure in stirring up strife.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thrasher, William" TEIform="index"/>William Thrasher
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Thrasher, William" TEIform="persName">William Thrasher</persName>, at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
                                Sept. 24, 1896. Age 100 years 5 months and 1 day. S. A. C.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mariner, Lydia" TEIform="index"/>Lydia Mariner
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Mariner, Lydia" TEIform="persName">Lydia Mariner</persName>, at Sabbathday Lake, Maine. Nov.
                                16, 1896. Age 83 years and 16 days. Sister Lydia has been a true and faithful member of
                                this Society from early childhood. We shall miss her kind ministrations and loving
                                words. A. G. M.</p></div3></div2><pb n="15" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books &amp; Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For peace or war--Which? " TEIform="index"/>For Peace or War—Which?
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Ellen Goodell" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">For Peace or War—Which? An address by Ellen Goodell Smith, M. D. Those who are interested
                                in the subject of "Peace on Earth," will also be interested in the perusal of this peace
                                loving address. "A thousand years hence, or less, the people of earth will look upon our
                                shafts of granite, and terrible arsenals, the torn and battered flags and war
                                equipments, battle ships and war histories and tales of Libbey and Andersonville, our
                                traffic in slaves, and Sunday School church brigades, with feelings akin to our own, as
                                we look backward upon the relics of the dark and middle ages." Publisht at Dwight, Mass.
                                Price 10 cts. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Green's Greek-English lexicon to the New Testament" TEIform="index"/>
                                Green's Greek-English Lexicon, To the New Testament
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Green's Greek-English Lexicon, To the New Testament. This is a small work of some two
                                hundred pages, and yet it contains several thousand words and may be obtained at the
                                trifling expense of thirty-five cents. The Preface to this little work is from the pen
                                of H. L. Hastings, who writes, "This Greek Concordance obviates the necessity for an
                                exhaustive citation of the passages containing any particular Greek word, and brings us
                                back to the proper sphere of a Lexicon, as a book defining the words contained in the
                                language." Publisht by H. L. Hastings, 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass. Whatever may be said
                                about the publications of Rev. Irl R. Hicks by those who do not fully understand the
                                facts, there is no denying the truth that his paper and Almanac have come to stay. His
                                splendid journal, Word and Works, is now entering its tenth year, largely increast in
                                circulation and in every way improved, until it deserves the national reputation it has
                                attained. His 1897 Almanac is now ready and is by far the finest and most beautiful he
                                has yet issued. It contains 108 pages, including cover artistically printed in colors,
                                and is filled from back to back with just what is wanted in every shop, office and home
                                in America. One feature of the Almanac for 1897 is a series of 12 original, beautifully
                                engraved star maps, with explanatory chapters, which could not be bought for less than
                                five dollars in any work on astronomy. As Mr. Hicks has so correctly and faithfully
                                warned the public of coming droughts, floods, cold waves, blizzards, tornadoes and
                                cyclones, in the years past, aside from the other varied and splendid features of his
                                paper and Almanac, these considerations alone should prompt every family to subscribe at
                                once for 1897. The Almanac is only 25 cts. a copy. Word and Works is one dollar a year,
                                and a copy of the fine Almanac goes as a premium with every yearly subscription. Write
                                to Word and Works Publishing Co. St. Louis, Mo. The twelfth annual issue of the Columbia
                                Pad Calendar has made its appearance in more pleasing form than ever before, having
                                scattered through its daily leaves many charming illustrations, with an appropriate
                                thought or verse for each day in the year. Among the topics are bicycling, outdoor lit ,
                                and good roads. The cycling fraternity, to say nothing of the general public, has
                                acquired a decidedly friendly feeling for the Columbia Calendar, and its annual advent
                                is always lookt forward to with interest mid pleasure. The 1897 calendar contains a
                                unique arrange- ment of dates that will prove very helpful and convenient to busy men,
                                and plenty of space is allowed for memoranda, so that the block may be used as a diary,
                                or in any event will become a storehouse of the many little things one desires to be
                                reminded of day by day. The twelfth edition is bright with contributions from friends
                                and riders of the Columbia bicycle, for such a host of friends has the calendar acquired
                                that it has become a custom- ary practice for wheelmen all over the country to jot down
                                their best thoughts and in- spirations after the exhilarating influence of a Columbia
                                ride and send them in to brighten the calendar's pages. In addition, the moon's phases
                                are indicated for the benefit of those who wish to know the best time for night riding.
                                One feature of the calendar is its neat stau 1, so arranged that the block can either oe
                                used upon the desk or hung upon the wall. The calendar can be obtained for five twocent
                                stamps b5' addressing the Calendar De- partment of the Pope Manufacturing Company at
                                Hartford, Conn. An even excellence makes the good things which The Ladies' Home Journal
                                promises unusually interesting and strong. The list is long and sturdy. One series of
                                papers alone would sell the magazine; that is, the three White House articles which
                                ex-l'resident Harrison is to write. No man has ever done what General Harrison will do
                                in these articles; show us what "A Day With the President at His Desk" means in one
                                article; in another tell of "The Social Life of the President," and in a third article
                                describe "Upstairs Life in the White House." Each of the articles will be profusely
                                illustrated. Another series equally fascinating is the one called "Great Personal
                                Events," in which some of the greatest enthusiasms which have occurred in America will
                                be revived; those wonljrful times when Louis Kossuth rode up Broadway ; when the young
                                Prince of Wales was here; when Jenny Lind sang in Castle Garden ; when Henry Ward
                                Beecher electrified his congregation by selling slaves in his pulpit; when Grant went
                                round the world; when Henry Clay bade farewell to the senate; when John Wesley preached
                                in Georgia, of which so few know. All these memorable events and others will be vividly
                                recalled, told more graphically than ever before, and illustrated <pb n="16" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/>
                                16 THE MANIFESTO. with pictures which have occupied twelve artiftsforoverayear. A third
                                series is unique and valu: ble from the fact that it will give women scores of ideas for
                                their homes. It will reveal what there is "Inside of a Hundred American Homes," and
                                cerefully reproduce pictures of one hundred completely-furnisht rooms in homes in this
                                country—from Maine to California—where taste has gone farther than money. Two new
                                department writers have also been exclusively engaged by the Journal; Mrs. S. T. Rorer,
                                who will hereafter have entire charge of the domestic department and give a series of
                                cooking lessons, and Dwight L. Moody, the famous evangelist, who is to put the result of
                                his life study of the Bible in a department entitled "Mr. Moody's Bible Class." The
                                artist Charles Dana Gibson, who treated the Gibson girl, will present six full page
                                pictures showing "The People of Dickens," while Alice Barber Stephens will alternate
                                with Mr. Gibson and present her idea of Six Types of American Womanhood," showing the
                                American woman in society, in religion, in business, in summer, in the home, and as a
                                mother. Mary E. Wilkins, the New England writer, will revive the old quiltingparty, the
                                ancient singing-school and the apple-paring bee in "The Pleasures of Our Neighborhood."
                                Sir Henry Irving is to tell how to study, read and present "Shakespeare in Small
                                Communities." Tosti, the song writer, will give his first piano composition. Sir Arthur
                                Sullivan is to present the first true and correct copy of "The Lost Chord" ever printed
                                in America. Reginald DeKoven, John Philip Sousa and Jakobowski (who wrote Erminie,")
                                have each written a waltz, while Ira D. Sankey has composed a hymn which he considers
                                greater than his famous "Ninety and Nine." Ian Maclaren will have a story, while Herbert
                                D. Ward's humorous serial, "The Burglar Who Moved Paradise," will run through the year,
                                followed by Hamlin Garland's new novelette, "The Spirit of Sweetwater." Jenny Lind's
                                daughter is to sketch "My Mother as I Recall Her," while George W. Smalley is to show
                                "The Personal Side of Bismarck," and "The Personal Side of the Prince of Wales" in two
                                lavishly-illustrated articles. Altogether, no magazine gives a list of attractions so
                                interesting and promising as does The Ladies' Home Journal, and certainly no periodical
                                does it, as does the Journal, for only one dollar per year. If it lias become a fad, as
                                it seems, for every girl and woman to take this magazine, it is an excellent one, and,
                                unlike many other fads, a sensible one. The Journal is publisht by The Curtis Publishing
                                Company, of Philadelphia. The Phrenological Journal and Science or Health for December,
                                opens with the Phrenological character of Horace F. Brown, of Michigan. This article is
                                prefaced with a beautiful illustration. Then follows Auntie J's story of a poor little
                                boy. Phrenotypes with mirthful illustrations, is the kind of Phrenology that interests
                                many readers. A quartette of writers by Jessie A. Fowler, illustrated with portraits of
                                Rev. John Watson, James M. Barrie, Mrs. Humphrey Ward and the late Wm. Morris. No. 5 of
                                Phrenology and Psychology by John W. Shull. Children precious and promising by Nelson
                                Sizer. This is beautifully illustrated. A large number of excellent articles beside
                                those that have been mentioned, may be found in this number of the Journal. Publisht by
                                Fowler &amp; Wells Co. 27 East 21st St. New York City. The Order of the King's
                                Daughters and Sons is described in an interesting and well illustrated article in Frank
                                Leslie's Popular Monthly for January. The author is Louise Seymour Houghton, one of the
                                leading spirits in the organization. It contains portraits of the principal officers and
                                many attractive views. Another important paper in this number is one on Bryn Mawr
                                College, by Madeline Vaughan Abbott, Secretary of that institution. It is the third
                                article of the series on "American Universities and Colleges," and is profusely
                                illustrated with interior and exterior views of the buildings. General Thomas L. Rosser
                                contributes an able article on "Personal Traits of Robert E. Lee, and there are papers
                                on "Canoeing Down the Rhine," "The Egyptian Army," "The Philippine Islands," and "Among
                                the Waikato Maoris," all spendidly illustrated. Frank Lee Farnell, the editor of the
                                magazine, writes of "Books as Christmas Presents;" there is some interesting matter
                                about plays and players; several excellent short stories are given, with an installment
                                of Edith Sessions Tupper's fascinating serial, "Father John," and the young folk's
                                department is as attractive as ever. The Record is indebted to Elder Greaves for a copy
                                of a prettily bound volume entitled Mount Lebanon Cedar Boughs, being a collection of
                                original poems written by members of the North family of Shakers. There are 315 pieces
                                in the book and their uniform technical excellence is perhaps the most striking thing
                                about them, A great many of them are carefully written sonnets, several in the
                                Shakesperian style, and there are all varieties of metres. The verses show the study of
                                good models. Very naturally most of them are of a pensive, religious character, and
                                there is scarcely a gleam of humor in any. The influence of Bryant can be traced in some
                                of the poems of nature and this excellent sonnet to his memory appears on page 274: — A
                                century's close dims not thy glorious fame, Thou loyal son of brave New England sires,
                                    <pb id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. Who at their lie-artli-stones kimllecl freedom's fires
                                \ And won by valorous deeds mi honored name A noblo lineage holds thee in claim; Thy
                                soul was cradled 'neaththese forest spires Where "God's First Temples" wakened high
                                desires, And inspiration fanned Faith's sacred flames Thy dream of youth in
                                "Thanatopsis" given Into thy closing daya its beauty wrought, And gave thee access to a
                                loftier heaven Than is by creed or cringing error brought. All honor to thy blessed
                                memory, Longlive the praise of thy sweet minstrelsy! Publisht by Peter Paul Book Co. of
                                Buffalo, N. Y. Price of book $1.00. From Berkshire Sun, Pitisfield, Mass. De. James M.
                                Peebles is now on Ms third voyage around the world. He has just past his seventy-fifth
                                birthday, and is in the enjoyment of the best of health. He says, "During this voyage we
                                shall take in Honolulu, the Feejees, New Zealand and Australia, the East Indies, Siam,
                                Malacca, Johora, Ceylon, India, Persia, Egypt, Palestine, Southern Europe, Rome andParis
                                to London." Dr. Peebles will be absent one year or more. We shall wish for him much
                                health and happiness, and a safe return to his American home.</p></div3></div2><!--
                        <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>