<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1011" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><date value="18801101" TEIform="date">November 1880</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">241-264</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> NOVEMBER, 1880. { MANIFESTO. G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, N. Y. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT
                        SHAKERS, N. Y. 'And they shall turn to you for a testimony:" "Go preach the Kingdom of God!" ADDRESS ALL
                        COMMUNICATIONS TO " The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1880. The Shaker Vol. X. No. 11. 60
                        Cents Per Annum. </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="241" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Acrostic" TEIform="index"/>AN ACROSTIC</head><byline TEIform="byline"><index level1="Alpha" TEIform="index"/>Alpha</byline><p TEIform="p">Suggested by a recent visit to the Canterbury, N. H. Society. True-hearted, zealous in the
                            right, Honestly seeking for the light. Each act a kindly deed: Seeking a crown of glory
                            rare, Holding no cross too hard to bear, Asking no easy path through life— Knowing the
                            world's a field of strife— Earning, when all of self has died, Right to come near the
                            Father's side: Such is the Shaker's creed. "Alpha," Pascoag, R. I</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ministration of light" TEIform="index"/>MINISTRATION OF LIGHT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName"/>Watson Andrews</byline><p TEIform="p">. I will sing, for my heart is joyful now, The light of the Spirit is on my brow; The portals
                            of heaven are all aglow, On the field of my inner sight. When the senses are still, all the
                            passions asleep, And the sentinel angels their vigils keep, A foretaste of heaven the soul
                            may reap, In these beautiful fields of light. How worthless, the best the world has then ;
                            How little the greatest of mortal men; How trifling earth's fashions and forms are, when
                            They're viewed from the fields of light. How precious the way that our Saviour trod ; How
                            wise and benignant the councils of God; How plain and inviting the " narrow road," That
                            leads to these fields of light. But when the gross passions assume the sway, And the fogs of
                            the senses obscure the day, How dark and forbidden appears the way That leads to these
                            fields of light. North Union, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Baptisms" TEIform="index"/>BAPTISMS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER</byline><p TEIform="p">. " I have a baptism to be baptized with ; and how I am straitened, pained, till it be
                            accomplished." Jesus saw work to be done, and was in earnest to do it. Without earnestness
                            there can be no baptism. On this solemn subject I feel straitened, lest my words should only
                            be words, and fail to incite to newness of life. The travail of spirit experienced by Jesus
                            opened up to him a number of baptisms as distinct and as well defined as are the steps on a
                            ladder. If we have no similar baptisms, we will hardly know whether we are in the path of
                            ascension or not ; and fail to feel a full releasement from the emotions, thoughts and
                            imaginations arising from our lower selfhoods. <pb n="242" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 242 THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. Of all baptisms a conviction for sin is the fundamental one. The prophet of old
                            saw their general order. First, finish binning. Secondly, put an end to its cause. Thirdly,
                            make reconciliation for iniquity. Fourthly, bring in everlasting righteousness. Fifthly,
                            anoint the most holy with power to reign over self. The first requirement, faithfully
                            fulfilled, will open to our vision our natural manner of going ; and will assure us that,
                            whatever evil any one has done, that there is a capability in us to move in the same
                            direction; and that there is no safety till we reach the spot, that, " when the prince of
                            this world cometh, he can find no place in us." Then we are in a condition to be fathers and
                            mothers to those who have gone astray, and are called from death and darkness—to feel their
                            states, and bear them out into the light of life. A renewal of baptisms and humiliations of
                            spirit can alone fit and prepare us to be mediators and redeemers. We may well rejoice and
                            be exceedingly glad, for heaven is here begun, and its light and warmth is given more
                            freely, and more assuredly, than is the natural sunshine. One of the functions of sunlight
                            is to awaken the dormant germs of vitality, and bring them forth into use, fruition and
                            beauty. Another is, to decompose dead bodies into ashes and gas. Standing squarely in the
                            light and warmth of divine sunshine, the germ of divinity within us will be quickened, and
                            the old man and woman, and their works, will be turned to ashes and buried in the graves of
                            forgetfulness. " I kill, and I make alive." In the first appearing of Christ, the Jewish
                            converts had the advantage of us—they had been to school. Moses had trained them
                            hygienically and morally ; these are the two grand divisions of human preliminary
                            experiences. In these departments there is room left for a wide increase; for hygienic and
                            moral law, covers more ground than did the Mosaic code. We are the descendants of heathen
                            ancestors, and have inherited their proclivities. " That which is bred in the bone, will
                            appear in the flesh ;" hence, if we are children of the light, we will need a baptism, not
                            only of having the " Law" written on our hearts, but of death also, to every habit contrary
                            to the fitness of things. If ever there was a baptism needed to qualify any one to fulfill
                            the duties of their day, the baptism of having the Law written on our affections is the one
                            now needed. If this is not accomplished in the body of Christ on earth, then that body will
                            not be able to meet coming events. The signs of the times require that we be thoroughly
                            equipped. Except a baptism correcting personal habits, and financial dealings be
                            accomplished, we will not be able to cast out evil spirits, whether in the body or out. The
                            question may be asked, if a baptism of newness of life has been experienced, what more is
                            needed ? This conception is suggestive of water baptism. Let us gather a little light on
                            this point. Baptisms consist essentially of earnestness of Spirit to pursue the right and to
                            shun even the appearance of evil. If there is a settling down after a movement has been
                            made, that baptism is exhausted; life that is but for a moment is not life everlasting. The
                            increase of the work of God will be by baptisms, because it is in the nature of mind to take
                            one step at a time, as in walking. " This is love that ye keep my commandments ." They who
                            confess and forsake sin, and are baptized into that love, will be saved. A state of feeling
                            neither cold nor hot is not accepted ; there can be no progress in it." " My son, give me
                            thy whole heart." " The earth shall help the woman." The progress made in total abstinence
                            from alcoholic drinks ; the establishment of institutions, curing the sick without the use
                            of drugs, by merely bringing the patient into affinity with the fitness of things ; the
                            declaration that physiological law is a unit; embracing food as well as drinks, the
                            conclusions of scientific men on the bad effects of tea and coffee, etc., fully sustain the
                            teachings of the Spirits during their special visitation over forty years ago. Their
                            feelings on the use of animal food clearly indicated the course to be pursued. Evidently it
                            was the intention of the heavens that we should have a start in keeping hygienic
                            law.—Outside of our Order a great work has been done. The old methods of treating the sick
                            are giving way before the onward move- <pb n="243" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 243 ment.
                            Even the diet of the public at large has been modified to meet the requirements of hygienic
                            light. The work of God never goes backward ; those who stand still will be passed by ;
                            non-compliance with light is negative opposition. Every increase of divine life includes
                            minor truths ; indifference to primaries will result in opposition to details. Jesus Christ
                            dwelt in the sphere of baptisms—of divine creative activities—bringing forth upon earth
                            social life as it is in the heavens. To be cold and without enthusiasm is as a machine not
                            in motion. Even in fulfilling the common duties of life energy is required as well as
                            patience. Never seek individual distinction; let it pass, for " Whoever would be high,
                            higher, highest, Must first come down to low, lower, lowest; And then ascend to high,
                            higher, highest, By keeping down at low, lower, lowest." As we advance in divine life- —
                            nearing the portals within which baptized Spirits dwell — forbear thinking we have but to
                            sit down and enjoy good company —company is best enjoyed after something has been done.
                            Faithfulness in a narrow sphere has but prepared us for the more extensive un" foldments of
                            the higher life and its duties. Jesus Christ, by the power of his baptisms, descended to the
                            Spirits in prison, bound in fetters by the habits they had formed. He came to their
                            conditions, clothed his spirit with " sweet reasonableness." " Come, let us reason sweetly
                            together," and hell will dis. appear. Sweet reasonableness improves al[ conditions, and
                            opens the way for heavenly growth and culture.</p></div2><div2 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Founder of the first community" TEIform="index"/>THE FOUNDER OF THE FIRST COMMUNITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sproat, Granville T." TEIform="persName"/>Granville T. Sproat</byline><p TEIform="p">A Brief Sketch of Pythagoras, the celebrated Grecian Philosopher. . Judging from the record
                            of ancient history, the first community was founded by Pythagoras, the celebrated Grecian
                            Philosopher, who lived some six centuries before Jesus; or two thousand, four hundred and
                            ninetyfour years ago. The place of his birth was Samos, a beautiful island in the
                            Mediteranean sea. It was the custom in those days for the people to consult the oracle or
                            prophet, at Delphi, concerning their future history, and that of their families and nation.
                            The father of Pythagoras consulted the oracle with reference to his son. The answer was this
                            : " He shall surpass, in beauty and wisdom, all that ever lived; and shall be of the
                            greatest advantage to the human race in every thing pertaining to the life of man." When
                            Pythagoras was about eighteen years old, he started for Egypt, to learn wisdom from the
                            Egyptians. A remarkable story is told of his voyage thither. He went on board a vessel bound
                            for Egypt. The crew were expecting a stormj' passage. But to their surprise, it was
                            uncommonly calm and prosperous. They had heard much of Pythagoras, and they attributed to
                            him, the remarkable weather that had blessed them on their voyage. His appearance, too, and
                            conversation, had impressed them, so that they looked upon him as a superior being. They
                            gave him a place among their Gods. They worshiped him. At the close of the voyage, they took
                            him and bore him from the vessel to the shore, and built an altar, and made an offering to
                            him of such fruits, and other precious things, as they had brought with them from their
                            Grecian home. They then left him to pursue his journey to the land of the Pharaohs.
                            Pythagoras, on his journey to Egypt, stopped at Sidon, and became acquainted with the
                            disciples of Mochus, the famous physiologist. Through their instructions he completely
                            changed his dietetic system. He would eat only vegetable food. He rejected all animal food,
                            as stimulating to the animal nature. He believed in the effect of a simple and proper
                            regimen on the development and action of the soul; of the necessity of temperance and
                            simplicity, in living to the health and purification of the spirit. " The foundation of all
                            religion and virtue," said he, "rests here;" and Pythagoras, regarding it as degrading for a
                            man of piety to live to gratify the palate, and pamper the body, employed only those
                            articles of food as had no disturbing influences on the spiritual natureBeans, though a
                            vegetable, Pythagoras re- <pb n="244" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 244 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. jected and classed
                            them, in their effects, with animal food. Pythagoras remained in Egypt twenty-two years, in
                            pursuit of divine wisdom. From thence he was taken by the soldiers of Cambyses, and carried
                            captive to Babylon. There he formed a friendship with the Magi, and received instruction in
                            the ancient learning of the Babylonians. He cultivated music*, mathematicsf, and
                            astronomy^:; and stored his mind with the wisdom of the Chaldean sages. On his return to
                            Samos, Pythagoras established his famous school, or circle, known as the " Circle of
                            Pythagoras." But the people of his native island were dull scholars in Pythagorean
                            philosophy; and he left them, and journeyed into Italy; and there formed the first community
                            of which we have any record. He had many followers, amounting it is said to six hundred, who
                            were not only excited by his discourses to the study of philosophy, but to an amicable
                            division of the goods of life in common; from whence they were called Ocenobitce (people
                            living in common). Here are some of the rules and resolutions of the community which
                            Pythagoras, at that time, established. 1. We will cut off, by all possible means, as by fire
                            and by sword, all that fosters disease in the body. 2. We will cut off all that hinders the
                            soul in its progress towards perfection. 3. We will cut off all that causes dissension and
                            disunion in the community. 4. We will never rebuke a servant in anger, or until we can do it
                            with a gentle and quiet spirit. 5. We will never return evil for evil, be* Pythagoras
                            invented an instrument to measure niusical intervals; thus using the influence of divine
                            harmony as a spiritual medium to elevate and educate the soul. + Pythagoras was the father
                            of Mathematics and Geometry; and all remember the wild delight with which he was
                            transported, on solving the problem that the square of the hypothenuse, in a right angle
                            triangle, is equal to the square of both sides. $ It is an historical fact that the
                            Copernican theory is but a revival of the system of Pythagoras, and that, so many centuries
                            before the Christian Era, he taught that the earth was round, and that the earth and planets
                            revolved around their centre sun. lievmg it to be more holy to be injured, than to injure
                            any living thing. 6. We will do all this, because it brings us into closer communion with
                            the Gods. Like the Hebrew Samson, Pythagoras would never suffer a razor to be put upon his
                            head or face. Hence he was called by many," The long haired Samaian." Of his power over the
                            brute creation, many stories, doubtless some of them myths, are told. Meeting the Daunian
                            bear that had done much injury to the inhabitants, it is said, that "having stroked it with
                            his hand a long time, he fed it with maize and acorns, and compelled it, by an oath, never
                            after to touch any living thing. The bear immediately went and hid himself in the mountain
                            and never after injured man or beast." Seeing an ox in a pasture, eating green beans, he
                            advised the herdsman to tell the ox not to eat beans. The herdsman laughed, and said "he did
                            not understand the language of oxen; if Pythagoras did, he had better speak to him."
                            Pythagoras went and whispered into the ear of the ox, and he was never known to taste of
                            beans afterward. Hence he was called the " Sacred Ox of Pythagoras." His disciples believed
                            that he had the same power, as the fabled Orpheus, over animals ; and could magnetize them
                            by the power of his voice. Of his spiritual vision many things are told. On seeing a ship at
                            sea, with a prosperous wind, he foretold its shipwreck, which actually occurred. He
                            predicted an earthquake in Sicily, which took place. Such was his power over animals that he
                            could take up any poisonous thing, and not be injured. In Tyrrinia, he took in his hands a
                            small serpent, or viper, whose bite was fatal, and received no harm. His disciples believed
                            that he had the same power as Jesus in calming the seas; and once did it, that his followers
                            might reach the shore in safety. Many other wonderful things are related of him; such as
                            being in two places, many miles apart, at the same time — his spiritual body in one of the
                            places; his physical body in the other. Like Swedenborg, and Paul, and John, he ascended
                            into the heavens, and saw and <pb n="245" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 245 heard
                            wonderful things, too great for man to utter. But it was in his divine system of philosophy,
                            that Pythagoras excelled all who had ever lived before him. " Sano mens in sano corpore "— a
                            sound mind in a sound body, was his motto. The necessity of a pure and simple diet to the
                            serenity, health, and happiness of the soul, was always faithfully inculcated by this divine
                            philosopher. "To be like the Gods, we must live like the Gods," he said ; " and avoid all
                            things that disturb the serenity of the spirit."' Such is a brief history of the great and
                            good Pythagoras, one of the most famous of the philosophers of antiquity ; who lived five
                            hundred and eighty-six years before Jesus was born. Pythagoras taught the '"music of the
                            spheres." This music of the spheres has been considered an idea altogether fanciful; but the
                            immortal Kepler applied the Pythagorean theory of numbers, and musical intervals, to the
                            distances of the planets; and a long time after, Newton discovered and acknowledged the
                            importance of the application. " The planets dance before Jehovah ; and music is the echo of
                            their motions." Canaan, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Witchcraft" TEIform="index"/>WITCHCRAFT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline><p TEIform="p">" Rebellion is as the sin of witchcraft." Under the American Government, there is no such sin
                            as witchcraft, because there is no church connected with it. In these United States,
                            Spiritualism stands upon precisely the same footing as other sects and denominations.
                            Spiritualism, operating within the jurisdiction of any religious organization that believes
                            in Spiritualism, without the consent of the organization, is witchcraft. Thus, in any
                            church, Protestant or Catholic, Spiritualism is condemned as witchcraft. Among believers,
                            Spiritualism out of order is nothing else but witchcraft, and witchcraft is rebellion
                            against the constituted church authority.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unsuspected devils" TEIform="index"/>UNSUSPECTED DEVILS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. HAMPTON</byline><p TEIform="p"> In my pilgrimage to the higher life, and especially after I had made some considerable
                            headway against my lower animal nature, and stood in a measure of peaceful victory over my
                            meaner, baser proclivities, I was amazed to find a host of other devils ready to demand my
                            allegiance, and, what was still less reassuring, I noticed that many whom I knew had
                            traveled much farther in the self-denial to the grosser qualities of our common nature than
                            I had, were still very much under the influence of lesser evils or little foxes that were
                            most ruinous to the vines in the new vineyard of the Lord. So sorrowfully prevalent did I
                            find these conditions to obtain, both in my own experience and the observations I made upon
                            others, that I gradually began to suspect that, through a kind of transmutation, we had
                            merely stopped the growth of inferior proclivities in one direction to let them crop out
                            with greater vigor in another ; and that in regard to our actual spiritual status we were to
                            some extent deceived, and were not so far along, as we had supposed, in our heavenly
                            pilgrimage. The more I examined myself, and the more I observed in others, the more I became
                            impressed that this unfortunate transmutation was a possibility — nay more, a fact. Our
                            rudimental condition seems to present so many modifications of downward tendency, and we
                            possess such a perversed and persistent disposition to allow them, and such a repugnance to
                            rising out of them, that no sdoner do we commence a war of extermination against any
                            particular adversary than we begin to cultivate a partiality for some other obscure devil we
                            had scarcely noticed before to make up for our loss. ( For many big and little devils Dangle
                            on the wicked tree (of lower Tendencies) ; And man is sunk to lower levels Than he suspects
                            himself to be." No sooner is man a little elevated above his ordinary rudimentary sins and
                            shams, than he is immediately ready to say to his <pb n="246" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 246 THE SHAKES
                            MANIFESTO. an end to all peace, and nearly a total loss to the Church at least, if not to
                            the individual of nearly all that was gained in other directions. " For, if I cannot be
                            forgiving, But must hold a hateful grudge, Against another, dead or living, My religion's
                            all a fudge. No deception can be greater, More than all things else I say ; Thus allows a
                            carnal nature, Room to work another way." " Finally, the wisdom that is from above is First
                            pure and then peaceable, Gentle and easy to be entreated ; Full of mercy and good fruits,
                            without Wrangling and without partiality." And it should be a matter of solid concern with
                            each Zion traveler that " the whole body of the sins of th# flesh be, though gradually yet
                            persistently eliminated from the character, and not that some unsuspected and utterly
                            blighting and destructive qualities be left to grow into confirmed habits, till age
                            paralyzes all the powers and energies of soul and body, and leaves us under the ine vitable
                            necessity of giving constant pain to all around us ; and finally carrying these dreadful
                            conditions with us to a world where they cannot be tolerated; but where the fearful
                            retribution of solitary confinement will hold us in its sinister grip, until ay deep
                            sufferings and repentance we have ' thoroughly purged our floors, gathered our good wheat
                            into garners, and burned up the chaff with unquenchable fire." Union Village, O.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our daily reckoning" TEIform="index"/>OUR DAILY RECKONING</head><p TEIform="p">If we sit down at set of sun, And count the things that we have done And counting find One
                            self-denying act, one word That eased the heart of him who heard, One glance most kind That
                            fell like sunshine where it went, Then we may count the day well spent. But if through all
                            the live-long day We've eased no heart by yea or nay ; If through it all We've nothing done
                            that we can trace, That brought the sunshine to a face ; No act, most small, That helped
                            some soul, and noting cost, Then count the day as worse than lost. fellow traveler a few
                            steps behind him : " Stand thou there, for I am holier than thou." Here his lower lusts are
                            being right away transmuted to selfrigMeousness; a thing he might never 'have suspected
                            himself of, while estimating himself as little better than an animal from the prevalence and
                            immanence of ;his baser proclivities. In a vast number of ways, as plainly as in that above
                            stated, is man in danger of this fatal incubus upon his spiritual energies, and the
                            self-deception of supposing himself to be in a fruitful travel, when he is only playing a
                            losing game of bo-peep with himself. " When we would walk a little straighter, And for some
                            special victory pray, We're apt to give our carnal nature, Room to work another way." Anger,
                            intemperance, impatience, unfor- ' giveness, revenge, and a thousand other • hateful
                            qualities seem to stand ready to '' claim that indulgence we fhave denied to ] " the flesh
                            with the affections and lusts." ' " But to hate the flesh and let my temper Have the upper
                            hand of me, ' Or to wear a fretful simper, ( When I ought to pleasant be ; j I must discover
                            soon or later, Think about it as I may, Only gives a carnal nature, A Room to work another
                            way." I One man I have in my mind consoled T himself under the pressure of other sacrifices
                            that, at least, " he could eat all he pleased." p " But stupid stuffing is not travel;
                            Eating, drinking to excess, Nothing better suits the devil, Than to see such work as this. "
                            Well he knows that such flesh haters, Cannot make the business pay, While they give their
                            carnal natures Room to work another way." Here follows another case of transmutation : " If
                            I cannot be obedient To the order every day, But must deem it more expedient Have the time
                            to have my way; Here I evidently falter; And in vain I preach and pray; My old nature's
                            slipped the halter, And has sloped another way." But when the metastasis presents symptons
                            of unforgiveness, and settled moroseness, then the case is lamentable, for here is</p></div2><pb n="247" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth always safe" TEIform="index"/>Truth always safe
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">TRUTH ALWAYS SAFE. Men talk of "dangerous truths," as if't Could be That truth is
                                    ever dangerous or unsafe ! 'Tis only we and our imperfect ways That are at fault.
                                    Nettles touched timorously Sting to the quick ; but grasp them with a will, And they
                                    are harmless a^ sweet beds of balm. And so with Truth approach her with distrust Or
                                    fear, she stings us with her positive, Sharp weapons, and we cry out, " We are hurt
                                    ! " But front her boldly and she harms us not ; Nay, wrestle with her, hold her till
                                    the day Breaks, and the cry bursts from our desperate lips, " I will not let thee
                                    go, except thou bless ! " And we shall know her as she is, a sweet, Strong, helpful
                                    angel, sent to us of God, And blessing ere she goes. Only half-truths Are dangerous;
                                    of them, my soul beware ! Look to it that they cheat thee not with shams, And
                                    flattering, specious forms of lower good, When the supremest good is in thy grasp,
                                    Or may be for the reaching after it.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Friend's intelligencer" TEIform="index"/>Friend's Intelligencer.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian's God and Christ" TEIform="index"/>THE CHRISTIAN'S GOD AND CHRIST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>Giles B. Avery</byline><p TEIform="p">An address Delivered at Alfred, Me., Aug., 29th, 1880, by . Laying aside the bias of Creeds,
                            the prejudices of denominational influences which divide and sub-divide society; ofttimes
                            engendering strife, contention and hatred among friends, we hope that all are met on the
                            level of love of brotherly and sisterly kindness to seek after truth, and to seek it from
                            any and every source from which we may obtain it. A Creed is not a religion! We live in an
                            age of marvelous revolutions, a time in wThich the human mind is more actively seeking after
                            truth than ever before; when all principles of philosophy, science, art and religion are
                            being canvassed as never before, in the history of our race. " Gerald Massey," the great
                            Spiritualist of our age, has truly said: " Creeds, Empires, systems, rot with age, But the
                            great people's ever youthful; And it shall write our future's page, To our humanity more
                            truthful; The gnarliest heart hath tender cords, To waken at the name of brother ; And time
                            comes, when brain scorpion words. We shall not speak to sting each other.' A writer has
                            said: " Creeds are the stones with which so called Christians build church walls of
                            separation between each other to divide the brotherhood and sisterhood of humanity and
                            engender hatred and strife." The whole world is out of the simple course of truth; as it
                            were, up side down, and we propose to commence our discourse making our initiatory text a
                            finality. " Finally, my brethren, whatsoever things are true, whatsoever 'things are honest,
                            whatsoever tilings are just, whatsoever tilings are pure, whatsoever things are lovely,
                            whatsoever things are of good report, if there be any virtue, if there be any praise, let us
                            think on these things." Phil, iv, 8th. We make our quotations from the Bible ; but we take
                            this text as authority. We live in an age when our Bible, by some classes of society, is
                            much vilified, and set at naught, ridiculed, disregarded and many of those who do so boast
                            of morality, virtue, and of their fidelity, yet perhaps many of those persons do not
                            consider how much they owe for this character to their good Christian mothers and fathers
                            who tutored their young lives and instilled therein many principles of the Christian
                            religion ! All civilized nations have their Bibles, even those whom wTe sometimes look upon
                            as heathen ; the Hindoos, and others, some of them hav«, for a Bible, fourteen or fifteen
                            volumes, either of which is larger than our great Bible. In becoming infidel to our Bible,
                            as a whole, there is a danger of becoming infidel to the truth, to God ! As we quote
                            therefrom we would here present our view of the Bible. A stranger once accosted the speaker,
                            holding up the Bible by its two covers between his fingers ; said he, " Do you not believe
                            that every syllable between these two covers is the inspired word of God ? " We replied, so
                            far from believing that every syllable between these two lids is <pb n="248" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 248
                            THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. the ward of God, we do not believe even one of its syllables is the
                            word of God! Dear friends, do not be startled! We are not infidels to God and truth nor to
                            the Bible ! This Bible tells us that " The word of God is sharp and powerful, piercing, to
                            the dividing asunder of soul and spirit, and of the joint and marrow and is a discerner, of
                            the thoughts and intents of the heart." Now do the words in this Bible do this ? We all know
                            they do not ! The word of God is an inspiration of soul life, a baptism of truth! The Bible
                            is a record, more or less faithful; some of it is a record of the word of God; some of it a
                            record of the word of holy angels : some of it a record of the words of holy men, while
                            other portions of it are a record of the evil deeds of some of the basest men the world ever
                            knew, and ought to have been burned a thousand years ago, as its influence, of these things,
                            is a false guide — a great injury to the morals and religion of the present generation. We
                            deprecate the present practice of our country, and others, of publishing all the vices and
                            crimes of society; and the devices with which much crime is committed ; it teaches the
                            rising generation how to do evil; for we are all creatures of influences, more or less
                            affected by ail we read, hear and see. Robert Owen declared man to be solely the creature of
                            circumstances, and, of course, witliout accountability ; but this is not the fact ; where
                            there is ability, there is attachable accountability, and that justly. But " We are come
                            unto Mount Zion, and unto the city of the living God." Mark this, "the living God." " Te the
                            heavenly Jerusalem, and to an innumerable company of angels ; to the general assembly and
                            church of the first born, which are enrolled in heaven, and to the spirits of just men made
                            perfect, and to Jesus, the mediator of the New Covenant, and to God, the Judge of all.''—
                            Heb., XII, 22d, 23d, 24th. Indeed, we are come to the day of judgment. The peculiar
                            characteristic of the kingdom of Christ is " the day of judgment," and the " end of the
                            world." " Now is the judgment of this world; now shall the prince of this world be cast
                            out." This was the watchword of Christ's second coming. " In this the children of God are
                            manifest, and the children of the devil; whosoever doeth not righteousness is not of God,
                            neither he that loveth not his brother." These things " are of good report, let us think on
                            these things." Our God is a living God, a God of love; but the God character manifest to
                            mankind has widely differed, in different ages; the race has been progressing in knowledge,
                            and with this progress there has been a change of the idea of God. Jesus spake many things
                            to his hearers in parables, because they were not able at that time to bear the plain truth.
                            One of these we wish here to quote : "A certain householder planted a vineyard, and set a
                            hedge about it, and digged a wine fat, and built a tower, and let it out to husbandmen, and
                            went into a far country. And when the time for fruit drew near he sent his servants that he
                            might have of the fruit of the vineyard, and the husbandmen beat his servants; and beat one,
                            killed another, and stoned another. Again lie sent other servants more than the first, and
                            they did unto them likewise ; but, last of all, he sent unto them his son, saying, " They
                            will reverence my son.'' But when the husbandmen saw the son, they said among themselves,
                            this is the heir, come, let us kill him, and let us seize on the inheritance ; and they
                            caught him, and cast him out of the vineyard, and slew him. When, therefore, the Lord of the
                            vineyard cometh, what will he do unto these husbandmen ? They say unto him, he will
                            miserably destroy those wicked men, and let out his vineyard to others, who shall render him
                            their fruits in their season. "Jesus said unto them, did you never read in the Scriptures, '
                            The stone which the builders rejected, the same is become the head of the corner ?' This is
                            the Lord's doing, and it becomes marvelous in our eyes." This parable refers to those
                            mediators, or vice-gerents of God, who, from Noah to Moses, from Moses to Christ, down
                            through the ages, have been baptized with the spirit of the Lord, to communicate to man for
                            his evolution and development o higher spheres of life. This householder is God; this Son,
                            Jesus Christ, whom the husbandmen so wickedly slew, then under;ook to seize upon the church
                            of Christ, his <pb n="249" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKES MANIFESTO. 249 vineyard, and to appropriate
                            its fruits to themselves. Now, these husbandmen — the professed Christians of the fourth
                            century, at the time of the inauguration of the Nicenian Creed— made a decree that this son
                            of God—Jesus— whom their predecessors (the wicked Jews, as they called them) slew, is very
                            God / One of a holy Trinity of Gods — consisting of the Father, Son, and Holy Ghost — three
                            male Gods in One God! and the Son as old as his Father, and older than his Mother ! What an
                            idea of God ! What a monstrosity ! What pure philosophy could conceive of such a being? Then
                            having lost the true baptism of the Holy Ghost, this fallen church substitutes for it the
                            water baptism of John's dispensation, which was simply the introduction to the baptism of
                            the Holy Spirit; and losing thereafter the spirit and life of this baptism, which required
                            the confession and repentance of sins, both physical and spiritual, they then resorted to
                            the animal blood of Jesus, and introduced a baptismal dispensation of this, for the
                            remission of sins — a baptism of blood ! the blood of Jesus, the innocent "Lamb of God." The
                            second God of their Trinity, to satisfy the revenge and vengeance of the Father God, for the
                            sins of his creature man ! Thus vesting this God with the worst of human passions. The
                            Nicenian Creed runs thus : " That Jesus died for our sins is a doctrine much to be desired,
                            and very full of comfort to the true believer." What a Father God ! How cruel ! How unjust !
                            What a base idea of God, the character of whom would be an unjust element of humanity ! But
                            Watts fitly describes it, when he characterizes it in the following verse : " Rich were, the
                            drops of Jesus' blood, that calmed his frowning face; That sprinkled o'er a burning throne,
                            and turned his wrath to grace." Of this a Shaker poet hath said, and truthfully; " Eternal
                            wisdom never planned, A heresy so dark and damned." At the same time these believers in
                            Jesus as God, and his death as necessary for man's reconciliation with the Father God, look
                            upon the Jews as wicked for killing him. A writer of the Shaker Church of our day has justly
                            remarked: " If it was God the Father's will that Jesus should be killed, that his. physical
                            blood might wash away the sins of mankind, then the Jews, instead of doing a wicked act in
                            killing Jesus, were simply doing the will of God ; and instead of being vilified, they
                            should be canonized as saints." These vicarious atonement Believers, having a bloody God, of
                            course have a bloody religion ! Like God, like priest, and like people! The poet Milton
                            fitly describes their influence thus: " The mind and conduct mutually imprint, And stamp
                            their image in each other's mint; Each sire and dam of an infernal race, Begetting and
                            conceiving all that's base. Thus men go wrong with an ingenious skill, Bend the straightway
                            to their own crooked will, And with a clear and burning lamp supplied, First put it out,
                            then, take it for a guide." Thus has the professed Christian world done relative to the
                            precepts of Christ. They first call the baptized Jesus, God, then have him killed for their
                            ransom; then worship him. Watts thus sings this characteristic creed• " Well might the sun
                            in darkness hide, and shut his glory in, When Christ — the Mighty Maker died, for man, the
                            creature's sin." Thus having a dead God, Christ and Holy Ghost; for the Creed says, " these
                            three are One," it follows, as a consequence, a dead religion, without the power of
                            salvation from sin, without the inspirations of the Holy Spirit! Only think of it; what a
                            mystery of Babylon. Among all of the denomination of religionists calling themselves
                            Christian, not one among them all, if we mistake not; except the Quakers and Shakers, but
                            ignore spiritualism! Whereas, spirituality is the very foundation and life of the Christian
                            church, and the pristine state of humanity was a life in communion with the angelic hosts.
                            But, what is the character of this vaunted Christianity of our nation? Is it not reproached
                            by the life character of some nations we are accustomed to look upon as heathen? Dr. Malcam,
                            Baptist missionary <pb n="250" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 250 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. to Burmah, tells us the
                            Buddhists have abol ished all sacrifices of life and blood, auc their altars are now crowned
                            with leaves anc flowers. That they have such care for al' life that when he came to a zayat
                            (saloon) and stopped to rest, presently a woman came and brought him a nice mat to sit on ;
                            soon another came and brought him a glass of cool water, and very soon a man came and
                            brought him a half dozen oranges; but none of these persons seemed to think of soliciting
                            pay! Compare this with the history of our so called Christianity whose theology, aye and so
                            called Christian practices, abound in bloody sacrifices, and whose conquering power has been
                            blood letting by the sword, to win souls to a faith in its creed, and whose peace-makers are
                            murderers! True, the Bible speaks of "the blood of Christ cleansing souls from all
                            unrighteousness;" but, this " blood of Christ" is not the crimson flood drawn from the veins
                            of Jesus! The blood is the life, and is used figuratively to represent the life of Christ,
                            the same spiritual baptism that crowned the character of Jesus. And this life, living as
                            Jesus lived, will save, to the uttermost, all souls who will so live. The Bible abounds in
                            figurative language, and often requires to be thus understood. When King David said, " The
                            ploughmen ploughed upon my back, they made long their furrows ;" are we at liberty to
                            suppose that King David's back was as large as a ten acre field? When Solomon said, "Put a
                            knife to thy throat if thou be given to appetite," is it to be presumed that he encouraged
                            suicide? And thus we might extensively illustrate. But the present age understands this kind
                            of language. You will recollect, that during our late civil war (though, by the way, all
                            wars are very uncivil and barbarous), the United States had a big cannon they called " The
                            Peace Maker." And another they called " The Swamp Angel." These appellations, and their
                            applications, are characteristic of very much of the Christianity of the day. But returning
                            to the God idea, as no people can be better than their God, let us go back and trace it up.
                            The lowest idea of God known to humanity is that called Fetichism. A great mountain, rock or
                            mighty river, dense forest, etc., some object of human wonder, is called God, and worshiped.
                            Next higher, the sun, moon and stars, objects of light and heat, are called gods, and
                            worshiped, and why not, being the developers of all life, vegetable and animal? Next we have
                            images of men and beasts, made of wood, stone, silver and gold, as gods, because it came to
                            be discovered that man, with all his deformities, is the most perfect being that God ever
                            made. Next in progress we have the God revealed to Moses, who was seen in the burning bush
                            called "a God of consuming fire," called himself simply " I am ;" that is, I exist, but, so
                            incomprehensible that you cannot fully know me! Why ? Because 1 am a spiritual Being and you
                            are not yet spiritually developed. But, even this God character, as Moses understood it, was
                            one of war, blood, murder and revenge, who dealt largely in the law of Lex talionis. " An
                            eye for an eye, tooth for a tooth; who so sheddeth man's blood, by man shall his blood be
                            shed ;" requiring his people to slay all their enemies, old and young, male and female,
                            except the virgin women. What were these to be saved for ? And to take, by force, their
                            lands and possessions. What a God character this! Requiring his people to make sacrifices
                            not only of beasts, but of men! But he did indeed show some advancement, for he required
                            them to make some sacrifice of their usts also. '' Come not at your wives for three days "
                            before ascending the mount Sinai to meet their God, and receive his laws. Still we have
                            another higher character of God revealed to Jesus Christ, God as "¦Heavenly Father ; " and
                            instead of murders, a dispensation of mercies, of love, of forgiveness. ' If ye forgive not
                            men their trespasses, neither will your Heavenly Father forgive your trespasses." This God
                            character is that revealed by the male Christian Church; the ¦ Church of the eastern world.
                            And now we have yet a still higher God character revealed, that of God as a Heavenly Father
                            and Mother ilso ; for who ever heard of a Father withjut a Mother ? And since Jesus Christ
                            is the son of God, who ever heard of a son born <pb n="251" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            251 to a Father without a Mother ? The thing is simply a negation, an impossibility. And as
                            it required a man, Jesus, to reveal the Fatherhood of God, even so it required a woman to
                            reveal the Motherhood of God, and to introduce the Church of the Second Coming of Christ in
                            his glory, according to the promise. Paul said, truly, "The woman is the glory of the man,"
                            " and theman " (in his capacity of male or female) '' is the glory of God." But the man is
                            not without the woman in the kingdom of God, no more than in nature. Jesus, aside from his
                            baptism, was not the Christ, but to become such, he had to be born again ; thus it is clear,
                            his birth of Mary did not make him such. Had he become the Christ by his first birth, pray
                            what would his second birth have made of him? Jesus was simply an inspired man; was
                            constituted the Christ of his day, par excellence, by his spiritual birth through baptism
                            of-the Holy Ghost, and in this capacity became the Elder Brother," the first born of many
                            brethren. He said: " Except a man be born again, he cannot be my disciple." Had Jesus proved
                            false to his call and mission, some other medium would have been prepared as Jesus was, to
                            receive the Christ baptism; for the manifestation of the Christ was the product of evolution
                            of the race of man ; and it embraces both the male and fe male, for the Christ is a Heavenly
                            Bridegroom and Bride, when manifest in " His Glory " at his second coming.'1'' The manner of
                            his second coming was to be according to the manner in which his going into Heaven was
                            manifest- How was that? A cloud received him out of their sight." What kind of a cloud? A
                            cloud of witnesses, not a watery vapor floating in the horizon over our heads. This " cloud
                            of witnesses " should also be the ones in whom, and through whom Christ should make his
                            Second Appearing, as the Mother Christian Church of the Western world. This Church is the
                            Holy City, the New Jerusalem, which the prophetic vision, ist, St. John, saw " coming down
                            from God, out of Heaven, as a Bride adorned for her husband." But where shall Christ make
                            his second appearance? The scriptures tell us: "To a nation bringing forth the fruits
                            thereof." Where is that nation to be found which lives in peace, in love and righteousness?
                            Wherever, and whenever it may be, there and then will Christ be manifest. Where is the
                            nation prepared to receive the second coming of Christ in, and through the female? How can
                            this be until woman has a right to an equality with man in the possession of her person, in
                            the management of her social and domestic relations, in her religious devotions, and in the
                            making of the laws that take cognizance of and tax her property — a right to suffrage? Go to
                            Turkey, where woman is a mere vassal; go to China where, when you ask a woman the number of
                            her family and she only counts the boys, the girls being of no account. Could the second
                            coming of Christ in his glory be manifest there? In no wise. As well talk of light without
                            sunshine or electricity. At present, not a nation now exists on the globe where the woman is
                            enjoying all her rights with her fellowman as a citizen ; but the good time is nearing, when
                            this, our nation, can sing the ransom song of freedom for woman, and then can Christ make
                            more manifest in her the Church of the New Jerusalem, coming down from God out of Heaven, as
                            a Bride adorned for her husband. We do not worship either Ann Lee, or Jesus; we worship God.
                            A man at Old Orchard Beach, some eight years ago, said to me that the evidence that Jesus
                            was God was because Jesus was worshiped. Well, Peter was worshiped, was he also God ; and,
                            if Jesus was the " Elder Brother of many brethren " were they also Gods, to be worshiped?
                            The American Government has put the name of God on our silver dollars, and money seems to be
                            the God in which millions now trust; but is it a proper object of worship for a Christian?
                            While we hold between our fingers the silver dollar of our country and read upon it "In God
                            we Trust" we hear the voice of Jesus ringing in our ears: '' Render unto Caesar the things
                            that are Caesar's, and unto God the things that are God's. We would not speak slightly of
                            the religious profession of any denomination, nor the religious devotions of any individual;
                            for we <pb n="252" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 252 THE SHAKBfi MANIFESTO. revere the sincere devotions of any
                            and every soul, even though they may be very far from the highest standard of truth revealed
                            to man; and there is a measure of truth and godliness in all denominations; and the
                            discipline of the Church is profitable, of all professors of Christianity; but we must speak
                            the truth as we understand it to-day. The coming of Christ is the " End of the World " in
                            all souls who enter into its covenants, and obey its behests; and this is a •'New Covenant"
                            of which Jesus, and all his faithful followers are the mediators ; and such are those, '' or
                            lame, or blind, or dumb, on whom the ends of this vain world are come"—They are the virgin
                            followers of the " Lamb of God who taketh away the sins of the world " from all who live as
                            he lived. This Church is one of peace ani love, not bearing the character of that Church
                            portrayed by St. John, who was drunk with the blood of the saints and the martyrs of Jesus,
                            who slew in her so-called " Holy Wars," almost unnumbered millions under the pretense of
                            sustaining the rights of the Church, and many millions to convert them to Christianity with
                            the sword,as did old Rome under the rule of its Emperor Constantine. Marriage, as an
                            institution of this world only, we do not abjure, but insist that those who marry should
                            obey the law of God in generation, to use the commerce of the sexes for offspring only. But
                            it is an institution not belonging to the Kingdom of Christ/ " That which is born of the
                            flesh is flesh, and that which is born of the spirit is spirit." " And they that are in the
                            flesh cannot please God," nor be the subjects of Christ's Kingdom ; for his kingdom is not
                            of this world; while marriage is necessarily a worldly institution. In answer to the
                            question which the Jews put to Jesus, Whose wife, in the ressurrection, should the woman be
                            who had been possessed of seven husbands? He replied, '' ye do err, not knowing the
                            scriptures, nor the power of God ; for they that are in the resurrection neither marry nor
                            are given in marriage, but are (in this world) as the angels in Heaven.''' He said: "I am
                            the resurrection," that is, my life is the resurtion life." But, " all men cannot receive
                            this saying;" that is, to "make themselves eunuchs for the kingdom of Heaven's sake." "He
                            that is able to receive it, let him." There is no compulsion, but every one shall be
                            rewarded according to his works; and " they who sow to the flesh, shall of the flesh reap
                            corruption; while they who sew to the spirit shall of the spirit reap life everlasting." The
                            visionist St. John saw Christ descending to earth in his glory, in a cloud of witnesses,
                            saying : "Behold, I come quickly, and my reward is with me to give to every man according as
                            his works shall be." Not to justify them in sin, and give them mansions in Heaven for
                            believing that Jesns did good things. Now, these are among "the things of good report; let
                            us think on these things."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Angel of patience" TEIform="index"/>THE ANGEL OF PATIENCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whittier, John Greenleaf" TEIform="persName"/>JOHN GREENLEAF WHITTIER</byline><p TEIform="p">BY . To wearjr hearts, to mourning homes, God's meekest Angel gently comes; No power has he
                            to banish pain, Or give us back our lost again; And yet in tenderest love, our dear And
                            heavenly Father sends him here. There's quiet in that Angel's glance, There's rest in his
                            still countenance ! He mocks no grief with idle cheer, Nor wounds with words the mourner's
                            ear; But ills and woes he may not cure, He kindly trains us to endure. Angel of Patience !
                            sent to calm Our feverish brows with cooling palm; To lay the storms of hope and fear, And
                            reconcile life's smile and tear; The throbs of wounded pride to still, And make our own our
                            Father's will, 0 ! thou who mournest on thy way, With longings for the close of day, He
                            walks with thee, that Angel kind, And gently whispers, " Be resigned ; Bear Up, bear on, the
                            end shall tell The dear Lord ordereth all things well !"</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Is it so with you?" TEIform="index"/>Is IT SO with YOU?</head><p TEIform="p">— A miserly, rich old man, on being rebuked for his parsimony, replied : " True, I don't give
                            much; but if you only knew how it hurts me when I give any thing, you wouldn't wonder."
                            That's the trouble with all of them.</p></div2><pb n="253" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Recompense of reward" TEIform="index"/>THE RECOMPENSE OF REWARD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The thorough Christian is under continual promise of a comfortable reward; and the
                                anticipations of those who work for Christ, as they feel this spirit directs them, are
                                those which, if they can be imagined, they cannot be described. Renunciations numerous,
                                and constant denials of self were the most prominent characteristics in the instructions
                                of Jesus to his disciples in days of yore, and are of Christ to his present disciples.
                                And activity in these renunciations and self-denials prompts the reflection at every
                                breathing place or station: " What therefore shall we have " for all these
                                renunciations? We want pay ; we unwillingly work unless we can feel some of the
                                compensation continually, and have confidence in the solvency of the Bank of Heaven to
                                meet our just demands at the close of a Christian's life labors. According to our Shaker
                                testimony, to be a follower of Christ is to take upon ourselves the responsibility of
                                living Christ's life; and this life is replete with renunciations of indulgences, which
                                give the greatest pleasure to our earthly, carnal senses. In the general catalogue of
                                the things Jesus renounced, and taught should have a resemblance in his disciples, are
                                Marriage and the engagements in fleshly lusts; private, personal, selfish possessions,
                                of which the brethren of the Church could not share ; the gratification of retaliating
                                an insult to an equality, at least, of the injury done; and the exercise of the spirit
                                of emulation in Pride, Vanity, together with all the elements that incite an unbrotherly
                                aristocracy an'd worldly superiority. These are first principles ; yet the unlearned and
                                inexperienced, who too often are ripe in years, but not in fruitful reflection, affect
                                that they are finalities. From this cause they very reasonably arrive at a station,
                                where progress as Christian necessity is not made, nor seemingly possible to be made.
                                Then is seen "the resting on the oars," and relying upon first principles to bring the
                                inexpressible riches promised the faithful. Yet these come not. The inmates of all
                                Shaker Societies have to admit that they have rivals " worthy of their steel" the world
                                over. There are thousands, if not millions who claim to be living strictly virgin,
                                celibate lives. Again, there are some individuals who have from the deepest
                                conscientiousness expended several fortunes upon suffering humanity, living themselves
                                in pauper-like style that they might be able to do the most good. We can read almost
                                daily of those who are spending lives and fortunes in the interests of peace — peace in
                                families and among nations. Even in the popular pulpits of our day, we find the most
                                caustic testimonies againatpride, vanity in dress and other unneighborly behavior. We
                                are made aware, as we travel our public thoroughfares, that there are numerous
                                societies, composed of numerous individuals, who have discarded all worldly gayety,
                                amusements of nearly or quite every character, and these discarded for a purpose.
                                Intemperance in eating, drinking, and its every other form has its inveterate foes ; and
                                their contraries have most <pb n="254" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 254 THE SHAKES MANIFESTO. noble
                                advocates. What of all this? Unless the righteousness of the saints, exceeds that of the
                                partial saints " what therefore shall we have ? " It behooves every individual who
                                esteems himself or herself a radical apostle of Christ to ask, wherein their
                                renunciations as Christians are adding to their personal worth of character, without
                                alloy, fitted for the heavens, on earth, or elsewhere. We are certain that the outlines
                                of a Christian life are far removed from a wordly,earthly character. We are just as
                                assured,that unless these outlines, these first principles— Virgin Celibacy, Community
                                of Interests, Non-resistance, and Freedom from Worldly Ambitions and Behavior, — are
                                used as stepping stones of progress, as lower rounds, leading to higher rounds in the
                                ladder leading to personal excellence as Christians, we shall ask, and ask : " What
                                therefore shall we have ? " and reckon without our host. Shakerism leads individuals
                                quickly into and through rudimentary Christianity. Unless its adherents use these early
                                lessons to rise above, and press beyond first elements, they can rest upon the somewhat
                                unsatisfactory recompense of rewards resulting therefrom. ' But the call is to " press
                                beyond " these ; and to attack, defeat, remove and replace all inferior habits — for
                                instance, jealousy, envy, vituperation, personal preferences, uncharitable criticisms,
                                unsocial, unhappy and unhandsome communings, and the like, —and replacing these by the
                                addition of a large love, boundless charity, harmless and endearing behavior, the very
                                opposite of the selfish accuser of the brethren, and to know, or wish to know only the
                                purity, the goodness, and greatest exaltation in godliness of fellow travelers, — herein
                                is a work of travail, of birth into a new, created world, and its companionship and
                                results will be a most satisfying, present heaven, and the prospects, an inexpressible,
                                but reliable recompense of rewards for all they cost. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Men who are worth fifteen millions and upwards" TEIform="index"/>Men who are Worth
                                Fifteen Millions and Upwards</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The following 20 men are estimated to be worth the sums following their names: Win. H.
                                Vanderbilt.......... $100,000,000 Fair of California............ 50,000,000 Flood of
                                California......... 50,000,000 Mackey of California........ 50,000,000 August
                                Belmont.....______ 30,000,000 Senator Sharon.............. 15,000,000 Senator
                                Jones............... 20,000,000 Astor of New York.......... 75,000,000 James G.
                                Bennett............ 30,000,000 Jay GonM___.............. 75,000,000 Russell
                                Sage............... 75,000,000 S. J. Tilden................. 25,000,000 Keene of New
                                York......... 20,000,000 Solon Humphreys........... 15,000,000 Sidney
                                Dillon................ 15,000,000 Edward Clark.............. 25,000,000 Oakes Ames,
                                Jr.............. 15,000,000 Perry H. Smith of Chicago.. . 15,000,000 Peter
                                Cooper___............ 20,000,000 Pierre Lorillard..........___ 15,000,000 And every one
                                of these magnates, and thousands more in a similar fix would feel insulted, if told they
                                were postively unworthy and unfit for the kingdom of heaven. And if one should address
                                them, as with authority, and with a little effectual compulsion added : " Go sell all
                                thou hast and give it to the poor " whom you daily defraud, they would feel like
                                re-enacting the crucifixion scene. Inordinate <pb n="255" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. 255 wealth induces and sustains inordinate poverty ; while in the church of
                                Christ there are neither rich nor poor; but'*Ye are brethren." And yet, why are there so
                                many members of modern churches, some who are very rich and some very poor? The answer
                                is simple and plain: Because they are not Christians, excepting by profession; and
                                profession without' possession of Christ's love of equality is barrenness.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Foreign missions and home necessities" TEIform="index"/>FOREIGN MISSIONS AND HOME
                                NECESSITIES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">It is a very strange fact, but fact it is, that Foreign Missions are very much more
                                popular than the relief of local sufferings. It is a positive shame to think, that such
                                were the abominable inconsistencies of the professional Christians in a popular church
                                in New York city, that they actually subscribed on a recent Sunday $16,000 for foreign
                                heathens, while in the four weeks previous, a charitable association in the same
                                neighborhood had application from 5,986 families for relief from the pangs of
                                starvation; while a visiting committee in the Sixth Ward found thirteen hundred persons
                                without shoes! It was just such inconsistencies which caused England's poet, Elliott, to
                                write: " Their Bibles for the heathen load our fleets; Lo! gloating eastward, they
                                inquire, 'What news? ' We die,' we answer,' foodless in the streets.' And what reply
                                your men of Gospel views? Oh! ' they're sending bacon to the Jews.' Their lofty souls
                                have telescopic eyes, Which see the smallest speck of distant pain, While at their feet
                                a world of agonies, Unseen, unheard, unheeded, writhes in vain."</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Broad Christianity" TEIform="index"/>BROAD CHRISTIANITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">It is the most brilliant feature in the theological world to-day, to notice the depth and
                                breadth now being assumed by a genuine, rational, consistent Christianity — that of
                                dissolving party and churchal lines among prominent leaders of heretofore strongly
                                biased sects. It is a very bold assumption for certain prominents of "close communion"
                                Baptists and "straight lined " Presbyterians, to declare it high time for a closer union
                                of the churches; and that unless a fruitful move is made in this direction, churchal
                                influences are barriers to religious progress, rather than assistants! The call is
                                abroad, and it is a happy omen indeed, to let religion sink so much deeper than mere
                                theology that the latter will sink into oblivion by the continued presence of a rational
                                religion. This move certainly threatens to rob Christianity of the barnacles of
                                sectarian theology; and making the distinctions between right and wrong no less
                                significant, make brotherly love and union the basis of a new creation of a practical
                                religion among men. All hail!</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="This number of the manifesto" TEIform="index"/>THIS NUMBER OF THE MANIFESTO</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We present some excellent contributions in this our November issue. We offer no apology
                                for the length of the excellent address of our honored publisher. In it will be found
                                some hard hits at popular, but irrational theologies, while it illuminates the simple
                                purity of Christ's life as being genuine Christianity. We are almost certain that the
                                unbigoted minds of our readers will discover some " do evils " that have previously been
                                unsuspected by <pb n="256" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 256 THE SHAKES MANIFESTO. them, while they read
                                Bro. Hampton's article. Bro. Eraser will be more than ever suspected of being a
                                practical, good-sensed logician, while we all know and love him for his enthusiasm for
                                the right. Elder Evans has a pithy, characteristic article; but too short by half. -The
                                sweet singer, Andrews, is " with us once again," and we all hope for more. Our Indian
                                historian, Sproat, has taken up an interesting topic; while our learned collegian
                                brother, Bussell, is as ever unusually interesting. Our music this month is sweetly
                                harmonious, an honor to our talented professor of music at Enfield, N. H. Is it not a
                                good number?</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Make friends" TEIform="index"/>MAKE FRIENDS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Life is very critical. Any word may be our last. Any farewell, even amid glee and
                                merriment, may be forever. If this truth were but burnt into our consciousness, and if
                                ruled as a deep conviction and real power in our lives, would it not give a new meaning
                                to our human relationships ? Would it not make us far more tender than we sometimes are
                                ? Would it not oftentimes put a rein upon our rash and impetuous speech ? Would we carry
                                in our hearts the miserable suspicions and jealousies that now so often embitter the
                                fountains of our lives ? Would we be so impatient of the faults of others ? Would we
                                allow trivial misunderstandings to build up a wall between us and those who ought to
                                stand very close to us ? Would we keep alive petty quarrels year after year, which a
                                manly word any day would compose ? Would we pass old friends or neighbors on the street
                                without recognition, be. cause of some real or fancied slight, some wounding of pride,
                                or some ancient grudge ? Or weuld we be so chary of the kind words, our commendations,
                                our sympathy, our comfort, when weary hearts all about us are breaking for just such
                                expressions of interest or appreciation as we have in our power to give ? — Christian at
                                Work.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Do thy little" TEIform="index"/>DO THY LITTLE</head><p TEIform="p">Do thy little — God has made Million leaves for forest shade — Smallest stars that glory
                                bring. God employeth every thing. Then the little thou hast done — Little battles thou
                                hast won, Little masteries achieved, Little wants with care relieved, Little words in
                                love expressed, Little wrongs at once confessed, Little favors kindly done, Little toils
                                thou didst not shun, Little graces meekly worn, Little slights with patience borne —
                                Those shall crown thy pillowed head, Holy light upon thee shed. Those are treasures that
                                shall rise Far beyond the smiling skies.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Little things" TEIform="index"/>LITTLE THINGS</head><p TEIform="p">" Though little I bring," Said the tiny spring, As it burst from the mighty hill, " 'Tis
                                pleasant to know, Wherever I flow, The pastures grow greener still." And the drops of
                                rain, As they fall on the plain, When parched by the summer heat, Refresh the sweet
                                flowers Which drooped in the bowers, And hung their heads at our feet. Though the drops
                                are small, Yet, taking them all, Each one doing all that it can To fulfill the design Of
                                its Maker divine, What lessons they give unto man ! May we strive to fulfill All His
                                righteous will, Who formed the whole earth by His word ? Creator divine, We should f.ver
                                be thine, And serve Thee, our God and our Lord.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Weak but strong" TEIform="index"/>WEAK BUT STRONG</head><p TEIform="p">I will tell you a true story for the children to hear, and leave each one to enforce its
                                lesson in his or her own way. The bit of a girl is not one of the " goody good"
                                children, but a perfect bunch of mischief who needs <pb n="257" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE
                                MANIFESTO. 257 constant watching. She had taken a fancy to play with the key of her
                                father's desk, often taking it out for the purpose. One day he told her never to take it
                                out again, fearing it might be lost Some few days after he was lying half asleep on the
                                sofa, the little daughter playing beside him. The sudden stillness of the room roused
                                him to the fact that she had disappeared, and seeing the door to the nest room, where
                                the desk was, open, he stole softly toward it to see what the child was doing. There she
                                stood, just in front of the coveted key, both tiny hands clasped behind her, and leaning
                                forward on her tiptoes, she kissed it gently. Then father crept unseen to the sofa, and
                                in a mOment she came and stood beside him, both hands still folded behind her, and said:
                                " My' did'nt touch the key, 'cause papa told her not to." Surely if a tiny creature like
                                this could put temptation behind her, we grown up folks ought to have strength enough
                                to.— Boston Transcript.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind words" TEIform="index"/>KIND WORDS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Harcourt, Helen" TEIform="persName"/>HELEN HARCOURT</byline><p TEIform="p"> Kind words' are of value, though nothing they cost; By harsh, bitter accents, many souls
                                have been lost. Then deep in thy heart this memory bear, Nor drive, by unkindness, a
                                friend to despair. Refuse not forgiveness, for, oh, then, alas ! Thou breakest the
                                bridge over which thou must pass. With the set of the sun let thy anger go down, And
                                banish away every stern, bitter frown.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Principle of right" TEIform="index"/>THE PRINCIPLE OF RIGHT</head><p TEIform="p">Amos Lawrence once said, when asked for advice, " Young man, base all your actions on a
                                principle of right; preserve your integrity of character; and, in doing this, never
                                reckon the cost." A noble sentiment, expressed by a worthy man. But a different
                                sentiment is expressed to-day by men who have influence on account of publicity, who
                                have worshipers, on account of talent, but who, by a peculiar juxtaposition of opposite
                                natural tendencies, or, rather, by a reckless inconsistency of example, speak, in
                                thunder tones, to young men that are ready to take advice: Young man, sacrifice every
                                principle of right for the sake of selfish ends ; and, in doing so, never stop to count
                                the cost to yourself or to society. An ignoble sentiment, but too frequently
                            expressed.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I won't" TEIform="index"/>I WON'T</head><p TEIform="p">The other day a boy burst out a crying in school, and he cried as if his heart would
                                break. Did another boy pinch or hurt him ? No. Was his spelling lesson too hard? No.
                                What were those tears for? His teacher called him to her side, and asked Freddy what the
                                matter was. " I want to go home. Oh, do let me go," sobbed Freddy. " What for my dear
                                child ?" asked the teacher in her own kind way. " Oh,'! said Freddy, " I said ' I won't'
                                to my mother before school, and I want to go home and tell her how sorrow I am, and ask
                                her to forgive me." Then they were penitent tears, the best tears a child can shed. But
                                then you must remember, 'Tis not enough to sari We're sorrow and repent, And still go on
                                from day to day Just as we always went. Repentance is to leave The sins we loved before,
                                And show that we in earnest grieve By doing so no more.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Golden percepts for the young" TEIform="index"/>GOLDEN PRECEPTS FOR THE YOUNG</head><p TEIform="p">Bishop Middleton furnishes the following : Persevere against discouragement Keep your
                                temper. Employ, leisure in study, and always have some work in hand. Be punctual and
                                methodical in business, and never procrastinate. Never be in. a hurry. Preserve
                                self-possession, and do not be talked out of conviction. Eise early and be an economist
                                of time. Maintain dignity without the appearance of pride; manner is something with
                                everybody, and every thing with some. Be guarded in discourse, attentive, and slow to
                                speak. Never acquiesce in immoral or pernicious opinions. Be not forward to assign
                                reasons to those who have no right to ask. Think nothing in conduct unimportant or
                                indifferent. Rather give than follow examples, preserve a strict temperance, and in your
                                transactions remember the final account.</p></div3></div2><pb n="258" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soda for burns" TEIform="index"/>Soda for Burns</head><p TEIform="p">.—All kinds of burns, including scalds and sunburns, are almost immediately relieved by
                                the application of a solution of soda to the burnt surface. It must be remembered that
                                dry soda will not do unless it is surrounded with a cloth moist enough to dissolve it.
                                This method of sprinkling it on and covering it with a wet cloth is often the very best.
                                But it is sufficient to wash the wound repeatedly with a strongsolution.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To loosen glass stoppers" TEIform="index"/>To Loosen Glass Stoppers</head><p TEIform="p">—Put on one or two drops of sweet oil round the stopper, close to the mouth of the
                                bottle; then put it a little distance from the fire. When the decanter gets warm, have a
                                wooden instrument with a cloth wrapped tightly round it; then strike the stopper, first
                                on one side, then on the other; by persevering a little while you will most likely get
                                it out. Or you may lay the bottle in warm water, so that the neck of the bottle may be
                                under water. Let it soak for a time, then knock it with a wooden instrument as
                            before.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Doing up shirts" TEIform="index"/>Doing up Shirts</head><p TEIform="p">.— A shirt-board for ironing is a necessity in every well-regulated family. This should
                                be covered with at least two thicknesses of blankets, and have the ironing sheet, also
                                double, smoothly pinned over it, so that it cannot slip. Keep wax tied up in a rag to
                                rub the iron. The polish of collars, etc., done up at large laundries is given by means
                                of a polishingiron and by dint of much rubbing. It may be done by any good laundress,
                                but it takes much time, and is fearfully hard on the linen. Spermacetti added in small
                                quantities to the starch gives a pretty gloss. We insert this recipe:—Melt together with
                                a gentle heat, one ounce white wax and two ounces spermacetti; prepare in the usual way
                                a sufficient quantity of starch for a dozen bosoms; put into it a piece of this enamel
                                the size of a hazelnut. This gives a beautiful polish.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oyster pie" TEIform="index"/>Oyster Pie</head><p TEIform="p">.— Line a dish with puff paste or a rich biscuit paste, and dredge well with flour; drain
                                one quart of oysters, season with pepper, salt andbutter, and pour into the dish; add
                                some of the liquor; dredge with flour, and cover with a top crust, leaving a small
                                opening in the center.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fried oysters" TEIform="index"/>Fried Oysters</head><p TEIform="p">.— Select the largest, dip them in beaten egg, and then in bread or cracker crumbs ; fry
                                in equal parts of butter and lard until they are brown. They are very good dipped in
                                corn meal instead of crumbs.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pickled Oysters" TEIform="index"/>Pickled Oysters</head><p TEIform="p">— One quart vinegar, one ounce of allspice, one-half ounce of cinnamon, one ounce of
                                cloves, one ounce of mace; scald all together; when cold put in the oysters ; next day
                                "scald together.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oyster soup" TEIform="index"/>Oyster Soup</head><p TEIform="p">—Drain one quart of oysters, and to the liquor add one quart of boiling water; let it
                                boil; skim carefully; season with a little Cayenne pepper and butter, size of an egg;
                                add the oysters, and let it boil up once, and season with salt, and serve in a hot
                                souptureen.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oyster stew" TEIform="index"/>Oyster Stew</head><p TEIform="p">.— Put two quarts of oysters in the saucepan with the liquor, and when they begin to boil
                                skim them out and add a pint of cream or rich milk and seasoning; skim well; add to the
                                oysters butter to taste, and pour the hot liquor over them, and serve.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spanish pickled onions" TEIform="index"/>Spanish Pickled Onions</head><p TEIform="p">.— Cut onions into slices; put a layer of them in a jar; sprinkle with salt and cayenne
                                pepper, then add a layer of onions and season as before ; proceed in this way until the
                                jar is full, and pour cold vinegar over all till covered. Will be fit to use in a
                            month.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wood stains" TEIform="index"/>Wood Stains</head><p TEIform="p"> — A Carpenter — I want to stain some wood work in imitation of walnut and cherry, please
                                give directions? Ans.— Dissolve asphalt in spirits of turpentine and thin it down until
                                when tried on a sample it gives the right walnut shade. If a reddish tinge is desired
                                add a little dragon's blood by degrees until the color suits. One coat is enough. For
                                cherry, make a saturated solution of bi-chromate of potash in hot water, and when cold
                                brush this over the work, which should be of clear pine. Set the work in the light until
                                the shade darkens sufficiently, when it should be covered. The watery solution will
                                raise the grain of the wood. This should be sandpapered down and a coat of oil be
                            given.</p></div3></div2><pb n="259" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Agricultural</head><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keep potatoes in a cool..." TEIform="index"/>Keep potatoes in a cool...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Keep potatoes in a cool, dry, dark cellar, with good ventilation.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For throat distemper" TEIform="index"/>For throat distemper
                            </head><p TEIform="p">For throat distemper, grate fine a small green wild turnip, or, if dry, give a heaping
                                spoonful, mixed with bran or oats.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A lady says that to kill insects..." TEIform="index"/>A lady says that to kill insects...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A lady says that to kill insects, she uses one teaspoonful of kerosene to a gallon of
                                \yater, and sprinkles it on the plants with a hand-broom. It destroys green flies and
                                other pests.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Horses and cattle normally require..." TEIform="index"/>Horses and cattle normally require...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Horses and cattle normally require, in round numbers, four pounds of water for each pound
                                of dry substance in their food, while sheep require but about two pounds, half as
                            much.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Mississippi farmer dashes cold water..." TEIform="index"/>A Mississippi farmer dashes cold water...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A Mississippi farmer dashes cold water into the ears of choking cattle. This causes the
                                animal to shake its head violently, and the muscular action dislodges the
                            obstruction.</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Paragon tomato" TEIform="index"/>The Paragon Tomato</head><p TEIform="p">There is no tomato grown which, in our opinion, approaches the " Paragon," for abundance
                                of yield, form, flavor and color. All who are unacquainted with the "Paragon," will
                                thank us for introducing it to them.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blanket the horses" TEIform="index"/>Blanket the Horses</head><p TEIform="p">.— Save lameness and coughs by an immediate covering of the horses after a drive, if only
                                stopping for a few minutes. Do not cover the horse with blankets when he is- in exercise
                                ; not even in a storm ; but rub thoroughly, and cover after the horse has found
                            shelter.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Top-dressing" TEIform="index"/>Top-Dressing</head><p TEIform="p">If manure is needed for winter grain, now is the time to apply it. It may be used fresh
                                and coarse, without losing much in value. Even straw spread over the wheat is of great
                                benefit. Mulching is a protection against extremes of both heat and cold, and preserves
                                the crop during sudden and severe changes of the weather.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pasturing fall grain" TEIform="index"/>Pasturing Fall Grain</head><p TEIform="p">If the fall grain is in danger of jointing, it should be pastured without delay. It is
                                often a great help to the wheat or rye, to turn sheep or calves upon it. These eat down
                                luxuriant growth, and tread the soil firmly about the roots. If no other stock are
                                available for this purpose cows may be led into winter grain fields.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Poultry" TEIform="index"/>Poultry</head><p TEIform="p">Vermin are the greatest pest to fowls. They are worse in the winter than at other times,
                                because the fowls are confined more closely, and have not opportunities to free
                                themselves. Lice may be destroyed by whitewashing the house and roofs with lime-wash
                                mixed- with carbolic acid. Fleas may be destroyed by thoroughly greasing the roosts.
                                Clean straw should be supplied to the nests, and glass nest-eggs provided for early
                                layers. A glass-covered coop will be useful for an early sitting hen and a young brood
                                of chickens.</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A great deal of winter fruit..." TEIform="index"/>A great deal of winter fruit...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A great deal of winter fruit suffers early decay in consequence of a deficiency of
                                ventilation, especially during autumn and after the fruit is deposited. The Germans are
                                very successful in the ventilation of their cellars, by a communication with the
                                principal chimney, the heated air in which neces sarily maintains a current, which
                                sweeps out the noxious and stagnant gases from the vegetable and other contents. Apples
                                are safer in barrels either in a shaded place in the open air, or under a shed, than in
                                a cellar, till the frost comes on. Then they should be covered with straw and only be
                                taken into the cellar when severe frost comes on.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Guard your conversation" TEIform="index"/>GUARD YOUR CONVERSATION</head><p TEIform="p">If you say any thing about a neighbor or friend, or even a stranger, say nothing ill. It is a
                            Christian and brotherly charity to suppress our knowledge of evil of another unless a higher
                            public duty compels us to bear accusing witness ; and if it be true charity to deep our
                            knowledge of such evils to ourselves, much more should we refuse to spread evil report of
                            another. Discreditable as the fact is, it is by far the commonest tendency to suppress the
                            good we know of our neighbors and friends. We act in this matter as though we felt that by
                            pushing our fellows down or back we were putting ourselves up or forward. We are jealous of
                            commendation unless we get the larger share.</p></div2><pb n="260" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Departed this Life</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Robbins, Emily" TEIform="index"/>Emily Robbins</head><p TEIform="p">From Shaker Village, N. H., October 1st, , aged 73 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wilson, Peter" TEIform="index"/>Peter Wilson</head><p TEIform="p">Also, October 2, , aged 59 years.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Benjamin Bailey" TEIform="index"/>Benjamin Bailey</head><p TEIform="p">We find the following in a local paper: . Many of our older business men will be pained
                                to learn of the death of the good old man whose name stands above. He died at Alfred, on
                                Sunday, the 26th ult., at the ripe age of 81 years For about seventy years he has been a
                                prominent and trusted member of " The United Society of Believers," as they call
                                themselves—Shakers, as the world's people call them—and he has consistently exemplified
                                his profession. There are probably few men better known personally to the country
                                merchants and hotel keepers of York and Cumberland counties, and the whole eastern
                                portion of our State than he was. For many years, or until his eyesight began to fail,
                                lie made regular winter journeys as far east as Calais and Eastport, and even across the
                                border into the New Dominion, in selling the Shaker garden seeds which were formerly so
                                much used. He was a sterling character, firm as a rock in what he thought to be the
                                truth and the right, yet tender and loving as a child. In fact, another of his prominent
                                traits was love of children ; for them he always entertained a deep and universal
                                regard. We shall never cease to remember his sweet, tender affection for the young, yet
                                expressed in such a noble, manly tone of voice Only a month ago we enjoyed a visit at
                                the Alfred community, and not the least pleasant thing about it was the interview with
                                him and his brother, Merrill Bailey, himself now an old man of seventy odd years. His
                                memory of events, persons and dates was indeed remarkable. He overflowed with incidents
                                and anecdotes of men of prominence in this vicinity in other days, especially of such a
                                brilliant and witty man as was John Holmes. Some eighty years ago his father took up a
                                tract of land in the wilds of Colebrook, Coos county, N. H., and very entertaining was
                                the story of the hardships of his father and mother in that northern wilderness at that
                                time. But after a time he became converted to the doctrines of Mother Ann Lee, then
                                creating considerable interest in this country, and with his whole family he "gathered"
                                to the Shakers, where he worthily lived and died. Benjamin and Merrill Bailey, with
                                their most estimable sister, Eldress Jane Tarbox, lately deceased, were among the
                                principal supporters of the Alfred community for half a century, and they each bore
                                their burden like faithful Christians, as they were. Hail and farewell then, dear old
                                friend and honest man, we may not soon look upon thy like again, and some of the
                                sweetest memories of life will ever cluster around thy sterling and beautiful
                            character.</p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Received from George Wilcox..." TEIform="index"/>Received from George Wilcox...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Received from George Wilcox, Enfield, Conn., $40.00.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True courage" TEIform="index"/>TRUE COURAGE</head><p TEIform="p">'Tis easy to stand on a vessel's deck, On a vessel snug and trim, And watch the foam from her
                            flashing wake, And the rainbow bubbles swim ; 'Tis easy enough to climb the mast When hushed
                            the billows war, And zephyrs play With the pennon gay That floats from the highest spar.
                            'Tis another thing in the murky night, ¦ By the snaky lightning's glare, To climb and to
                            stand on the dizzy height, When the tempest's arm is bare ; When the masts are bending low
                            with the strain, And the canvas all is riven, And the angry blast Goes whirling past, And
                            the flying clouds of heaven. 'Tis easy enough to be brave and true, With nothing to set us
                            wrong ; "When the sky above is a cloudless blue, And the heart is full of song ; 'Tis
                            another thing when the stormy clouds Are darkening overhead, When the angel of wrath Stoops
                            o'er our path, And all about is lead.</p></div2><pb n="261" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sorting beans" TEIform="index"/>SORTING BEANS</head><p TEIform="p">A farmer's wife was busy Sorting beans. The good seemed hardly any, For the harvest time was
                            rainy. Bad for beans. The poor ones were so many, She was vexed and tired by picking Out bad
                            beans. For it took her many hours, And it tired her patience powers, Till she wished there
                            were no showers To spoil beans. Suddenly she stopped, and thinking Of the beans Now
                            finished, said with smiling : " What a fool to let the riling Come, the pleasant hours
                            beguiling, For bad beans. " When I come to have another Sorting beans, I will save me half
                            the trouble, And my pleasure will be double, While I burst the hideous bubble Of bad beans.
                            " For instead of always looking For bad beans, I will leave them, while with pleasure I will
                            gather out and treasure, Till I fill my little measure With good beans." There's a lesson
                            from this story — Sorting beans. Life is full of smiles and madness, Many griefs, and
                            sometimes gladness, Much of joy and more of Sadness — Like poor beans — And our work in life
                            is sorting, As with beans. We can go through life and end it, Leaving the best things, that
                            lend it Charms, and only spend it With bad beans. But there is a way that's better Sorting
                            beans. Choose the good, and when life closes There will be less thorns than roses, For the
                            garnered good disposes Of poor beans.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="That man is a bad preacher in the pulpit who..." TEIform="index"/>That man is a bad preacher in the pulpit who...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">That man is a bad preacher in the pulpit who is not a good preacher out of it ; and no man in
                            the world has a right to stand up for God, if God has not adorned him with personal
                            holiness. We should preach by what we are as well as by what we say.— Rowland Hill.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Secret" TEIform="index"/>THE SECRET</head><p TEIform="p">"I noticed," said Dr. Franklin, "a mechanic, among others, at work on a house erecting but a
                            little way from my office, who always appeared to be in a merry humor, who had a kind word
                            and cheerful smile for every one he met. Let the day be ever so cold, gloomy or sunless, a
                            happy smile danced like a sunbeam on his cheerful countenance. Meeting him one morning, I
                            asked him to tell me the secret of his happy flow of spirits. ' My secret, Doctor/ he
                            replied, ' is that I have got one of the best wives, and when I go to work she always has a
                            kind word of encouragement for me, and when I go home she meets me with a smile and a kiss,
                            and then tea is sure to be ready, and she has done so many things through the day to please
                            me, that I cannot find it in my heart to speak an unkind word to anybody.' What an influence
                            then, to soften the heart of man, a woman hath. To make it the fountain of cheerful and^pure
                            emotions ! Speak gently, then ; a happy smile and a kind word of greeting, after the toils
                            of the day are over, cost nothing, and go far toward making a home happy and peaceful."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mutual forebearance" TEIform="index"/>MUTUAL FORBEARANCE</head><p TEIform="p">No Christian grace is likely to be called into play more frequently than that of mutual
                            forbearance. If we resent every apparent injustice, demand the rightings of every little
                            wrong, and if all the other parties in the circle claim the same privilege, what miserable
                            beings we shall all be, and how wretched life will become ! We need to guard against a
                            critical spirit. Some people carry microscopes fine enough to reveal a million animalculge
                            in a drop of water, and with these they can find countless blemishes in the character and
                            conduct even of the most saintly dwellers on the earth. There are others who are always
                            watching for slights and grievances. They are suspicious of the motives and intentions of
                            others. They are always imagining offenses, even where none were most remotely intended.
                            This habit is directly at variance with the law of love, which thinketh no evil. — Week Day
                            Religion-</p></div2><pb n="262" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pilgrim's transition" TEIform="index"/>THE PILGRIM'S TRANSITION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, J. G." TEIform="persName"/>J. G. RUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p"> ENFIELD, N., H, 1. Take courage toiling pilgrim, 2. 0 do not fear nor falter, 3. Tho' called
                            to pass thro' waters, 4. And thro' the heated furnace, God's promises are sure: With zeal
                            pursue thy course; Engalfing billows swell, Tho' thou art called to pass. 4 Press on and
                            take the kingdom, The kingdom must be taken, Fear not to face the surges, Re fined as gold
                            of Ophir, Its boundless wealth secure; By violence and force, With thee it shall be well;
                            Thou shalt come forth at last; Earth's pleasures prove as bubbles, No giving back in terror,
                            Attending guardians ever Take courage then good pilgrim, They yield no lasting peace,
                            However great the foe; Will guide thy feeble barque, Affliction may be thine, But heaven's
                            gifts immortal Bring endless, rich increase. The Lord is thy Defender, His power thou shalt
                            know. And thou shalt find a refuge, Within the Gospel Ark. But in the realms supernal, With
                            glory thou shalt shine pa.</p></div2><pb n="263" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dream" TEIform="index"/>A DREAM</head><p TEIform="p">The next morning they entered on their mission. During the night one of the party had a
                            dream. He saw ten virgins clothed alike. Five of them were much engaged storing up in
                            vessels something that had the appearance of oil. I asked, what is that you are storing up ?
                            In a soft, kind tone the reply was : " It is the oil of the light of the coming
                            dispensation." The other five had also vessels, but instead of oil they were mostly filled
                            with earthy, gritty matter. All their vessels being about full they rested from their
                            labors. The shades of night began to gather over them, and they all fell fast asleep. About
                            midnight a great sound was heard. The angels of light warmth and growth sounded their
                            trumpets aloud, saying: "The two anointed ones who trod the wine-press alone have gained
                            another victory over the beast. Go ye out to meet them. Rejoice and be glad, for your
                            Redeemer lives." Those who had oil lit their lamps and joined in the rear of the advancing
                            procession. There was joy in every heart, and songs of gladness brightened every spirit.
                            Away in the distance I saw the heavens open to receive the weary yet joyous pilgrims. I
                            waited till all the glorious throng had entered the abode of bliss. The doors of heaven were
                            left freely open, but none could enter but those who had in their spirits the oil of the
                            light of the new dispensation. As the last of the procession entered I heard a voice saying:
                            "I am the beginning and the end of dispensations; work while it is day." Another voice
                            exclaimed: " The various dispensations throughout all the ages have been, and are, that evil
                            may perish from the earth, from the hearts of men." With reluctance I turned from this
                            joyous scene, every heart beating in unison with the fitness of created things, while the
                            social harmonies of angelic spheres welled up and flowed over with delight in the happiness
                            of the neighbor. Even the grass under .the feet of the heaven-bound throng seemed happy.
                            With a sad heart I sought my way back. The glories of the heavens had departed, and left me
                            in a gloom of more than Egyptian darkness. An angel of mercy appeared and led me to the
                            abode of those who were left behind. O, the darkness and the wailing ! I felt I could shrink
                            into nothing if they could but be relieved. I tried to soothe their troubled spirits, but I
                            found it was best to sit down and weep and wail with them. They upbraided one another, that
                            following this and that example was the cause of all this trouble. It gives me pain to think
                            of their revilings. I gathered enough to know that in the years past it was the will of God
                            that His chosen people should come to a further knowledge of His laws preparatory to the
                            coming dispensation ; they preferred not to be disturbed. Thus they left themselves in the
                            outer darkness, the very darkness they bewailed. Their wailing was so intense that a cold
                            shudder ran through me, and I awoke.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Philosophy outdone" TEIform="index"/>PHILOSOPHY OUTDONE</head><p TEIform="p">The assertion that simple and effective tests will expose all of the so-called physical
                            phenomena is denied by the Springfield Republican, which says; <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"An unbelieving person has produced his own slates, not merely hinged and locked,
                                    but actually screwed together ; has placed them on a table in his own house, at some
                                    distance from the medium ; has sat holding both the medium's hands beneath his own,
                                    and heard, as it seemed, the writing going on beneath the slate ; has taken away the
                                    slates unopennd, and the screws in the absence of the medium, to find the inside
                                    written full on both sides with what seemed to him words characteristic of one whom
                                    he knew to be dead."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Springfield republican" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Slave pompey's logic" TEIform="index"/>Slave Pompey's Logic</head><p TEIform="p">— " Pomp, when your master died, he left word in his will that you should be buried in his
                            vault." " I thanks you, ma'am," said Pomp, \" I thanks you for that ar ; but I'd rather
                            not." " Rather not, Pomp ! why ? " " 'Cause, missus, I'm feared that when the devil comes
                            for old massa, he might make a mistake and take old Pomp."</p></div2><pb n="264" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life within" TEIform="index"/>LIFE WITHIN</head><p TEIform="p">How hard it is to feel that the power of life is to be found inside, not outside; in the
                            heart and thoughts, not in the visible actions and show; in the living seed, not in the
                            plant which has no root ! How often do men cultivate the garden of their soul just the other
                            way ! How often do we try and persevere in trying to make a sort of neat show of outer good
                            qualities, without any thing within to correspond ; just like child ren who plant blossoms
                            without any roots in the ground, to make a pretty show for the hour ! We find fault in our
                            lives, and we cut off the weed, but we do not root it up ; we find something wanting in
                            ourselves, and we supply it not by sowing the divine seed of Heavenly principle, but by
                            copying the deeds that the principle ought to produce. Temple.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Impure water-toads and squirrels in wells" TEIform="index"/>IMPURE WATER-TOADS AND SQUIRREL
                            IN WELLS</head><p TEIform="p">The quantity and variety of filthy matter which is found deposited at the bottom of wells, in
                            some localities, are astonishing. We recently had occasion to examine the debris taken from
                            a well which had been cleaned the year previous, and among the accumulation were decaying
                            toads and squirrels. These creatures had been probably attracted by the water, to reach
                            which they had clambered down the wall till they reached the solid rock into which, for
                            several feet, the well had been excavated, when they were precipitated to the bottom, and
                            could not retrace their steps. To obviate a repetition of the same annoyance the stone well
                            has been removed down to the solid rock, relaid in hydraulic cement, and carried some three
                            feet above the surface of the ground and finished for some distance around the top with
                            cement underlaid with stones. On this solid foundation a curb has been so closely fitted as
                            to exclude even crickets and grasshoppers, which are so apt to find their way into wells. To
                            those who detest impure water and would avoid perhaps the sickness of an entire family, the
                            above plan, or the adoption of some better precaution against the contamination of wells, is
                            recommended. This is the season when springs and wells are usually low of water, and
                            therefore it is the best time for cleaning the bottom of the latter and repairing the walls
                            if found defective.—[Scientific American.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Extract from a vision" TEIform="index"/>EXTRACT FROM A VISION</head><p TEIform="p">" And I saw an angel flying in the midst of heaven, crying with a loud voice," Away with your
                            " dead body," which has hitherto obscured the sun of revelation. Jesus, a son of God,
                            standing upon the heights of time made an aperture into the spiritual heavens, and his
                            professed followers can no longer stuff his dead body into that aperture. And I saw
                            angels—disembodied humans — descend to earth ; and the spiritually blind received their
                            sight, and exclaimed " I see angels asT men walking." And as I passed down the broad avenue
                            leading to the depot I observed a " broad " and a " narrow way." The broad way only had a
                            gate ; significant that the broad way begins to have some barriers to unrestricted travel. I
                            thank God and take courage that the world is advancing to higher aims and ends — to true
                            religion — which is light and love, virtue and peace, unadulterated and immaculate.—
                            Prophet.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Comprehensive prayer" TEIform="index"/>A Comprehensive Prayer</head><p TEIform="p">. — Thomas a' Kempis, who died just one hundred years before the German reformation, is said
                            to be the author of this prayer, " Give me a clear understanding against all error, a clean
                            heart against all impurity, a right faith against all doubtfulness, a firm hope against all
                            difficulties, fervent charity against all indifference and negligence, great patience
                            against all disturbance, holy meditation against every filthy imagination, continual prayer
                            against the devil's assaults, good occupation against the tiresomeness and drowsiness of the
                            heart, and lastly, a devout remembrance of thy holy passion against the wounding of the soul
                            by .vices. Assist me, Oh ! my God, with all these, Thy good gifts, and confirm me in all Thy
                            holy words. Amen."—Alliance-</p></div2><!--
                    <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>