<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0609" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shakers, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><date value="18760901" TEIform="date">September 1876</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">65-72</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="65" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER Official Monthly.—Published by the United Societies. WHAT IS TRUTH P1 "THE KTKENAL
                        RKIJIlSrQTJISI3[M:E!3SrT OF ERROR." Vol. VI. G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR. \ SHAKERS, IY, SEPTEMBER,
                        1876, ' j No. 9. PUBLISHER.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our saviour" TEIform="index"/>OUR SAVIOUR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/>ELIJAH MYRICK</byline><p TEIform="p">Tins oft-repeated phrase, by force of tradition, centers the mind on the man Jesus, as the
                            Saviour. Ho was, indeed, one of the world's saviours, by living and teaching " the way, the
                            truth and the life." The power of salvation has always been trusted to the perishable arks
                            of human frailty. Hence the eternal progress of truth and light cannot be taken upon the
                            authority of any individual as a finalty ; though they may lead in the way, and become
                            saviours, by their precepts and examples of holy living. It is not sufficient authority that
                            Jesus, or any one, predicated their rule of life upon certain principles ; the basis of
                            these principles — the result of so living — the cause and effect as exemplified in their
                            lives, is the only test — the evidence for an acceptable pattern and guide. With all due
                            respect to the individual, the prophet, it is ours to understand the primary moving cause,
                            as our rule of action, our saviour, as really as they. "And why, even of yourselves, judge
                            ye not what is right?" What Christianity has done for one mortal, it can do for another. The
                            interior germ of Christ is as indestructible as God — the foundation — the star of hope that
                            never sets. It needs the heavenly, the divine atmosphere to develop it into life and growth.
                            And they who have been most baptized ; who have ascended nearest the apex of human
                            possibilities, are saviours, inasmuch as by precept and example they draw others up to their
                            attained elevation. We see in the Christian dispensation an important evolution in human
                            progress, the resurrection from the natural, the rudimental, to the spiritual, the angelic ;
                            and in it is God's divine economy to check excess of population, no more to "destroy men's
                            lives, but to save them." We see in that divinely-inspired Hebrew youth, a man, a right true
                            man, obedient to a higher law; in no sense a celestial, aborigian exotic, transplanted to
                            earth. But the then highest, mortal type of the divine — a noble man — becomes a " son of
                            God." Dependence on past saviours has ever been the bane of individual advancement.
                            Salvation and propitiation rested in the hands of mediators long ago departed. Orphans
                            clinging to the garments of their ancestors, hoping to extract life from what once covered
                            the living: accepting embalmed virtue for the bread and waters of life; for pastures,
                            cultivated fields, forever green. With such a sense of dependence, of infancy, where is the
                            growth into full Christian stature? WThere the voice of courage and aggression against the
                            citadel of sin ? Are not those saviours who bear the ark of the covenant of truth in their
                            own hands ? Who overcome the world and walk in the way of the truth and the light ? Those
                            who go down into the waters, and uplift fallen humanity, and minister to them till they arc
                            also lifted up — saved ? Such are saviours, present saviours, whose lives are so many
                            monuments of heroic manliness, and holy living, to mark how high the tides of divine life
                            have risen on earth. It bids us take courage, and be glad, for what man has done, he may do:
                            " yea, and greater works." For God is not exhausted, nor the fount of inspiration dried up.
                            By obedience to Christ — the divine, inherent in man, Jesus became a son of God. And to all
                            who look, for his second appearing, I would say, "Already Christ is come." Christ has
                            appeared in " a cloud " of living witnesses for truth, who have exchanged the world for
                            heaven's diviner truths, and are working for the growth of their souls. Jesus gave us the
                            proof-sheet of his best endeavors. Let us read it with the eye of reason, and hearken with
                            the ear of understanding ; and with him go on to perfection, singing the song of
                            never-ending joy. Such are the world's saviours. Harvard, Mass,</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Discipline of goodness" TEIform="index"/>DISCIPLINE OF GOODNESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Erickson, Larz" TEIform="persName"/>LARZ ERICKSON</byline><p TEIform="p">What is it to be good ! How does the goodness of the heart reveal itself? A man or a woman
                            that obtains the goodness of the heart is, in a great measure, a saviour. Soft, mild and
                            kind words are the signs that proceed from a pure heart. A pure heart is like a good spring,
                            always full. And it is noticed far and wide that many come to drink, and gain strength, so
                            long as the heart, as water, keeps clean. But if the spring gives dirty water, people lose
                            their desire for it, and soon none will visit it to be refreshed. The same with a man and
                            woman called out from the world to be saviours. If they become offended, and speak harsh and
                            bitter words, they do great harm to themselves and others. Let us watch and keep our spirits
                            pure ; then we will save many souls and be happy in our saving element. Let us labor to know
                            ourselves as we are, and strive daily to live like our Christian pattern. Then we will think
                            more of our brethern and sisters than of ourselves. Let us not be self-righteous ; it is not
                            the safe way to find fault with almost everybody but ourselves. They that gain the most
                            purity and goodness of heart, find the most fault with themselves, and very little with
                            others. They are the most able to fulfill the law of Christ: "Esteeming others more than
                            themselves." Pleasant Hill, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Is woman any longer responsible?" TEIform="index"/>IS WOMAN ANY LONGER RESPONSIBLE?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, Ruth" TEIform="persName"/>RUTH WEBSTER</byline><p TEIform="p">Ever since Adam and Eve were expelled from the Garden of Eden, woman has had to bear the
                            reproach of leading mankind into sin. About one hundred years ago God raised up a woman, and
                            endowed her with wisdom to bring forth a testimony by which mankind might be led out of sin.
                            Many thousands have realized its efficacy. Henceforth, let every one who continues in sin
                            after hearing the gospel testimony, bear the reproach himself, and not cast it on woman. ]f
                            mankind had been as ready to have been led out as into sin, long, ere this, lewdness would
                            have ceased in the land, and long since, war would have been no more. Unum Village, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritualism" TEIform="index"/>SPIRITUALISM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">The Ruling Church, when it believed in Spiritualism, persecuted Spiritualism as witchcraft
                            and necromancy. It ceased to persecute Spiritualism only when it ceased to believe in its
                            verity. The skepticism, or infidelity of Protestantism shut the door to the Spirit world —
                            declared the canon of scripture closed — that all revelation had ceased. The Holy Scriptures
                            — to be translated, revised and interpreted by the priesthood — remaining as the only guide
                            and rule of faith and practice. When Protestant infidelity had thus abjured present
                            revelation — denied its very existence, for either miracle or mischief, denied the existence
                            of ghosts, or disembodied spirits, it affirmed that the dead lay buried in the soil of earth
                            till the last trump should sound. Illogically, Protestants did believe in the devil and his
                            imps, as the source of witchcraft. They hung, burned and tortured men, women and children,
                            as real spiritual mediums. Yet did not believe in Christ Prophets and Prophetesses, whom God
                            raised up to rebuke their own sorceries and murders. Protestantism is Infidelity — Atheism
                            in its childhood. It was skepticism — Rationalism — not Christianity — that in the Church
                            finally stopped the persecution of Spiritualists, in Old, as in New England. On the last
                            trial for witchcraft, a woman accused of walking on her head, Judge Mansfield decided that
                            she could so walk, if she chose, as no English law was thereby violated. When the angel of
                            Spiritualism has, by his great power, confounded Church unbelief and infidelity, what will
                            deter thai Church, if it possess the civil power, from treating Spiritualism as witchcraft,
                            or necromancy ? SHAKER VILLAGE, III. <pb n="66" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 66 With the same faith and the
                            same power as of old, the Church will make blood flow to the horses' bridles. Spiritualism
                            ie furnishing the faith, and the Church works with indomitable energy to marry the state to
                            gain the power. The People of these United States are like the dwellers upon the sides of
                            Mt. Vesuvius. They await the upheaval of the internal fires and forces that will spread
                            desolation far and wide. Let the Vesuvians remove from the mountain ; and let the United
                            States citizens remove all Bibles from Public Schools — all Priests from public Institutions
                            — Legislative Halls, Courts, Army and Navy, and it will be well. Otherwise, it is only a
                            matter of time, when all are crying Peace and Safety, that sudden and overwhelming
                            destruction will come upon this great American Republic.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tell-tale compass" TEIform="index"/>"THE TELL-TALE COMPASS."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gorham, Theodore" TEIform="persName"/>THEODORE GORHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">Vessels in the merchant service plying year after year from one port to another, find it of
                            great advantage to sail in as direct a line as is practically possible; for on the ocean as
                            on land " time is money." Charts are prepared with great care, and furnished to Vessels,
                            showing the most direct, that is, the shortest course to take in order to reach a given
                            destination. It is a known fact that some of the lines of ocean steamers plying between New
                            York and Liverpool make the trip month after month and do not vary one mile out of a given
                            path. This would be an impossibility were it not for the mariner's compass. I shall not go
                            into details about the compass, as all understand the principle on which it is constructed,
                            but I will say that few except those who have tried it, know what vigilance and
                            concentration of mind to say nothing of the physical labor it requires on the part of the
                            man at the wheel to keep the needle pointing in a given direction in spite of tides and
                            counter-currents for two and sometimes four consecutive hours. On board of well-regulated
                            packets none but first-class seamen are allowed to steer the vessel, for every time the
                            vessel goes even one point out of the way for a short time, it delays the ship just so much
                            on her journey and she is just so much longer in reaching port. It used to be the custom and
                            is still on many ships, thought necessary for the officers of the deck to occasionally look
                            at the compass to ascertain if the wheelsman was faithfully performing his duty, but lately
                            there has been devised what has been called by sailors the "Tell-tale Compass." This is
                            fastened or hung overhead to the ceiling of the officer's cabin, face downward, the card of
                            this compass is changed diametrically opposite on account of being inverted in order to make
                            it agree with the compass on deck. The officer has only to cast his eye up to this "
                            tell-tale" in order to know how the ship heads, and if the poor sailor who may not have
                            closed his eyes for the last twenty-four hours should neglect his duty for one minute, he
                            might be informed of it in language not selected from scripture or the rules of the
                            fastidious Chesterfield, but in a language which you will understand when I say is peculiar
                            to sea captains. Moral : We all have a vessel to steer through the ocean of life, let us
                            endeavor in spite of counter-currents and adverse winds to keep our ship straight in the
                            path of rectitude, that the master when he looks into our hearts—"the tell-tale compass" —
                            may ever find us faithful to our charge. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Try again" TEIform="index"/>"TRY AGAIN."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Neal, Sarah A." TEIform="persName"/>SARAH A. NEAL</byline><p TEIform="p">If the first attempt to accomplish a noble purpose proves a failure, " try again." Could
                            every one be made aware that the road to success led through a country of failures, much of
                            the despair that now blights the zeal of very many because their first efforts do not prove
                            successful ones, would be blown away by the breezes of new endeavors. It would not indicate
                            that our individuality was defective, should many failures crown our exertions for superior
                            development; but our inability would become apparent, did we permit ourselves to submit to
                            the morbid influences of non-exertion because some trifling obstacle seemed, for the time
                            being, to impede our early, intended success. Little satisfaction can come home to the inert
                            soul, who moves not a willing body in the cause of right. What if our attempts prove only
                            failures many times ; perseverance will finally lift us to the summit of success, for they
                            who labor truly, labor to win, even though their day of victory be afar, and no good
                            achievements have been secured, without costing some one very much ardent labor. What phase
                            of life could we present, in this, our centennial year, if there had not been some unusually
                            persevering minds, and toiling hands to develop the present status of tilings, of which our
                            country is now so proud to exhibit ? And what had been our gospel cause, if some individuals
                            had not possessed the fortitude to defend Christian principles, against the opposition which
                            is always sure to arise when any advancement is made as an innovation in a new direction ?
                            Surely we could hardly have boasted of present growth toward the angelic life, had not
                            successive trials paved the way to even our present acquirements So let " try again " be our
                            first thought, after having failed to succeed in carrying out any good undertaking, even
                            though we repeat our purpose many times. At least, may we all keep trying, until we achieve
                            that one victory over self, which will be more than equal to many failures in any scientific
                            pursuit. And we need not despair, should we fail to realize this attainment until after this
                            life's ultimate; even then we can lay by our mortality in peace, for over death's river our
                            banners of victory would greet us, encouraging a continual and eternal "try again."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dogmatist's creed" TEIform="index"/>THE DOGMATIST'S CREED</head><p TEIform="p">Believe as T believe — no more, no less ; That I am right, and no one else, confess; Peel as
                            I feel; think only as I think; Bat what I eat, and drink but what I drink ; Look as I look;
                            do always as I do, And then, and only then, I'll fellowship with you. That i am right, and
                            always right, I know, Because my owu convictions tell me so ; And to be right is simply this
                            : To be Entirely, in all respects, like me. To deviate a hair's breath, or begin To
                            question, and to doubt, Or hesitate, is sin. I reverence the Bible, if it be Translated
                            first, and then explained — by mo. By churchly laws and customs I abido, Tf they with my
                            opinions coincide. All creeds and doctrines I concedo divine, Excepting those, of course,
                            Which disagree with mine. Let sink the drowning, if he will not swim Upon the plank that I
                            throw out to him ; Let starve the hungry, if he will not oat My kind and quantity of broad
                            and meat; Let freeze the naked, if he will not be Clothed in such garments As are cut for
                            me. 'Twere better that the sick should die than live, Unless they take the medicine T give;
                            'Twere better sinners perish than refuse To be conformed to my peculiar views, 'Twere better
                            that the world stand still than move In any other way Than that which I approve.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/>PRAYER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ross, Ellen" TEIform="persName"/>ELLEN ROSS</byline><p TEIform="p">Prayer is the guide to self-knowledge; inclining us to look after our errors in order to pray
                            against them. It is a motive that prompts us to vigilance, teaching us to guard against
                            those errors, which through self-examination we are enabled to detect. Prayer is an act
                            prompted by the heart, and is to me one of the most sacred of subjects. Along the pathway of
                            life, through our frequent waywardness, we are forced to acknowledge our dependence on
                            holier influences, and thus we are inclined to ask aid of our heavenly Parents to assist us
                            in resisting evil and doing good instead. As the tree, shrub or tender plant without the aid
                            of air, moisture or sunlight bears neither blossom nor fruit, so must it bo with an
                            individual who breathes no fresh atmosphere of hope ; is watered by no reviving and
                            sustaining influences of prayer, neither warmed into life by the sunlight of confiding love
                            through prayer. When I reflect upon the great ocean of human life, which, though governed by
                            intelligence, has waves more turbulent, rocks and shoals more dangerous, then the vast ocean
                            of waters that covers so much of the globe, I cannot suppress a feeling of gratitude to God
                            that each and all may, through earnest intercession, realize strength and courage, equal to
                            their needs. Prayer appears to me to be a beautiful law of our being ; necessary to the
                            spirit's growth into higher conditions, and away from the mere sensual plane. Christ
                            exhorted his disciples to " pray without ceasing lest they enter into temptation ;" and is
                            it any the less needful that his followers now should enter into^the same earnest, prayerful
                            spirit ? Have we not to resist the temptations to sin as did the disciples of old 1 Surely
                            in our present day of trial, we need to implore the Parent of love to open the fountains of
                            truth and light to us. That soul which has been sustained by the sweet influences of prayer,
                            is not content with its own spiritual well-being, but cheerfully exerts its noblest energies
                            to bring others to the true light. It has been said, "_" the prayers of the righteous avail
                            much." Have we not a few righteous souls among us ? And if these, not having the ability to
                            preach, would offer up their sincere and earnest prayers to God, for those who have not the
                            night, and know not the way, would not their prayers avail something? Would not a rich
                            blessing attend them ? I certaiuly feel so. The sincere prayer, humbly offered, gives reT H
                            K S H J± K E R . <pb n="67" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> lief to the tried soul, peace to the turbulent mind,
                            and gladness to an aching, sorrowing heart. I speak too, from my own experience ; for often
                            when I have felt my own weakness, and trials rolled roughly along my pathway, I have looked
                            to the Divine source for strength to resist the current of temptation that swept over me.
                            Often-times I have felt to exclaim, ''Sweet is the hour of prayer." Had I not faith in
                            prayer, and did I not place my confidenco in God, I am sure, long ere this my frail bark
                            would have been overwhelmed by the waves of fierce temptation, and have been driven far from
                            the peaceful shores upon which I now stand. " Sweet is the holy hour of prayer." Union
                            Village, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Parental call" TEIform="index"/>PARENTAL CALL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES G. RUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">Not in thy strength alone, thou feeble one, Wilt thou the powers of darkness overcome ; But
                            in the strength of Him who reigns on High, Thou needst not fear to meet the enemy. For thou
                            wilt surely conquer, and no power Can thee withstand in that victorious hour. The Lord
                            Jehovah is thy sure defense, His word is Truth, His strength Omnipotence. Go forth to battle
                            with thine armor on, And never cease the strife till victory 's won. The Lord hath called
                            thee to this glorious strife ; Be true, and thou shalt win Eternal Life. RESPONSE. The
                            solemn call which now to me is given, To cheer me on to my sweet home in heaven, I will not
                            slight; nor waste my precious time In worldly follies that would bar the mind From purity,
                            and things that are of God ; But I will walk the path my Saviour trod, And in his love abide
                            : — rememb'ring now To seal by faithfulness, my earnest vow, To walk with Christ: —to turn
                            not from the way. However dark and gloomy seems the day, Nor when temptation, with its
                            charming smile, Would tarry near, my footsteps to beguile. But I will think of Jesus, at the
                            hour When Satan sought, with feigned display of power, To make the lowly Nazarene a slave To
                            his vile shrine, — the answer Jesus gave Was " Get behind me, Satan! " Vict'ry gained 1 Our
                            blessed Jesus, spotless, still remained; Nor did the tempter tarry longer near, But
                            instantly withdrew : then did appear The angel ministers of love divine, And Jesus'
                            countenance again did shine With greater radiance, even, than before ! And in his Father's
                            name, the ensign bore, Of peace and good will unto suff'ring men. And I will also think of
                            Jesus, when On Calvary's height, his mission full to seal, He suffered martyrdom, with none
                            to heal, Or even soothe his agonizing wounds, Nor heed with pitying ear his dying groans !
                            "0 Father," then he prayed, with all in view, " Forgive them, for they know not what they
                            do." And thus, by cruel hands he suffered, bled ; A crown of plaited thorns upon his head, —
                            On either side, through mock'ry, scorn and hate, Two vagrant sufferers sharing, each, his
                            fate One weeps— repents-— and unto Jesus cries, And is, that hour, with him in Paradise! O
                            boundless grace ! this lesson here we learn, The vilest sinner may to God return ! These
                            solemn thoughts awaken in my breast, Emotion's deep, of unfeigned gratefulness, And earnest
                            feelings to endure the strife. Whatever be the cost: a carnal life Is requisite for
                            sacrifice, to find That better life — eternal and divine. And this shall be the burden of my
                            day, To walk as Jesus walked — to watch and pray. Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If we are annoyed by noticing that others watch our conduct..." TEIform="index"/>If we are annoyed by noticing that others watch our conduct...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">If we are annoyed by noticing that others watch our conduct, it is a sign that our conduct
                            may be improved, by our properly watching it ourselves.Shakers, N. Y. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Langridge, James" TEIform="persName"/>Jas. Langridge</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes by the way, no. 3" TEIform="index"/>NOTES BY THE WAY—NO. 3</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">Choice op Language:—While we cherish with fondness, the hope that the future will abound in
                            the perfected gifts of our kind Heavenly Father, we cannot wholly throw off the pressing
                            responsibilities of the present, which are really the stepping-stones to that state of
                            millennial blessedness. The beautiful adornings which the Christian graces so abundantly
                            proffer to us, are greatly enhanced by the careful cultivation of every department of the
                            mind. While we admire all that gives to it tone or character, we have at this time chosen to
                            dwell more particularly upon the right use of Language, As the object of all Christian
                            teaching is to encourage a cultivation of the better qualities of man, it would seem that
                            great care should be exercised in the selection of the words which we speak or write. We
                            should study to so express ourselves, that we may favorably impress those who dwell within
                            the circle of our influence. It is too often the case that reverential subjects are sadly
                            mutilated by the introduction of coarse and even vulgar expressions. Instead of carefully
                            selecting from the thousands of words those which will induce an elevating conception, and
                            upon which we may look with pleasure, even as upon the heavenly constellations, we are too
                            often treated with the very reverse. Like the florist, who, among his beautiful flowers,
                            cultivates those which are unsightly and even noxious, simply because they are more readily
                            obtained. Our Father, through one of His prophets, has said, " I will turn to my people a
                            pure language." A language, ah, a language that men and angels may use and not be ashamed.
                            Why should we not do all in our power to have this prophecy fulfilled in our lives t In this
                            we work with the Lord for His honor and our peace. Defective orthography and false syntax
                            are far preferable to the coarse and undisciplined manner of speaking, which enters so
                            largely into our conversation. Why use the refuse of language any more than the refuse of
                            food ? It is contaminating not only to the breath of the speaker, but to the ears and mind
                            of the hearer. Let us study simplicity, not affectation, and write and speak as we would in
                            the presence of the angels of God. If the subject is upon that which is spiritual, heavenly
                            — the language should correspond. Every sentence should be infused with the spirit of the
                            beatitudes, and every word chosen with that care which the theme demands. If the inspiration
                            of prayer becomes the leading object of the mind, pray also that a reverential spirit may
                            dictate the expres sions which are made, lest we betray ourselves in speaking or writing
                            that of which the ungodly will be ashamed. Avoid extremes. How beautifully and peacefully
                            some will lead us along up through wisdom's path of pleasantness to the very gates of the
                            New Jerusalem, and then in one breath dash us among the swine, and to their wallowing in the
                            mire. If perchance we are led to speak or write of the lake which burneth, as some say, with
                            brimstone and fire, no less care should be exercised than in the preceding. . There can be
                            no propriety in the careless use of words, even in the denunciation of that which is
                            obnoxious to the spirit of the pure in heart. Shaker Village, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progress: multum in parvo" TEIform="index"/>PROGRESS: MULTUM IN PARVO</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fonda, J. Jesse" TEIform="persName"/>J. JESSE FONDA</byline><p TEIform="p">Love is life. Harmony is heaven — only in a heavenly state of mind, can heaven come to any.
                            Jesus' prayers brought angels to him, not to us. Jesus' merits saved him. Our merits will
                            save us. Each soul is a manger, cradling a saviour—God in us. The blood of one cannot atone
                            for the sin of another. Good results can only flow from being good. Every thing seems to
                            have been formed spheroidal— having a mundane and spiritual existence — a principle to pass
                            from one sphere to another. The highest spherical attainment culminates in the acme of
                            wisdom — God — and is the throne, whence comes all law of heaven. Keeping the law of the
                            sphere occupied must result in the highest happiness of that sphere. Violation of law is
                            sin, and brings hell to the participant. The Christ follower is a progressive being, passing
                            on from sphere to sphere. He travails, and by practical demonstrations ignites " a refining
                            fire" — ending in regeneration — thorough spirituality. Each stage of progression, being an
                            advance from the one abandoned, must not only enjoy all the light that preceded it, but must
                            combine with the new light, forming another series, and causing an iridescent atmosphere,
                            that introduces new laws of government, expanded views of true enjoyment; new actions,
                            thought, language — the gross having passed " the refining fire" and appears as " tried
                            gold." There are a vast number of " hermeneutics" who desire us to adopt their peculiar ways
                            of thinking; but it is preferable to let inspiration be its own solvent, and by fulfilling
                            the laws of the highest sphere to which we have attained, exercise our acknowledged right to
                            "prove all things and hold fast to that which is good." Sonyea, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unselfish love" TEIform="index"/>UNSELFISH LOVE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/>J. M. PEEBLES</byline><p TEIform="p">The tendency of the spiritually minded is from grossness to refinement — from promiscuity to
                            chastity — from chastity to holiness — from holiness to divinity. The higher the moral
                            ambition, the more complete and victorious the virtue ! This Adauiic battle-ground cleared,
                            the kingdom of God has come with its newness of life — "Not according to the ilesh, but
                            according to the spirit." The Apostle John declared that he had passed from death unto life;
                            because he loved the brethren. 27iis love can never degenerate into license, nor its liberty
                            into anarchy ; for it is a principle, disrobed of earthly passion — a holy resurrection. All
                            men are my brothers; all women my sisters; all children my children ; and I am every
                            mortal's child. Deep is our interest in every infant born into earth life. Its destiny is
                            linked with ours,and our love flows to it free, to all humanity free as God's sunlight. Let,
                            then, our country be the universe ; our home the world ; our religion to do good ; our rest
                            wherever a human heart beats in harmony with ours ; and our desire be to enkindle in the
                            breasts of earth's millions the fires of aspiration, aiding them in their progress up the
                            acclivities of life, even to the very gate of heaven. Let all the love that can be attracted
                            THE SHAKER. 67 <pb n="68" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 68 THE SHAKER. from our inmost being be appropriated by
                            the poor, and the crushed, and the needy, and the fallen — by you, the world, the angels.
                            Then will be actualized the words of Jesus — "All mine are thine, and thine are mine."
                            During that precious pentecostal hour, when the divine afflatus streamed down in rivers of
                            light from angelic abodes, not only " many believed," but they were so baptized into those
                            unselfish loves of the spiritual world that they resolved to " have all things in common."
                            When these universal loveprinciples are made practical the soil will be as free to all to
                            cultivate as the air they breathe ; gardens will blossom and bear fruitage for the poor, and
                            orphans will find homes in all houses, there drawn by the music of tenderest sympathy; the
                            brows of toiling millions be wreathed with white roses — symbols of perpetual peace.</p></div2><div2 type="music" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Music, no. 9" TEIform="index"/>MUSIC, NO. 9</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, J. G." TEIform="persName"/>J. G. RUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">Rhythm resumed. — Allusion being made to various methods of time-keeping,that of counting
                            comes next for consideration. This method is executed by allowing an equal space of time to
                            elapse between every two counts. Then, with a fore-knowledge of the proper length of tones,
                            ability may be acquired for measuring them by the more preferable way of counting the time,
                            as by this method the mind is forced to perform its office, and but little chance given for
                            counterfeit rhythm. Singers, who practice this method, acquire the ability to keep the time
                            for themselves, and, therefore, need but little assistance aside from themselves while in
                            the practical performance of music. As this method seems most reliable in its results, but
                            little would need to be said of others, such as the use of various kinds of instruments,
                            invented for the purpose. To be brief upon the subject, it might be asserted that any method
                            adopted, that would force the mind to execute its work, would be preferable to one that
                            simply addresses itself to the eye, leaving the singer but little more proficient in the art
                            than if he had received no tuition at all. As evidence of this assertion, take, for example,
                            certain points in the simplest elements of musical science. The quarter rest (p) requires
                            the same amount of time, in its use, as does a quarter note; but being a space of silence is
                            but little regarded, as many singers seem to get the impression that a piece of music must,
                            of necessity, be one continuous prolongation of tone from beginning to end! Again, the
                            relative length of notes — in many cases — is but little regarded, especially the dotted
                            quarter, and dotted eighth, which, in Even Time, are generally followed by the eighth and
                            sixteenth; but little notice is taken of the fact that the dotted quarter and eighth, when
                            together, should have the same time as would two quarter notes; or that the dotted eighth
                            and sixteenth should have the same time as two eighths, but the former, though written | " ^
                            is often performed * * p, while the latter, though written j ^, is performed I , the time in
                            both cases being mutilated by non-observance of the relative length of notes. It lias ceased
                            to become a mystery in the mind of the writer, why organists and pianists— as a whole — are
                            so much more proficient in rhythm than vocalists seem to be, when the fact is apparent that
                            counting is almost as conspicuous as fingering in their lessons of practice. One more point,
                            in brief, and we leave, for the present, the subject of rhythm. The term measure — according
                            to its general acceptation — is the space between the bars. Primarily, their number of kinds
                            is four, viz.: Double, Triple, Quadruple and Sextuple. The variety of forms these measures
                            often assume are puzzling obstacles for singers to meet. Three of the measures have each
                            three forms, while the fourth has four. (See illustration.) While no satisfactory reason has
                            ever been given for this seemingly useless variety of forms, the writer is much inclined to
                            the opinion of one prominent professor of music (A. _ZV. Johnson), who neither theoretically
                            nor practically — if memory serves correctly) — recognizes more than one form in each kind
                            of measure,—which form he designates by the figure denoting the number of counts in the
                            measure; which in Double is marked 2, in Triple 3, etc.,with the exception of Sextuple,
                            which is marked ^". In this measure the singer takes the eighth note (J) as the standard
                            count note — making six counts in the measure, or, if preferable, making two counts in the
                            measure, by allowing the time of three eighths to one count; whereas, in the other measures
                            the quarter note is invariably the standard count; and by this method the afflicting
                            obstacle is easily removed. ILLUSTKATION. Triple. Quadruple. Sextuple. Double measure.
                            tlfl**iltttl*ttV4 Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER. Monthly —60 cents per annum. A DUAL ADVOCATE OF CIIRIST PRINCIPLES.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tone of the churches" TEIform="index"/>THE TONE OF THE CHURCHES</head><p TEIform="p">Tins age is not termed a religious age; but we are assured that we live in a time, when
                            genuine religion was never more prevalent than now. This evidence is manifested by the
                            liberality so redundant, almost everywhere. Should Moody and Sankey prove failures
                            otherwise, they must ever stand as the correct thermometers of the religious feelings of
                            to-day. Wherever they have gone, the silent prayers of Moody, and the sweet songs of Sankey
                            have taken the people by storm — a storm they have been waiting for a long time — a storm
                            which even royalty has succumbed to, and which means, a storm, against which " the gates of
                            hell " do not yet know how to prevail! Royalty and Peasantry alike have paid their tributes;
                            and we common people, who live between, have clapped our hands and been very joyous over
                            such an event. We have exclaimed: — " The Millennium is Coming ;" and when the misanthrope
                            has said: " So is Christmas," we have set the sails of our Patience to wait so long. We have
                            clapped our hands, and said " Amen ! " just like any Methodist, and " Oloky to God," and "
                            So be it," have not been uncommon nor idle expressions. We have clapped our hands, and said
                            " God Bless!" — any and everyone who will break down these aristocratic barriers to true
                            religion — fine sense and " our church " — and we stand ready to " leap with joy " at the
                            expected evidences of liberality that shall say: " We do not care what you believe, if you
                            are honest. Are you sincerely seeking the Christ? If your lives bespeak for you the evidence
                            that Christ is with you, away with all man made tenets, barriers and partitions. Let us take
                            hands upon the Christ life; let us live it, at any, every expense of ourselves and our
                            particular church, and Amen !" is the universal chorus. And now more than ever seems to be
                            the cry : " Let us love Jesus," and " Live like Jesus ;" and " Live with Jesus!" recognizing
                            the truth, that if we ever live with Jesus, we must live like Him. Never was Spiritualism so
                            dull, nor Methodism so equipendent; Episcopalianism has used up its reserve; and
                            Presbyterianism experienced all, and more than it wanted of the closest communion ; while
                            Con gregationalism finds there is something besides its idols to worship — to live and to
                            die for! The Baptists are living — for better purposes,— they love their neighbors better;
                            while the various this and thai of theology bring up the rear of chorus, that the millennium
                            ia so near. If we go to the Celestial Empire, we are pleased with its progress and salutes ;
                            and we are assured that Mohammedan will soon kisa the Greek Church with other than lips of
                            blood. The Tenor of the Churches means a religious peace — a cessation, even an
                            indifference, to the most selfish theology. As Jews, as Christians, as Mohammedans, as
                            Protestants, Catholics, and as Siiakeks, we are nearly ready to agree, that he or she who
                            lives the best life, is the best man or woman, and the best representative religionist,</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="By whose authority?" TEIform="index"/>BY WHOSE AUTHORITY?</head><p TEIform="p">Hero aro some Shaker lladicals. However unpleasant, are they true? Ciiiustianity that is
                            popular to-day ia very unlike the original. Reveling in the name, the majority of men and
                            women live no better than before the introduction of Christianity. Do they live nearly as
                            well ? Christianity intended the conversion of Jews and Gentiles. Prom what? Jesus called
                            the fisher men. Some were married, some were not. Jesus taught marriage to be good under
                            Judaism ; but there was something better to be observed under Christianity. Consequently,
                            the unmarried entered a chaste, Christian virginity — so did the married — and all became as
                            brethren and sisters. Those who had private, personal property, " great possessions," gave
                            to the poor — shared their substance with the church, and became no more wealthy than its
                            poorest members. It was the glory of the Jews to war. Jesus taught the only good of war, and
                            of any retaliation whatever, to have been prior to the " new gospel" he was commissioned to
                            introduce. Before Jesus, the Church and Caesar were one. Jesus urged a distinction. Popular
                            Christianity has revoked these credentials. It makes a sacrament of marriage — destroying
                            even the appearance of virginity. By whose authority ? <pb n="69" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE 69 Men of "
                            great possessions " are invited and needed by it; and the comparative pittance they bestow
                            upon the poor does not change the complexion of the distinction of rich and poor found among
                            the churches. By whose authority are the rich men and women retained in any Christian
                            church? By whose authority must the poor continue to share so unequally? War is a very
                            respectable feature of modern Christianity, so called. During invasion or rebellion popular
                            Christianity has made Peace, and Peace Societies disreputable. Captains, Colonels and
                            Generals of unchristian, savage war, are the ornaments of churches called Christian.
                            Soldiers carry the New Testament in their knapsacks — presented by war-loving Bible
                            Societies — which scriptures particularly applaud and teach of the Prince of Peace, whose "
                            servants do not, will not fight;" yet these same soldiers are taught by their churches and
                            chaplains, not to " forgive their enemies" until after they have killed them! The American
                            Peace (?) Society, during the late rebellion, found itself obnoxious to the churches ; and
                            it " Resolved; That we call this no war, but a merited castigation upon a slaveholding,
                            rebellious community!" "No war," indeed! Again, we call attention : The popular Christianity
                            of to-day is not genuine Christianity. It does not "follow me" — Jesus. It is not a virgin j
                            church, but violates, by its sacraments, rather j than protects and preserves virginity. It
                            fostera pride and lust, riches and poverty — i and these have ever transformed the true !
                            church into a devil's harem. By whose authority are there rich and poor members of any
                            church called Christian? We need a Jesus, with a power equal to " a whip made of large
                            cords." The popular churches of today compose and present an unequaled Babylon— mixture of
                            church and State — and almost complete expulsion of genuine Christianity. This is a thinking
                            age. People will no longer be hoodwinked by priestly paraphernalia and craft. They begin to
                            see the errors of man-made creeds — ambushes of unmeaning words — by which selfish, ungodly
                            men have led the people blindly — forsaking the true faith, under pay of the devil and the
                            applause of the people. " Oh, that He would come," and ask the popular churches in " the
                            broad way," by whose authority, the pattern — the Church of Pentecost — has been so
                            completely reversed ? Men and women! think of these things, as applying to us individually.
                            The Church of Christ will ever be unpopular with those who love not the life of Jesus well
                            enough to live it — yet, "they that are ashamed of me, and of my words, of them I will be
                            ashamed." Herein is presented the radical testimony of Shakerism against popular, worldly
                            Christianity. Is it needed ? Will it be heeded? Will not the people awake to honesty,
                            denying not Christ, but themselves, and ask with us, BY WHOSE AUthority the order of the
                            christian Church has been so thoroughly reversed ? </p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="That crow question" TEIform="index"/>THAT CROW QUESTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">In Aug. No. of Shaker, we defended our course in regard to the Crow — its extermination from
                            gardens and cornfields, etc. Using Cowper's rule, we believe still, that it and our course
                            were tenable and correct. But as there is too little kindness in the world, and we had all
                            better suffer more wrong than do any, we extract from a private letter, the following from
                            Elder F. W. Evans, which he undoubtedly wrote with many dry smiles : * * * « Think you wrong
                            on the Crow question I A more thorough knowledge of that bird, his habits, food, etc., would
                            make you his friend. The author of the " Vestiges of Creation," places the crow, as the bird
                            of greatest variety and capacity — a typical bird. There is not much that passes for food
                            among the birds and beasts, that the crow will not eat. Is capable of high culture — can
                            talk in case of necessity, like a parrot — can steal like a man! But on principle, the crow
                            is the farmers' friend. Plenty of crows, no mice, no snakes, no vermin, no potato bugs.
                            Crows are better than Paris-green. This is fit only for antichristians' use. Let the crow
                            live and your own life will be more secure. We shoot no birds to save our seeds and
                            cherries. They eat the insects and worms out of such productions, thus saving them."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Insects, children, and cats" TEIform="index"/>INSECTS, CHILDREN AND CATS</head><p TEIform="p">In France, the Minister of Public Instruction, Mr. Waddington, appreciating the effect of
                            combined and widely-extended action upon the prevalence of insect pests, issued a circular
                            to the schools of i the country, wherein is described in forcible terms the serious results
                            which will ensue if the insect j tribe is to continue to revel with impunity ; and
                            especially calls upon the school-teachers to point out to children what insects are, and
                            what are not ; noxious; and further, to condemn most strongly : the killing of birds, or
                            taking their nests, and j asserts that the law will hold parents responsible j for the acts
                            of their children in this respect. The editor of Appleton's Journal, in commenting upon
                            this, suggests the query whether our public schools cannot do more than they now do to teach
                            children to think about many matters in which they now too often err, from sheer ignorance.
                            It occurs to us that much benefit would accrue to the public if an elementary course of
                            entomology were introduced into our normal schools, so that our teachers, knowing something
                            themselves, could influence the children under their charge to act as efficient aids to the
                            farmer, in concerted action toward destroying our injurious insects. Children are naturally
                            destructive, and a little effort, rightly exerted, would make such a duty as is implied here
                            a pleasure, and a pleasure which, sufficiently encouraged, would be productive of a
                            wide-spread benefit. — Scientific Farmer. Jane Q. Swisshelm, in a late letter from Brussels,
                            writes in strong condemnation of the cats in this country. As we have often heard foreigners
                            observe, she strongly asserts that the absence of cats in Europe is the prominent cause of
                            the exceeding multiplicity of beautiful birds of song and plumage in that country. She says
                            she has heard more bird-songs in Brussels in seven weeks than she would hear in this country
                            in almost as many years ! If the cats and children kill so many birds, which would sing so
                            much and kill so many insects, is it not a duty to study the above suggestions ? And is it
                            wrong to kill hundreds of cats ?</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><p TEIform="p">A late number of TJie Spiritual Scientist presented nearly a page of good material, copied
                            from our Daniel Fraser's " Divine Afflatus," duly credited, entitled " The Future of
                            Spiritualism." Says Peebles : " To be a spiritualist, is to hold conscious intercourse with
                            the world of spirits, and to live a spiritual life — such as was Jesus Christ's." This is
                            excellent. Now, let us take this lantern, and discover how many spiritualists there really
                            are — such as live the life Jesus did. That was a sad commentary on the unequal footing of
                            general society, where a woman, with her three little ones, was driven by an unfeeling New
                            York landlord from her garret, and had taken refuge on the grave of her husband in
                            Greenwood, and where they were found quietly starving to death, amid the millions of dollars
                            worth of useless furniture. Wherever there is a rich man or woman, let each remember that
                            they are so, because some one else is made correspondingly poor. The words of Wordsworth are
                            true to-day, as when he wrote: " Homoless, near a thousand homes I stood, And near a
                            thousand tables, pined and wanted food 1 " A package by express the other day proved to be
                            some home-made linen for our external wear, from that kind and thoughtful mother at Enfield,
                            Conn., Anna Erving. All our gospel friends will forgive us, for immediately ejaculating for
                            their benefit, something like Luke 10:37. We are in receipt of two valuable Sunday School
                            periodicals: The Sunday School Times, Phila., Pa., and The National Sunday School Teacher,
                            Chicago, 111., are conducted on very Bimilar principles. While both show exceeding care, and
                            a desire to interest the little ones in scripture lessons, we are unable to decide which is
                            the better. The " Battle Axe" — a new periodical, published in the interests of peace! — by
                            a thorough annihilation of theological errors. There can be none too many of such ; and we
                            are very favorably impressed with the platform upon which it has started, and proposes to
                            run. Address, Independent Tract Society, Worcester, Mass. The critical, surgical,
                            annihilative commentary of Elder H. L. Eades, of South Union, Ky., in Religio Phil. Journal,
                            Aug. 8, upon an article written by one Billings, a seceder from Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., was well
                            merited, and handsomely imposed. We thought all the time we were reading it, we had rather
                            be a Shaker than to be Billings ! We have received from the Editors of the American
                            Agriculturist, N. Y., a copy of a small work on " Broom corn and Broom making " — one of the
                            neatest little works imaginable. It is just such a digest as we have desired for a long
                            time. We had already secured some material for such a work. On page 12, it refers to our
                            people and their connection with broom corn as follows: " It is said that the Shakers of
                            Watervliet, N. Y., first made brooms for sale in 1798, though the plant was cultivated for
                            home use some years previous to that time. Shakers and others, soon engaged in the business
                            to what then seemed a large extent." The brooms that were first made by us in this Society,
                            were the "round broom;" the handles being cut in the " bush " and smoothed with drawing
                            knife and sand paper. The common and popular "flat" broom, was invented and made by Theodore
                            Bates; and the machine for turning the handles was first conceived and made by the late
                            Jesse Wells, both of this place — Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="70" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Misplaced fear" TEIform="index"/>MISPLACED FEAR</head><p TEIform="p">All languages have a literature of terror about death. But living is far more terrible in
                            reality than dying. It is life that foments pride, that inflames vanity, that excites the
                            passions, that feeds the appetites, that founds and builds habits, that establishes
                            character, and, binding up the separate straws of action into one sheaf, hands it into the
                            future, saying, "As ye have sowed so shall ye reap ;" and again, "As ye reap, so shall ye
                            sow!" Yet life, which is the mischief maker, is not at all feared. Death, that does no harm,
                            and ia only the revealer of life's work, is feared.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rock of rest" TEIform="index"/>Rock of rest
                        </head><p TEIform="p">THE ROCK OF REST. MATTHEW XVI. 18. Tossed on many a wave of doctrine, Restless, weary, ill at
                            ease With beliefs that quiet others, But as vague to me as these; I have done with idly
                            chasing Phantom lights that rise and fall; Drift no more with drifting doctrines — Grown
                            indifferent to them all! Shall I long regret the visions Of a rest so idly woood ? Shall I
                            long go on deploring Creeds, that but opinions proved? Quenched be every weak emotion! Bring
                            my future weal or woe, Weal nor woe shall blight or bless mo — Faith, nor creed, shall move
                            me now! Murmuring thus, there came a whisper From the Friend who knew me best: ' Seek the
                            rock on which I builded: On that rock alone is rest." Suddenly, with light supernal, Faith,
                            the higher reason, came, And my foot touched base eternal — Benedictions on his name!</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion and science" TEIform="index"/>RELIGION AND SCIENCE</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The theories of the world wrought out by early priest-philosophers were in great
                                    part made up of such grotesque notions; and having become variously implicated with
                                    ethical opinions as to the nature and consequences of right and wrong behavior, they
                                    acquired a kind of sanctity, so that any thinker who in the light of a wider
                                    experience ventured to alter or amend the primitive theory was likely to be
                                    vituperated as an irreligious man or atheist. This sort of inference has not yet
                                    been wholly abandoned, even in civilized communities. Even to-day books are written
                                    about the "conflict between religion and science," and other books are written with
                                    intent to reconcilo the two presumed antagonists. But when we look beneath the
                                    surface of things, wye see that in reality there has never been any conflict between
                                    religion and scionce, nor is any reconciliation called for where harmony has always
                                    existed. The real historical conflict, which has been thus curiously misnamed, has
                                    been the conflict between the more-crude opinions belonging to the science of an
                                    earlier age and the less-crude opinions belonging to the science of a later age. In
                                    the course of this contest the more-crude opinions have usually been defended in the
                                    name of religion, and the lesscrude opinions have invariably won the victory; but
                                    religion itself, which is not concerned with opinion, but with the aspiration which
                                    leads us to strive after a purer and holier life, has seldom or never been attacked.
                                    On the contrary, the scientific men who have conducted the battle on behalf of the
                                    loss-crude opinions, have generally been influenced by this religious aspiration
                                    quite as strongly as the apologists of the more-crude opinions, and so far from
                                    religious feeling having been weakened by their perennial series of victories, it
                                    has apparently been growing deeper and stronger all the time. The religious sense is
                                    as yet too feebly developed in most of us; but certainly in no preceding age have
                                    men taken up the work of life with more earnestness or with more real faith in the
                                    unseen than at the present day, when so much of what was once deemed all-important
                                    knowledge has been consigned to the limbo of mythology. John Fiske, </quote></cit><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl">in <index level1="Atlantic monthly" TEIform="index"/>Atlantic Monthly</bibl></p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Fiske, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Fiske</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Make your Heaven here" TEIform="index"/>MAKE YOUR HEAVEN HERE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sunderland, J. T." TEIform="persName"/>REV. J. T. SUNDERLAND</byline><p TEIform="p">There is no royal road or short cut to Heavon. If you want a Ileaven for yourself in the
                            world to come, prepare it for yourself in the life that now is. You have no reason to think
                            you will enter upon tho next life in any wise changed in character from what you are when
                            you leave this. " He that is holy, let him be holy still. He that is unholy, let him be
                            uuholy still." And the character with which you leave this world will be the slow and
                            natural growth of the years of your whole earthly life, and cannot be the result of any
                            thing else, tho teaching of any theology or man to the contrary notwithstanding. The true
                            conception of human existence doubtless is as one in this world and the next —this the rill,
                            that the river; this the dawn, that the day ; this the bud, that the flower; this the blade,
                            that the full corn in the ear. Heavon is not something to be won or got or bought, either by
                            ourselves or somebody else for us ; but it is somothing to grow into. In the next world you
                            are simply your own self, only moved on, and moved up. Swedenborg somewhere gives us a
                            representation of persons who had died, and did not, for a considerable time, even know that
                            they were dead. Their old thoughts and feelings and loves and desires of the earthly lifo
                            remained, and the world which they had entered did not at first seem different from the one
                            they had left, only it was spiritual instead of physical. Hence they went on with their old
                            employments and ran the rounds of their old pleasures. Only by degrees did they perceive
                            their change of states —and that as they themsolvos became, by natural processes of growth
                            and development, capable of deeper seeing and higher knowledge.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Carlyle on teaching" TEIform="index"/>CARLYLE ON TEACHING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Carlyle, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">An old letter of Mr. Thomas Carlyle'a on teaching, written in 1859 to a young man who asked
                            his counsel, has just been published. In it he says: " The grand secret (worth all the
                            others together, and without which all the others are worth nothing and less) for
                            inculcating and teaching virtues and graces is, that a man honestly, and with more and more
                            of silent sincerity, have them himself, lodged there in the silent deeps of his being ; they
                            will not fail to shine through and be not only visible but undeniable in whatever he is led
                            to say or to do, and every hour of the day he will, consciously and unconsciously, find good
                            means of teaching them. This is the grand indispensable requisite ; this present, the rest
                            is very certain to follow; the rest is mere matter of detail, depending on speciality of
                            circumstance, which a man's own common sense, if he is in earnest toward his aim, will
                            better and better instruct him in. The business, I am sorrowfully aware, is often enough
                            undertaken without this indispensable prerequisite —nay, in general, there is a dim notion
                            abroad that a man can teach such things by merely wishing to do it and without having them
                            himself ; but the fatal result inevitably is, he teaches, cau teach, nothing but hypocrisy
                            and unblessed apery and mendacity. It is a kind of salvation to his poor pupils if they, in
                            a dim way, see through him, and refuse to imbibe the slow poison of such teaching. I fancy
                            you to be an ingenuous young man, aiming manfully to do your best in the vocation which has
                            fallen to you ; and I hang up far ahead, I hope, this ugly but true warning upon a certain
                            path which all mortals of us ought to avoid and abhor much more than we do at present."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Social impurity" TEIform="index"/>SOCIAL IMPURITY</head><byline TEIform="byline">[The following extracts are from a sermon, preached to a congregation, in the
                            aristocratic city of Pittsfield, Mass. There is so much genuine Shaker preaching in thorn,
                            we aro very happy to quote them for the benefit of our readers. Would to heaven that the
                            42,000 clergymen of the United States were as bold for truth as the <persName reg="Clymer, J. F." TEIform="persName"/>Kev. J. F. Clymer, now of Glens Falls, N. Y. Our thanks to It. M.
                            Offard, for putting the same in tract form.— Ed.1</byline><p TEIform="p">There is a willful and woeful ignorance among ail classes in regard to the cause, the effect
                            and enormity of this crime. All men ought to know that God has woven laws into every tissue,
                            and nerve, and muscle, and bone of the human body, tho violation of which is just as much a
                            sin as to break any law of the decalogue. The laws of God graven on our bodies havo not
                            received that attention from divines and public teachers that their importance demands. We
                            have had acres of sermons on the ethics of Christianity, as they apply to the soul; but
                            scarcely a word on the relations of Christianity to the body. In the rigmarole of extreme
                            religionists, the body is regarded as a vile, burdensome thing, an earthly pest to tho soul;
                            hence the shameful ignorance of physical laws among some Christians, and their feverish
                            anxiety to get to heaven. I pronounce the human body the grandest combination of physical
                            elements in the universe; the incarnation of the divine ideal of material beauty ; the
                            temple of the soul; the sanctuary of the Holy Ghost — "Know yo not that your bodies are the
                            temples of tho Holy Ghost?" Licentiousness is pre-eminently a body sin. It smites this
                            temple of tho Holy Ghost with the dry rot. All men, especially young men, ought to know that
                            this physical sin is hell fire in the bones, and will burn up their bodily powers, leaving
                            the soul homeless and Godless forever. Men of God everywhere ought to cry aloud and spare
                            not, that this iniquity may cease in tho land. Criminal fastidiousness and counterfeit
                            delicacy confront me, and forbid the revelation of covered corruption. Ah, these are they
                            who are so busy with the proprieties and elegancies of outside life, that no time is had for
                            securing pure inwardness. The descendants of the Pharisees are not all dead. Whitewashed
                            sepulchres are not out of date yet. Remembering that pure delicacy is a spring sunk deep in
                            the solid rock of integrity, whose clear waters send up no mire nor dirt, I will drink from
                            the limpid stream and go on. Licentiousness shows itself in tho solitary vice of youth. The
                            hard facts of life and eminent physicians tell us that this secret sin is well-nigh
                            universal. Medical men, eminent for ability, say there is scarcely a youth of twelve years,
                            of either sex, who has escaped its ravages. Fond parents are self-deceived when they think
                            their children are innocent. A noted physician says, among tho thousands of youths who have
                            come under his notice, scarcely one in a hundred is free from it. Most parents think it the
                            wisest wisdom to keep their children in ignorance of the divinely appointed relations of the
                            sexes, hence they never warn them against this vice, or tell them of tho dreadful ruin it
                            brings upon body and soul. Fathers and mothers while you maintain this ominous silence, vile
                            books, lewd pictures in art galleries, wicked companions and leprous newspapers, and obscene
                            theatre bills are slowly, but surely, training your children in this vice. Our literature
                            reeks with licentious filth. Many of our young men pass by the study of history, art,
                            science, and the Bible, counting thorn trash, and sit for hours gormandizing the "New York
                            Weekly," the " Fireside Companion," the " Day's Doings," and the " Police Gazette." Very few
                            of you suspect tho ruin that the social evil is working among our youth. Through it the best
                            energies are wasted. The rich current of vitality is poured out like water, and strong
                            nerves are shattered and unstrung Then comes tho fatal resort to stimulants to hold up the
                            tottering frame. Then the mad bowl becomes a dire necessity of existence. Then, when
                            sickness comes, there is no vitality to resist the inroads of disease. Many a youth has gone
                            on thus, week after week, and month after month, showing daily the signs of decay, and no
                            one asks the cause of his troubles. The listless eye, the pale cheek, the fitful appetite,
                            the spiteful temper, these are all nature's signals of this sin. At last the victim dies.
                            The community all stand aghast at such a strange providence. The minister stands over the
                            coffin and echoes the voice of the community, and calls this a " mysterious providence that
                            removes one so promising from our midst." It is false. He fell a victim to the violation of
                            God's laws written in his body. God did not kill him ; he killed himself. A man need not put
                            a knife to his throat, or a pistol to his breast to become a suicide. A man may eat, or
                            drink, or lust himself to death. Under the lead of lewdness, a young man may fritter his
                            life away infinitesimally, and society will lay the blame on God. Be not deceived. God is
                            not mocked; whatsoever a man sovveth, that shall he also reap. Punishment for violated THK
                            SH^KEH, <pb n="71" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> law is one of the surest things In God's universe. No one
                            violates a law of his body, or any part of it, with impunity. Parents, believe me when I
                            tell you that many of your children are dying daily through this vice. If an unwise silence
                            has put a gulf between you and your children, draw near unto them and they will draw near to
                            you, Fold them in your arms, and in the sanctity of your homes, at the holy shrine of a
                            mother's love, and under the pavilion of a father's affection, tell them of the woe that
                            waits on this vice. Young men, I come to you as the angel came to Lot, and cry out, with my
                            heart in my mouth, escape for your lives from this Sodom ! Fly! fly to yon mount of purity,
                            or else it will soon be forever too late. The violations of the law of chastity are not all
                            outside of marriage relations. Marriage is of God. Its chief corner-stone is love : Its
                            other foundation stones are joy, peace, long-suffering, gentleness, goodness, faith,
                            meekness, temperance; its superstructure, a Christly character, wrought out in a pure
                            fatherhood and a chaste motherhood. Put marriage on any other basis than pure love, and you
                            break the seventh commandment. Let your prime object in marriage be any other than the
                            upbuilding of the soul in godly principles under the law of parentage, and you prostitute
                            the purest institution of God among men. Christ recognized the necessity of pure love in
                            wedlock so much that he classes it with his own love for the church, and makes It the ideal
                            of our love for him; Hear Him speak through Paul, "Husbands, love your wives, even as Christ
                            also loved the church ; " with sacrifice, with self-abnegation, and self-renunciation -such
                            a love as suborns every lower motive to a divine purpose. Again, " Wives, submit yourselves
                            unto your husbands, as unto the Lord," not as unto a base and gross humanity. Nothing short
                            of the purest love that can throb in human breast will meet the divine idea of Christian
                            marriage; nothing less than pure love will make our homes the type of heaven, as God
                            intended they should be. Enter into marriage with every thing else but love, and no matter
                            how gorgeous your wedding, or how magnificent your dwelling, your home will be a little
                            hell. Whereas, two youthful souls, with true love, will make an Eden out of a hut. Some
                            teach that so long as the bounds of civil law are not passed in marriage, there is no sin;
                            that the law of chastity cannot be violated inside the marriage relation, hence vast numbers
                            of otherwise good people refuse to know any law of temperance on this question. Do you not
                            know that the Saviour's interpretation of the seventh commandment, found in Matthew, v. 38,
                            applies to married persons this side of civil law, as well as the other side ? The pure
                            Christ has given a heart meaning to the seventh commandment, which covers the relations of
                            husband and wife to each other, as woil as their relations to others. God has dedicated
                            marriage as a sanctuary of love and purity; and they who make it a convenience for revelling
                            and grossness, transform it iuto a den of thieves. Husbands, Christ's love for the church is
                            the standard set up for you. Wives, the love of a true church of Christ is the example for
                            you; then shall your union be a "perpetual fountain of domestic sweets." 1. If you would
                            avoid this great evil, in all its forms, have nothing to do with bad books or leprous
                            newspapers. Parents, know the names of the author and publisher of every book your children
                            read, and especially those books they read at night, with the lamp by the bedside. In the
                            company of a bad book, you may ruin in an hour what has been the work of a life-time. The
                            way to ruin is cheap ; for ten or flfteon cents you can buy a book or paper that will damn
                            you forever. 2. I warn you, keep your Imagination pure. Be more terrified at the presence of
                            an impure thought than at the presence of a robber in your house at midnight. 3. Keep your
                            conversation clean. Descend not to furtive flings of lustful wit. Resent, with all the
                            lightning in you, the man or woman who retails in your presence the fllthiness of stray
                            speech, or ill-chosen words. i. Have good, pure men and women for your companions, or walk
                            alone all through life, till the pearly gates burst open at your touch, to let you Into the
                            holy city beyond the clouds 5. Avoid all the modern excitants and stimulants of food or
                            drink, that flre the blood and set the THE SHAKER. passions in a blaze. Live on simple food.
                            Eat as little of animal food as possible, and you will have less of the animal to contend
                            with in yourself. Avoid the midnight air of club rooms, billiard saloons, ball-rooms and
                            restaurants. Thus you will have pure blood ~ for a man's blood always gives color to his
                            morals. Lastly, Walk in the spirit—Rom. viii. 1-U.- "For to be carnally minded is death, but
                            to be spirituually minded ia life and peace."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Song of peace" TEIform="index"/>A SONG OF PEACE</head><p TEIform="p">I. The grass is green on Bunker Hill, The waters sweet in Brandywine; The sword sleeps in the
                            scabbard still, The farmer keeps his flock and vine ; Then, who would mar the scene to-day,
                            With vaunt of battlefield or fray ? II. The brave corn lif ts in reglmenta Ten thousand
                            sabres in the sun ; The ricks replace the battle tents. The bannered tassels toss and run,
                            The neighing steed, the bugle's blast. Those be but stories of the past III. The earth has
                            healed her wounded breast, The cannons plough the field no more ; The heroes rest! Oh, let
                            them rest In peace along the peaceful shore ! They fought for peace, for peace they fell:
                            They sleep in peace, and all is well. IV. The fields forget the battles fought, The trenches
                            wave in golden grain ; Shall we neglect the lessons taught, And tear the wounds agape again
                            f Sweet mother nature, nurse the land. And heal her wounds with gentle hand. V. Lo I peace
                            on earth ; Lo ! flock and fold, Lo ! rich abundance, fat increase, And valleys clad in sheen
                            of gold Oh, rise and sing a song of peace ! For Theseus roams the land no more, And Janus
                            rests with rusted door.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Miller, Joaquin" TEIform="persName"/>Joaquin Miller</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Aggrandizement" TEIform="index"/>AGGRANDIZEMENT</head><p TEIform="p">Money is now exactly what mountain promontories over public roads were in old times. The
                            barons fought for them fairly: the strongest and cunningest got them ; then fortified them,
                            and made every one who passed below pay toll. Well, capital now is exactly what crags were
                            then. Men fight fairly (we will, at least, grant so much, though it is more than we ought)
                            for their money; but, once having got it, the fortified millionaire can make every body who
                            passes below pay toll to his million, and build another tower of his moneycastle. And I can
                            tell you, the poor vagrants by the roadside .suffer now quite as much from the bag-baron, as
                            ever they did from the crag-baron. Bags and crags have just the same result on rags. — New
                            Aye.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Slaughter of birds for their plumage" TEIform="index"/>THE SLAUGHTER OF BIRDS FOR THEIR
                            PLUMAGE</head><p TEIform="p">Mr. Alfred Newton writes a striking protest to the Times against the wholesale slaughter of
                            birds for the sake of ornamental feathers. He quotes the proceedings of a single sale of
                            feathers to show that to supply that sale alone, 9,700 herons {or egrets) must have beon
                            destroyed. All these feathers are said to have come from India last autumn. Mr. Newton
                            observes that no country could supply 10,000 herons in a single breeding season, without
                            nearly rooting out the stock. Moreover, 15,000 humming birds and upward were Included in the
                            sale, of which 740 were of a single kind. As far as we know, none|of these birds really
                            diminish the stock of food available for man, so that in destroying them for mere show we
                            empty the world absolutely of a certain portion of its beauty and happiness, while the
                            beauty is certainly by no means made up in the ornamentation of feminine toilets which is
                            thus procured. In this age of fine moralities does no one really bestow a thought on the
                            morality of such reckloss spoliation of life as this? — London Spectator.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Grape cure" TEIform="index"/>THE GRAPE CURE</head><p TEIform="p">According to the Pall Mall Gazette, among the most agreeable hygienic processes extant must
                            be reckoned the grape cure. There are on the continent numerous establishments devoted to
                            the use of the remedy; two in France, Aigle in Savoy, and Celiestes-Bains in the Ardeche ;
                            three, at least, in Switzerland — Veyteaux, Vovey, Montreaux; and many in Germany, Austria,
                            the Tyrol, and Hungary. The juice of the grape, containing, according to medical authority,
                            25 per cent of its weight in active agents — glucose, tartaric acid, potash, chalk, soda,
                            oxide of iron, and manganese in combination with sulphuric acid, phosphoric acid, etc. —
                            there is some reason for comparing this "organic mineral water," as it has been called, with
                            the inorganic, the curative powers of which are so universally recognized, and for expecting
                            similar results from it. The cure is very simple. It consists in eating an immense quantity
                            of grapes, the thin-skinned sweet white varieties being best for the purpose. The patient
                            takes but little ordinary food, and is required to eat three or four pounds of the fruit a
                            day just at first, the quantity being gradually increased to eight, ten, and even twelve
                            pounds of grapes. This is, if possible, to be eaten in the open air, in the vineyard whence
                            the supply is derived —an arrangement which, no doubt, greatly conduces to the efficiency of
                            the cure. It is frequently undertaken in their private practice by French physicians, who
                            possess the matorial for it in the incomparableChasselas, of which such quantities are now
                            selling in Paris.</p></div2><div2 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit of the farm" TEIform="index"/>SPIRIT OF THE FARM</head><p TEIform="p">Tite practice of trimming leaves from tho vinea to expose grapes to the sunlight, we have
                            found by experience to be an error. Instead of grapes ripening quicker, those trimmed wore
                            several days later than those left unexposed to the sun. The quality of the fruit from
                            trimmed vines aleo suffers. ^ Keep this until next season : A neighbor of ours had suffered
                            exceedingly from onion maggot. He used plaster last season and reduced his loss twothirds.
                            This year lie rolled his bed until the ground was hard; sowed it, and as soon as the onions
                            would bear it, tread the earth on both sides next to the onions, so as to press them snugly.
                            We visited his onions lately—not the sign of a maggot anywhere. ¦£¦ Jeremiah Low, of this
                            place, has been a valuable, amateur gardner. Recent mishaps, with threescoro and ten and
                            more years, add to his inability to do. But he has produced somo valuable new fruits — early
                            pears, corn, grapos, mulberries, the white wax bean, and a thornless black-cap raspberry,
                            ever-bearing, that we do not believe can be equaled in the world. • -feA. J. Downing
                            advocated the ploughing of orchards, and our experience has invariably proved, that doing so
                            is much tho best plan — turning under clover or some green crop — rather than pasturing or
                            idling. -fa Great differences exist between the wheat fields of Shaker farms in Genesee
                            Valley. Recent reports say, some yield only ten bushels to the acre, while others are
                            yielding thirty. Why this difference on alluvial soils? -^A spading machine is the latest
                            novelty, and a valuablo one too. Tested in Albany county, last week of July, it spaded as
                            fast as three horses could walk with it, a surface three feet wide. The Country Gentleman
                            says : " If it had spaded only two feet wide, two horses could leave the ground in better
                            trim than ploughing, cultivating and harrowing" — three operations. Its work is eight inches
                            in depth.</p></div2><pb n="72" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Centennial blessings" TEIform="index"/>CENTENNIAL BLESSINGS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Busby, Ann" TEIform="persName"/>ANN BUSBY</byline><p TEIform="p">Mount Lebanon, N. Y. Blessed year of our Lord — eighteen hundred seventy-six — Every blessing
                            does afford — With the daily cross affixed. Every avenue is open For advancement in the
                            right, All the captive chains are broken, And the day succeeds the night. Lot tho spirit,
                            now unfettered, Glory, halleluia sing, Triumphing in the victory, Which the cross of Christ
                            does bring. Blessed year of our Lord, Let sweet melodies arise, Wo will sing with ono
                            accord, Of salvation's glorious prize, Of the rapid lino of travel, To our Father's Kingdom
                            new, Wo will bravo each rising trial, And the heavenly way pursue; By confession and
                            repentance, We will weave us garments fair, Rejoicing, that our spirits, We, for glory, may
                            prepare. May this year of our Lord, New centennial blessings bring, On the rulers of our
                            land — On the peasant and the king ; May our blest and lovely Zion Be replenished by his
                            hand, And the gospel testimony, Sounded forth o'er sea and land. May the preaching of the
                            prophets, In the wilderness bo heard, Preparing all the people, For the coming of the
                        Lord.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>SOCIETY RECORD</head><p TEIform="p">The Ministry of Mt. Lebanon and Watervliet loft the latter place on Aug. 1, for an extended
                            tour of all the Western Societies. Let us all yearn for them a successful journey. Also, let
                            us remind our western brethren that, though they are strong in spirit and for the Cause,
                            they must use some care not to overwork them, and lot them return on time. </p><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Shakers, N. Y. Crops coming in splendidly. Hay and grain an abundant yield —best quality.
                                Fruits of smaller varieties, excepting Raspberries only medium crop. Apples, Pears,
                                etc., promises most largoly,|whilo the gardeners, broom and sweet corn growers are
                                counting- a relief by dollars, not far distant. Health apparently superb. The Colorado
                                bug troubled our earl]) potatoes considerably—in some families bushels were picked from
                                tho vines, and their fates were "tho end!" -£</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H. An intenso drouth still prevails. Nevertheless, crops coming In
                                satisfactorily. An especial good word for potatoes ; which, notwithstanding the immense
                                army of beetles, have done well. Busy lingers have, in days and weeks, destroyed
                                mil----hundreds of thousands! Sales of brooms and seeds moderate. The dairy good. From
                                the average of 30 cows, seventy cheeses have been produced, besides 65 or 70 lbs. of
                                butter woekly. Sixteen calves reared. Pail and Tub business resting; but must begin
                                again soon. " Hope so, we want one." Health of Society good; and we report goneral
                                prosperity throughout, -fe</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p"> Enfield, Conn. Bro. Richard Van Deusen has a pear orchard of four acres, which we almost
                                imagine, this season he challenges the world with. The Church Family havo begun a new
                                Dwelling House —form of Greek Cross —96 feet long, and cross-wise. This building is to
                                bo heated by steam. New Depot being built by tho Society. Albert Battles is proposed as
                                P. M. for a now P. O. Hereafter, friends! direct all letters for Enfield, Conn., to "
                                Shaker Station, Hartford Co., Conn." Bro. B. S. Kellogg, we are glad to hear, is
                                improving. Get up, and well. -jjj</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Groveland, New York" TEIform="index"/>Groveland, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> GROVELAND, N. Y., about this time is experiencing a refreshing season of Mt. Lebanon
                                baptism. Although wheat is only moderate, yet no complaint is heard of tho general
                                appearance and harvest of crops. Zeal generally is prevalent at the Centre, and that
                                "happy family " at tho west continues " happy." -fa </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hancock, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Hancock, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> Hancock, Mass. A passage through this village lately, inspired our heart of hearts with
                                much hope. There is much of God in Hancock, —for order prevailed. Fences, buildings,
                                ("many new ones,) wero superior to tho heretofore, and the kindness of Bro. Ira Lawson
                                unequaled. *fe </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Canterbury, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p"> Canterbury, N. H. The hay crop is secured, every load of the same gathered in best
                                condition. Blue berries thick, fifty bushels will bo gathered by our families this
                                season. Health of Society remarkably good in view of tho hot weather we have had. Sorry
                                to Tiear of one case (A. C. S.) that has been very bad, but glad to hear of the
                                convalescence, and the acknowledged causes —unphysiological conditions. Public audiences
                                too largo for tho house of worship —have had thoughts of taking up contributions for its
                                extension. People in this neighborhood of the best class, but poor as we are (!) and wo
                                have but little hopes of the desired amount. The reason of their poverty must be because
                                they are so good. ^ Being in the closest accord with our Publisher, we urge an
                                immediate, and comforting response, to the Circular he has so recently issued to tho
                                various trusteeships individually; and may each response be a hearty Amen ! yy </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bright Side" TEIform="index"/>Bright Side
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Bright Side. — Dr. Johnson used to say that a habit of looking at the best side of
                                every event is better than a thousand pounds a year. Bishop Hall quaintly remarks, "For
                                every bad there might be a worse, and when a man breaks his leg, let him be thankful
                                that it was not his neck." When Fenelon's library was on fire, 'God bo praised," ho
                                exclaimed, "that it was not the dwelling of some poor man. This is the true spirit of
                                cheerfulness and submission — one of the most beautiful traits that can possess the
                                human heart. Resolve to see this world on the sunny side, and you havo almost won the
                                battle of life at the outset. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No cross, no crown" TEIform="index"/>No cross, no crown
                            </head><p TEIform="p">No Cross, no Crown. — Coleridge remarked, that the temper of tho present age inclines it
                                to every enervating indulgence. Men appear to think tho Christian armor an unnecessary
                                incurubrance; they have no desire to engago in any combat, to undergo any trial: if
                                religion is to bo cultivated, it must be as one of the jftiie aria — as an element of
                                belles-lettres ; they forgot or despise the saying of Bishop Patrick, that there is no
                                passage to celestial glory but by some crocs; that we must suffer with Christ, as well
                                as confess Him, if wo would be with Him in Paradise.</p></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>TO EVERGREEN SHORES</head><p TEIform="p">We had only just committed the little conceit under this caption for Aug. No. when we
                                received the following:</p><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ballou, Ira" TEIform="index"/>Iha Ballou
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At Enfield, N. H., May 15, <persName reg="Ballou, Ira" TEIform="persName">Iha Ballou</persName>, aged
                                79.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Morrill, Rowena" TEIform="index"/>Rowena Morrill
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At Enfield, N. H., July 5, <persName reg="Morrill, Rowena" TEIform="persName">Rowena
                                    Morrill</persName>, aged 75.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miner, Rhoda" TEIform="index"/>Rhoda Miner
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At North Union, O., July 9, <persName reg="Miner, Rhoda" TEIform="persName">Rhoda Miner</persName>,
                                    nearly 81.</p></div4></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>