<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0206" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><date value="18720601" TEIform="date">June 1872</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">41-48</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="41" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">'• I WILL SHAKE ALL NATIONS, AND THE DESIRE OF ALL NATIONS SHALL COME ; AND I WILL FILL THIS HOUSE WITH GLORY, SAITH
                        THE LORD. Published Monthly, by and under the direction of the Mt. Lebanon Bishopric. Vol. II. G. A. Lomas, Editor.
                        SHAKERS, ALBANY CO., N. Y., JUNE, 1872. No. 6 Fifty Cents per Annum.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker societies" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Societies</head><p TEIform="p">THEIR PURPOSE AND MAINTENANCE. We would, in present article, deal with this subject as connected with the
                            consecrated services of those individuals which the Good Spirit seals as acceptable members of said Societies.
                            The very common idea prevails that the Shakers are rich. Viewed from whatever point any may take, the very
                            reverse of this is true ! We have large possessions, but we have large numbers as occupants and possessors ; and
                            there are thousands of farmers within a few miles of Shaker homesteads, who possess more earthly wealth than the
                            Shakers would, were they divided into families as small as theirs. In the "Constitution" of the United Societies
                            we find that the sole aim, purpose and intent for the accumulation of any and all possessions in the power of
                            the Societies honorably to secure, to be for " charitable and religious purposes " only. None, not even the
                            Bishops of the Societies, have any right to disburse the funds derived from the consecrated services or
                            donations of individuals, for any other purposes whatever. It will clearly appear to any reasonable individual,
                            that a Society whose financial basis is like ours, must be the very reverse of a money-making institution. This
                            being so, many will ask, how are the Societies maintained and improved ? It is a fact, well known, that the
                            Shakers rely upon the adhesion of individuals outside of their order, to increase or sustain their numerical
                            forces—no children being born in the Societies. Many of Society's pillars entered it when very young, others in
                            riper years. Some became acceptable members after reaching the meridian of life, able to sustain themselves and
                            a little more; while many others are unable to do even this. Many, advanced in years, seek admission to Society
                            under the well-founded assertion that they are '' able to pay their way " at the time ; and it will appear
                            cogent to all, that if Society is sustained, some must considerably exceed an ability to sustain themselves, and
                            willingly consecrate that ability to the cause, or it must fail. Here, then, we have the key to Society's
                            improvement—the consecrated offerings of those able to bear to Society more than they cost it. Many children
                            have been adopted, in the hope that their riper years will not only compensate Society for its fostering care of
                            their youth, but add largely to its facilities, whereby their spiritual fathers and mothers, less able brethren
                            and sisters, other adopted children, and themselves may be assured a happy maintenance for all time to come;
                            making Society a permanent institution for the sinsick Zion-traveler who earnestly pleads for a privilege to
                            devote his or her life to a cause so holy and just. We enter into a " Covenant " at maturity of years, that our
                            whole being, without reserve, shall willingly be devoted to the upholding and upbuilding of Society; and
                            sacredly attaching our names to this instrument, forbids our demand, if not our acceptance, of a single dime for
                            services so consecrated. " Can a man rob God? " Nor does Society invite this consecration without giving us a
                            solemn assurance that it takes us " for better or for worse, in sickness and in health," in old age, and through
                            unforeseen accidents and difficulties, so long as we fulfill our part of the "compact" to which we, at mature
                            age, have understandingly and vol- untarily attached our signatures. This " Covenant " has passed the ordeal of
                            the best legal acumen and criticism in our country, and pronounced a safe document for the preservation of
                            Society for the purposes it sets forth, and an impassable and imperishable barrier to the cunning design of
                            malignant apostates, than whom Society has no more ignoble, unworthy foe. Bearing in mind many, who, in parting
                            with Society as their Alma Mater, have ever respected and honored her; yet some of those departing have, with
                            unexampled ferocity, demanded large sums—a division of Society's substance, little of which was gathered by
                            their efforts in her behalf, but rather by the life-services of the saints departed, and the living faithful.
                            Such would bring Society to an end of practically fulfilling its sacred obligations to faithful adherents, and
                            obliterate the very purposes for which Society was established. And why ? Because they have chosen to depart
                            Society! Dark times were those, when Society suffered the unjust allegations of living in secret
                            impurity—hypocritically professing, but failing to demonstrate a pure life ! Those times are past, and now the
                            very reverse is believed; and we mean to take advantage of the change, and ask, how do we do it? For the purpose
                            of keeping our sacred obligations intact, we have rules which act as safeguards, securing to us spiritual
                            protection, while making us better able to enjoy and enhance the physical blessings of Society. By the
                            carnally-minded, these regulations are pronounced silly, unnecessary, tyrannical. But those who admit the
                            feasibility of living a Shaker life, find in these apparently insignificant regulations the secret of our
                            success, while we challenge any to live as purely as we do together, without them. United as we are to Society,
                            we become its humble servants, and so far part with our identity, that even our correspondence with relatives or
                            others becomes a part of Society, and our every breath is drawn for Society's good; and thus, in the language of
                            one of Kentucky's wise statesmen, " we challenge the world to furnish a truer, purer example of consecration to
                            God than a faithful Shaker!" We, who represent Society to-day, have been put in trust with its substance, and we
                            mean to transmit the same, unviolated, to our successors. We enjoy the benefits of Society as far as we are
                            faithful representatives. We have no individual pos- sessions, and only as we enjoy the benefits of Society in
                            common with our God-serving brethren and sisters, they are not ours. These blessings, deriving their origin and
                            continuance from and by the consecrated services of the self-denying, we are unable by the " Covenant," as well
                            as unwilling, to share this goodly substance with the self-gratifying crowd of ungodly doers. Being thus bound
                            by the most solemn act of our lives—signing the " Covenant "— we fulfill our obligations to our predecessors,
                            ourselves, and to our God, by devoting our temporal gains to the purposes as aforesaid only. We wish it
                            distinctly understood that we never have admitted any as members, with promise or intimation of reward,
                            excepting a share of Society's benefits, while in it; and we never will. We posi- tively assert that we are not
                            using conse<pb n="42" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. crated funds for the aggrandizement of the few, to the exclusion of
                            the general body; and despising the recreant policy of renegades, we declare Society to be carrying out its
                            original plan—first, for the care of the bodies and souls of its members, and the residue, if any, is being
                            applied to " charitable and religious purposes " only. Believing our Society to be founded upon principles that
                            are eternal and just, that God is the Architect and Builder, we mean to do our duty fearlessly; and we warn the
                            foolishness of man from any further attempts at defrauding Grod-loving souls of their Grod-given rights. If our
                            institutions are founded upon the selfishness of man, we know they will soon pass away, and the sooner the
                            better; but if they are of Grod, they will endure forever—the whole world to the contrary notwithstanding,—and
                            this we believe. *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Address of Antoinette Doolittle" TEIform="index"/>Address of Antoinette Doolittle</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">TROY, MARCH '2i, 1872. A renowned preacher came to the conclusion, many years ago, that " there was nothing new
                            under the sun ; nothing but what had previously been." We recognize the law of cycles, but are disposed to
                            believe that some new things occur in each successive cycle. It is rather a new thing for Spiritualists and
                            Shakers to meet in con- vention ; but we hope this meeting will not be in vain. We do not see any reason why a
                            season like the present may not be one of interest and profit, if Love is our guide, Truth our aim ; and we "
                            abide in Faith, Hope and Charity, that beautiful trinity of graces which, when woven together, form a strong
                            cord that cannot be easily broken." There is great power in Love, and strength in Truth. Error is weak, fragile,
                            and must eventually be shaken by Truth, and be broken in pieces. We cannot do anything effectually against the
                            truth; but when we work with it, then are we strong. It has been said, and ivell said, that " theol- ogy is not
                            religion." When any human soul pours forth its best treasures, gives its best and truest feelings in devotional
                            exercise, in prayer, in song, in speaking of the things which pertain to the kingdom of God, or in the joyful
                            and sacred dance, whether they be Roman, Greek or Jew, such offerings ascend as sweet incense unto spheres
                            celestial, and are treasured as memorials there. Theology points in different directions, is diversified; like a
                            " trumpet giving many and uncertain sounds." Religion is the language of the soul, it is one with goodness and
                            truth. Religious aspirations go forth seeking the fount where sin-dyed garments miiy be washed from every stain,
                            and be made white and clean; for the divine elements which give life to the soul, will bring it into harmony
                            with Angels of purity and love. Religion is the product of a spiritual baptism, which, as at the Pentecostal
                            feast, fills the soul with the fire of truth, resulting in jractical works of righteousness, producing unselfish
                            love, and teaches that the best and strongest proof that can be given of love to God is, loving and serving our
                            brother and our sister who are with us in the daily walks of life. Is there anything more needed at the present
                            time than an increase of the Holy Spirit saptism ? And is not the present a good time ;o seek, that we may find
                            it ? Let us resolve ;o walk hand in hand with " the spirit that is able to lead into all truth." Then, if our
                            patlnvay, at times, lies through the thorny maze, or we pass through the furnace or the flood, " as our day, so
                            will our strength be." Many pilgrims have journeyed on before us, who are now marching the streets of the
                            Heavenly Jerusalem, in the spirit land, with palms of victory in their hands, and crowns of glory on their
                            heads. Spiritual philosophy alone cannot satisfy the soul's needs; we want, we must have the very life and
                            spirit of it, that will make new creatures of us; will mould and fashion us into the image and likeness of those
                            beautiful spirits which we so much love and admire. We need not wait until we put off the mortal coil before we
                            bask in the sunshine of God's redeeming love, and enter into rest. We may, through faith, prayer and
                            self-sacrifice, bring the summer-land to us. We are complex beings—have two natures. The love of goodness and
                            truth belongs to the higher—the Angel nature. The love of pleasure, derived from the sensuous and animal,
                            without regard to principle, and the law of use, belongs to the lower, the inferior part of our being—whichever
                            we serve, that becomes our master. When under the influence of gross passions, the senses—hearing, seeing,
                            smelling, tasting, feeling—all become perverted. But when we turn from low and selfish loves, to the divine of
                            our being, then the senses become refined, and we begin to understand that beautiful saying, " Blessed are the
                            pure in heart, for they shall see God." And we enter into communion with the spirits of the higher spheres. We
                            hear angel voices— they gently lay their hands upon us, and pronounce benedictions over us. They feed us with
                            the bread of heaven, and give us to drink of living waters. Pure breezes come to us, laden with the fragrance of
                            flowers which bloom in celestial gardens. The music of the heavenly spheres breaks over our spirits, as the
                            waters of the deep cover the bodies of those who plunge beneath the swelling tide. When we are fully baptized
                            with the Christ spirit from the resurrection Heavens, we hunger no more for those things which the natural
                            unregenerate man and woman feed upon, contend for and glory in. Our desires and appetites are changed. By the
                            light of divine revelation we perceive new truths—feel new life and power. We put off the old corrupt deeds
                            committed in darkness and ignorance, by confession and repentance; and give new pledges, that henceforth our
                            deeds shall be wrought in the light—in God. This is the Shakers' method of getting a new heart—of being born
                            again—changing the life and character. This is not the work of a day—but a progressive work from faith to faith,
                            accompanied with good practical works. And there is nothing more needed to-day than living faith, actualized.
                            There are many beautiful ideas and theories in our time; but many have been so fearful, that they should depend
                            on their own good deeds instead of imputed righteousness'—that the golden rule of doing unto others, as we would
                            that they should do unto us, is a thing of the past, gone out of date—and become obsolete, except with a few
                            old-fashioned people. But nothing can be truer than the saying of the Apostle James, that " Faith, if it hath
                            not works, is dead, being alone," Whatever is honest, true and just, pure and of good report (in angelic
                            circles), should have a place in our thoughts, and take form and shape in practical works. But we are now living
                            in a time that is fraught with great events; every day and hour has its history. Scientists, Rationalists and
                            Spiritualists are all at work. A new cycle is opening upon us. Present revelation is solving mysteries of the
                            past, unlocking the doors of the spiritual temple in the inner spheres, where all the prophecies of the ages
                            past, given by Angels, through saints and seers, pointing to the present and future work of God upon earth, are
                            treasured without human alloy. The prophets of to-day are penetrating those spheres and searching the records
                            there. Timehonored theories, ecclesiastical dogmas and priestly rule cannot stand before the advancing light of
                            the present time. The old theological heavens are passing away with a great noise, caused by the conflict
                            between the old and new; but the fan is in motion that will blow away the chaff. The ancient Prophets and
                            Apostles, who did their work in their time and have gone to their reward, but whose doings and sayings were
                            recorded for the benefit of their pilgrim brethren who should follow them on life's journey, cheerfully lend
                            their aid to the toilers in the field to-day. Their sympathies fire with us, and their eyes are upon us. Every
                            cycle has its prophets—as guiding stars; and they are the burning candles of the Lord to light the spiritual
                            temple on earth, for the time being. When they have done their work, they will pass away; but the candlesticks
                            will remain, and other lights will be placed in them. Are there no new cycles in the spirit spheres ? If we
                            could look into the interior spiritual heavens at the present time, we should see mighty forces at work there.
                            The male and female are conjointly working in unison with the dual Godhead for the redemption of souls who are
                            out of the body. The heavenly harpers are attuning their harps anew: singing a new song: for the marriage of the
                            Lamb is come, and the hosts of heaven rejoice. The celestial fires are rekindled, and scintillations have found
                            their way from heaven to earth, and are kindling a fire here that will not be easily quenched. The good old
                            prophet Jeremiah, who stands in the first rank among the ancient prophets, looked through his spiritual
                            telescope down through the ages to our own time and saw, 42 <pb n="43" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. with a prophet's
                            eye, that there would be " a new thing in the earth. A woman should compass a man." The spiritual is not first,
                            but is preceded by the natural. And already on the natural plane, " a sound of going in the tops of the mulberry
                            trees " has been heard ; and woman has caught the sound, and is gathering her forces for battle. She feels that
                            the time is fully come for her to work; to battle against error, and to aid in pulling down the false and
                            building up the true. Many fears are entertained for the safety of woman who engages in this work ! It is said,
                            " she claims rights and privileges that would be imprudent for her to possess; that already she is growing bold
                            and venturesome." But it must be remembered that man has the start in the race some thousands of years, and it
                            will require some energy and will-force to overtake him. Now, Jeremiah was either a true or a false prophet. If
                            true, his prediction must be fulfilled some time. The question is, when, and in what way ? Perhaps when that
                            prediction is fulfilled, we shall be better prepared to understand the " great wonder that appeared in heaven,"
                            seen by John, of the Isle of Patmos, clothed with the sun, and the moon under her feet." Think of it. " A new
                            thing in the earth," and " a great wonder in heaven," which must have been a new revelation there, or it would
                            not have been a wonder. The admirers and worshipers of Paul do not like the idea that woman must help roll
                            forward the car of progress ; they would much prefer that she should continue to " learn in silence of her
                            husband at home, with due sub- jection." We will say, " Peace to the ashes of the dead." We will not contend
                            with Bro. Paul for aught that he said or did, in his time, but will venture to say, that his day is over, as far
                            as the woman question is concerned. His counsel in that respect does not meet the needs nor demands of the
                            nineteenth century. Man has worked unaided by woman's influence in many departments of life, through a long
                            period. We will not say that he has not made progress. But now, a new era has dawned, and woman is called into
                            the field to act her part; and as well might we undertake to bring back the years before the flood, the
                            antediluvian period, as to change the course of events, or bind the spirit that is moving in this respect! There
                            are times and seasons in God's providence, just as much in the spiritual as in the natural; and we must work
                            according to his designs and his time. We do not go forth and scatter our seed over the land with the
                            expectation that it will germinate, and grow and produce a harvest, when the cold breath of winter is upon us,
                            and the snow-capped hills and ice-bound streams tell us it is neither seed-time nor harvest. Then how important
                            is it that we watch and strive to understand times and seasons, spiritually. Not merely " watch lest we enter
                            into temptation," which is very essential, but watch the seasons as they roll around. Are there wise men and
                            women, prophets and prophetesses in the ranks of the spiritua' Israel of to-day, who discern times and sea§ons,
                            so that they understand what Israel ought ;o do ? Is the present a seed-time? If so, et us work ! " sow the
                            seeds of truth in the morning, and withhold not in the evening. Let us sow by all waters." While some plant,
                            others may water; but God will give the increase in his own time. The duality of Deitjr is, to me, a beautiful
                            :dea ! To feel that we have a loving mother in Deity, who watches over, loves and cares for her children, and
                            feeds them from the great spiritual store-house in the heavens, touches a chord in my heart, and causes a thrill
                            of J03that nothing else could do. As long as we have all male Gods in the heavens wo shall have all male rulers
                            on the earth. But when the Heavenly Mother is revealed, and is sought unto as freely and confidingly as the
                            Heavenly Father, then will woman find her proper sphere of action, and be able to fill that sphere. Under the
                            guidance and direction of Wisdom and Love, she will work effectively against social, moral and political evils
                            on the natural plane of life, and help to elevate the race. Then, when the Spirit calls them to leave the
                            generative plane, and rise into the resurrection Order, to commence a new and purely spiritual life, on the
                            Pentecostal Church plan, it will be easy for them to become brethren and sisters in one heavenly communion,
                            breaking their bread together, spiritually and temporally. And, having their hearts and affections purified,
                            they will begin the song which will never end, and join in the dances of them that make merry—being filled with
                            holy rejoicing, that they are able to conquer the world in themselves.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers" TEIform="index"/>The Shakers</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Hooser, Samuel" TEIform="persName"/>SAMUEL HOOSER</byline><p TEIform="p">I often heard of Shakers, while in my native land, That they were a deluded, a blind bewitchingband; Such awful
                            news was spreading1, too horrid to relate, How wicked they were acting, in the Ohio State. At length I went
                            among them, to see how they went on, I quickly was convinced that these reports were wrong; I found them such a
                            people as I had never seen. So bright, so pure, so holy, and much opposed to sin. I often heard of Zion, but now
                            I've found the place, The city that's adorned with truth, and love, and grace; My heart was struck with wonder,
                            to find such gloi-y there, Where all was peace and union, without a single jar. I found Pd got to Zion, where
                            saints and angels dwelt, Such piercing streams of glory my soul had never felt; This is no place of darkness,
                            but one eternal day! Here doubts and fears are banished, and Satan cannot stay. I cried edien to pleasures of
                            every other kind, I'll give up all my idols, and leave the world behind; I've found the blessed people, with
                            whom I'll bear the cross, And count all earthly glory but vanity and dross. Here is the holy fire that burns all
                            sin and shame! The guilty sons of Babel cannot endure the flame. I'll shout eternal praises to Zion's King and
                            Queen, That I have found a gospel that saves the soul from sin. O why was I so stupid, to stay away so long! And
                            labor in confusion, with Babel's mixed throng But since I've found the city where Christ in glory reigns, I'll
                            bid adieu to Sodom, and all its dismal plains. Salvation here is flowing, from sin and dross refined! I'm
                            willing here to tarry, and leave my lusts behind, I feel my soul united to this despised flock ; Let earth and
                            hell oppose us, we're safe upon the rock. Though persecution rages, we'll boldly shout and sing, We shall be
                            safely guarded by Salem's conquering King; Amidst all tribulations, we feel our love increase, Altho' the world
                            may hate us, in Zion we have peace. Sweet union here is rolling, all through this happy place; Hei-e flows the
                            crystal fountain, and God unveils his face; Fair lilies here are growing, that never fade nor die; No other
                            ground produces such fruits of peace and joy. How blessed are the people who are admitted in, And dwell secure
                            in Zion, delivered from all sin! Their joys are still increasing, their songs are ever new, They love their
                            great Creator, and all their brethren too.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cross" TEIform="index"/>The Cross</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL ORCUTT</byline><p TEIform="p">What is the cross ? or wrhat is there in the cross which is objectionable ? Let us see. Of all who present
                            themselves as candidates for heaven, it is required that they become peni- tent for sin, poor in spirit, humble
                            as a little child; that they deny self, crucify the flesh, set the affections on things above, hunger and thirst
                            after righteousness, forgive enemies, and submit to persecution for Christ's sake. Yea, the whole man is to be
                            brought under new influences, to be governed by new principles, and to live for new ends. Self-denial,
                            selfdiscipline, and self-conquest are made indispensable prerequisites for the kingdom of heaven. This is the
                            cross. It stands in the path of life. Christ is the way; there is no other way; there can be no other. To
                            proceed in that way, we must embrace the cross. The cross is irksome and disagreeable only to the carnal mind;
                            it is its nature to be so. By bearing it, a man shall see and know what he is. To neglect the cross is to
                            neglect all; it is like going to the feast without the wedding garment, or like going forth to meet the
                            bridegroom without light, and without oil in our vessels. We may try to substitute something else for the cross,
                            but it will be all in vain. As long as we continue unwashed and impure, we are unsafe. Thus reads the
                            proclamation : "Except a man deny himself, and take up his cross, he cannot be my disciple." The Saviour has
                            conquered and reigns. We must conquer and reign also. No one can enter the kingdom of heaven, unless he be a
                            disciple of Christ. But no one is a disciple who bringeth not forth good fruit. Observe, it is not the person
                            who hears or believes the word, but the doer, that is, the prudent and wise man. It is folly to try to cany the
                            world and bear the cross together. The elements of the world cannot be united with the cross. Such a union is
                            declared impossible by the gospel, of which the influence, doctrines, tendencies, and final issues are contrary
                            to the maxims, prac- tices, and interests of the world. The Christ has pronounced the decision, "No man can
                            serve two masters."</p></div2><pb n="44" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reason" TEIform="index"/>Reason</head><byline TEIform="byline">BT <persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>ABRAHAM PERKINS</byline><p TEIform="p">Faith is the effect of evidence, the assent of the mind, proceeding from light, and standing in close connection
                            with the attributes of God, perfectly uncontrollable by any human power. Proportionate with knowledge of
                            scientific truth, faith is made perfect. Therefore, when founded on just and eternal principles, principles
                            nourished and lived, man is made better; while on the other hand, faith based on that which is perishable and
                            false, he is relatively made worse, however sincere he may be, or however true to its support. Hence the
                            importance of a knowledge of genuine godliness; and hence the necessity of an education that develops the
                            understanding, enlarges the mind, and capacitates it for the reception of the seed of divine truth, in which is
                            embraced a power to unfold the principles of all science, revealing a law in every creation and handiwork of
                            God. We are therefore compelled to understand that all we see, hear and feel is the effect of cause; and however
                            mysterious and incomprehensible to man, yet it is the result and operation of law, understood by a higher
                            intelligence. God is a rational Being, and as order is His first law, His works must necessarily be in
                            comformity to order and law. As a consequence, with God there is no miracle. Man being finite, is incapable of
                            comprehending the infinite beyond that which is necessary for the profitableness and happiness of himself, and
                            the acknowledgment of miracles would be the admission of other means of creation than by divine law, an
                            incongruity in universal law, and a detraction of wisdom from the character of the Almighty, which is heretical
                            to true faith, an offense against Christianity, and a doctrine untenable.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Success to the shaker: an acrostic" TEIform="index"/>Success to the Shaker. AN ACROSTIC</head><byline TEIform="byline">—BT <persName reg="Neal, Sarah A." TEIform="persName"/>SARAH A. NEAL</byline><p TEIform="p">Sad though thy march, lovely pilgrim, toil on! Unaided by many, rejected by some; yet Continue thy course, fair
                            Shaker sublime, Cease not to sow good, for now is seed time. Each virtue engraven upon thy fair face, Shall yet
                            merit love from the whole human race. Speed on, (hen, forever, thou herald of truth, To the far distant nations
                            of earth go ye forth. O ! halt not at trifles; climb the rough, rugged road To perfection's fair height, in the
                            kingdom of God. Heaven opens in splendor, the day now doth dawn, Earth's joys are dispersing as dews of the
                            morn. Soar aloft, then, O, Shaker ! and quicken thy speed, Henceforth be thy motto, to sow the good seed. Angel
                            bands will attend thee, and give thee success; Kind friends read thy columns with great earnestness. Eternal the
                            truths, on thy banner arrayed, Right shall yet rule the day, and cast wrong in the shade.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reform—the motion seconded" TEIform="index"/>"Reform."—The Motion Seconded</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Prentiss, Shubael" TEIform="persName"/>SnUBABL PRENTISS, SHAKERS, K. T.</byline><p TEIform="p">On reading 0. C. Hampton's article on Reform, n\y mind was very agreeably impressad, and I wish to express to him
                            my approval of it. I would say to Bro. Oliver and others, go ahead. It is time that all loathsome habits, such
                            as smoking, chewing and snuffing tobacco, and all excesses of eating and drinking should find no place among us
                            as believers in all true reforms. There is also a fashionable custom of using alcoholic drinks as medicine, in
                            cordials, bitters, etc. Whether the drug steeped in the alcohol is most desired, or the same swallowed as a
                            cover for the alcohol without it, I leave each to determine. I hold an opinion. I have seen bad habits formed
                            from this fashionable practice. Medicine can be prepared without alcohol, but would it then be as desirable ?
                            How much would then be used? Very little, I think. Doctors would starve for want of business; and they ought to
                            starve if they could not find better employ. I long for the day when humanity will be represented by " sound
                            minds in healthy bodies,"—bodies equally sound "as the beasts that perish." Would not it be as profitable
                            business for the generative world to take as much pains in the production of humanity as is now exercised for
                            quadrupeds ? I second the motion for " reform " on humanity's account, and in contemplation of Zion's needs.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the dear shakers of Enfield, N. H.:" TEIform="index"/>To the Dear Shakers of Enfield, N. H.:</head><p TEIform="p">My visit with you, my dear friends, has been pleasant, and I trust, very profitable to me spiritually. When I
                                reflect upon the general appearance of your Society, and recall the candid expressions of happiness and
                                content, together with the inspired instructions given me, bearing upon the eternal principles of life, I
                                think no real seeker after truth can fail to recognize the high-toned intelligence, the urbanity and purity
                                of character exemplified among you, without having a desire to advance in the scale of being to a purer and
                                holier life; aspiring to combine ail the best attributes of humanity in a true life. I feel to tender my
                                heartfelt gratitudo for the kind attentions received among you, and I would that all who come into your
                                circle might receive from you the baptism which I received. Although I am in the world, surrounded by all
                                classes of minds and diversities of character, perhaps I can do some good in proclaiming the good tidings of
                                saving power, vouchsafed to your people. Though not in form like your order, I have long been familiar with
                                the exercise of dancing in spirit, or, as it has been denominated, " dancing before the Lord," and holding
                                sweet communion with departed saints. The field is broad in which many are rejoicing in the reappearance of
                                God, as manifested through Jesus. And generations yet unborn shall rise up to be glorified in the true
                                worship, as manifested through the Shakers— a life worship. I am often shaken, to prove that God is spirit,
                                and must be worshipped in spirit and in truth. After leaving jour place, we spent several weeks with our
                                friends in Boston, Fall River, and in the Connecticut valley, and in each place all Avere interested with
                                the account of our visit to the Shakers. Some of my Spiritualist friends expressed a fear that they should
                                lose me out of their ranks; but so far as principles are concerned, I believe true Spiritualists and Shakers
                                to be nearly synonymous. Your books will have a faithful perusal, and " The Shaker " shall have a free
                                circulation. May the white-winged angel ever wave peace and prosperity over your beloved communit}^. Your
                                friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blossom, Eliza" TEIform="persName"/>Eliza Blossom, Middle Granville, N. Y.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My kind friend Eliza:" TEIform="index"/>Mr Kind Friend Eliza :</head><p TEIform="p">I received your very kind letter, and though I have so long deferred answering it, I would say, we hope and
                                trust with you that your visit with us will be productive of good. We are also pleased to know that you
                                appreciate the life and spirit which we are striving to maintain, and that you realized, in some degree, a
                                baptism of the spirit from the resurrection heavens, while with us. We believe that any one who receives the
                                degree of light and truth which is so manifestly evident you have received, though dwelling outside of the
                                relations of our Church, if true to the convictions of right in their own souls, cannot fail to realize,
                                when coming among us, something of the purity of life which we maintain, and the true love that draws us
                                together, and proclaims us the true, unselfish Christian Church. But no one can know much of our real inward
                                lives, unless they enter into the work unreservedly, and do as we have done—honestly confessing every known
                                sin before the "witnesses of God; striving to forsake them; making restitution for every wrong done to
                                others, as lies within our power. Those who have done this work, can testify that it yields them
                                justification, is as a consuming fire to the corrupt and sinful passions of their depraved natures, and
                                gives them power to rise, step by step, into the high and holy element of spiritual life. It expands our
                                love for our fellow beings, creates new fathers and mothers, new brothers and sisters, making the household
                                of Christ our nearest and dearest relations, who are free and welcome to enjoy every blessing that we
                                possess, both spiritual and temporal, in sickness and health. Hence, the temptations so prevalent outside of
                                our order, to sacrifice principle and chastity to obtain the means to pander to fashion, and procure the
                                necessaries of life, are not felt in our communities. Oh, Eliza ! when I go abroad among the rich and poor,
                                and see the contrast in their earthly comforts—some toiling to gain an honest livelihood by the sweat of the
                                brow, not able to obtain enough to clothe them decently, or supply the demands of hunger, while another
                                class revel in luxury, my spirit molts into sympathy, and I lift a prayer that the heavy chains of slavery,
                                which still rest upon the human family, may be broken. I bless the spirit so earnestly at work, to set poor,
                                down-trodden woman free from the bondage in which she is held (and I fear, by her own free will, too,) a
                                servant to passion, to the spoliation of her own health and happiness. What a contrast from my sweet Shaker
                                home, where not only the outside of the cup and platter are clean, but the inside also! Where love,
                                uncontaminated with worldly, fleshly lusts, bears sway, and keeps the whole household in order. Oh, may our
                                Eternal Father and Mother hasten the day when light shall be shed upon the souls of men, that they may
                                behold the beauties of this glorious Millenial, which has dawned upon <pb n="45" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. us,
                                and realize, by experience, the true happiness which the life of purity and entire consecration affords.
                                Though you have passed through many trying scenes of suffering and persecution, to attain to so great a
                                degree of the knowledge of God, you receive, if your experience is similar to ours, untold blessings for
                                every sacrifice, yea, a treasure, far surpassing all worldly riches, honor or fame. You say that some of
                                your Spiritualist friends Were afraid they should lose you from their ranks. We think, when they see us as
                                we are, they will not fear the loss of you or any other good member, but will strive to bring themselves up
                                to our standard, and rejoice to see any one forsaking the perishing joys and pleasures that are now urging
                                millions into the common vortex of human depravity. You say, " The field is broad in which many are
                                rejoicing in the reappearance of God, as manifested through Jesus ; " also, *' Generations yet unborn shall
                                rise up to be glorified in the true worship, as given through the Shakers." Here, I see, is a prophecy. Our
                                kindest love to yourself and daughter, we remain your true friends, The Shakers.</p><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Caroline" TEIform="persName"/>Caroline. Enfield, N. H.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Future work of spiritualism" TEIform="index"/>The Future Work of Spiritualism</head><p TEIform="p">As Spiritualists, our work measures and overarches all the reforms of the age. To continue it successfully
                            requires brave, enthusiastic and self-sacrificing men and women; Media passive, pure and holy in every
                            aspiration; speakers with tongues of lire, hearts pulsing with prayer, intellects rich in genius and culture,
                            and souls touched with the baptism of the living Christ. We are in the Second Coming. The angels are already in
                            the clouds of heaven. There is about to be a religious revival such as the world has not seen for eighteen
                            centuries. Christians will be converted; outsiders will inquire the way to Zion; Christ spirits will lead them;
                            the white faces of martyrs will illumine their pathway. After the cross, the crown. The very foundations of the
                            old social, political and theological religions are being shaken. " I will shake earth and the heavens also,"
                            said God by the prophet. The world is becoming literally a world of Shakers. The most stupendous drama In
                            history is now unfolding. The sixth trumpet has sounded. The books are open. The world is the stage; nations the
                            actors. The fig tree has put forth. The angels of the spiritual dispensation are calling us to judgment. My soul
                            pleads for you " yet a little longer," and the "spirit and the bride say come.'' Are your lamps trimmed and
                            burning? Answer as in the presence of God's angels. Let us, Oh Spiritualists, be true to our convictions; true
                            to our moral and religious natures ; true to the principles of purity and right; then should our mortal barks
                            speedily strand, or go down even, they will only sink to rise yito those calmer seas that make divinely
                            beautiful the love-lands of the angels.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/>J. M. Peebles</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My shaker faith" TEIform="index"/>My Shaker Faith</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Barrett, Andrew" TEIform="persName"/>ANDREW BARRETT</byline><p TEIform="p">What thanks and praise to God belong, Who gave to me this precious faith; It is an anchor, firm and strong. The
                            best estate a Shaker hath. Thanks be to God for holy faith, That bears me through all trials sore, And like a
                            light in shades of night, A stay when angry billows roar. When trials weigh my spirit down, And troubles like
                            the tempests beat, Faith is my guide, and points the way— Directing sure my erring feet. It leads my bark
                            through calms and storms, And like a skillful pilot, too, It proves to me of greatest worthFaith is the guide I
                            will pursue. Faith is my armour and my shield— A heavenly weapon, bright and sure; It makes my greatest foes to
                            yield, And gives me courage to endure. Faith is the holy gospel ground, Where heavenly beauties ever show; Where
                            plants of purity abound, And innocence will thrive and grow. Lord, may this living faith increase— Grow daily
                            stronger in my soul; It is the guide that leads me o'er All dangerous rocks, each tempting shoal. It is the
                            compass that directs The soul to heaven's port above; To dwell with those who live in truth, And bonds of
                            everlasting love.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mother" TEIform="index"/>Mother</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">By the same process by which we trace out the existence of the Supreme Being, and the various attributes which
                            are generally ascribed to him, we arrive at the conclusion that there are in the Divine nature both masculine
                            and feminine principles. The universal Father and Mother are necessary complements of each other. Both combine
                            the formation of worlds, on which their image is indelibly impressed. So plainly is this inscribed there, that
                            one needs only to open his eyes to be able to read the inscription wherever he turns his gaze. It requires no
                            metaphysical acumen, no laborious investigation, to reach this result, but merely the simple process by which we
                            attain to ordinary truth, so that one who has admitted this truth into his mind, wonders that a thing so plain
                            should have escaped the observation of reflecting minds in Christendom for so many ages. Yet we may account for
                            this from the fact that, instead of looking into the great volume of nature, spread open before them, they have
                            drawn their ideas from the Scriptures, where masculinity alone is generally ascribed to Deity. Other nations,
                            whom we, Christians, in our self-conceit, have been accustomed to style ignorant, God-forsaken heathen, have had
                            clearer perceptions of thi truth. Gods and goddesses both have formed the groundwork of their theology, however
                            absurd many of its details may appear to us. There are reasons for believing that Jesus acknowledged the fact
                            that Mother as well as Father subsist in Deity, though our canonical gospels represent him as using exclusively
                            the term Father when addressing or speaking oi God. In the Gospel, according to the Hebrews, translated into the
                            Greek and Latin languages by Jerome, one of the early Christian fathers, was a passage quoted by Origen, another
                            early Christian father, which represents Jesus as saying, "My Mother, the Holy Spirit, took me and brought me to
                            the great mountain Tabor." The book from which this was quoted, was not ranked a; canonical by those who made
                            the selection from among all the Christian books anciently written, yet is as likely to have been genuine as
                            those thus classed. Eusebius, the early ecclesiastical historian, says, " The Ebionide use only the Gospel
                            according to the He- brews." These were a body of Christian living mostly near Jerusalem in the earlies' times.
                            Regarding the Holy Spirit, then, as Mother we see the propriety of the words of Jesus addressed to Nicodemus,—"
                            Except one be jorn of the spirit, he cannot enter into the cingdom of God." This is not a mere figure of speech,
                            but alludes to the real and substan;ial work of regeneration wrought in the beiever, so that in life and spirit
                            he becomes a lew creature, being completely transformed from the earthly to the heavenly life. The Divine Father
                            and Mother, through the ministrations of angels, both male and female, devoted Jesus himself to the life of
                            unchanging love. " Ye shall see heaven open, and the angels of God descending to and ascending from the Son of
                            Man," were words addressed by him to the guileless Nathanael, which assured him and other disciples of their
                            prospective induction into the profoundest truths of the heavenly life. Various figures were used in the ancient
                            prophecies, expressive of the female principle in Deity. In the 115th Psalm she is represented by the Queen
                            sitting at the right hand of the King, whose " throne God is for the age of ages." Her name is " to dc
                            remembered in every generation, and the people shall acknowledge her from age to age." (See Septuagint version.)
                            The pre-eminent influence in the Church of Christ, which is to govern that and ultimately the whole world,
                            emanates from Deity as Father and Mother, in the psalm represented by the King and Queen, to whom all inferior
                            authorities must finally submit. In the book of Zechariah, their repre- sentatives are described as " the two
                            Anointed Ones—two Christs—who stand by the Lord of the whole earth." In rebuilding the temple spoken of by the
                            same prophet, the hands of Zerrubbabel—strange to confusion—laid the foundation, and his hands were to finish
                            it; yet, " This is the word of the Lord to Zerubbabel: Not b\r might, nor by power, but by my Spirit, saith the
                            Lord of hosts." The mountain difficulties in the way of its erection were to be removed by the Spirit as the
                            Divine Mother, and the cap-stone was to be put on " with shouting, Grace, grace to it." There is an allusion
                            here to the practice of giving some expressive name to a building, when its frame has been raised, or the
                            finishing stone laid on, by those engaged in erecting it. The practice is still kept up in some places even in
                            this country. From the top of the edifice one calls out to another, asking what name shall be given to it, and
                            the other replies by giving the name selected, which is confirmed by the unanimous shout of all present. The
                            name to be given to the temple, when the finishing stone should be put on, was to be Grace, or Beauty, one very
                            expressive of the finishing work of the Mother of salvation. Grace, representing not only the Divine favor, but
                            the refinement, beauty and perfection of spirit in all those who are the subjects of it. The Hebrew word,
                            rendered Grace, is the one from which we have derived our proper name Ann, and those translated "to it" read
                            Lee, as any one may see, who is familiar with the Hebrew. When the mountain of a carnal nature, which hides from
                            the soul the Sun of Righteousness, was leveled to a plain in Mother Ann, by her unceasing efforts, aided by the
                            Holy Mother Spirit, then Grace and 4:5 <pb n="46" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. Beauty shone forth in her character in a
                            re- markable degree; then was she constituted Mother in Christ, able, by Divine assistance, to help others to
                            effect the same work in themselves, and thus to become the sons and daughters of God in the very highest sense
                            of the terms,—the legitimate offspring not only of the Eternal Father, but also of the Co-eternal Mother.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What induced you to join the shakers?" TEIform="index"/>''What Induced you to Join the Shakers?"</head><byline TEIform="byline">BT <persName reg="Webster, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName"/>ELIZABETH H. WEBSTER</byline><p TEIform="p">'T was not that I might win a name Among1 the gay and fair; For earthly flatt'ries are but tame, They'll vanish
                            into air. Nor to enjoy the transient bliss The child of pleasure knows; 'T was not a selfish cause as this, That
                            so much good bestows. 'T was not for ease or wealth I pined— Enough of all I had; I heard that constant toil I'd
                            find, In "^Jhaker land so sad.1' I thirsted for the " living spring " Whence true enjoyment flows ; Its little
                            streams did comfort bring— I'd seek it where it rose. I longed to gain the heavenly grase, That dwelt in Christ,
                            our head; That strengthened him to " grow apace," And raised him from the dead. I saw him suffering, meek and
                            mild, Yet bold and firm for right; In agony, whilst others smiled, And watchings all the night. I saw him cast
                            earth's honors by, Reject the offered crown ; And with his Father's will comply, Nor pomp, nor splendor own. "
                            My kingdom 's not of earth,'' he said, And proved it by his life, As on the altar all he laid, Nor murmured at
                            the strife. I heard him when his mother came, Her much loved son to see, Amidst the gathering crowds exclaim— "
                            My mother—who is she ? 'T is such as do my Father's will, My friends and brethren are; " These are the ones my
                            joy doth fill, To me they're dearer far. I heard him called a friend of wrong, For teachings such as these; I
                            saw him lashed with cruel thongs, Nor would their wrath appease. I saw him his disciples meet, Ere yet his
                            hornhad come, And thus with tones of love entreat— "Be followers of the Lamb." I've looked around with anxious
                            eye, Far o'er this wondrous earth, To find those who theni3elves deny, And follow him in truth. One seeks for
                            gold, the miser's trust, With eager, panting heart; Another worships mortal dust, Nor gives to Christ a part.
                            Another, though of Christian name, Still follows his own lusts; And while he worships still the same, His good
                            my soul distrusts. Bright beings I could round me see, Of gentleness and love; By nature clad their souls must
                            be, Not " wisdom from above.'1 But where are those who battle long, With anger, pride and sin; And fight with
                            courage bold and strong. Their foes that lurk within ? I heard of spirits who had fled From thoughtless scenes
                            of earth, And in the life which Jesus led Praised him with joy and mirth. I found this holy love embraced " The
                            Brotherhood in one; " They " dwell in love," as Christ has said, And " by these fruita are known." Their faith
                            and works together blend, To make the whole complete, Nor idly dream that faith will lend, A robe for glory
                            meet. In Christ-like purity they dwell, And keep a conscience clean; Their blessed Lord they love full well, And
                            honor Zion's Queen. The virgins in the dance rejoice, Old men and blooming youth, And daily praise, with solemn
                            voice, The God of love and troth. These are the ones, exclaimed my soul, Who walk with Christ in white; Whom
                            purity and love control, And they are God's delight. But when I saw how high they stood, And still how very low.
                            How great a price they pay for good, How few the straight way go,— I shuddering, asked myself, can I So great an
                            offering make, And be content to daily die, My Saviour's yoke to take ? •'A fire I kindle,'' Jesus said, " Which
                            will the house divide," What though the dross be there consumed, The gold is purified. But who can paint how
                            great my grief, When those I loved, reviled; And sent me forth, a bruised leaf, My fondest prayers denied! My
                            babes in mercy to me spare, The ones for whom I live; And let them have the tender care My fond heart loves to
                            give ! Who will their little griefs assuage, And comfort in distress, And teach them in their infant age, Plow
                            to forgive and bless? Alas! a mother pleads in vain, The vow to love 's forgot; But strength from the angelic
                            train Comes whispering, "fear ye not.1' But can I bear reproach and scorn, From those who once have loved? Can I
                            be thrown, a worm forlorn, Upon the Best Beloved ? O, can I share the humble lot, Of those so poor and low, And
                            like my Master, have no spot Of rest while here below ? Can I endure from all to part, My loved and valued
                            friends; And drink, though with a bleeding heart, Of every cup he sends ? The same good spirit that shed light,
                            Now spake within my breast; And gave me strength to choose the rieht, Where I find peace and rest. The
                            conflict's now with inward foes— I'll kiss the chastening rod; My part I'll bear of Jesus' woes, My all I give
                            to God. Though sorrows rise. I'll never fear; The " goodly pkakl " I've found; 'T was this, my friend, that
                            brought me here, On consecrated ground.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ann Lee's testimony of Jesus" TEIform="index"/>Ann Lee's Testimony of Jesus.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lee, Ann" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Job Bishop testifies hearing Mother Ann say: "Jesus had to overcome the nature and spirit of the world, the same
                            as we have; and you must all do the same, or you can never go to God." </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> Back numbers of present volume are in all cases supplied to subscribers; and we shall continue thus to do until
                            July, when it will be optional with subscribers.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Parable no. 3" TEIform="index"/>Parable No. 3</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Pelham, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. PELHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">Vicarious Atonement.—Jesus a Surety. There is another phase of vicarious atonement, presenting man as a debtor,
                            instead of setting him forth as a criminal, guilt)1of capi- tal offense. Paul speaks of Jesus being made "the
                            surety of a better covenant." We will here give the comment of the famous commentator, Dr. Gill, who thus
                            explains : " Christ is the surety of the better testament or covenant. Heb. 7, 22. The word signifies one that
                            draws nigh. Christ drew nigh to his Father in the counsel of peace, and undertook to be the saviour and redeemer
                            of his people. [The Dr. seems to have been present at that counsel !] He substituted himself in their room and
                            stead ; he interposed between the creditor and the debtor, and became surety for the payment of the debts of the
                            latter, and so stood engaged for them and in their room. Christ is not the surety for the Father to his people,
                            but for them to the Father, as to satisfy for their sins, to work out a righteousness for them, and make them
                            happy [in their sins], which is an instance of matchless love." To illustrate this view of the vicarious
                            atonement, we set forth the following parable : M. is indebted to G., and becomes hopelessly insolvent, and
                            prays G. to forgive him the debt, as he is rich and able to lose. Nay, says G., the debt is just, and unless you
                            pay up, or give security, I will forthwith have you arrested and cast into prison, and you shall not come out
                            thence till you pay the uttermost farthing. In M.'s extremity, the benevolent J. comes along, and offers himself
                            to G. as M.'s "surety," and is accepted. G. then addressing himself to M., said, " Remember, justice cannot be
                            set aside. I have a thousand other debtors, or may have, and if I were to give way in this instance, they would
                            all be on hand, wanting forgiveness. I will have my own, and I will either take it out of you or your surety ;
                            when the debt is paid, you and I will be on good terms again." But M. still pleading, says, notwithstanding J.
                            is becoming my surety, I am nformed that he has failed, and is as poor as I am, and he proves the truth of this
                            statement by the infallible word—the Bible—which declares that, " tho' J. was rich, he became poor" (2 Cor. 8,
                            9), and J. says, " of himself he can do nothing." This being the case, you will have to forgive him, for when
                            the principal and surety both fail, the debt must be canceled. I beseech you, therefore, to forgive me at once,
                            and not trouble him, as he is innocent, and in reality does not owe this debt. Nay, nav, says G., eternal
                            justice shall never be cheated so. I will let all intelligences in all worlds know that they may never hope to
                            escape my justice ! Finally J. was arrested, and though he declared h_had not one cent more than to meet his own
                            wants, and not even that without help, yet G. pushed the prosecution, till, in some mysterious way, J. was
                            furnished with means, and discharged the debt. It is said that this mystery was revealed to a certain hierarchal
                            order, self-styled orthodox, who professed great intimacy with G., who 46 <pb n="47" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SH^KEH. had
                            entrusted them with a knowledge of his secret decrees. They stated that G., J., and one H. were joint partners
                            in trade, the title of the firm being " FatJier, Son, and Holy Ghost," and J. was furnished with the means of
                            paying the debt out of their joint funds, which, however, all belonged to G. Thus G., the great stickler for
                            justice, secretly paid the debt himself in this underhanded way, in order to keep up a show of his inflexible
                            character for justice. Many sensible people thought that the ends of justice would have been quite as well
                            answered, and the ends of Jove and benevolence much better, to have forgiven the debt at once. But we have not
                            got to the end of this matter. This G., who had hitherto been thought somewhat of a benevolent sort of person,
                            being rather overstrained about his eternal justice, so as almost to exclude mercy, now began to develop a most
                            malignant character. With all his bluster about justice, he himself violated her nature m the most shocking
                            manner. After M., through his "surety," had paid the debt, and been discharged, G. had him arrested for capital
                            offense, and without any formal trial, sentenced him to eternal torments. J. again plead M.'s cause, and again
                            offered himself for surety. G. is inexorable ; says no surety is allowed in cases of capital offense. M. shall
                            meet his sentence, or you, J., shall suffer the full extent of his punishment as his substitute. Justice must
                            and shall be satisfied. Poor, merciful, sympathetic J. agrees to become a substitute of the whole race of M.,
                            and the inexorable, unforgiving G. accepted the offer, and as it reads, Acts 2, 23, J. was delivered up by the
                            determinate counsel and foreknowledge of G., and suffered a most painful immolation. His offer to do this was on
                            the condition that the ivhole race should be saved. " He tasted death for every man." Yet G., after agreeing to
                            this, only extended the benefit of J.'s substitution and suffering to a few select sinners, called the elect,
                            but vowed eternal vengeance on ninetenths of mankind. Thus G. displayed his " glorious justice," by defrauding
                            J. out of far the greater portion of those whom he had suffered and died to redeem. Such is the character which
                            orthodox Calvinism gives to the infinitely good and wise Creator of heaven and earth—the God and Father of our
                            Lord Jesus Christ.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our happiness" TEIform="index"/>Our Happiness</head><byline TEIform="byline">BT <persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL ORCUTT</byline><p TEIform="p">The happiness derived from the performance of good deeds is of the highest, of the purest kind; it is, indeed,
                            the only lasting enjoyment. The vilest sinner on the earth, if he has done one good action, has a perception of
                            this truth. Then how strange that millions should risk their health, their life, and their eternal happiness
                            upon the pursuit of those pleasures which end in pain, and should entirely neglect this source of enjoyment,
                            which is accessible to all, and Avhich not only brightens life, but removes the sting of death. Since this life
                            is a preparatory state, to be succeeded by one in which every spiritual power will be greatly expanded, and
                            every capacity for happiness or misery will be greatly enlarged; and since the state of our future being will be
                            determined by the manner in Avhich this brief opening of our existence is spent, is it not surprising that any
                            intelligent being should over-estimate and depend upon the fleeting things of Time ? Should not the thought, " I
                            must live forever," shut every eye, and turn every heart from these trifles, and arouse every power of the soul
                            to the work of preparation for eternity.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker cemetaries" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Cemeteries</head><byline TEIform="byline">BT <persName reg="Sawyer, Otis" TEIform="persName"/>OTIS SAWYER</byline><p TEIform="p">" Why do Shakers appear to have so little respect for their deceased members ? Why do they neglect to furnish
                            them monuments, and bedeck their graves Avith flowers, shrubbery ? etc." I answer : First, living objects of
                            charity—those who cannot wait for remembrance—are all around us; those in the grave do not suffer. Secondly, we
                            abominate idolatry; and such "cities of the dead " as Mt. Auburn and Greenwood are the fashionable institutions
                            of idol worshippers. Money is lavishly, wickedly spent thus, while the living poor have not where to lay their
                            heads, or wherewith to appease their hunger. We do not believe in a physical resurrection, nor that our dear
                            departed lie in the ground; neither will they ever have need to use the decaying mortality again—this having
                            subserved its purpose, as an old, worn-out garment, it is laid aside forever. We look to those mansions, "
                            eternal in the heavens," for those we loved on earth; for "in my Father's house there are many," agreeable to
                            the condition each has attained unto in the great work of salvation. When assembled at our funerals, the souls
                            of our departed loved ones often make their presence known, and their voices chime with ours as we sing: "And
                            when I am called to leave earth, so fair, O chant not a mournful refrain; Let angelic music float free on the
                            air, Count all earthly losses my gain! " We are sorry to part Avith loved gospel companions, but we do not
                            foolishly express our soitoav by mournful habiliments and badges. We mourn only for the "dead in trespasses and
                            sin"—for those who, having tasted of " the powers of the Avorld to come," turn back to the " beggarly elements
                            of the Avorld"—for these we sincerely mourn. We never shock our oavii nor other souls by singing, "Hark! from
                            the tombs," etc., for Ave seek in no such place of " rottenness and dead bones" our needed inspirations. We need
                            erect no monuments to bear witness what we wish to remember of them; their virtues are engraven on our hearts as
                            perpetual reminders of good examples. Our graveyards are simple, yet unostentatious. They please our spirit
                            friends, Avho visit us, more than would an intemperate display of marble. Virtues are more enduring than
                            granite, and in these our faithful friends have laid up treasures that are safe from moth and rust. We believe
                            in decently interring the mortality of those who are happily released from the troubles of earth. A plain slab,
                            Avith name and age, mwks the spot. Mother Ann Lee's grave differs not at all from those of her surrounding
                            children. We advise that the various appropriations now uselessly expended on cemeteries, should be used for the
                            elevation of the downcast, homes for the destitute, and for charitable and religious purposes generally. Then
                            would humanity be honored Avith lasting remembrances, and angels delight in the resurrection of the people from
                            dead icorks to living shrines,—from the honoring of the dead to the association of the living. We die as did
                            Jesus—unto sin; like him we are daily crucified—unto the world ; we realize a present reAvard with an increasing
                            happiness. With him we are enjoying life eternal; and if, like his, our earthly grave should be unknown", no
                            harm will accrue to any, nor should Ave care.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Short sermons" TEIform="index"/>Short Sermons</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Buckingham, D. A." TEIform="persName"/>D. A. BUCKINGHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">The doctrine of James Whittaker (one of the founders of our Institution), was, " Be what you seem to be, and seem
                            what you really are, and not carry two faces." Dissimulation of character is too prevalent in the world;
                            particularly is it out of place among Christians, or those who profess to be such. What fraud, Avhat doAvnright
                            knavery is practiced among mankind under the cloak of religious profession ! Seeming to be what they are
                            not—Christians. True Christians being themselves honest, are apt to place confidence in those who profess to be
                            so, but often, when perhaps too late, find that many sail under false colors. "Repentance," said he, "will yet
                            be the most joyful sound ever heard by mortals. True repentance is forsaking sin. Where Christ is, there is
                            power to put away sin from the soul; and Avhere there is no power to put away sin, there is no Christ"—no real
                            Christianity. Repentance is preceded by confession. " He that covereth his sins, shall not prosper, but Avhoso
                            confesseth and forsaketh them, shall find mercy." Mother Ann Lee, Avhen instructing her disciples or immediate
                            folloAvers, said to them, " Own God''where you find Him, Avhether in man, luoman or child." There is some good,
                            some degree of virtue in all men ; even a child may possess the germs of Christianity, Avhich, if properly
                            cultivated, Avill grow and flourish in life. Parents and guardians of the young should seek to plant the seeds
                            of truth and honesty in them, Avhile their spirits are yielding and susceptible. " Train up a child in the Avay
                            he should go," is a maxim of long standing. Virtuous principles should be early inculcated, that in after life
                            they may bring forth fruit—thirty, sixty, or a hundred fold. Christians should so live daily as to be walking
                            with Christ in the present tense, and enjoying a foretaste of the bliss of immortal 47 <pb n="48" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER. and angelic life. Sin is the great obstacle, hiding from mortals the beatitude of the heavenly spheres.
                            It veils from us the glorious future, as well as depriving us of present happiness. " Be ye perfect, even as
                            your Father in heaven is perfect." Not so much what we now are, as what we may, can, or must be— the ultimate of
                            good works. Now, to arrive at perfection of any kind requires time and growth,—not an immediate effect, but a
                            gradual change, step by step, or from one degree to another. A true Christian character is attainable only in
                            regeneration—being born anew, born of God, in which state or condition a soul " cannot sin, because thejr are
                            born of God. We progress by and through faith. " Faith," we read, " is a gift of God "—seed planted in the soul,
                            where it must germinate, mature, and perfect. Man lives by faith until he can obtain something better to subsist
                            upon. Experience or knowledge is more reliable and substantial than faith. The latter is only " the substance
                            ofthings hoped for, and an evidence of things not seen." Hope leaves a convert in expectation, not really in
                            present enjoyment. For, according to the Apostle, " we hope not for that which we see and enjoy." Have good
                            regard for the consciences of men, wherever they are, and respect the sincere, devotional worship of all
                            persuasions, whether Mohammedan or Christian. Sincerity will commend the soul to God. It is the heart God looks
                            at. " He is no respecter of persons, but in every nation he that feareth him and worketh righteousness, is
                            accepted of him." " Pray without ceasing," saith the Apostle. How can a man's thoughts be constantly in prayer?
                            By being constant in Christian duty. Af kindness, deeds of charity, hands to work, and soul to God—these form
                            the most effective prayer, as well as the loudest preaching. Prayer, to be effectual, must be fervent —nothing
                            doubting. "The effectual, fervent prayer of the righteous availeth much."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-examination" TEIform="index"/>Self-Examination</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Ervin, Anne" TEIform="persName"/>ANNE ERVIN</byline><p TEIform="p">It is remarkable that in the New Testament there is no elaboration by the Apostles of this subject, which must
                            present itself to the thoughtful Christian as one of the very first importance. A few, though very valuable
                            thoughts are to be found scattered through St. Paul's writings, such as " circumcision of the heart; " to the
                            Corinthians, " Examine your- selves whether ye be in the faith ; prove your own selves; " before any one come to
                            the Lord's Supper, he urges that " a man examine himself." Neither James, Peter, Jude, nor John contains a word
                            directly inculcating the necessity of heart-search. Yet all their teach- ings incidentally require more or less
                            to give them practical effect. Nothing in the writer.'s opinion could better illustrate the essential
                            distinction between our forerunners, the primitive Christians, and ourselves, than the fact that the former
                            advanced doctrines which in themselves require a certain amount of selfexamination, but failed to see that a
                            deep, vital, an intense and ever-increasing heartsearch is one of the essentials of spiritual life. But we, who
                            are called to partake with our Lord of a continual feast, not of an external ommemoration of his death, but to
                            partake forever of the same death, suffering, and joy; we who are called in very truth to be a royal priesthood,
                            whose sovereignty is over death ; whose only acceptable offerings are those of a meek and pure spirit; whose
                            treasures consist in the sweet graces of Christ; whose conquests are only of our own evil natures,—it behooves
                            us surely with every energy we possess to search and diligently try our hearts, that we may progress in our high
                            calling. For it is quite certain that never shall we rise in the resurrection, until we have thoroughly seen
                            ourselves. Oh, what depths of depravity has every honest mind discovered within itself! What a distance between
                            itself and the divine intelligence ! What depths of humiliation has every sincere struggler experienced from
                            deep self-sight! But in the discovery of this depravity, in this sense of loss and of humiliation, there is
                            promise of ultimate safety. It is certain that no one has found salvation without experiencing these sufferings.
                            Now, to enter upon serious self-examina- tion, we have need to bring an intelligent understanding of the purpose
                            of our work. We are called to travel out of death into life. Death is every moral evil which diseased humanity
                            inherits ; life is purity, love, unselfishness in heart and mind. What a world of work is here involved for
                            every soul! A lifetime, in which every thought and effort has been directed to this great work, is not
                            sufficient to subdue every evil propensity of the heart. And unless we enter into the work with a single and
                            simple determination to conquer, we shall not be likely to meet with much success. Surely then it is needful to
                            strain every nerve to see our failings, because, until we do see them, we are unable to eradicate them. When we
                            have seen that we possess certain failings, we must be ready to admit to ourselves that we do possess them. If
                            we do not, we shall not grapple with them. When we have seen and admitted to ourselves our failings, we must
                            devote our attention with all diligence and patience to eradicate those evil propensities. The single-hearted
                            should not be impatient with themselves, nor should they be surprised if, with the honestest effort, they
                            sometimes fail to come quite up to the standard they have set for themselves. Soil which has for a length of
                            time been injured by bad tillage, needs care, skill, patience, to bring it to a crop-bearing state. There are
                            some who bring to the gospel work, much of honest intention in many respects, but who, to excessive love of
                            approbation, join painful incapacity for internal search. Now these persons cannot fail to be aware of this, and
                            they should beware of themselves. Herein is their great cross. Let them thankfully labor day and night until
                            they do really gain an insight of themselves. Let them keep before themselves the greatness of the work they are
                            called unto. To these may appropriately be applied the saying of St. James respecting those who hear the gospel,
                            yet do not its requirements, that they are like "unto a man beholding his natural face in a glass; for he
                            beholdeth himself, and goeth his way, and straightway forgetteth what manner of man he was." Those who are
                            endowed with a capacity to see and remember their own failings, are indeed greatly blessed. Let them be careful
                            to improve to the uttermost this faculty. But ye, who are critical of the faults of others, I say unto you,
                            awake ! This is not the work you are called to. Remember that the righteous scarcely be saved." Those who are,
                            with single purpose of heart, laboring to subdue themselves, looking neither to the right hand nor to the left,
                            who "shut their eyes from seeing evil" in others, but are constantly alive to their own evil natures; these, by
                            constant internal search, toil and suffering, scarcely be saved. Where then shall ye appear, who are occupied in
                            observing how little others are carrying out the principles of meekness and godly fear that ye are neglecting ?
                            Remember that the angel Michael, that bright and perfect being who is striving to perform his Work upon you,
                            dared not to bring a railing accusation against Satan, when he contended with him. Oh! remember that true
                            self-examination will produce that fervent charity which will close your lips from speak- ing aught against
                            another, and will save those who love you the painful sight of beholding you very bitter against others for the
                            failings which you possess in even a greater degree. Remember, if you possess the Spirit of Truth, he will
                            search out for you the thoughts and intents of your own heart; that he will pierce you even to the dividing
                            asunder of your soul and spirit. But alas! how many gain a glimpse of surface light; how few penetrate the
                            interior !</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>[Obituary]</head><p TEIform="p">The following obituaries have been lately reported:</p><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Goodnough, Joseph" TEIform="index"/>Joseph Goodnongh
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Goodnough, Joseph" TEIform="persName">Joseph Goodnongh</persName>, Watervliet, N. Y., March 17, aged 83.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Holt, Thomas W." TEIform="index"/>Thos. W. Holt
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Holt, Thos. W." TEIform="persName">Thos. W. Holt</persName>, Canterbury, N. H., April 6, aged 71.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Foster, Clarissa" TEIform="index"/>Clarissa Foster
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Foster, Clarissa" TEIform="persName">Clarissa Foster</persName>, Canterbury, N. H., April 2, aged 73.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Myrick, Jesse" TEIform="index"/>Jesse Myrick
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Myrick, Jesse" TEIform="persName">Jesse Myrick</persName>, Harvard, April 10, aged 92.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Quance, Hannah" TEIform="index"/>Hannah Quance
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Quance, Hannah" TEIform="persName">Hannah Quance</persName>, Enfield, Conn., April 4, aged 45.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pease, Clarissa" TEIform="index"/>Eldress Clarissa Pease
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Pease, Clarissa" TEIform="persName">Eldress Clarissa Pease</persName>, Enfield. Conn., April 15, aged 59.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Annis, Henry" TEIform="index"/>Henry Annis
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Annis, Henry" TEIform="persName">Henry Annis</persName>, Enfield, N. H., May 2, aged 68.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="American Spiritualis" TEIform="index"/>The American Sjnritualist</head><p TEIform="p"> is worthy the support of all progressive minds. Its Spiritualism is in the right direction—teaching to "walk in
                            the Spirit"—and thus we claim that it precedes The Shaker as a John Baptist. A. A. Wheelock, 29 Beekman St., New
                            York. $2.50 per year.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="[Members of society]" TEIform="index"/>[Members of society]
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Elder F. W. Evans, Mt. Lebanon, Columbia Co., N. Y. " Galen Richmond, Shakers, N. Y. " Calvin G. Reed, Jit.
                            Morris, Livingston Co., N. Y. " Simon Mabee, West Pittsfield, Mass. " Stoughton Kellogg, Thompsonville, Conn.,
                            Shakers. " Albert Battles, Tyringham, Berkshire Co., Mass. " Wm. Leonard, Ayer, Mass., Shakers. " Jonas Xntting,
                            Shirley Village, Middlesex Co., Mass. " B. H. Smith, Shaker Village, Merrimack Co., N. H. " Henry Cummings,
                            Enfield, Grafton Co., N. H. " John B. Vance, Alfred, Shakers. York Co., Me. " Joseph Brackett, West Gloucester,
                            Cumberland Co., Me.. Shakers. " Chas. Clapp, Union Village, Warren Co., O., Shakers. " Ezra Sherman, Preston,
                            Hamilton Co., Ohio, Shakers. " Stephen Ball, Dayton, Shakers, Ohio. " Jacob Kulp, Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co., Ky.
                            " J. K. Eades, South Union, Logan Co., Ky. " J. S. Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio, Shakers. 48</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>