<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0707" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shakers, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><date value="18770701" TEIform="date">July 1877</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">49-56</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="49" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER. OFFICIAL MONTHLY.—PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. " %° yreucl{ the kingdom of
                        %oAl" Jpe testimony of efarnnJ tt[ath.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lord's prayer" TEIform="index"/>The Lord's Prayer</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName"/>WATSON ANDREWS</byline><p TEIform="p">A very popular preacher has said : " No man can conscientiously pray that prayer." ;' Thy
                            kingdom come? Thy will be done on earth as in heaven?" " No man can pray it; it goes
                            crashing through a man's world of self-love, like a hundred-pound shell through a river
                            steamer ! What; the will of God done on earth, as it is by the angels of heaven ! They '
                            neither marry nor are given in marriage.' They have no banks, no deeds, no mortgages, no
                            money ; millionaires, paupers, nor fashion plates ! " The above preacher seems not to have
                            been aware that this prayer has been granted—by power being given to men and women to
                            overcome the same world which Jesus overcame ! All carnal, unspiritual desires, and their
                            gratification, are possibly overcome ; all sources of happiness, that aspire to make the
                            physical senses superior to the spiritual, are capable of being dethroned. Those things that
                            "perish with the using" are far from being eternal. We ask those who are interested in
                            eternal life, to read of Jesus, and study Shakerism. The prayer is accomplished. N. Union,
                            O.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dependence" TEIform="index"/>Dependence</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">"If thy presence go not with me, carry us not up hence." If the individual souls of Abram and
                            Moses sought after God as a divine director of their souls, through invisible agencies, or
                            mediators, called the Lord, or angel of the Lord, when those men had become the head of a
                            body composed of like-minded individual souls, that body could well say, by its mouth-piece,
                            "If thy presence go not with us, carry us not up hence." The same is equally true of our
                            organized body. The life of God in the human soul is the one thing needful to preserve from
                            evil and to empower the soul to be and to do good. Consequently, every true member of such
                            body should pray that the visible head and lead of such body be led by the Holy Spirit of
                            the hrAible church in the spirit world.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion vs. science" TEIform="index"/>Religion vs. Science</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, Oliver" TEIform="persName"/>OLIVER PRENTISS</byline><p TEIform="p">n all ages and stages of human existence, the religious element has been, s, and ever will be
                            manifest. Its modus operand! is the exponent of progess made, from lowest planes to subimer
                            elevations. In the remote past, eligion regarded science as the enemy, and brought suit. For
                            centuries, the issue has been on rial before the high court of judicature — enlightened
                            public sentiment — and now religion begins to enter a nolle prosequi. Science, instead of
                            being the enemy of religion, begins to be regarded, by most advanced minds, as the lever,
                            kindly given, whereby religion^ may lift itself to sublimer forms of thought. When religion
                            and science, in the natural order, shall so practically cooperate as to get up children in
                            good shape, there will be material for the advance movement—the building up of the
                            resurrection order—the higher spiritual Shaker life. And then this little planet may begin
                            to take rank with its more mature compeers.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Memorandum, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>Memorandum.—-No. 2</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER</byline><p TEIform="p">Righteousness divides itself into three branches. Before the first appearing of Christ, the
                            tree of righteousness had only two—physiological and moral. On the first advent of Christ,
                            the third began to grow—" Resist not evil. Pray for those who despitefully use you." In the
                            second appearing, the fruit of the third branch (which we this day enjoy) is, " Love your
                            neighbor at the expense of self i " not as yourself. He who is the greatest, is with us now
                            the servant; not, " let him be so." The first branch takes cognizance how we use, or abuse,
                            our bodies. The second, how we use, or abuse, others. The third involves manifestations of
                            divine law. A tree brings forth its fruit in the air and sunlight, yet its roots are in the
                            earth, and nourished and borne up by the earth ; otherwise there would be no fruit. So,
                            also, physiological right eousness is the substratum that sustains manifestations of moral
                            and divine fruit Physiological law is a unit. To ab stain from alcoholic mixtures has beei
                            considered almost a fulfillment of al physiological law. Not so. Alcoho indeed injures the
                            nervous centers, .anc - drives furiously the machinery of life , imparting not a particle of
                            nutriment to ustain or repair the occasional waste ; and, in the end, may devastate the
                            whole physical domain. But does inemperance in eating, and the use of mproper articles in
                            our dietary, do lothing? Is it not as much of a crime o over-burden and strain the organ of
                            igestion as it is to stimulate the brain ? s it not as much a violation of law to jreak down
                            the liver with butter, and muttered beef-steaks and greasy compounds, as it is the nerves
                            with alcohol? is the specter Dyspepsia, a strained tomach and a broken-down liver, to dc
                            sympathized with in its cravings any more than the cravings of the tippler? Are not the
                            habits and the example of the one as destructive, in the long run, as the other? Have they
                            not one common source? We all allow that the spirit of our Father and Mother—God—cannot
                            dwell in a drunkard. Can it abide where violations of dietetic law have found a resting
                            place, and are pertinaciously adhered to. To establish righteousness in all things is to
                            increase our happiness. As a furtherance in that direction, the following, as a beginning,
                            is offered : First,—Never eat to over-distension of the stomach. Second,—We are not
                            constructed to live on concentrated food; hence, the use of superfine flour is not
                            advisable. Third,—Do not tax the liver with greasy foods, even butter ; use it sparingly,
                            and never at the same meal with animal food. Fourth,—Never relax the organ of digestion with
                            warm drinks while eating : they embarrass digestion. lea obstructs the renewal and repair of
                            our bodies. Fifth,—Accustom yourself to good air, by night and by day ; and to a
                            temperature, in cold weather, not higher than 65 degrees. Sixth,—Never use saleratus, soda,
                            nor baking powders ; they are alkaline ; are good to make soap with, and window glass. They
                            are not assimilable ; and when present in the blood, hinder assimilation, and impress on
                            that fluid their own chemical affinities, which are contrary to the affinity of venous blood
                            for oxygen. Further, alkaline matter breaks up the coagulating power of the blood, makes it
                            watery, and induces a diminished, vital cohesion of that important fluid, impairs bodily
                            strength, and creates languor and debility. Even common salt should be sparingly used. The
                            Arctic explorers of 1876, when arrested by the ice. betook themselves to sledges; but the
                            men were so weak, from the effect of salted foods, that they could not proceed with vigor,
                            and those who became exhausted had to be dragged back to the ship. Seventh,—To feel faint
                            from performing the ordinary duties of life, is an indication that alkaline matter, bad air,
                            etc., have had something to do in the case. The foregoing is kindly presented to those of
                            youthful years, and to all whose habits are not irrevocable.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Only" TEIform="index"/>Only</head><p TEIform="p">Only a seed—but it chanced to fall In a little cleft of a city wall, And taking root, grew
                            bravely up, Till a tiny blossom crowned its top. Only a flower—but it chanced that day That
                            a burdened heart passed by that way; And the message that through the flower was sent,
                            Brought the weary soul a sweet content. For it spake of the lilies so wondrously clad ; And
                            the heart that was tired grew strangely glad At the thought of a tender care over all, That
                            noted even a sparrow's fall. Only a thought—but the work it wrought Could never by tongue or
                            pen be taught; For it ran through a life, like a thread of gold; And the life bore fruit—an
                            hundred fold. Only a word— but 'twas spoken in love, With a whispered prayer to the Lord
                            above; And the angels in heaven rejoiced once more; Fora new-born soul " entered in by the
                            door."</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Epitomic history of the Watervliet shakers, no. 3" TEIform="index"/> Epitomic History of
                            the Watervliet Shakers. No. 3</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Buckingham, D. A." TEIform="persName"/>D. A. BUCKINGHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">BUSINESS MATTERS. In the year 1790, Believers in this ¦ place had a family garden, occupying
                            about two acres of land. Joseph Turn• er supervised it, and began to raise a i few seeds for
                            sale. Previous to this, it ¦ was not customary in this part of the I country to raise garden
                            seeds to vend. • When any neighbor lacked seeds, anl other, who had them, would give him :
                            what he wanted, and no more thought I of asking pay than he would for a bucket ¦ of water.
                            But as the inhabitants ; increased in numbers, and began to 1 cultivate the soil, the demand
                            for veg¦ etables and seeds increased apace. , Joseph Turner survived but a few years ; 1 and
                            then Ebenezer Alden superintended Vol. VI. ( G. A. LOMAS, Editor, ) | Shakers,N. Y.. \ JULY,
                            1877. ( N. A. BRIGGS, Publisher, ) ( Shaker Village, N. H. \ No. 7. <pb n="50" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 50
                            THE SHAKER. the business. He invented the "Printing Box," for hand-printing upon the
                            seed-bags, the name of the variety, instead of writing upon them, as formerly. After a few
                            years, David Osborne came from Lebanon to this place, and officiated as trustee. He did much
                            to advance the seed business. In 1811, the Shakers here raised, in all, about three hundi-ed
                            dollars' worth of seeds. Not far from this time, Morrell Baker, jr., taking a lively
                            interest in this branch of business, took great pains to select and procure genuine seeds to
                            cultivate from, in order to have the genuine article to vend. From 1811 to 1840, inclusive,
                            the seed business had so magnified that the sales increased to thousands of dollars per
                            year, and eventually proved to be our most staple branch of business. But at a more recent
                            date, others have entered into the business extensively, and the competition has been so
                            great, that little profit now arises to the producer of seeds. But the times have changed
                            greatly. Impi'oved plans for cultivation — new inventions for dispensing with and saving
                            hand-labor, combined with the now greater ease of transportation, keep the business lively.
                            City mai'kets must be supplied with vegetables — seedsmen must have their seeds, and the
                            cultivator must continue his part of the business to make a living. Let us not despair of
                            keeping up in the business. The reputation of Shaker seeds has been of long standing. People
                            look for the old stamp, " Shaker Seeds," for the genuine article. And although some few
                            unimportant errors (greatly magnified by our enemies,) have now and then accidentally
                            happened to spot a long life of prosperity and good reputation, yet we are determined, now
                            as ever, not to slacken our energy in procuring good, even the very best seeds that can be
                            raised, to supply the market, and give satisfaction to those who purchase Shaker seeds. When
                            broom-corn was first introduced into the Society of Shakers at Watervliet, in the year I791?
                            it was grown in the garden as was other corn. In the year 1798? it began to be an article of
                            some importance, and considerable attention was paid to its cultivation. A few brooms were
                            manufactured for market purposes, and sold at the fair price of half a dollar each. The
                            handles were of soft, maple timber, and were turned in a common foot-lathe. The machinery
                            for making the brooms was, in the beginning, very simple. It consisted merely of a roller of
                            wood, turned by a short crank, for the purpose of winding on the cord ; and by placing one
                            or both feet against this roller, the tightness of the twine was governed ; and the broom
                            was made by holding the handle in one hand and applying the brush with the other while
                            winding. The next process by way of improvement, some few years after, was the addition of a
                            bench to the roller, in a frame fastened to the bench, with a ragwheel to hold the cord,
                            when wound upon the roller with short crank as before. The manufacture of two dozen of
                            brooms per day, well made, was considered an exploit, quite equal to the same of six or
                            eight dozen at the present day. Not only in the manufacture of the broom, but also in the
                            culture of the material—the growing of the crop —there have been made very great
                            improvements by ourselves and others. One man, with one horse and a double planting
                            machine,—i.e., a machine that will plant two rows at once,—can now plant from ten to twelve
                            acres per day. And the labor of one man for four months will raise and harvest six acres or
                            more, which will give an average product of six hundred pounds per aci"e. The manner of
                            removing the seed from the brush was, in the beginning, very simple. But now, we have
                            machinery for removing the seed of some three or four acres a day. (See New American
                            Cyclopedia, Vol. III., page 74J5 for general history.) This branch of business, which is
                            believed to have commenced among the Watervliet Shakers, is now most extensively carried on
                            throughout the United States. Believers have aimed to keep pace with all the improvements
                            hitherto advanced in the broom business, and are still found holding their good reputation
                            in the manufacture of this article. Indeed, this Society can furnish all the different
                            varieties of brooms and brushes now in general use, in their most approved styles.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes by the way, no. 9" TEIform="index"/>Notes by the Way, No. 9</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">" How little is correctly known concerning us." We take this notice from a letter of one of
                            our gospel friends, who is in a neighboring state on a mission of peace. Shall we not, with
                            equal propriety, add—How very little we do to extend this so much needed correct knowledge
                            of our order. More than a hundred years have already passed since the word of God was
                            delegated to mortals, by which we were called out from the world. Our publications have been
                            very limited. They have been sufficient, however, to render us ample information of the
                            trials and perils which they passed through to establish the home which, to thousands since
                            that day, has proved, in the fullness of the term, a haven of rest for both soul and body.
                            One of the greatest of blessings is a good home, surrounded by all the necessai'y comforts
                            of life, and in daily association of friends who have been proved faithful by the cross of
                            Christ; but a greater blessing, by far, is to be able to publish the gospel of " glad
                            tidings," and verify the truth of this by practical demonstration. If most of the
                            information existing in society at the present time represents our order in an obscure or
                            false light, then that information, in many cases, proves very injurious to the Society, and
                            should we not, on our part, study to modify this state of wrong education. We may be both
                            ignorantly and maliciously represented. The effect upon society is often the same. Whoever
                            has been thus unfortunate, as to suffer from evil report, knows full well the magical
                            influence of the traducer upon society. There may be much in our order that is not as it
                            should be ; and, happily for us, we do not, as yet, claim to have reached the perfected
                            state ; but if the principles of the order were more fully and clearly represented, and
                            better understood, I think we should grow more in favor with God and man." Our gospel
                            fathers and mothers, who have passed on before us, were firm and fearless in their testimony
                            against every phase of wrong doing; but, as a general thing, held their peace and their
                            faith as St. Paul advised,—"have it to thyself before God ; " and when their enemies sought
                            to injure them by slanderous reports, it was their custom to silently bear the stigma.
                            Perhaps it was the most judicious course they could have taken. At any rate, it was their
                            way. As the population of the country rapidly increases, so in proportion do the silly and
                            designing stories increase in the minds of corresponding men and women. The age of our
                            church has thrown into the woi-ld hundreds, if not thousands, of disappointed, unprincipled
                            and malicious-minded seceders, whose reports are heralded from city to city. All this needs
                            a counteracting influence, and an invitation for a closer inspection into the principles
                            which underlie the gospel work, and into the practical lives of those who form the order.
                            To-day we live in a land of publications. Thousands and thousands of printing presses are
                            running day and night, and from ten to twenty thousand impressions of books, pamphlets and
                            papers are thrown out upon the world every hour, from a large number of these presses. It is
                            emphatically a reading age. Every form of trade, every phase of professional life, and, no
                            less, every order of religious organization, must publish their programme if they wish to be
                            known. Religious bodies, like dealers in merchandise, must place before the world what ttiey
                            wish to have accepted ; and this should be done day after day, so long as the world stands.
                            It needs an illustration of their creeds, forms, ceremonies, and the order of the cross
                            under which they live, whether it be of Adam, Moses, Jesus or Paul, and then allow the
                            children of this world the privilege of accepting or refusing. To neglect this, is to
                            neglect the education of the public mind. If neglected, we might as well fold our hands and
                            brace ourselves securely in the corner, and demand bread, as to think of securing, in this
                            manner, either religious progress or prosperity. The social life of the Shakers should be
                            better known. The rules and regfulations which govern them from day to day ; the care which
                            they exercise over each other, and that which is given to the children that they receive
                            into the society, and, above all, the discipline of the cross of Christ, which is the light
                            of life to the order. We should adopt no rules, nor admit any practice, of which we need be
                            ashamed. If, through the providence of God, this spiritual work is committed to our trust,
                            does it not follow that, as is our interest, so will be our prosperity ?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True worship" TEIform="index"/>True Worship</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">True Worship is something universal. It is to be in everything. It is for all
                                    times and for all spots. " The hour cometh when ye shall neither in this mountain,
                                    nor yet at Jerusalem, worship the Father," were our Lord's words to the Samaritan
                                    woman. Jew and Samaritan had been fighting about places for worship. Jesus comes to
                                    say, neither this place nor that place—but all places for it. We are all of us more
                                    Jewish or Samaritan than we think. We are all of us rearing our Jerusalems or
                                    clinging to our Gerizims. We are all of us sectionalizing religion—gathering it to
                                    special places, special times, special things ; calling these sacred—those profane.
                                    There was an old man in New England who combined the occupations of farmer,
                                    horse-dealer and colporteur. In his " works of mercy," as he called them, he
                                    distributed tracts gratuitously, sold Bibles and other religious books at cost to
                                    those who could pay for them, and gave them away to those who could not. "But,".said
                                    the old man-—not flippantly, as it might seem, but earnestly— "when I start on a
                                    work of mercy and stop to deal in horses, I never have good luck; the fact is, I
                                    don't want the Lord around -when I'm trading horses." There it is. That tract and
                                    Bible distribution was that man's Gerizim or Jerusalem, but worship held simply
                                    there, would not prevent him from being over sharp in a bargain when horses were in
                                    question. That is sectionalizing religion ; piling up Gerizims and building
                                    Jerusalems for it; forgetting its universality. There was a tottering colored man
                                    who gained his living by cobbling shoes. His work was not elegant. He was not
                                    defthanded. But he was thorough. Said one to him, " My friend, after this cobbling
                                    on earth is done, how about the other world ? Have you any hope for a better world?"
                                    " Ah, master, I am nothing, as I told you, but a poor cobbler; but I feel when I sit
                                    here that the Good Master is looking at ine, and when I take a stitch it is a
                                    stitch, and when I put on a heel-tap, it is not fiafier, but good leather." That is
                                    the true and Christian idea as over against the Jewish or Samaritan. Religion not in
                                    Jerusalem or Gerizim only, but religion in everything. Worship not only in special
                                    places, and about certain things, but worship in all places and about all things.
                                    True worship is neither in this mountain nor in that, but is in this and that and in
                                    all others. It is an atmosphere in which the whole life is to breathe and live and
                                    be carried on. It has to do with Saturday as well as Sunday; with the bargain as
                                    well as with the prayer; with the table of the daily bread as well as with the table
                                    of the Lord. They say that two million tons of the purest silver are held in
                                    solution by the sea, enriching each drop of its waters. It is thus that a pure
                                    worship is to interpenetrate the life, touching and glorifying its shyest thought,
                                    its most common ac^n. True worship is for Jerusalem and for^Rerizim and for
                                    Nazareth, too. It is for church and street. It is for sacrament and for the daily
                                    service of the store, or shop, or school, or home. Maine is more stringent than ever
                                    in her liquor-law amendments. W. Hoyt, in </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian union" TEIform="index"/>Christian Union</bibl></cit></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hoyt, W." TEIform="persName"/></byline></div2><pb n="51" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Procrastination" TEIform="index"/>Procrastination</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES G. RUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">Oh thief of time! how oft my heart Hath sorrowed 'neath thy slavish reign ! My promises to
                            act my part, So often broken in thy name. At early dawn I kneel in prayer,— My Heavenly
                            Parents' blessing seek;— I pray and promise then and there, I will in duty's pathway keep.
                            Yet ere the glorious orb of day Attains its full meridian height, Some luring scene my mind
                            will sway, And close from duty's path my sight! Still, on I go in heedless state, Unmindfnl
                            of a Parent's care;— Some selfish sense to satiate— I care not /tow, nor when, nor where!
                            Some kindly act I fail to do, Some kindly sentiment to breathe ; A sinful charmer claims my
                            view, And many trusting hearts I grieve. But soon the busy scenes of day Are closing with
                            approaching night, And as reflection bears the sway And brings my wrongs before my sight, I
                            pause in sorrow for a while, In retrospection view the day; Alas! Am I perdition's child? In
                            confidence how can I pray. And yet I dare not trust to sleep, That state so near akin to
                            death, Unless some faithful guardian keep A watch around me. Ah, my breath Would fain give
                            utterance to prayer, But only can I weep and say Kind Father, all thy love and care
                            Ungratefully do I repay. Unworthy as I am of thee, Yet still I know thou art the same Kind
                            Parent—full of charity, And still this wayward child will claim. But I will pray to thee
                            again, And ask forgiveness for the past, With promise henceforth to abstain From all that
                            would thy blessing blast. I ask for thy protecting care Throughout the dreamy hours of
                            night, That no temptation may ensnare, Or draw my mind again from right. With blest
                            assurance that thy power Will safely shield me from my foes, I'll cease the musings of the
                            hour, And close my eyes in calm repose. The morning light renews again The promises, so
                            often made, From every evil to refrain, And let a better sense pervade Through all the
                            active hours of day, That I may multiply no more Ungrateful actions by the way, That marked
                            my steps the day before. But often am I forced to count On some unfortunate defeat, Neglect
                            to draw from heaven's fount,— Thus some forbidden fruit I eat. And thus my precious time I
                            spend, In mingled happiness and grief; Procrastination—I contend Thou art this unsuspecting
                            thief. I would do -well, but thou art near To intercept each grand design ;
                            Procrastination—I will hear No more to thee—thou thief of time ! When duty's path before me
                            lies, Unpleasant though it oft may be, In life's true dignity I'll rise, And do each duty
                            cheerfully. The present is my only time ; I know not of my future state, But, with an
                            earnest, cheerful mind, I'll " learn to labor and to wait."</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sallie and Ida May Dill left their place of employment..." TEIform="index"/>Sallie and Ida May Dill left their place of employment...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Sallie and Ida May Dill left their place of employment, without permission, about five
                            o'clock P. M., which Avas deemed sufficient cause for dismissal! The Shakers had borne years
                            of worse indiscretions with them, and retained them.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Miller, George Noyes" TEIform="persName">Geo. Noyes Miller</persName> of Wallingford, Conn., a
                            genuine "nephew of his uncle," in The American Socialist, thus happily hits the Enfield,
                            Conn., Shakers in his</byline><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes on the shakers" TEIform="index"/>Notes on the Shakers</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">In a recent visit to one of the Shaker settlements, we were pleased to observe by
                                    many tokens that they were not the unprogressive people which they are often
                                    represented to be, and that they seemed to be losing their fear of the effect of a
                                    larger culture upon their members. In the neat and prettily ornamented children's
                                    school-room we saw not only a Tellurium for aiding the teaching of Astronomy, and
                                    other signs of a wide, educational range, but a grand and glittering piano. In the
                                    children's singing room there was also a cabinet organ, and in the visitor's office
                                    we espied what appeared to be a new and complete set of the American Cycloftczdia.
                                    Here and there, too, a stray picture or bit of needle ornament made a conspicuous
                                    mark on the ancient and primitive plainness, like garden flowers which have passed
                                    their palings and crept into the rigid highway. Then again, the new buildings of the
                                    Shakers are open to the ingress of the modern improvements. The large and thorough
                                    ly built brick mansion which they were finishing, when we were there, was heated by
                                    steam with a vast and imposing system of pipes, boilers and fixtures of the latest
                                    construction. Hot and cold water was to be supplied to every floor. One of their
                                    newlymade workshops is the most thoroughly finished and neatly furnished Community
                                    building that we ever saw. Its dazzling floors, its glass doors, its cemented
                                    cellars, its inside painting, its stairways brightly carpeted from basement to
                                    cupola, even the matching of the glittering oil-cloth in the long halls and
                                    galleries, made us marvel in mute astonishment. The lady who accompanied us, and who
                                    had a decided taste in Communistic household matters, dropped her hands in despair
                                    of ever attaining such perfection. The little group of Shakers, who were showing us
                                    about with their patient, gentle mien, looked on with mild surprise at our wonder.
                                    The Shakers, though unquestionably a very earnest people, are not so austere in
                                    their conversation and manners as many suppose. On the contrary they seemed to us to
                                    be quite as fond of banter and by-play of a genial, innocent kind as people
                                    generally. They are ready to laugh at a joke. When our lady companion possessed
                                    herself of the quaint Shakeress cap and confined her curls under it, they seemed as
                                    gleeful as we were over her sudden demureness. As the Shakers are not so austere in
                                    their manners, neither are they so ascetic in their life as many might imagine.
                                    Without being luxurious", they live very comfortably. Their members travel
                                    occasionally, and in summer little parties of them sometimes go a distance of fifty
                                    miles to recreate on the sea-shore. The Shakers have not given so much attention to
                                    regulating their diet as have some Communities, but still they may be said to be
                                    quite fairly hygienic. Graham and Indian breads are constantly on their tables, and
                                    they eat some fruit and but little meat. If we might be allowed to make a suggestion
                                    to them in regard to their table, we should perhaps say that they ate too much pie.
                                    May be they don't know that some foreigner has said " all Americans die of pie." We
                                    coulc not help wishing further that they would lc the Turkish Bath into the noble
                                    newbuildin into which steam has pushed its way; bi doubtless they will open their
                                    doors to i sometime. " Cleanliness is next to godliness." As we were walking between
                                    the various buildings, over the neat stone walks, we stopped with a sudden start on
                                    perceiving that we were about to put our foot down on what "appeared to be a grave.
                                    There in the alk was a plain flat stone bearing the age nd other rude memorials of a
                                    departed soul. "Why!" we exclaimed with sudden awe, some one seems to be buried
                                    here." Our Shaker companions explained that in emodeling their cemetery they removed
                                    all le old stones and put marble slabs in their places. The stones had been used for
                                    repairng their walks, and we soon got quite acustomed to them. We afterward visited
                                    the haker cemetery. It was situated on a high and pleasant knoll, and was surrounded
                                    with a low and open iron fence, the heavy posts of which were sunk into a stone
                                    foundation. The marble tombstones were all of the same size and were placed in
                                    straight rows, giving an appearance of perfect uniformity. A Shaker burying-ground
                                    is an interesting place to visit on account of the uniformly great age to which its
                                    memorials bear witness. They prove the truth of Nordhoff's assertion that "
                                    Communists are long-lived." But far more interesting than the dead are the living
                                    among the Shakers. There are beautiful characters among them, some as grand and
                                    rugged as oaks, others as sweet and gentle as wildwood flowers. A born Communist in
                                    stopping under their kindly and hospitable roofs, feels, in spite of some
                                    differences of belief, that he is still breathing his native, peaceful atmosphere,
                                    in which brothers are "dwelling together in unity."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="American socialist" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True uses of shaker property" TEIform="index"/>True Uses of Shaker Property</head><byline TEIform="byline">[In a remarkably able letter to the Cincinnati Gazette, our talented Bro.<persName reg="Amery, G. B" TEIform="persName"/>G. B. Amery [sic.] thus discourses upon a subject which very many
                            unthinkingly and unfavorably criticise.—Ed.]</byline><p TEIform="p">We who maintain the faith have entered into a most solemn contract by which we covenant
                            ourselves to sacredly hold and transmit to our successors the dedicated and consecrated
                            interest of the society. And as our covenant states that " the sole object, purpose, and
                            design of our uniting in a covenant relation as a church or body of people in gospel union
                            was, from the beginning, and still is, faithfully and honestly to receive, improve, and
                            diffuse the manifold gifts of God, both of a spiritual and temporal nature, for the mutual
                            protection, support, comfort, and happiness of each other as brethren and sisters in the
                            gospel," etc., we cannot but feel that, as stewards of this most sacred trust of a church
                            which thus abolishes poverty, we cannot be too careful in our dealings with those who either
                            forfeit their right to membership or voluntarily relinquish it. It must be borne steadfastly
                            in mind that our religion provides not only for the spiritual needs of its members, but a
                            perfect equality obtains, and is enjoyed by every member of the society, in everything
                            pertaining to temporal matters. We wear the same quality and style of clothing ; eat the
                            same kind of food at a common table ; enjoy equal privileges of social intercourse with each
                            other; and have and hold equal right and title to real and personal property, which has
                            been, now is, and forevermore shall remain dedicated to the sacred uses and purposes for
                            which the society was organized. * * * * Our society, like your orphan as} lums, or other
                            endowed institutions, has and must confine itself, in its ministra tions, to those who are
                            within, or thos who may desire to enter in, and could o more carry on its functions, were it
                            o follow up and care for those who reect its advantages and protections than ould your
                            orphan asylums follow up leir charges after they had left, and when, by a sad experience,
                            they had proven by numerous overt acts that hey, if they could, would destroy the ery
                            foundation of the institution which lad sheltered them. If either they or we should thus
                            squander our resources, we would soon destroy our respective nstitutions and put an end to
                            our abilty to benefit even those who are really worthy. * * * *</p></div2><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ann Lee: a sketch of her history and character" TEIform="index"/>ANN LEE. A SKETCH OF HER
                            HISTORY AND CHAKACTER</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Ann Lee was born Feb. 29, 1736, in Manchester, England. She was the daughter of a
                                    blacksmith, an onest man, but too poor to send his family to school, nd Ann did not
                                    learn to read nor write. She was rought up in habits of industry, working in
                                    factoies, and at one time as a cook in the Manchester inrmary, and was always "
                                    distinguished for faithfuless, neatness, prudence, and economy." The Shaker
                                    Communities are born in her image in respect to lese practical virtues, and we may
                                    no doubt trace leir neglect of education to her example. She was thoughtful child,
                                    ami early subject to religious imressions. It is said also that she conceived in her
                                    ery youth a great abhorrence of the sexual relation, s impure and abominable. She
                                    was married, notwithstanding, and had four children; but, as they all led in
                                    infancy, her domestic experience may have iily increased her repugnance to what
                                    before she nought sufficiently odious. If her condemnation of narriage was a revolt,
                                    as some suppose, from the ife of suffering that this series of disastrous births
                                    mposed upon her, it would be hardly more than natiral. At the age of twenty-three,
                                    subsequent to her marriage troubles, she became united to a sect in the neighborhood
                                    of Manchester called Shakers. This sect was an offshoot of the Quakers, holding
                                    similar views, but remarkable for greater physical manifestations, such as dancing,
                                    shouting, trembling, etc., from which they received the name of Shakers. They seem
                                    to have had a great deal of genuine illlumination and spiritual power. Ann soon
                                    became a wonderful medium of the supernatural influence that was working among them,
                                    and was wrought upon in a surprising manner for the space of nine years, alternating
                                    between deep spiritual suffering and heavenly visions and revelations. One who was
                                    well acquainted with her at this time describes her experience thus: " In watchings,
                                    fastings, tears and incessant cries to God, she labored day and night for
                                    deliverance from the very nature of sin; and that, under the most severe tribulation
                                    of mind, and the most violent temptations and bufletings of the enemy; the agony of
                                    her soul was often so extreme as to occasion a perspiration of blood. Sometimes, for
                                    whole nights together, her cries, screeches and groans were such as to fill every
                                    soul around with fear and trembling. By these painful sufferings and deep
                                    morliiieations her flesh sometimes wasted away like that of a person in consumption,
                                    till she became so weak and emaciated that her friends were obliged to support and
                                    nourish her like a helpless infant; although she possessed by nature a sound and
                                    strong constitution, and an invincible fortitude of mind. Though Ann was wrought
                                    upon in this manner, more or less for the space of nine years, yet she often had
                                    intervals of releasement, in which her bodily strength and vigor were sometimes
                                    miraculously renewed, and her soul was at times filled with heavenly visions and
                                    divine revelations. By these means the way of God and the nature of his work
                                    gradually opened upon her mind with increasing light and understanding." During
                                    these nine years, though hor manifestations were the source of great enlightenment
                                    and strength to the society, she lived in all obedience to the leaders, without
                                    assuming any special claim to respect. In 1770 she was imprisoned with others of the
                                    society, on the charge of violating the Sabbath by their noisy demonstrations in
                                    their meetings; and in the prison she had a new and extraordinary revelation. She
                                    had been in deep prayer to G od that he would show her what was the real foundation
                                    of man's loss, and how he could be recovered and saved from sin, which she had
                                    ceased to hope for from any religion yet obtained, when,according to the words of
                                    her biographer, " her soul was filled with divine light, and the mysteries of the
                                    spiritual world were brought clearly to her understanding. She had a full view of
                                    the mystery of iniquity! of the root and foundation of human depravity, and of the
                                    very act of transgression in the garden of Eden. Here she saw whence and <pb n="52" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. wherein all mankind were lost from God, and clearly
                                    realized the only possible way of recovery." On coming out of prison she
                                    communicated to the society this revelation; and her testimony it was said was
                                    accompanied with such searching power that " all who heard her were tilled with fear
                                    and trembling ; they saw that the candle of the Lord was in her hand, and she was
                                    able to search every heart, and try every soul among them; and from that time she
                                    began to be acknowledged as the visible leader of the church of God upon earth." She
                                    henceforth " bore an open testimony against the lustful gratifications of the flesh,
                                    as the source and foundation of human corruption, and testified in the most plain
                                    and pointed manner that no soul could follow Christ in the regeneration while living
                                    in the works of natural generation." Some of the society received her testimony,
                                    while others rejected it. Of those who received it, it is said they had visions,
                                    revelations and gifts; while those who rejected it fell back into darkness and the
                                    common course of the world. Mother Ann, as she was now called, remained the center
                                    of a little band in England about four years, when, by special revelation, she was
                                    directed to repair to America, where it was promised the millennial church should be
                                    established, Eight of her most faithful followers accompanied her, including her
                                    husband and brother. A story is told of the Shakers on the passage as follows: The
                                    captain had forbidden their peculiar demonstrations on board; but they, fearing God
                                    rather than man, went forth in the dance with songs and shoutings. The captain was
                                    enraged, and threatened to put them overboard, actually proceeding to carry out his
                                    threat, when a plank starting, the ship sprang a leak, and he was glad of their
                                    assistance at the pumps. They were in great peril, but Mother Ann maintained her
                                    confidence in God, and said, " Captain, be of good cheer; there shall not a hair of
                                    our heads perish; we shall all arrive safe at America." Shortly after, a wave struck
                                    the ship with great violence and closed the plank into its place, which wonderful
                                    circumstance was viewed by all on board as nothing less than a miraculous
                                    interposition of Providence. Mother Ann arrived in New York, August, 1774. She seems
                                    to have lived in that city the most of the time for two years, though part of her
                                    company went up the river to Albany, and she made them occasional visits. They were
                                    ail dependent on their owrn labor, and she found a place in a respectable family
                                    where she washed and ironed for her support. Her husband was employed by the same
                                    family. In the course of her life in New York, he apostatized from the faith and
                                    opposed Mother Ann's testimony, urging her to renounce it and live like the rest of
                                    the world. She said she was willing to do anything for him but violate her duty to
                                    God. He said if she refused to live with him as a wife, he would take another woman,
                                    which he did, and thus ended the connection between Mother Ann and Abraham Stanley.
                                    In September, 1776, Mother Ann and her company collected together and made a
                                    settlement in the woods of Watervliet, where they quietly occupied themselves, mid
                                    the tumults of the Revolutionary war, in improving their circumstances, while they
                                    waited for the opening of their testimony at the appointed time. They went on with
                                    their rugged labor, and held their solemn meetings there in the wilderness three
                                    years and a half, when the time came, as inmie-. diately foretold by Mother Ann, for
                                    their showing to the world, in the year 1779-80 a great religious excitement
                                    occurred in New Lebanon and the towns adjacent, which was characterized by singular
                                    physical manifestations. Some of the subjects of these manifestations visited
                                    Watervliet, and there they thought they found the key to their experiences. The
                                    report of these visitors brought others, and the fame of Mother Ann was soon
                                    extended far and wide, and converts increased rapidly, coming out oi' ail
                                    tienominations and from all parts of the country. Her personal power in testimony
                                    appears to have been wonderful, and there is no doubt she was charged with a
                                    superhuman life, which kindled a lire wherever it passed. The spirit of persecution
                                    naturally arose, and under a charge of treasonable correspondence with the enemy of
                                    the nation, Ann Lee and some of her leading adherents were put in prison; but they
                                    were released after five months, there being no evidence to justify their
                                    imprisonment. The attempt to suppress them in this way, was more than a failure, of
                                    course. It was th^occasion of extensive increase. The following year Mother Ann with
                                    six of her associates made a journey into Massachusetts, as far as Harvard, visiting
                                    on their way many who had embraced their testimony, holding meetings, and
                                    beingvisited by great multitudes hi the towns they passed through. It was at once a
                                    triumphal tour and a march to the cross. They suffered constant personal abuse, and
                                    in some places narrowly escaped with their lives; but our authority says, "they were
                                    blessed in their labors with many powerful gifts o God, and succeeded iu planting
                                    the word of God in the hearts of many." They were gone two years and seem to have
                                    left the germs of several Shakei Communities which have since flourished in Massa
                                    chusetts. Mother Ann died soon after returning to Watervliet, when she could not
                                    have been more.than forty eight years old. Her work was short and swift She was
                                    certainly a prophetic character, who had»a mission like an arrow from the bow of the
                                    mighty, vhich she fulfilled and suddenly disappeared. It is impossible to study the
                                    record of Ann Lee and believe that she was an impostor or hypocrite. She had a
                                    spiritual guidance and was faithful to it. Her strength was her sincerity. She
                                    sought not the lonor of man. She does not appear to have assumed any such place as
                                    her followers have given her. Her iccepting the title of Mother was not without
                                    example. There was a Mother in the Manchester Society which she came out of. James
                                    and Jane Wardley were the "ministry" of that Society, and Jane Wardley was called
                                    Mother. Ann Lee joined them by confessing her sins to Mother Jane. She was not a
                                    vulgar egotist. If she was ambiious, she knew the true secret of leadership—how ;o
                                    abase herself and to be among her disciples as )ue that served. She frequently
                                    waited on those ;hat came to see her with all the attention and assiduity of a
                                    menial. She set the first example of all he precepts she inculcated. No one can
                                    doubt that she was pure in her sense of purity. She established the law of celibacy,
                                    but otherwise he Shaker system appears to have been intellectualized and developed
                                    by her successors rather than lerself. She is said to have foretold the order which
                                    ler followers have come into, and this order embodies her spirit, as every one can
                                    see; yet it was not until after her death and that of her immediate successor, that
                                    the Shakers entered into Communism. She appointed James Whittaker—one of the eight
                                    from England—her successor. He lived only three rears, and was succeeded by Joseph
                                    Meacham, a Watervliet convert, an efficient business man, who, in the space of five
                                    years, collected families of believers together and founded twelve Shaker
                                    Communities—the first and parent society at New Lebanon, and eleven others in
                                    different places in Massachusetts, Connecticut and New York. He was the real author
                                    of the Shaker organization, and they are indebted to his practical sagacity for much
                                    of their success, though Ann Lee prepared the moral material, without which he could
                                    have done nothing. Her favorite doctrine, next to celibacy, was thrifty
                                    habits—industry, prudence, economy. She says to her young converts on the one hand,
                                    "You have a privilege to take up your crosses in the prime of your activity; if you
                                    take up your crosses against the lust of the flesh, while you have power to please
                                    yourselves, you offer to God the first fruits of your lives; and there is a glorious
                                    crown for all who take up their cross against the flesh in this world." On the other
                                    hand, she says, " You must be diligent with your hands, for godliness does not lead
                                    to idleness. The devil tempts others, but an idle person tempts the devil. When you
                                    are at work doing your duty as the gift of God, the devil can have no power over
                                    you, because there is no room for temptation." Here is her righteousness on the
                                    right hand, and on the left celibacy arid thrifty habits. She had visions and
                                    revelations as wonderful as Swedenborg's, we should judge, but she did not bestow
                                    their tediousness upon the world, as he did. She was more like Christ in that she
                                    was a doer, instead of a talker or writer. Her words were few. But she really left a
                                    stupendous work, one that has been the admiration of mankind. The American
                                    Cyclopaedia says: " It is a fact worthy of n6te, that the Shakers are the only
                                    people on this continent, if not in the world, wTho have maintained successfully for
                                    more than seventy years a system of living, one of the fundamental principles of
                                    which is community of property." And the author of The Millennial Church said truly,
                                    writing thirty years ago, that the system of a full united interest had never been
                                    established and maintained for any considerable length of time except in two
                                    instances; that of the Pentecostal church, and the Shakers. Ann Lee appointed her
                                    successor, and the Shakers have received their leaders by that method of election
                                    ever since. Each ministry has been appointed by its predecessor. In this the Shakers
                                    take for then example oth the Jewish and Christian dispensations God appointed
                                    Moses, they say, and Moses appointed Joshua. God also selected David from the sons
                                    of Jesse, and David- selected Solomon from his own sons. It was when the Israelites
                                    departed from this manner of succession, that they were plunged in po litical
                                    troubles. Under the gospel dispensation Christ chose his apostles, and these
                                    apostles appointed their successors; and it was when the primitive Christians began
                                    to elect their own bishops, say they that the unity of the church was destroyed. The
                                    Shaker government, as we understand from their books, is on this wise : " The
                                    Ministry at New Lebanon is called the Head of Influence, and is sov ereign over all
                                    the Communities of the sect wherevei located. It is composed of four persons, but
                                    one o: the four is pre-eminent; he appoints the other three and has power to depose
                                    them at will. He has su preme authority. [We claim that the quadruple ot the
                                    ministry have supreme authority. If any case should arise where a difference of
                                    opinion exists among the four, the presiding Minister would do liver the ultimatum.
                                    Appointing and deposing by mere caprice, are unknown to the order of Minis
                                    try.—Ei&gt;.] The other three are his advisers anc assistants. He appoints the
                                    ministry of every othei Community, and also the trustee in whom the prop erty of any
                                    Community is invested, and lastly his own successor. Each local community has a mini
                                    s try after the model of the mother church, which has power to appoint subordinate
                                    officers—elders and eldresses whose duties are spiritual, and deacons and
                                    deaconesses whose duties are temporal. The leacons and deaconesses are subordinate
                                    to the elders and eldresses, as the latter are to the ministry. Through the whole
                                    society the inferiors report to he superiors. Authority is transmitted from the lead
                                    down, and one rank obeys another—a species of government which may be an oppressive
                                    despotism or the most beneficent rule in the world, according o the character of the
                                    central power. All who come into the " full privilege " of the order ay everything
                                    at the feet of the ministry, never to be reclaimed. But there are three classes of
                                    members. first, novitiates, who receive the doctrines of the Shakers, and conform to
                                    their general requirements and enjoy their spiritual oversight, but who, on account
                                    of family embarrassments remain outside and manage their own temporal concerns.
                                    Second, a class who live in the Communities and unite in their abors and worship,
                                    and give them the use of their &gt;roperty, perhaps, but who on account of heirs
                                    in he world, or for some acceptable reason, retain he ownership of it and the right
                                    to withdraw it, without claim of interest. Then there is a third class, who make an
                                    entire consecration of their property and services to the society, cutting
                                    themselves off from any claim of restitution or compensation. [Here follow extracts
                                    from the Shaker covenant.] In respect to habits of thrift Ann Lee stamped her image
                                    on the Society with remarkable exactness.Their books say there is no law or
                                    compulsion necessary d regard to work among them ; for such a spirit of industry
                                    pervades the order, that a lazy person cannot abide in it. Their ministry, elders
                                    and deacons all have some manual occupation in which they engage when not occupied
                                    with the duties of their particular calling. Ann Lee was unlettered, but she had a
                                    theory of education which the wisest would do well to study. Obedience was her first
                                    principle. That was the grand lesson for early childhood. She reasoned that children
                                    who are governed by their parents, acquire the power of xelf-govermneiit, which is
                                    like the rudder of a ship, and worth more on the sea of life than talents or
                                    knowledge or riches. Next in order was the ctiltivation of the whole moral nature;
                                    and lastly, intellectual training. She believed learning is wrorse than nothing to
                                    the wicked, and that moral training is the basis of all other kinds of culture. If
                                    she had lived longer she might have broadened her system and appreciated more the
                                    reciprocal influence of the moral and intellectual; but she certainly put the right
                                    thing first. Give vis the Shaker virtues to make a happy home rather than all the
                                    learniog in the world without them.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="American socialist" TEIform="index"/>Am. Socialist</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No religion without justice" TEIform="index"/>No Religion without Justice</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ruskin, John" TEIform="persName"/>JOHN RUSKIN</byline><p TEIform="p">People are perpetually squabbling about what will be best to do, or easiest to do, or
                            advisablest to do, or profitablest to do ; but they never, so far as I hear them talk, ever
                            ask what it is just to do. And it is the law of heaven that you shall not be able to judge
                            what is wise or easy, unless you are first resolved to judge what is just, and to do it.
                            That is the one thing constantly reiterated by our Master—the order of al] others that is
                            given oftenest—" Do justice and judgment." That's your Bible order; that s the ''Service of
                            God;" not praying nor psalm-singing. You are told, indeed, to sing psalms when you are
                            merry, and to pray when you need anything ; and, by the perversion of the Evil Spirit, we
                            get to think that praying and psalm-singing are "service." If a child finds itself in want
                            of anything, it runs in and asks its father for it. Does it call that doing its fathei a
                            service ? If it begs for a toy or a piece of cake, does it call that serving its father?
                            That, with God, is prayer; and he likes to hear it. He likes you to ask Him for cake when
                            you want it; bu He doesn't call that "serving Him.' Begging is not serving. God likes mere
                            beggars as little as you do. He likes honest servants, not beggars. So when a child loves
                            its father very much, and is very happy, it may sing little songs about him ;' but it
                            doesn't call that serving its father. Neither is singing songs about God serving God. It is
                            enjoying uirselves, if it is anything ; most probaDiy it is nothing ; but if it's anything,
                            it ts serving ourselves, not God. And yet we are impudent enough to call our peggings and
                            chantings "Divine Servce." We say, "Divine service will be performed'"(that's our word—the
                            form of it gone through) "at n o'clock." Alas !—unless we perform Divine servce in every
                            willing act of our life, we lever perform it at all. The one Divine work—the one ordered
                            sacrifice— s to do justice ; and it is the last we are ever inclined to do. Anything rather
                            than that! As much charity as you choose, but no justice. "Nay," you will say, " charity is
                            greater than justice." Yes, it is greater ; it is the summit of justice—it is the temple of
                            which justice is the foundation. But you can't have the top without the bottom ; you cannot
                            build upon charity. You must build upon justice, for this main reason, that you have not, at
                            first, charity to build with. It is the last reward of good work. Do justice to your brother
                            (you can do that, whether you love him or not), and you will come to love him. But do
                            injustice to him, because you don't love him, and you will come to hate him. It is all very
                            fine to think you can build upon charity to begin with ; but you will find all you have got
                            to begin with begins at hornet and is essentially love of yourself. You wellto-do people,
                            for instance, will go to "Divine service" next Sunday, all nice and tidy, and your little
                            children will have their tight little Sunday boots on, and lovely little Sunday feathers in
                            their hat*; and you'll think, complacently and piously, how lovely they look ! So they do ;
                            and you love them heartily, and you like sticking feathers in their hats. That's all right;
                            that is charity ; but it is charity beginning at home. Then you will come to the poor little
                            crossing-sweeper, got up also in its Sunday dress,—the dirtiest rags it has, —that it may
                            beg the better , we shall give it a penny, and think how good we are. That's charity going
                            abroad. But what does Justice say, walking and watching near us? Christian Justice has been
                            strangely mute and seemingly blind ; and, if not blind, decrepit this many a day. She keeps
                            her accounts still, however,—quite steadily—doing them at nights, carefully, with her
                            bandage off, and through acutest spectacles (the only modern scientific invention she cares
                            about). You must put your ear down ever so close to her lips to hear her speak ; and then
                            you will start at what she first whispers, for it will certainly be, "Why shouldn't that
                            little crossing-sweeper have a feather on its head, as well as your own child ? " Then you
                            may ask Justice, in an amazed manner, " how she can possibly be so foolish as to think
                            children could sweep crossings with feathers on their heads?" [ Then you stoop again, and
                            Justice says 11—still in her dull, stupid way,—" Then, <pb n="53" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 53
                            why don't you, every other Sunday, leave your child to sweep the crossing, and take the
                            little sweeper to church in a hat and feathers ?" Mercy on us (you think), what will she say
                            next! And you answer, of course, that "you don't, because everybody ought to remain content
                            in the position in which Providence has placed them." Ah, my friends, that's the gist of the
                            whole question. Did Providence put them in that position, or did you? You knock a man into a
                            ditch, and then you tell him to remain content in the "position in which Providence has
                            placed him." That's modern Christianity. You say, " We did not knock him into the ditch."
                            How do you know what you have done or are doing ? That's just what we have all gof to know,
                            and what we shall never know, until the question with us every morning is, not how to do the
                            gainful thing, but how to do the just thing ; nor until we are at least so far on the way to
                            being Christian as to have understood that maxim of the poor halfway Mahometan, "One hour in
                            the execution of justice is worth seventy years of prayer."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Washing-day wail" TEIform="index"/>A Washing-Day Wail</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leggett, Ezra T." TEIform="persName"/>EZRA T. LEGGETT</byline><p TEIform="p">Since light first, in beauty, bathed mountain and main, And sunshine and shadow danced over
                            the plain, This, born of the night, and that, born of the day, Alternate, each chasing the
                            other away ; Since daj-s were first sacred to cross or to crown, And noted when nations rose
                            up or came down ; Or told of the comet, the flood or the pest, When sinners were roasted, or
                            saints to be blest; When Satan sent raging the fire or the flood, Or Caesars set flowing
                            whole rivers of blood ; Of days that our sorrows remember so well, Since Satan wooed woman,
                            and paradise fell, Not one that so fritters poor woman away, Brains, body arfd soul, as the
                            dread washingday. Once man was s-o pure, as we all ought to know, But innocence clothed
                            hirn^ in time long ago, (What hosts of good orthodox Christians there are, If fthis ^ere the
                            fashion, with nothing to wear.) Had Satan but left father Adam a/one, Soft soap and hot
                            water had never been known ; Had Eve but refrained from the apple, and then, How happy the
                            fates of both women and men ! Since stars sung, in heaven, the birthday of time, Our
                            washing-day woes never sounded in rhyme; The mists of that awful day veil from the sight Our
                            terrible toils and more terrible plight; Though hope springs afresh witu each new
                            washing-day, And hearts beating high banish fear far away, Yet, as the dark shadows grow
                            long on the wall, Hard work and cross, purposes tell on u.s all; And long ere the sun, in
                            mere pity, g oes We're looking Jlke an^is bereft f Ila v crowu. : At morn, we were roses
                            bespangled with dew ; At even, our roses give place to the rue ; lien even our tongues,
                            never wearied before, }row faint from o'erdoing, and warble no more. We'd like to be angels,
                            though outside of heaven, \nd would, were not washing-day one in each seven, When burthened
                            beyond all endurance to bear, With hands in hot water, and hearts in despair, Though angels,
                            it oft has occurred to our mind, ?he saints would be bothered to tell of which kind. 'Tis
                            awful to think how we're given to dirt Since Adam did penance by wearing a shirt: More awful
                            the thought that this image of sin, So often washed out, yet may often wash in. If dirt were
                            abolished and woman made free, How happy the world and its women would be! Then flood-tides
                            of joy would our hearts overflow And drown out the memories of suffering below. Oh, when our
                            millenium comes, by and by, And smiles shall chase every salt tear from the eye, Then woman
                            shall dawn, as a star overcast, To move in her sphere of true freedom at last. Then
                            washing-day be as a lost art of yore, Or dream that has haunted, but haunts us no more; Then
                            Earth shall forget, over mountain and main, The fall in her Eden fresh blooming again. We
                            pray thee, good angels, come down from above, And fill us up full with true courage and
                            love, That, if we must suffer, our hearts may be strong, To bear and forbear as we journey
                            along.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Musings" TEIform="index"/>Musings</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fletcher, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>RICHARD FLETCHER</byline><p TEIform="p">Musings are not always amusing. Self-denial is no cross where there is an object thought
                            worthy the pains. Hence we must make people feel need of self-denial before expecting them
                            to be willing to practice it. Good ! Old Father Time cannot be bribed nor cheated. Our
                            neighbors grow old as fast as we do. Dentists, tailors, shoemakers, milliners, barbers make
                            much profit by simply trying to make folks look younger, but they cannot hide wrinkles of
                            care. No cure for them without a peaceful conscience. " Progression'' consists as much in
                            growing old truths and virtues, as in living out entirely new theories. Plenty of room left
                            yet in the fields of meekness, purity, goodwill and honesty for us to improve, before
                            expanding too fast in virtues of coarse diet, faith in materialization, or other sensational
                            theories that lead more to religious contro versy than real good. ------»o«-----Consider the
                            weeds, youthful gardenei Are jou half as deep-rooted in principle a those plaguy mallows? as
                            "vigorous as middle-aged parsley ? as persevering as thistle? as cool in trial as a bunch of
                            chick weed? as straightforward and obstinate i the right as a yellow- dock? Then may yo
                            thrive as a pig-weed in a rainy season. e; How many men are eager to enlist i bloody war for
                            mere love of excitement, ris! ; ins comfort and life itself! How few ca s seethe nobility of
                            enlisting as a follower . the " meek and lowly celibate," to the layin l" I down of carnal
                            lives and the infinite joy o I gaining victories over sin. Are city preachers so cramped for
                            room lat they cannot swing off on their own eachings ? Some of them talk sublimely,
                            &gt;ut act rather awkward in reaping the harest of their daily lives. Will some
                            revivalists remember tin-roofrs and other patent roofers in their prayers. their morals are
                            no tighter than their roofs, their souls are in danger. Among the teachings of Jesus are
                            many hints of beautiful truths, like buds, which it is now time for us to develop. Such as
                            Brotherhoods and Sisterhoods with unselfish community of goods. Strange that popular pulpit
                            talkers seldom refer to this form of society. How natural to be proud of family name, as
                            though it were a credit to any of us what earthly family we are of. Rather let us have a
                            pride to be worthy of love and esteem of good souls--never mind what their last names are,
                            they cannot help that. Why do we need so much urging to be Christlike? Because Christian
                            virtues have such shallow soil in our natural hearts that they need constant care. Bands of
                            thieves, counterfeiters, and carousers do not spend much time urging one another to remain
                            true, though the world be against them. Nay, lower motives are always dragging on down hill
                            paths. Thistles need no cultivation. Who would try to raise new varieties of parsley?
                            Children cry most because they cannot have their own way, not so much from pain. And
                            Christian pilgrims find greatest trials in fighting conceit and self-will. As well might you
                            stretch clothes-lines on telegraph poles and try to send messages, as to niake folks better
                            by quarreling about Bible texts. Is it "intuition" or "judgment" that causes any one to
                            write the words " in haste " on the front side of postal cards, in hopes that it will go
                            faster than the next mail train? For teachers and pupils: This sentence contains all the
                            vowel sounds in order : "A large, tall, black-haired man re-iead nine lists of old used
                            up-tunes. Why ! My ! " Half the expense of time, money and energy wasted in getting up a
                            collegiate boatrace, gambling scene, would pay for hauling all the cord-wood in New York
                            State to Saratoga, where a grand college wood-sawing match would give noble vent to youthful
                            ambition and perspiration. Just as great excitement could be indulged in and no danger of
                            rupturing blood vessels nor drinking too much. Query: Has God a united body of people on
                            earth living very different lives from the masses ? We believe there ought to be. Suppose a
                            young man or woman, feeling the duty of striving for the highest practical Christianity,
                            does not plead the common apology of Paul, but chooses to "do better,"' gives up that form
                            of selfishness that claims to make one of opposite sex happy for life, and unites with a
                            body of congenial soul-companions, thus making happy hundreds of other human beings Why do
                            natural relations suddenly become alarmed for the safety of said youth's soul? Many times
                            have they kindly offered to help him or her choose a companion for life. Now, when a less
                            selfish sacrifice is made for the good of one hundred-fold of true, living companions, there
                            is a great stir, bitter talk and sad waste of scripture language. Mere words of texts are
                            quote without half an idea of their real meaning They cry: "You are not fulfilling you
                            mission on earth, of living to God's glory You ought to settle down in earthly discon tent,
                            like the rest of us, support the ol blks (as nine tenths of them do not,) and ive a good
                            human life." Strange logic! If their advice should be bllowed, nine chances in ten the
                            natural mrents would rather end their days among xangers ; " God's glory ' 'would be
                            embodied n a large percentage of aborted beings, and the "good, human life " consist in
                            getting an easy living. Groveland, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, June 12, 1877" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, June 12, 1877</head><p TEIform="p">Brother Albert: Noticing that correspond ence occasionally enters the columns of our neat
                                and good little paper, we venture to send yovi a part of a letter from a friend in
                                Pennsylvania, who visited us about four years since. That visit is the only one she has
                                ever made us. So you see her opportunity for becoming acquainted with the principles, or
                                manner of Shaker life, has been very limited. Her sentiments may, like the single
                                fruit-seed dropped by the wayside, be spiritually utilized by some weary, earthly
                                pilgrim. We trust that all sentiments in favor of right living will assume its proper
                                place in the spiritual unfpldment of humanity. Professing to be children of the "
                                resurrection," we feel it our high privilege to be in sympathy with the testimony—with
                                every repeti tion of testimony, purposing restraint to perverted passions and
                                appetites—the sinful ways of an unregenerated self-pleasing class, from which so much
                                misery, suffering and degradation are realized at the present time. " The Shaker"
                                certainly holds a worthy place in the Christian's cause, and obtains our truest
                                sympathy; hope its vitality will remain so good that it may continue to edify, refresh
                                and instruct us in those things which are " altogether lovely." Good health prevails,
                                and our doctors now have a chance to oversee and to make their gardens. We close with
                                kind love.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Betsey" TEIform="persName"/>Betsey Johnson</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear sister Betsey:" TEIform="index"/>Dear Sister Betsey:</head><p TEIform="p"> Your kind letter was duly received, but my many cares prevented me from answering it at
                                that time. I feel lonely ; somehow I walk before the Lord with fear and trembling. I do
                                not become reconciled as I had hoped to have done before this. The world does not seem
                                bright and fair as it used to. I have grown tired of living in it. Many times a day I
                                leave my work, and with tears I cannot repress, I take my Bible and seek to find in it
                                the comfort I can find no where else. I want to be free from the burden of sin. I had
                                hoped to come and labor with you, and live, perhaps, a useful life; but my brother has
                                no one to care for him, and he will not come with me. " Ephraim is joined to his idols;
                                let him alone." It may be that the passion that commonly rules mankind may lead him to
                                choose another companion, when my services will no longer be required; if so, I will
                                take my little girl and seek among you that peace and quiet that the world cannot give.
                                The world seems colder and harder since visiting you, and I will not mix with it. I read
                                everything in " The Shaker " you kindly send to me, and prize it highly. I would never
                                tire of "The Shaker." God bless "The Shaker." Give my love to all the dear sisters, and
                                write again, please</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Baker, Victoria" TEIform="persName"/>Victoria Baker To Betsey Johnson, West Pittsfield,
                                Mass.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="San Francisco, May 29, 1877" TEIform="index"/>San Francisco, May 29, 1877</head><p TEIform="p">Editor of Shaker: Somebody does me the inestimable favor of sending me The Shaker. If
                                anything stands to my account, I will cheerfully pay it. If The Shaker needs help, let
                                me know. * * *</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Thompson, I. N." TEIform="persName"/>I. N. Thompson</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wilmington, Del., June 6, 1877" TEIform="index"/>Wilmington, Del., June 6, 1877</head><p TEIform="p">G. A. L.. Ed.: * * * I read every issue of The Shaker with an interest <pb n="54" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. awakened by no other publication. You may be encouraged, when there is
                                light shed from it into old Delaware people. * * * The Shaker should be well supported.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="R., S. J." TEIform="persName"/>S. J. R.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New Bedford, May 28, 1877" TEIform="index"/>New Bedford, May 28, 1877</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Friend: Enclosed you will find 60 cents to pay for The Shaker. I will say that the
                                paper is very satisfactory to my mind and I could only wish that it was published weekly
                                and enlarged to the size of the religious press of Boston. Why not publish it weekly,
                                and raise the price? I believe the growing, liberal sentiment of the New England
                                community would sustain such a paper, especially that large class who are sick of the
                                teachings of " orthodoxy," with its Sabbaths, vicarious atonement, and very many other
                                absurd doctrines. In conclusion, I wish The Shaker God-speed in its mission to redeem
                                the world. Yours truly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peckham, Caleb C." TEIform="persName"/>Caleb C. Peckham</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Brother:" TEIform="index"/> Dear Brother:</head><p TEIform="p">* * * I am not anxious to part with too many of " Plain Talks " as vet. Could we not
                                arrange for new editions of it, or for some other matter similar to it, in its
                                convenient form, to answer correspondents? * * *</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="D., C." TEIform="persName"/>CD Shakers, N. Y.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North Union, Ohio, May 30, 1877" TEIform="index"/>N. Union, O., May 30, 1877</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Editor: * * * We lately had a communication sent to us, signed by eighteen persons,
                                asking, " What shall we do to inherit eternal life ? " We replied by sending some copies
                                of "Plain Talks" and late copies of The Shaker, which answer these purposes well. The
                                Shaker is silently but surely doing a great work among the people. * *</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., J. S." TEIform="persName"/>J. S. P.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Editor:" TEIform="index"/> Dear Editor:</head><p TEIform="p">The last Shaker is received with much joy. All seem to be interested with it, and I do
                                not know why they should not. It is a beautiful paper, and must accomplish much good in
                                the world. The only unfortunate thing concerning it is, that we print so few to
                                circulate.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. B. Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Voice from Maine" TEIform="index"/>A VOICE FROM MAINE</head><p TEIform="p">G. A. Lomas—Dear Editor: I am now eighty-four years of age, and as I realize each day the
                                swiftness of time and the uncertainty of this life, I wish to leave upon record my
                                testimony. Our cause is a glorious one; I have given my life to its support, and do not
                                now regret it; its progress gives me great joy. Our Savior said, " Suffer little
                                children to come unto me and forbid them not, for of such is the kingdom of heaven." I
                                would become more and more like a little child, willing to be led, simple and teachable.
                                Dearly do I love the virgin life for its purity and sweetness. I have never bewailed my
                                virginity, nay never. O that thousands who are this day suffering under yokes of
                                bondage, and are slaves unto sin, could realize the happiness so real which I enjoy. For
                                every cross patiently borne, I have been doubly rewarded; and as I look around among my
                                dear brethren and sisters of the household of faith, I feel that the promise made so
                                long ago, by him who suffered (even unto death), has to me been verified. In early youth
                                I consecrated myself unto the Lord, my time, my talents, and my little all; in lieu
                                thereof I have been blest with an hundred fold of fathers and mothers, sisters and
                                brothers, houses and lands, and I have an heavenly inheritance beyond the grave. The
                                fear of death is taken from me. Long years ago I set out to serve God. My sins have gone
                                to judgment; I confessed them all one by one, and commenced to live the angel life ; a
                                life of holiness unto the Lord. This brought to me, as it will to every soul, " the
                                olive branch of peace." I can lie down at night, and feel at rest and peace with God and
                                all mankind. Our glorious cause is so great and good. too much cannot be said in its
                                praise. We are blest beyond all others, for not only do we find in this new relation a
                                kind and loving father, but unto us is given a tender mother, who is ready to sympathize
                                with us, and lift us above natural, earthly elements, on to a spiritual and heavenly
                                plane. There is no name more sweet to me than the name of my mother in the new creation,
                                Mother Ann Lee ; her testimony is mine; a keen testimony against all evil and
                                uncleanness,and a love for souls jar superior to all earthly loves; her gentle influence
                                is like that of an angel, calm and peaceful. May the sound of this precious gospel yet
                                reach every land and all nations be blest with a hearing of our Mother's pure testimony,
                                which giveth such life to the soul. " The Shaker " is an angel of comfort. 1 hail its
                                coming with great joy, and am always anxious to read its contents. I have read every
                                page since its commencement with care and deep interest, and so long as my sight remains
                                to me, I shall take pleasure in perusing its columns. Now and then there is an item on
                                early rising; this pleases me well. All my life I have been an early riser; it has given
                                me health and happiness. You that are seeking for health, adopt my rule to rise in the
                                summer season at four or halfpast four o'clock, go out in the cool of the morning and
                                breathe the pure air, which is so invigorating, and you will feel the better for it.
                                Indolent persons do not enjoy life. I have sometimes seen the expression in print, "We
                                are wearing away;" now it is better to wear out than to rust out, and to my aged friends
                                I would say, let us live while we are here and keep up our interest in things temporal
                                and spiritual. This is not our abiding home ; we are only learning how to live in this
                                world, and may the knowledge we obtain in this, our earth life, be of some use to us in
                                the great hereafter, when we shall have done with those things that perish with our
                                using. Dear Brother Albert, I want to tell you how much I love to go to meeting,—it is
                                my life. I attend all our meetings, public meeting with the rest. The poet says : "I
                                have been there and still would go. 'Tis like a little heaven below." I can say the
                                same. Health and happiness go hand in hand, and if we would be happy we must be truly
                                good. A thousand thanks to you, dear brother, for the interest you take in our "Shaker."
                                God bless you, and may the angels keep and help you forever. Keep the fires of truth
                                burning until ail error is consumed. God is truth, and he will have a people on the
                                earth who truly love and worship him. When I shall have gone to the " Evergreen Shores"
                                I shall not forget you, nor be unmindful of your labors here, together with our worthy
                                brother, Nicholas. I would that our "Zion Home " become more beautiful by the addition
                                of true souls to those already gathered in ; but the harvest is not yet. We are sowing
                                the seed that in God's good time will spring up and yield an abundance, then will come
                                the reapers, " to gather the good and the true." God speed the day. / shall live to see
                                it, yea, I shall live forever in the spirit. Accept love; an overflowing measure for all
                                who dwell in the valley, keeping a Benjamin's portion for yourself. Your Gospel Sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hurd, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna Hurd. West Gloucester, Me.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lawyers, doctors, soldiers and ministers..." TEIform="index"/>Lawyers, doctors, soldiers and ministers...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Lawyers, doctors, soldiers and ministers have commonly mistaken their callings. The first
                            should teach how to keep, not how to evade the law. The second, how to keep us well, rather
                            than thrive on our sickness. The third are hired to be shot at, and they hide themselves.
                            The fourth talk of, rather than walk in Christianity. That, according to Alger, "Everyman is
                            keyed to some measure, and tuned to some song!" THE SHAKER. Monthly—60 cents per annum. A
                            DUAL ADVOCATE OF CHRIST PRINCIPLES,</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Defend the faith" TEIform="index"/>Defend The Faith</head><p TEIform="p">Never was there a time when lukewarmness concerning the true faith of Christ should be
                            counted out of question— refused hai-bor— by Believers, more than now. Every wave of the
                            spiritual ocean brings to the top thinking men and women, who deem all literal creeds as
                            dead, compared to the life-giving fruits that evolve from living Christ'slife. Very many are
                            looking more to the life Jesus lived, as the element that will save them from further
                            sinning and its consequences, rather than to any physical death or scriptural promise. "To
                            whom shall we go?" is swelling the bosoms of many whose anxious hearts will alone be
                            satisfied by the fruits of the Christ life. And to whom shall such go ? Shall it be to those
                            who are not, or who are living as the great Christ-pattern lived ? While beautiful sermons
                            and songs, affecting prayers, appeals and exhortations, are reverberating through our land
                            in revival spirit, the really earnest for Christ will demand of Christian professors, lives
                            fruitful with present salvation from the sins of the xuorld; lives bearing the daily
                            identical crosses of Jesus, and wearing the crozvns of the Christ. The days of mere theology
                            , and technical differences of church polity, as forming party lines and divisions of
                            Christ, are in the past; and never was there a time when the honest in religious feelings
                            were more ready to throw to the winds the barnacle hindrances to angelic life, nor a period
                            when so many are lookingfor the nearest representation of Christ to-day manifested in living
                            humanity. Arise, in the might and power of the blessed faith—in defence of the cause—by
                            those most irresistible and convincing proofs of true religion the fruits of daily,
                            Christian self-denial. Love, and be like Jesus. Let our resistance be what his was—against
                            the whole retinue of lusts that compose the world ! Let all men and women see that our Mt.
                            Zion leads to a life above and beyond the power of the world to give or to take from us. And
                            in our o renewed and continual defence of the true faith, let us, pointing to the virgin
                            character of Jesus; to his daily selfdenials ; to his love for the higher angelic life ; to
                            his abstinence from the lusts of the world, and to his wholesouled consecration to the work
                            of saving others, be able to say, " Christ is with us, and illustrated in our lives!" Let
                            our lives be an impregnable Christian fortress, and guiding star to the unprotected.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="At no time in the memory of 'the oldest inhabitant'..." TEIform="index"/>At no time in the memory of 'the oldest inhabitant'...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">At no time in the memory of " the oldest inhabitant," have Shaker principles and life
                            attracted more attention, nor more favorable comment, than now. Let every Shaker be
                            determined these shall be well-deserved. 'Tis a mercy to be wakened from a deep sleep in sin
                            by a fall into deep sorrow.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="After the flood" TEIform="index"/>After the Flood</head><p TEIform="p">On or about April 25, Sallie Dill and her daughter Ida May passed to the life beyond this,
                            from Cincinnati, by poison administered by themselves. These parties had lived among the
                            Shakers sixteen or more years, but, getting unreconciled, chose sexual and other free dom of
                            worldly life, became unconditioned to remain, and left the precincts of Shaker society for
                            an element more fitted to their conditions. Shaker life had spoiled them for worldly
                            indulgences ; nor them alone, for it does so for every one who embraces its doctrines.
                            Better had mother and daughter —better had hundreds of others—better had those, now fostered
                            by our system, never heard of the Shakers,—than, becoming converts to Shakerism, turn
                            afterward to indulge in the beggarly elements of the world. Let every one, in and o"ut of
                            Shakerdom, fully realize this truth. We fain would be silent upon this subject. But for
                            weeks the press of the country has teemed with recitals of this distressing double suicide ;
                            and so various have been its conclusions, we deem it duty that we speak. Among many other
                            bulletins of the papers, we find : " The Horrors of Shaker Life ! " " The Shaker Tragedy,"
                            etc. The sum is this: These parties had been Shakers; departed the rules so far as to
                            necessitate their expulsion ; the outside world, whose practices, sexually, they had engaged
                            in, frowned upon them, and burdened beyond endurance, they died as they did. It was not
                            their "horror" of Shaker life, but their degradation from the purity of Shaker life, that
                            did the deed. "Oh," wrote Ida, " never, never leave the Shakers! You will find, if you do,
                            that there is no pleasure in the world. I have not had a happy moment since I left home."
                            And much else to the same purpose. Invariably their letters showed a "horror" at having left
                            the society. In no case did either ever intimate abuse. They had been happy in "the only
                            place worthy the name of home," and having repeatedly forfeited their right to its
                            privileges, found their "pitcher broken at last!" The curious features of this case strike
                            us, that at or about sixteen years oi age, Sallie, the mother, was introduced to society
                            with a babe in arms, seeking shelter from a world that had deceived her and wronged her
                            babe. At or about sixteen years of age, the daughter followed so closely in the unfortunate
                            steps of her mother, and the mother sympathized so closely with the daughter as to make
                            their retention in society and the maintenance of its laws irreconcilable. The world at
                            large may "refuse to be comforted" by any apparent unreason that the mother should be taken
                            into society in such a sorry plight, and yet, the daughter expelled from society for a
                            similar and sorrier offence. The mother, when taken, had committed no offence against
                            society; afterward, mother and daughter had so far transcended society's demands, that a
                            resi54 <pb n="55" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 55 dence among those who' do not aspire above human
                            i^eproductions became a necessity, for a time at least, that society's laws be vindicated !
                            After the flood of vituperation upon the society, mingled with a honey and balm from the
                            ever-to-be-remembered portion of our country's press, we would draw important lessons from
                            this sad picture. Among our people to-day may be numbered young people, comprising quite one
                            half, if not more, of the entire societies. And it is the important question for us to have
                            answered, how much better can we expect of the world than Sallie and Ida May found therein?
                            Who or what can relieve us from the convictions consequent upon our having found a faith
                            which has given us such a "happy home," and taught us of a life superior to mere animal,
                            lustful indulgences, which '"''perish with tising" every time? Let it be understood by the
                            press of our country, and duly considered by those within the pale of Shaker societies, that
                            these open their arms of protection to save souls from the pollutions of a worldly, fleshly
                            life. And if any choose not to be so saved, they are, after a struggle with us, welcome to
                            their choice, and we are relieved of any consequences, even of those that afflicted Sallie
                            and Ida May Dill.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><p TEIform="p">We yield large space, in this issue, to what a contemporary periodical says of the founder of
                            the Shaker Order. By the assurance we give, that it is copied, we are not open to the charge
                            of an overweening adoration, nor to an unwarrantable bigotry. When the root of any society
                            or association is holy, or on the highway to holiness, then its fruits may be judged
                            likewise. It is a fact very worthy of mention that the character and career of Mother Ann
                            Lee are attracting unusual attention about these days—that others are paying homages
                            exceeding our own, to this beloved mother. Already is known to be in formation a society
                            whose "corner stone" is Ann Lee, and it having no reference to the Shakers! All right,
                            friends, go ahead, God bless you, and help you leave all lusts of the world where she left
                            them ! We shall not be jealous of you. If we should be permitted the publication of a
                            private letter to ourself, we would make millions start with surprise, at what one of the
                            greatest mediums of to-day, philosopher, poet, writer and speaker, says of Mother Ann Lee !
                            Himself the organizer of societies and now leading one in this country, yet with a love for
                            Ann Lee excelling the most child-like devotion ! Cheer, brothers, cheer ! We would
                            respectfully inform many kind friends who have recently written us from Boston, New York,
                            Philadelphia, Worcester, San Francisco, anc other places desiring our presence to speak for
                            and to them, that we are no in the lecture field at present; and would dndly refer you to
                            the Elders of Noviiate Orders as the pi'oper parties to give he desired information and
                            assistance. Very mindful of your kindness in the Dast, we must necessarily decline personal
                            invitations at present, Our Covenant might be very interesting reading to some ; and for
                            those nterested we may in future present it entire. Reference is made in the lengthy, quoted
                            article on Ann Lee to our government, which we in a note attempt to correct. It should be
                            thoroughly understood, that centralization of our government is not, nor can be considered,
                            under the spirit of our Constitution. By it, four persons of both sexes constitute the
                            central authority—no less. Four similar appointees stand as Elders of the people. Four of
                            both sexes are the usual number acting as Trustees, while two or more, of either sex, are
                            demanded in the fulfillment of the directions of our Covenant. It will therefore be seen
                            that while pompous human nature would seek individual centralization in the use of our
                            worldly possessions, all care has been taken to avoid temptations to domineer and deprive
                            the brethren. With our Covenant, fully operative, no one man nor woman can act unadvised.
                            None can deprive any of rights it gives them, thus robbing not only one, two, or three
                            individuals, but all composing society, of God-given privileges. None feel this Covenant
                            more binding than the central, Ministerial authority- For, it is easy for any to perceive,
                            that by assuming or permitting an authority in any one individual, to arbitrarily decide for
                            all the rest, would render the Covenant, so sacred to us, not only inoperative, but dead ;
                            and a death-blow would inevitably succeed, which would mean the failure of Shakerism.
                            Readers and writers, please study our Constitution; and Brethren, look WELL TO THE
                            MAINTENANCE AND SAFETY op" our Covenant ! For, in the words of that great, legal light, John
                            C. Spencer: "Gentlemen, look well to, and keep this Covenant intact your selves; and then,
                            no other power on earth can break it!"</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Items</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Canterbury, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Canterbury people are far ahead in matter of public religious services. We have hac sent
                                us a large octavo sheet, containing the hymns and songs of one day's service. These are
                                distributed among the audience, Avhich i the better enabled to unite with Believers in
                                worship. The entire sheet evidences religiou enthusiasm, tact, and the prettiest
                                typography mortal eyes ever rested on. Public services began simultaneously, a
                                Canterbury and Enfield, N. H., May 6. Here in, again they lead ! </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North Union, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>North Union, O. </head><p TEIform="p">N. Union, O. Eighteen persons unitedly inquiring of thi#people, "What shall we do to
                                inherit eternal life?" The inquiry was fol lowed by visits. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whitewater, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>White Water, O.</head><p TEIform="p">Whitewater, O. The excitement occa sioned by the unfortunate Dills having sub sided, we
                                are, in the cool of a deliberate re view of the case, enabled to endorse every ac of the
                                Society as honorable and exemplary As intimated by the American Socialist, it was 'The
                                World's TragedjV beginning and endng, very properly, outside of Shaker domains, ^here
                                are valuable lessons to be learned from his case, by those within and those without
                                Shakerdom. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. The Ministry have ssued a circular, calling for a deeper interest n
                                all matters of a missionary nature, particularizing a more thorough maintenance and
                                circulation of The Shaker. They have the aeartfelt thanks of all lovers of The Shaker.
                                The circular was issued from the press at Canterbury. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet (Shakers, New York)" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Watervliet, (Shakers, N. Y.) "Plain Talks," pamphlet, a large edition of which was issued
                                from this place, is entirely exhausted. Ministry left here for Mt. Lebanon, May 16. They
                                will visit eastern societies. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant Hill, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hill, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">Pleasant Hill, Ky. The small fruit, so abundantly grown for years past in this place,
                                having been killed by the severity of winter and spring, the people philosophically
                                deliberate upon the waning of the preserving business of late years, through "extensive
                                competition and financial pressure," so that we are turning our attention, somewhat, to
                                other resources for a livelihood." The beautiful, profitable baptism of the Spirit,
                                particularly prevailing at this place for months, thank heaven, still continues. The
                                good believers, true, look upon it as a special providence ; while those of uncertain
                                stability, look askance upon the revival, lest it " move immediately upon their works!"
                                Let it move. "Evergreen Shore " reaps a saint from here. For lists of Ifovitiate Elders
                                of societies address this office, with stamp.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>THE CHILDREN'S GROTTO</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My dear children: Once again I am with you..." TEIform="index"/>My dear children: Once again I am with you...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">My dear children : Once again I am with you, and this time to remind you what power you
                                have in possession, to convince the world of its errors, and to teach of "that better
                                way"—the good, pure life of Jesus. "What can we children do or say?" Just the most
                                natural question to be expected. But, let me tell you that at twelve years of age^ Jesus
                                confounded the most learned people of his day, not by his superior learning of letters,
                                but by his spiritual impressions of a superior life. We have not the records of his
                                disputations with the doctors at that early age ; but from his after testimony we can
                                imagine, that, while he admitted the Law of Moses to be good, yet he insisted there was
                                something better than it! If war was good, peace was better; if love your friends and
                                hate your enemies was good, how much better it was to love enemies and friends too ! If
                                to be selfish six days, six years or longer, was any good, how very much better it was
                                to be so unselfish and noble as to love others better than one's self all the time ! And
                                so on, with hundreds of superior propositions, did Jesus, very likely, confuse the
                                doctors of his day. Now, dear children, every Shaker child that has learned the simple
                                principles upon which our church rests, can as surely confound mere professors of
                                Christianity to-day, as Jesus did the wise men of old ! Believe me; you will, when I
                                teach you how simply it is done. We will suppose you are twelve years of age, or
                                younger; and some learned priest asks you what you know of Christ Jesus? You will first
                                answer he lived a pure, virgin life, and demanded the same of all his disciples ! Who
                                could successfully dispute you here ? You will next declare he was such a lover of peace
                                and opposed to war, that he would not resis evil, but proposed to give " a kiss for a
                                blow,' and demanded this conduct of all who pro fessed his name ! What confusion you
                                woulc throw nearly all the D. Ds. of our land into And yet, how truly you would speak.
                                Next you would say, neither Jesus nor his true dis ciples had families that demanded of
                                them ny selfish end nor aim; only those who ived as he lived were relatives which he
                                ountenanced and owned ; and you might add :he question : " Is this the case with you,
                                docors?" And when you think, that to be a hristian is to be a follower of Jesus, the
                                Christ, not a mere believer of his doctrines, he direst confusion of mind will follow
                                the most learned, when the convincing facts of esus' life are presented, as they may
                                simply )e, by very youthful people. Christianity, as a great blessing to the race,
                                consists in simple obedience in life, not a mere acknowledgment of its truths.
                                Therefore, children, the docors with whom Jesus contended, were more able to defend
                                themselves, than are those who, professing great love for Jesus, yet deny him n nearly
                                every act of their lives! Let me encourage you to study the simple life of esus, and of
                                its being the centralpoint about which genuine Christianity can ever and only revolve.
                                Study it, for the grand reason of thus becoming truly Christian yourselves; ind then,
                                let your lights shine, let your actions speak, your minds work, and your tongues declare
                                the gospel to be "not pleasing to men, but God who trieth our hearts ! " Yours is an
                                extraordinary privilege of learning radical Christianity; and with the knowledge of the
                                simplest truths of Jesus, none ever contended nor confused the doctors of the Jewish
                                Temple, more than is in your power and province to confuse and confound the learned,
                                professional, but self-seeking and unpractical doctors of the Christian religion
                            today.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>BOOK TABLE</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="'What Shall I Do to be a Shaker?' Plain talks upon practical religion" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, George A" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Evening times" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">"What Shall I Do to be a Shaker?" Plain Talks on Practical Religion. By Geo. A. Lomas,
                                Editor of The Shaker, Shakers, N. Y. The writer favors "the eradication of all sexual,
                                sensual lusts," thinks "the holding of private property belongs to the earthly,
                                generative state;" that "Marrriage, War, Riches, Poverty, and Slavery" indicate a
                                depraved moral condition ; that Ann Lee, the Shaker Christ, who said, "Put your hands to
                                labor and give your souls to God," was the . Queen of social architects; and says the
                                Shakers "were thoroughly convinced of spirit communication, guidance and obsession long
                                before the Rochester Rappings." A vigorous and incisive statement of Shaker doctrines,
                                it shows an intelligent sense of reigning unrighteousness in society, customs, and
                                governments. The book inspires us with a deeper respect for Shakerism than we before
                                entertained.—The Word.</p><p TEIform="p">Evening Times, Albany, N. Y. To those who are at all interested in affairs at the cap*
                                ital of the Empire State, we advise them to subscribe for the Albany Evening Times. Its
                                columns are filled with the choicest reading and news ; it is a paper for family reading
                                : none but the most select and chaste of advertisements grace its borders, while its
                                editorials, according to the remarks of a political opponent, are "unequaled by any
                                north of the city of New York, and scarcely there." We know whereof we speak, and,
                                unsolicited, we give it the highest encomiums type are capable of expressing.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>EVERGREEN SHORES</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Roberts, Susannah" TEIform="index"/>Susannah Roberts
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Pleasant Hill, Ky., May 4, 1877, <persName reg="Roberts, Susannah" TEIform="persName">Susannah
                                Roberts</persName>, aged 86. "An honor to Mother Ann, and her followers, in this or the
                                better land." b. b. Di So, if in living we would live, And not in dying die ; To others
                                we must freely give Our love and sympathy; Must yield to Mercy's sweet control, Then
                                follow where she leads, And have a Jesus in the soul As well as in our creed!</p></div3></div2><pb n="56" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Voice of the spirit" TEIform="index"/>VOICE OF THE SPIRIT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. Hampton</byline><p TEIform="p">Union Village, Ohio. The regions of peace and pure love Are not for the giddy and vain, But
                            those who will wait for the wisdom above, And order and quiet maintain, And prudence, that
                            virtue divine, And patient endurance withal, The fpirit from all that is low to refine, And
                            banish the wormwood and gall. 2. And thus saith the spirit to me, From out the bright
                            heavens serene, In wisdom, O walk with the pure and the free, In the vale of my love ever
                            green. Thy future O scan and fore-see, •And hide from the evil to come Be thoughtful, and
                            silent, and turn unto me, And safely I'll gather thee home. 3. O hide from the tempest and
                            storm, In the temple of Wisdom and Love For there I will ever protect tliee from harm, And
                            fill thee with peace from above. No arrow that flieth by day, " Nor death-dealing meteor by
                            night, No pestilence walking in gloom and dismay, Shall fall on thy heavenward flight. 4.
                            And those who my discipline bear When the tempest is dark in the sky, In the hour of
                            silence, repentance and prayer, My presence shall feel ever nigh. And when your probation is
                            o'er, To the bright Summer Land you shall go, Where pain, and disease, and despair are no
                            more, My glory supernal to know.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">[The following articles are copied from The New Age, a fearless paper, in which people may
                            speak the whole truth—"hew to the line," caring not where the chips fly.]</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pious pretension" TEIform="index"/>Pious Pretension</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Washburn, L. K." TEIform="persName"/>L. K. WASHBURN</byline><p TEIform="p">The distinguishing characteristic of the religion of to-day is pretension. The mightiest work
                            of the Church is to make men and women profess religion. Belief is exalted above character,
                            and moral men are told that God does not care for them. The most prominent preacher before
                            the world to-day said, in a recent discourse, " To believe in Jesus is all the religion we
                            need;" and, we are sorry to say, that a great many people agree with him, for it is all the
                            religion they have. The popular motto of piety is: "Where Christianity is religion, 'tis
                            folly to be moral;" and so hypocrisy takes a front seat in the temple of Pretension, and the
                            man who cheats his neighbor and believes in Jesus is invited to lead the meeting in prayer.
                            Professional piety has done little more than make up a pious face. Its articles of belief
                            outnumber its good deeds. There is a great deal said about following Jesus, but we only hear
                            about these followers, we never see one. Where is the man that follows the commands or the
                            footsteps of Jesus? Jesus said, " Sell what thou hast and give to the poor." Who heeds the
                            command ? Do people know what sort of a man this Jesus was whose name they take so piously
                            on their lips? He was a friend of publicans and sinners. He was a companion of the poor and
                            lowly. He worked to help those whom the world despised and forsook. He associated with men
                            who broke the Sabbath law. Do people know what persons Jesus praised for their piety? The
                            Samaritan, hated and scorned by the Jew. The Publican, whom the Pharisee would not touch
                            lest he be contaminated. The poor widow, who brought two mites to the treasury of her Lord.
                            Do people know what Jesus taught? He did not preach the God of Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob,
                            but the God of the grass, the lily, and the sparrow. He did not say, Do as Moses told you to
                            do; but, "Why judge ye not of yourselves what is right?" He did not say, They shall have
                            eternal life who call me Lord, Lord ! but, '¦'¦They who do the will of my Father in heaven."
                            Where is the minister who pretends to be a disciple of this Nazarene preacher? who is doing
                            what Jesus did? who is commending the kind of persons that Jesus made models of piety? who
                            is preaching the God of nature's beauty and life? He is not to be found in a Christian
                            pulpit in the United States. Where is the man who professes to be a follower of Jesus, who
                            is following him? If men do not honor this man, then let them stop pretending to honor him.
                            If they do honor him then let them do as he did ; let them teach as he taught; let them live
                            as he lived; but I do not hesitate to declare that there cannot be found in a single church
                            in Christendom one person who honors Jesus enough to imitate his life. I raise no question
                            now of the virtue j of following Jesus, or of living as he lived. With that we are not at
                            present concerned. I merely assert that people who call themselves Christians care nothing
                            for the man whom | though accepting Jesus as their Elder "Brother, they call Christ, and
                            that the religion of these land who give him credit of being still far in people is only
                            pious pretension. Let men stop flitting on religion, stop -wearing it. To carry a cross upon
                            the breast is no surety that the heart that beats beneath it is pure and holy.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Genuine Christianity" TEIform="index"/>Genuine Christianity</head><p TEIform="p">To the Editor of the New Age :—I am very much pleased with the real work being done by your
                            journal, and that in this it is filling a niche in the age of progress that has long waited
                            for its advent. Well knowing its unsectarian character, I am almost dissuaded from entering
                            a criticism upon the very fine production of L. K. Washburn—"Pious Pretension." I fear,
                            however, the writer has too strongly urged his points of argument when he infers that
                            because popular Christianity is' very unlike the original of that name, there is none of the
                            original element operative today. Among other questions that could be answered
                            affirmatively, the following ai-e numbered : There are those who are following in his
                            footsteps to-day. There are those who are selling all to give it to the poor,— who do not
                            own a cent the^ call their own. There are those who are doing the will of the Father so
                            successfully as to have in possession a measure of eternal life. There are ministers who are
                            living and doing as Jesus did. There are people who, professing to follow Jesus, very nearly
                            succeed in doing so. Thei-e are people who, relying not at all upon the merits of the man
                            Jesus, deem his example, his life, worthy of all acceptation, until a greater shall come.
                            There are people who, THESHAKEH. advance of them in religious life, are yet so successfully
                            dealing in his virtues and lifeexamples as to be a very peculiar people, and the dispensers
                            of unpalatable truths through their lives. We would ask friend Washburn, or any other friend
                            interested, to visit some Shaker village, and therein, among many who have not yet travailed
                            to the new birth in Christ life, find others whose meat and drink it is to live just like
                            the author of Christianity. The article, " Pious Pretension," will do good—stir up many
                            professors to look to their practices; but will it not admit of some valuable criticism as
                            well ?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. LomasOffice of " The Shaker" Shakers, N. Y. -?</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is a higher exhibition of Christian manliness..." TEIform="index"/>It is a higher exhibition of Christian manliness...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is a higher exhibition of Christian manliness to be able to bear trouble than to get rid
                            of it. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The afflictions of this life..." TEIform="index"/>The afflictions of this life...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The afflictions of this numerous nor too sharp. a rough file. life are neither too Much
                            rustrequireth </p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There are more than one hundred rings..." TEIform="index"/>There are more than one hundred rings...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">There are more than one hundred rings, for bull-fights in Spain, and only twelve saving
                            banks. Some towns have a ring that have not yet a single school.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The heathenism of the Chinese..." TEIform="index"/>The heathenism of the Chinese...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The heathenism of the Chinese consists largely of f radical Christian truths, to which
                            so-called Christians are mere professors, not practitioners.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>