<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0203" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><date value="18720301" TEIform="date">March 1872</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">17-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="17" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">The leading article in this nnniber will be pnt in tract form, and may be procured at this office
                        at eiglit dollars per thonsand. Tsefnl to circulate. I WILL SHAKE ALL NATIONS, AND THB DESIRE OF
                        ALL NATIONS SHALL COME; AND I "WILL FILL THIS HOUSE WITH GLORY, SAITH THE LORD.' Published
                        Monthly, by and under the direction of the Mt. Lebanon Bishopric. Vol. II. G. A. Lomas, Editor.
                        SHAKERS, ALBANY CO., N. Y., MARCH, 1872. No. 3. Fifty Cents per Annum.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Universal church" TEIform="index"/>Universal Church</head><p TEIform="p">PROPHETIC ORDER VerSllS ORGANIZATION. Progress implies imperfection, or unattained
                            perfection, in an individual, or in a body. Prophecy is based upon the idea of progress.
                            Now, as the last and greatest of Jewish Prophets was Jesus ; and even his " testimony" is
                            affirmed to be "the spirit of prophecy" itself; the conclusion is logical, that the or-
                            ganizations resulting from his teachings and precepts, were not a finality, but that proph-
                            ecy and progress were still the law, not less than the hope of humanity; consequently the
                            disintegration of Christian organizations has been as uniform as their formation down
                            through the ages, and is still more potent and actively operative to-day, than at any pre-
                            vious period of mundane history. The first spiritual conference organized in New York, by
                            Partridge, Brittan, Benning, Gray, Halleck, and others, was itself a protest against all
                            organizations, not even a chairman being in order. Babel buildings are falling before the
                            angel of Spiritualism ; the Prophet—Shaker Church—alone remains in the land, to witness the
                            dissolution of all things—the overthrow of kingdoms, nations, peoples, tongues, and
                            Churches—upheaval, " turning things upside down." THE PROPHET. Who is the Prophet ? and
                            whence does he derive his almighty power and authority, that he alone remains, amid " the
                            wreck of matter and the crush of worlds?" The Prophet, before whom kings tremble, and be-
                            come as suppliants. " Pray for me, that the things which thou hast spoken come not upon me,"
                            is the voice of the despotic tyrant no less than of the necromancer. Samuel the Prophet made
                            and unmade kings in Israel. When Benhadad, king of Syria, was sick, "he sent Hazael to
                            Elijah, a Prophet in Israel, to inquire of the Lord, taking with him forty camels' burthen
                            of every good thing in Damascus," as a present, and received for answer, "Thou mayest
                            certainly recover, but the Lord hath shewed me, that thou shalt surely die." He then
                            informed Hazael that he would become king of Syria, and what he would do in Israel. To Saul,
                            Samuel said, " The Lord sent me to anoint thee king over Israel." Again : "Anoint Hazael to
                            be king over Syria, Jehu king over Israel, and Elisha to be Prophet in thy room." David also
                            was thus anointed king. The Prophet Moses " poured oil on Aaron's head, and anointed him
                            high priest." The higher law in Israel was, that no king, or high priest, was equal in power
                            to, or safe from being supplanted in office through, the order of | Prophets. Could anything
                            be more pertinent than the inquiry, Who is the Prophet, | and from what fountain does the
                            spirit flow that the anointing oil typified ? This is the more interesting from the fact,
                            that the gift of prophecy was common to the race, and was thus unlike other powers peculiar
                            to the Jewish organization, all of which were exclusive, and made the Jews themselves the
                            most separated and isolated of all people, " dwelling alone, not even being numbered with
                            the nations." PROPHETIC GIFT UNIVERSAL. So that a Prophet, when once his character as such
                            Avas established, was no longer held as belonging to any particular people; but, as we have
                            seen, was sought unto as a representative man, ranking above the officers of all human
                            organizations, however divinely appointed by tutelary deities. It was this conflict of
                            authority between the Prophets and the organizations, that caused the former to be so often
                            stoned and killed. " Which of the Prophets have not your fathers killed, and stoned them who
                            were sent unto them ? " "It cannot be," said the iconoclastic Jesus, " that a Prophet perish
                            out of Jerusalem : " and himself did not otherwhere die. The high priest, king, and
                            priesthood, were " the powers that be," who had been appointed of their God. From that
                            stand-point, what was a Prophet, but a rebel against the existing organization, or a martyr
                            under it ? By the law of self-preservation—the first law of nature—did he not deserve to be
                            persecuted and killed ? There were some thirty men, immediately preceding Jesus, each of
                            whom claimed to be "some great one"—the Messiah of the Jews. These had worn out the patience
                            of the Romans, so that Jesus was summarily dealt with. Gamaliel refers to this class as
                            those who had made much trouble, coming to "nothing" but their own dispersion or des-
                            truction. As the mushroom grows out of the dunghill which has hitherto produced only toad-
                            stools, so does the true Reformer and Prophet grow out of those elements which had pre-
                            viously produced a crop of spurious or imperfect Prophets and Reformers, for all of whose
                            idiosyncrasies, short-comings, and crudities, he is held responsible. " Save me from my
                            friends," is the fervent prayer of every genuine Reformer or Prophet. The half-way Chris-
                            tian, who cries " Lord, Lord," worshiping Jesus as one of the Three Gods who died to let him
                            live in lust uncondemned, of all others, is the greatest sinner, and the least known of the
                            Christ Spirit Abraham, the father of the Jewish nation, who, by common consent, is held as
                            the type of Jesus the Messiah, was himself a Prophet and friend of the Hebrew God. He met
                            Molchizedekj who (under the popular ruling) was a heathen; but he was " king of right-
                            eousness," a " king of peace," a celibate; being "without fiither and mother, and without
                            descent, beginning of days, or end of life, made like unto the Son of God (whoever that may
                            be), and abideth a priest continually." In plain English, Melchizedek was a Christian, who
                            had not only been ministered to by the Christ Spirit, from the seventh or resurrection
                            heavens; but he had incarnated that Spirit in his character, and was a " high priest of the
                            Most High God." Unto him, poor heathen Abraham very properly confessed ]iis sins, which
                            thenceforth became an established Jewish ordinance. He also paid the sacrificial tithes to
                            Melchizedek, not only for himself, but for all the Levitical priesthood (yet in his own
                            loins) down to Jesus, his descendant and antetype, who confessed his sins, if at all guilty,
                            to John the Baptist, the Christ Prophet, as did Abraham to Melchizedek ; for John was the
                            antetype of Melchizedek, as was Jesus of Abraham. PHYSICAL WAR CONDEMNED. Abraham had just
                            returned from the " slaughter of the kings," when Melchizedek, " the king of peace," taught
                            him that physical war was animal—brutal ; and wrong for him, and all that should proceed
                            from him. It took two thousand years for Abraham to reach that gift of peace in the person
                            of his descendant, Jesus, who, under the law of Prophecy and Progress, became the " Prince
                            of Peace," and was anointed king of righteousness; for "he loved righteousness, and hated
                            iniquity;" and the Christ Spirit also " anointed him with the oil of gladness above his
                            fellows." CELIBACY. It is said of Jesus (prophetically), " His life was cut off from the
                            earth, and who shall declare his generation ? " he having no physical (or natural)
                            posterity, like Abraham ; but, like Melchizedek, he too became a celibate, forsaking his
                            earthly generative relation of father and mother, of brother and sister, for those who knew
                            and did the will of God, this being eternal life, and not confined to earth, made him
                            without descent, beginning of days, or end of life ; thus receiving the kingdom of heaven as
                            a little child, precisely as the Shakers of our day commence their spiritual travel. <pb n="18" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 18 THE SHAKER PRIESTHOOD. Melchizedek was " made like unto the Son of
                            God." •' Thus, after the similitude of Melchizedek, there ariseth another priest, and
                            another priesthood. For Jesus is made a priest for ever, after the order of Melchizedek,"
                            outside of the Mosaic Law, yet including it as a " schoolmaster," to prepare souls for the
                            Christ Order—the Christian life. UNIVERSAL CHURCH. Thus does a ministration from the inner-
                            most (or seventh) sphere end the world of generation, physical war, and private property, to
                            all nations, in all times, and in all worlds. " Jesus was made higher than the heavens" of
                            generation, or the angels in them; from which alone the Jews had received their
                            ministrations. Nor do the generating, warring Gentile Christians receive ministrations from
                            any other than generative heavens and hells. REPENTANCE. John the Baptist, the greatest of
                            Jewish Prophets, the Melchizedek of his day, who told the soldiers to " do violence to no
                            man," was the minister of baptism to Jesus, who came to him acknowledging the order of con-
                            fession, as Abraham went to Melchizedek, and as Ann Lee went to James and Jane Wardley.
                            COMMON PROPERTY. Melchizedek and John were each a minister of the Christ Spirit, " the
                            second Adam, the Lord from heaven." Abraham paid tithes of his property, thus acknowledging
                            that it all belonged to the Lord. Jesus gave the whole, retaining not anything. "All things
                            common." PEACE. When Abraham and his posterity—all true Jews—did fight, it was as spiritual
                            mediums, always (like Moses and Elijah) depending upon the spirits to slaughter their
                            enemies. But Jesus would not call fire down from heaven, as did Elias, to kill; but learned
                            of the Christ Spirit to do good to all—evil to none; and to be "first pure, then peaceable."
                            PROGRESSION OP PRIMATES. From the day that Melchizedek blessed Abraham, the Jews traveled
                            towards Christianity—progressed. As the result of that progress, Jesus, probaby the best of
                            Jewish boys, progressed towards Christianity, until he " saw of the travail of his soul, and
                            was satisfied " therewith, by incorporating it into his character, so that the " prince of
                            this world" found nothing of it in him. CHRIST ANGEL AND INTERMEDIATE PROPHETS. The
                            intermediate Prophets, between Melchizedek and John the Baptist, were ministers of the
                            Christ heavens. It was this thai raised them above all earthly powers anc principalities,
                            above the kings and the holy anointed high priests, and the subordinate priesthood, while
                            acting officially as Chrisi ministers. But themselves, as men, were often far from being
                            Christians. Even Jesus was not born a Christian, but a Jew; "born of a woman, born under the
                            Law," and hat to work out his salvation as have all othei men ; only he had none but the
                            Christ Spirit to help him after John had baptized him. lence the Prophet Zechariah says that
                            he was shown, in vision, Joshua—Jesus—the high mest, " standing before the Angel of the jord
                            (the Christ Angel), and Satan at his ¦ight hand to resist him. And " the Lord "(Christ
                            Angel) said unto Satan, The Lord rebuke thee, 0 Satan. Is not this a brand plucked out of
                            the fire " (of lust) ? CONFESSION OF SIN. " If we confess our sins, God is faithful and just
                            to forgive us our sins, and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness." " Now (Jesus) was
                            clothed with filthy garments, and stood before the (Christ) Angel. And the Angel spoke to
                            them who stood before him (John and his disciples), Take away the filthy garments from him/'
                            by confession; and the Spirit said, " I have caused thine iniquity to pass from thee, and I
                            will clothe thee with change of raiment. So they clothed him with garments (a work of time);
                            and the (Christ) Angel of the Lord stood by," to help, and said to him : "If thou wilt walk
                            in my ways, and if thou wilt keep my charge, then thou shalt keep my courts, and judge my
                            house." It was conditional even with Jesus the Messiah, to whom Christ first appeared, to
                            begin the work of human redemption. And we have still the Spirit of Prophecy and the laws of
                            Progress operative unto the second appearing of the Christ Spirit in Woman, as the first had
                            been in Man. That second appearing has been and is often prophesied of. " Hear, 0 (Jesus),
                            the high priest, thou and thy fellows that sit before thee (Christians) ; for they are men
                            wondered at. For, behold, I bring forth my servant, the Branch." "A rod"—Jesus—"shall grow
                            out of the stem of Jesse ; and a branch "—Ann—" shall grow out of his roots"—the Gentiles;
                            "and to her shall the gathering of the Gentiles be; and his rest shall be glorious." " For,
                            behold, the stone—(Branch)—that I have laid before Jesus; upon it shall be seven eyes :
                            behold, I will engrave (by revelation) the engraving thereof, saith the Lord of hosts, and I
                            will remove the iniquity of that land in one day." " In that day, saith the Lord of hosts,
                            shall ja call every man under his vine, and under his fig tree." There shall be co-operation
                            in the civil Government; and also Communistic elements, out of which shall grow Christian
                            Pentecostal Communities of Gentiles, with " all things common," as the body, and an abiding
                            of the Christ Spirit as the soul, of the Universal Church. THE MAN JRSUS. Moses was a
                            Prophet of the God of Israel, but he had a vision of the Christ heaven, which was "the
                            (spiritual) mount" and was told to "make all things (in his natural order) after the
                            pattern" of what he saw there; that it might serve as a prophecy of the spiritual order yet
                            to come on the earth, to succeed, include, and supplant himself anc Dispensation. Moses
                            said, "The Lord thy God will raise up unto thee a Prophet, from the midst of thy brethren,
                            like unto me; unto him ye shall hearken." Such Avas Jesus who came teaching a higher law
                            than the Mosaic—more spiritual. CHRIST. Jesus askeci, " What think ye of Christ ? " " Whose
                            son is he ?" They said, " David's." " Why then does David, in spirit, call him Lord ?" " How
                            is he David's son ?" Now, inasmuch as Jesus never objected to being called the " Son of
                            David," it is self-evident that he knew the Christ Angel to be a distinct person—the second
                            or spiritual Adam— through whose agency he became a " Son of God;" and "to as many other men
                            as receive him, he" and his successors "give the same power to become sons of God."
                            SPIRITUALISM. If Paris were a spiritualist, she would comprehend, that, in killing " the
                            Communes " by hundreds, she is increasing their power to injure her; and furnishing them
                            with the strongest motive to use it—vengeance. Cannot she read ? or is she " drunk with
                            blood ?" " How long, 0 Lord, dost thou not judge and avenge our blood ?" asked the martyrs.
                            Until your fellow-servants, the Prophets, that shall be killed, as you were, is fulfilled."
                            In other words, until an infidel Government succeeds the Church and State Governments of
                            Christendom—Kepublics that are untheological. THE BRANCH, ANN LEE. The " Two Witnesses
                            "—male and female— inspired from the Resurrection—Christ— heavens, to " prophesy in
                            sackcloth and ashes, under persecution, during the " 1260 years " rule of this "Wilderness"
                            Christianity, closing in 1792, when the wwtheological civil Government of the U. S. ended
                            the power of Babylon priests to kill the Prophets. Up to this period, the spiritual truths
                            of their testimony had " tormented " the Church-andState organizations, whether Catholic,
                            Protestant, or Greek, in all of which are inter blended War and Peace, Marriage and
                            Celibacy, Riches and Poverty, Churches and Barracks, Monastic Institutions and Houses of
                            Prostitution, Charitable Orders and the Inquisitions of Rome and Naples, Prisons (like the
                            Tombs and Ludlow jail) and a hireling Police, with a hireling Priesthood, under a "One God"
                            and "Three God" system, which prays continually for the second coin^ ing of the man Jesus—as
                            Christ—who, now that he has appeared "in ten thousand of hid saints," proves to be the
                            English woman Ann Lee; and "to as many as receive her, she" and her successors "give power
                            to become " sons and daughters of the Lord God Almighty."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thankfulness" TEIform="index"/>Thankfulness</head><p TEIform="p">" In everything give thanks, for this is the will of God in Christ Jesus concerning you.''—2
                            Thess. ii. 18. Mark the reason why we should be thankful for all things : Because it is the
                            will of God. Let me ask myself this question : Am I thankful for everything ? Am I thankful
                            for that which displeases and crosses, as well as that which pleases and comforts me ? Do I
                            make a blessing of everything ? Do I rejoice when persecuted ? Do I pray for my enemies or
                            persecutors ? Am I thankful for <pb n="19" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 19 the opportunity of
                            giving up all for the gospel? Do I thankfully give up my own will, my feelings, words,
                            thoughts, and actions, to be governed by the Gospel, through my accepted Lead ? If I do not
                            thankfully give up all these, then I do not give thanks in everything. But I can go farther,
                            and say, that I am not only thankful for the opportunity of giving up all; but that I hare
                            done so, and am thankful I have given up Father, Mother, Sisters, Brothers, Wife, and child,
                            with all my relations, and worldly goods; and also that spirit that desires the continuance
                            of such relations ; and am ready to give up my own carnal life in all things, and be
                            thankful for the opportunity. Therefore in everything I give thanks. My particular thanks
                            are due to you, dear Editor, and Correspondents, for the genuine spirit of comfort I derive
                            from "The Shaker."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brown, Napoleon" TEIform="persName"/>Napoleon Brown. Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Living comparisons" TEIform="index"/>Living Comparisons</head><p TEIform="p">The rolling river as it flows From glacier fields on high, Dissolving from the mountain
                            snows, Like dew-drops from the sky, Leaps dazzling in the yellow sun, Rejoicing on its way,
                            It spans the chasms, one by one, And crowns them with its spray. Exulting in its new-born
                            joy, It bounds from hill to plain ; Ko heights impede, no depths destroy, Nor gathering
                            winds restrain. "Tis thus when dawns the better Way, With brightness on the soul; Out hearts
                            will bound like Lambs at play, Or ocean billows roll. But as Love's current grows more wide,
                            More gently will it flow ; Though strong as moves old ocean's tide, Yet soft as falling
                            snow. Each golden sun, each silver star, Swift as its mystic flight, Moves through the azure
                            fields afar, Still as the voice of night. Far down within the bosom deep, Where minist'ring
                            angels come, Where faith and hope their vigils keep, There is devotion's home. Thence from
                            each pure and trusting soul, Doth grateful incense rise ; Unspoken, thence heart anthems
                            roll, That gladden fairer skies. Pure gospel life is like a stream, That moves with even
                            tide ; No lightning-flashes o'er it gleam, No cataracts divide. But mirror'd in its waters
                            bright, The smiling stars appear, Like jewels from the crown of night, The Angels scattered
                            there. Thus may the current of our love, Like some fair river flow ; Though brighter than
                            the skies above, More deep than seas below. And while o'er Jordan's rolling stream The
                            glistening fields we see. Serene as is an Angel's dream, May our devotions be.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leggett, E. T." TEIform="persName"/>E. T. Leggett</byline></div2><div2 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bhagvat-Geeta" TEIform="index"/>Bhagvat-Geeta
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The Bhagvat-Geeta, sent us by The ReligioPhilosopical Publishing House, is a small, but in-
                            valuable work to the student of antiquity. The work is no doubt a Brahmic production ; but
                            the curiosity that afflicts one continually, is the wisdom prevailing in it, and to think
                            this was prevalent so many ages ago ! RE.7OIKDER. In a late number of The Christian
                            Advocate, Dr. Curry, Editor, there was published, as original matter, an article copied from
                            Scribner's Monthly, entitled " Shakerism'—vefloctlng very unfairly and untruthfully upon The
                            Shakers. We wrote the subjoined article in reply, by which the readers of Tire Shakes can
                            judge the Unchristian Advocacy of principles, in the article to which we reply. Our reply
                            was refused publication, and the refusal of the Editor was accompanied by the following
                            remarks : '• It seems to me, you ask very much of us, when you call on us to allow you to
                            defend in our columns a system that convicts our parents, ourselves and our whole people of
                            criminal carnality. You may think your system an eminently spiritual one ; we do not, but
                            quite the contrary. * * * Without any wish to shorten your liberties, but still looking upon
                            your system as a bad one, we are content to let you enjoy your peculiar notions," etc. These
                            views are such, that no sincere Methodist, being acquainted with The Shakers, would
                            willingly coincide with. By them we are able to judge what the spirit of intolerance would
                            do with us were we not so favored by the Providential Constitution of the IT. S. It would
                            crucify Jesus as readily to-day as ever; and knowing how soon the Consti- tution of the U.
                            S. would take a sectarian turn, when once the opening wedges of " God' and "Christ " are
                            entered therein, we are unreservedly and vehemently opposed to any amendment that will give
                            the Constitution of the IT. S. any theological signification, or that would make it an unfit
                            instrument for the Jew, the Mohammedan, the Christian, the Infidel—of any religion or of no
                            religion. And we warn all. that any sympathy with such amendment, adds weight to the bell
                            that will sound the death-knell of our free government, if it is ever destroyed. Now for the
                            rejoinder :</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakerism's defense" TEIform="index"/>Shakerism's Defense</head><p TEIform="p">Editor Advocate : In your issue of Dec. 28. is an article entitled " Shakerism." To remove
                            prejudices created thereby, and to prevent further misconceptions, we ask your kindly
                            consideration and publication of " Shakerism's Defense." We are well acquainted with the
                            author of " Shakerism" in The Advocate, having harmlessly experienced other intended rebukes
                            and sarcastic lectures upon Shakerism from his pen. We do not blame him—we do pity him—and
                            all others failing of a true comprehension of real Shaker polity. In one of Holland's
                            lectures, he observes: " I believe God loves the Shakers, but I do not think he admires them
                            !" Now, we do not ask admiration of our worship, our dress, nor of our self-denying
                            testimony; but if all good Methodists will love our lives, we will be satisfied with them.
                            In The Shaker for last November, we wrote upon " The Difficult Lesson,"—being learned by us,
                            and by us being taught to the world at large. We find Dr. Holland as ignorant of this "
                            Lesson " as the generality of readers, though he has had very favorable opportunities of
                            learning it. The worshipful exercises, which we permit strangers to witness, we are aware,
                            excite, in the minds of those misunderstanding them, less reverence than we feel; and in the
                            very worldly-minded, mirthful derision ; and such would mock the movings of the good Spirit
                            in a Methodist Church, or wherever else manifested. And yet, while many thousands an- nually
                            visit our meetings, coming, mayhap, with fun in their hearts; still, we believe, the
                            majority "tarry to pray with us" that the right will prevail. Of the continuance of our
                            Public Meetings as a successful missionary enterprise, we have a personal doubt; and while
                            expecting (not announcing) their discontinuance at no distant day, we believe they have done
                            much good. As in " The Difficult Lesson," we repeat, that the position of the Shakers on the
                            subject of Marriage, is very much misunderstood by even the vulture-eyed philosopher and the
                            lion-hearted reformer. The two planes of existence we present to the world, both right in
                            their individual spheres, give to marriage all it sacredly demands, and more than it
                            physiologically gets; and at the same time assert that Marriage is an earthly institution
                            only, and does not belong to the spiritual heavens—neither "heaven on earth" according to
                            Christianity, nor heaven " in that world which is to come." No Shaker, having been baptized
                            with fire and the Holy Spirit (and these are what make true Shakers), ever " acknowledged
                            that the society of woman, in the intimate relations of a wife, would be inexpressibly sweet
                            to him," nor many similar assertions in your article on " Shakerism." Any person who does
                            not realize greater blissfulness in being " a eunuch for heaven's sake," is not a Shaker!
                            and if making the profession, is either an infant in the faith, or a designing hypocrite,
                            seeking the " loaves and fishes." We do " assume (and know), that we live purer lives in the
                            abstinence of marriage," when complying with the injunctions of our faith to chasten every
                            deed, word and thought that would excite sensuality in the flesh ! Can you look upon such a
                            system as a bad one ? While we look upon marriage as honorable in its place—yet that place
                            is outside and beneath a Christian life—and those engaged in it as respectable when properly
                            respecting it; yet, to us, there is a sphere as far above the reproductive, as our estimates
                            of heaven are superior to our estimates of earth. Few, if any good Methodists believe that
                            the Angels marry; and can they object if the Shakers pattern the hosts of heaven in this
                            respect ? Certain it is, that as individuals approach Angelhood, they are adopting Shaker
                            principles, consciously or otherwise. The Shakers do look for a reward ; but not after the
                            storehouse or hay-stack theory, but in the effects upon their characters, of the causes they
                            engage in; and we realize daily, sufficient reward to repay us for all the cross we endure
                            from the absence of matrimony; hence the cross, so apparent to the devotees of marriage,
                            disappears to the thorough-going Shaker. To the Shaker, " The pleasures of an earthly life
                            can give no peace of mind ; But the gospel is full recompense for all we leave behind." "
                            The sweet sinfulness of marriage" is a term we never have used, and bearing as it does the
                            mark of the beast, we will not adopt it. A man is what he makes himself; whether level with
                            or beneath the brute creation, or as you give us the credit of aspiring, " preeminent among
                            the saints ! " By refusing to fall in love with the earthly, and by rising, cheerfully, in
                            love with the Angel-life, we do not " insult our own nor others' parents !" they, under the
                            light of God manifested to them, did <pb n="20" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 2O THE SHAKER. rightly; and yet
                            they were (unconsciously) not Christians ! That which was proper before the advent of
                            Christianity, or the adoption of the Christian profession, becomes, in as many respects as
                            the systems differ, very improper afterward; and to full Christians, the elements that would
                            make of us, first, husbands and wives, then fathers and mothers, and necessitate the
                            gathering of private property for the sustenance of all that is " mine,'" are unchristian
                            elements, however absurd or unpleasant the ideas may be to the mass of 'professing
                            Christians ! We claim an increase of light beyond the illuminations of our parents; and in
                            the face of this would fall under a condemnation our parents could not know of, should we
                            now do as they have done; and our personal feelings strongly object to the proposition "
                            that our virgin Sisters become Mothers " by any power with which we are acquainted. In these
                            opinions, " the Shaker maybe mistaken," but we opine not. The wholesale slaughter of virgin
                            purity, indulged in by the writer of " Shakerism," wherein he styies, it " a damaging
                            thought among the Shakers, celibate priests, monks and nuns, " reminds us how wide-spread is
                            sympathy for us, and how sincere are the imitators of the virgin spirit of our Lord. "
                            Marriage peoples the earth," said the sage, "but Celibacy increases the forces of heaven."
                            While admitting the good of marriage, we as readily assert its corroding effects upon true,
                            spirit growth, and for the acquisition of the superior good, reject its good and bad
                            together. And why find fault with us, and not with our much adored exemplar—Jesus ? Dr. II.
                            would not write such scurrilous remarks of the celibate Jesus—why of us ? We hate the
                            selfish spirit of the bachelor worse than he does. If we are engaging in aught that Jesus
                            did not, or which he failed to predict would come to pass, then we are not his followers. We
                            also recognize the heroism displayed by the missionaries of the various sects ; while we are
                            positive that carnal men and women will face all other dangers, rather than " crucify the
                            flesh, with its affections and lusts," in their own unregenerate hearts. So far as the
                            inuendo goes, that "marriage would be a greater personal purity on the part of the Shaker,"
                            that charge of secret sensuality lost all its force, years ago. The sum is this : Could we
                            enjoy the felicities of matrimony, exceeding the most finely drawn picture of the most
                            exaggerative, sensual novelist ; and could we produce offspring as perfect as was Jesus, we
                            should feel no more permission to engage in either, than we now feel, when " incompatibility
                            of temper " is so nearly universal, and when less healthful progeny than cattle is so
                            general. " Our lives are cut off from the earthly," as was our exemplar's ; and having
                            transcended the procreative plane, we experience the transmutation of our natural abilities
                            into spiritual relationships. We judge, Ed. Advocate, that the writer of " Shakerism," if
                            not your honor, has more faith in real Shakerism than he is willing to practice. By your
                            help we would place this article into the hands of every Methodist, and its substance in the
                            hearts of all liberal thinkers.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. Lomas</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trust in God" TEIform="index"/>Trust in God</head><p TEIform="p">O'Lord, in thy temple my soul shall abide; Though sorely afflicted, in thee I confide; Though
                            stripes be my portion, intensely to feel, The hand I will bless, that hath power to heal.
                            Lord, fashion me, subject to thy righteous will; Yea, search me, and try me, I will love
                            Thee still. Deprived of treasures and friends dear to me. My soul must be saved, and I'll
                            still cleave to Thee. Though early companions have sought the broad road, Yet nearer, still
                            nearer, I'll walk with my God ! The way may be narrow, the passage be straight, Yet the city
                            of God lies through the straight gate; The weak and world-loving, may quail at the fire,
                            That's kindled in Zion, for a purifier; In this cleansing furnace of God I'll be tried,
                            Though intense be the heat, yet in it I'll abide. The gold will not perish, though dross be
                            consumed; The purified only, by heaven are owned; t Prepare me thus Lord, for that rest
                            which remains For the people of God, without blemish or stain. In the first resurrection let
                            me have a part; Impressed be the image of Christ in my heart; Inspired by Angels with
                            meekness ami love, Endowed with wisdom that comes from above. O what avails pride, or the
                            pleasures of sin, Their fruits are all bitter, remembrance a sting ! A justified conscience,
                            a heart that is pure, Yield pleasures abundant, and these will endure. Heart and voice all
                            attuned, grateful praises I'll sound, On the Zion of God, where salvation is found. Bright
                            Angels bear witness, my vows I renew, Of a full consecration to God I'll be true.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sawyer, Otis" TEIform="persName"/>Otis Sawyer, Alfred</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eternal damnation" TEIform="index"/>Eternal Damnation</head><p TEIform="p">I have experienced much heavenly joy from enlightenment respecting this subject; and
                            believing, dear Shaker, that what has been so comforting to my own heart will be equally
                            comforting to that of other hungerers after truth, I venture to offer the following remarks.
                            What a fearful consideration to the feeling heart! The damnation for ever and ever of a
                            human being ! It is of the utmost importance that we should comprehend the nature and the
                            consequence of that most awful sin, of which the result is, by many, supposed to be eternal
                            damnation. Let us approach its consideration with feelings of reverent hope. First, the
                            Evangelists' report of Jesus' sayings on this subject are to be considered. Matthew's
                            account (xii. 22-37) is the fullest. According to him the circumstances were these : Jesus,
                            in a house in Nazareth probably (Matt. xii. 46; xiii. 1; Mark iii. 27, 31), had healed a
                            blind mute. This miracle, no doubt, seemed to him to be sufficient to convince hearts of
                            flint; but the cold and supercilious pharisees and scribes—some of whom had real faith in
                            him, but from self-interest confessed him not (John xii. 42)—sneeringly said that he did
                            those mighty works by means of devils : as some, in this day, say the Shakers at present do
                            their mighty works. As Jesus read these thoughts in their hearts, what bitterness of spirit
                            must have been his ! He had not yet overcome (John xvi. 33); he still could feel some human
                            anger. What selfrestraint must he have exerted to keep from pouring out upon them his
                            contempt and wrath! ; But the real bitterness and disappointment of his heart find
                            expression in the cry, ' Ye generation of vipers !' This was uttered in the spirit of John
                            the Baptist (Matt, iii. 7) with a force that must have struck terror into the hearts of
                            those who would not nonestly confess their faith in him, but who willfully spoke against
                            their conscience, and who said that his works were of the devil; lie denounced on such
                            eternal wrath. Though Jesus had said not long before, ' I am meek and lowly in heart' (Matt.
                            xi. 29), yet had ' the devil left him, for a season' only (Luke iv. 13). When Jesus had
                            overcome, his Avords were, ' Father, forgive them, they know not what they do.' They knew as
                            little what they did, when they spoke against his spirit, as they knew when they crucified
                            him. What is the meaning of the agony in the garden of Gethsemane, if Jesus did not gain
                            there a great victory over himself? Jesus felt this himself: for, almost immediately after
                            the denunciation, he said (Luke xiii. 50), 'I have a baptism (of fire) to be baptized with,
                            and how am I straitened till it be accomplished.' Are there no souls on the earth who can
                            feel all the anguish of these words ? St. Luke's account of the matter is substantially the
                            same. The only striking point is that, in his gospel, the denunciation is in the wrong
                            place; it is meaningless as it stands, and should be transferred from Luke xii. 10, and
                            placed after Luke xi. 20. No doubt some well-meaning saint of dark times has improved on the
                            evangelist. We must here lament the defects in the gospel records : of the accounts in each,
                            some are defective, others inaccurate. Where there are two, three or four accounts of the
                            same transaction, we must bring them together, being careful to read them all by the greater
                            light of this day, compare them, and extract the truth. Now, St. Mark's account contains a
                            striking qualification. The words are, ' hath never forgiveness,' yet is only ' in danger of
                            eternal damnation.' One would suppose the words 'hath never forgiveness' to mean the same
                            thing as ' eternal damnation '; yet, there come in the stangely qualifying words ' in
                            danger.' Next, the commentators on the testimony : St. Paul (Heb. vi. 4-8) says of 'those
                            who have tasted of the heavenly gift, if they shall fall away, it is impossible' (so it
                            seemed to him) 'to renew them again unto repentance'; he also says, ' they are like bad
                            soil, and nigh unto cursing.' Again : he says of those who sin willfully after having come
                            to a knowledge of the truth (Heb. x. 2G), that ' a fiery indignation,' or literally, '
                            rrvphg" ^fjXog', a zeal of fire shall devour the adversaries.' St. John, though his gospel
                            seems to be especially devoted to the spiritual teachings of Jesus, does not mention, in
                            that place, this imprecation by Jesus; but he has a few indefinite words in his general
                            Epistle, which may bear on this subject. He says : ' There is a sin unto death,' and ' I
                            (John) do not say that he (the sinner) tpuTrjcq nepl ineivrjg-, may solicit for that.' Here
                            we have before us all that is contained in the Gospels and Epistles of the New Testament on
                            this subject. It is clear that the sin <pb n="21" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHA^KEH. against the Holy
                            Ghost is committed by three kinds of sinners : by those who, blinded by their own lusts,
                            speak and act against the work of the Spirit; by those who, contrary to the convictions of
                            their conscience and from selfish motives, act in the same way ; and by those who, having
                            tasted of the heavenly gift, become barren by willful sin, and thus turn from friends to
                            adversaries. Jesus said, in a masculine, unqualified way, out of the bitterness of his
                            heart, * Those who say a word against the Holy Ghost are in danger of eternal damnation.'
                            This Jesus said, and this Peter illustrated, drawing his prophetic power from the spiritual
                            force of Jesus ascended (Acts v. 5). Yet we must observe that though Peter tells Ananias he
                            has lied to the Holy Ghost, and though he prophecies the death of Sapphira, there is no
                            mention of eternal damnation. They both fall physically dead, overwhelmed with terror at the
                            discovery of their sin, merely losing by their misconduct the privilege to work out in Time
                            the work of that day. Such sudden discomfiture to persons suffering from heart disease would
                            very easily cause death. God, foreseeing the effect of this event on the minds of after
                            ages, suffered it in connection with Peter's words. It is not to be supposed that Ananias
                            and Sapphira thoroughly understood the nature of their sin : even Peter himself had not
                            entered into the depths of love; for, to enter into those depths requires the full light of
                            truth. The words of Jesus, the illustration by Peter, are a manifestation of Power, the
                            Father in God. But, if there be any meaning in the Bride, which, radically, signifies the
                            principles of the Second Church of Christ, then has the present mani- festation through her
                            of Love, the Mother in God, softened the criminal's sentence; or, more exactly, has made
                            that sentence clear. So long as any blind their spiritual eyes by lust of any kind, or
                            willfully and selfishly shut their eyes to the light, so long will they ex- clude themselves
                            from seeing by the light, both in this world and in the world to come; and the more they
                            kick against the pricks of conscience, the more will they lay up for them- selves a treasure
                            of wrath. So far we have dealt with those who, not having entered into the rest of the
                            heavenly kingdom, do, from their external pride and hypocrisy, lose the joys of loving God
                            during the time of their impenitence. But, when a spirit has tasted of the joys of life, and
                            has walked by the light of the Spirit, yet the soul or flesh, from carelessness, or from
                            willful sin, or from the deliberate shutting of the eyes, involves the spirit again in void
                            and darkness, then is such a case very grievous. Oh, what tender pity ought we not to feel
                            for such souls ! Through ages on ages will their pride, theii vexation of spirit, keep them
                            from again humbling themselves, and from coming to the folc of Christ. During this time
                            their misery wil be tenfold enhanced by their knowledge of the permanence of the very
                            principles they deny, by their knowledge of the joys of the cross But ' a zeal of fire shall
                            devour them; the flames of the love of God (or, of the wrath of God; the sound differs, the
                            ivord is the same), which burn in conscience, shall blast out of ;hem that nature which
                            keeps them from happiness ; and, when they humble themselves, ;hey shall hear the divine
                            words ' thou shalt weep no more : he will be very gracious unto ;hee at the voice of thy
                            cry; when he shall iear it, he will answer thee' (Isaiah xxx. 19). Yet their work will be
                            harder, far greater their agonies in overcoming the nature of sin, than hey would have been
                            had they gone straight through in Time. Dear Shaker, I take the esson home to myself.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stroud, Thomas J." TEIform="persName"/>Thomas J. Stroud, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I want to be forgiving, and to be forgiven" TEIform="index"/>"I want to be forgiving, and to
                            be forgiven."</head><p TEIform="p">When we sing these beautiful words, do they find a response within our hearts ? and do we
                            practically carry this out in our daily intercourse with our fellow-beings ? Are we not all
                            God's creatures ? and have we not oftentimes felt the need of forgiveness ? "To err is
                            human, to forgive divine," is one of the truest of maxims. How soothing were the sweet words
                            of forgiveness, that fell on the ear of the erring one, who in bitterness of spirit cried, "
                            Father, I have sinned against heaven, and before thee, and am no more worthy to be called
                            thy son !" What were those words ? " Bring for+h the best robe, and p\it it on him; put a
                            ring on his hand, and shoes on his feet," etc. Again, we pray : " Forgive us our trespasses
                            as we forgive those who trespass against us." The question arises, How can our trespasses be
                            forgiven, if we withhold this boon from others ? How touching the words of our Saviour,
                            when, in sorest agony, he cried: " Father, forgive them, they know not what they do !" Let
                            us not only sing, " I want to be forgiving," but cultivate a spirit of forgiveness.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Settles, Mary C." TEIform="persName"/>Mary C. Settles, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Original parable, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>An Original Parable, No. 1</head><p TEIform="p">A certain benevolent judge was continually defamed by a wicked and malicious neighbor, who
                            had taken it in head that the good judge was his enemy, and that he intended some day to
                            imprison and torture him during the rest of his mortal life. The judge was anxious to
                            convince the wicked neighbor that he was his friend. That he loved him and wanted to do him
                            good; but the bad neighbor carefully evaded and kept out of his way. Finally the judge
                            called on a poor, honest neighbor to become a mediator, and sent him to the bad neighbor to
                            assure him that he loved him, and greatly desired that he would put away his enmity, which
                            made him so unhappy. You may assure him, said the judge, that love is better than hatred,
                            and that I long to have his soul filled with love, that we may both greatly rejoice
                            together. The judge also sent the bad neighbor divers good gifts by the mediator, to
                            convince him of his benevolent feelings toward him. The mediator plead so eloquently, and
                            set forth his employer's character in such lovmg terms, that lie melted the heart of his
                            neighbor, and being encouraged by the embassador, he confessed to him all the hard sayings
                            and evil actions he had said and done against ;he good judge. Come, said the mediator, go
                            with me and see the truth of my words, and 'eel the love and blessing there is in his
                            friendship. They went and had a most joyful meeting and the atonement (at-one-ment) was
                            complete. Their friendship grew into perfect love and so ever remained. Note.—The view given
                            in this parable, of the doctrine of atonement, supposes God to be unchangeably good, and
                            that the reconciliation is effected by a necessary change in man's understanding and
                            affections. But this is not the orthodox view, that will be given in PARABLE NO. 2. There
                            was a certain stern and inexorable judge, who plumed himself on the inflexibility of his
                            justice, boasting that he let no transgressor escape vindictive punishment. He had a
                            neighbor who hated and maliciously defamed him. The judge had the culprit arrested and found
                            guilty of a penitentiary crime, and sentenced him to imprisonment for life. The judge had a
                            son, a very benevolent young man who thought the sentence was cruel and unjust. He besought
                            the judge to be merciful to the offender and remit his punishment, saying, he believed he
                            could, by reasoning and persuasion, convince him of his error and bring about an atonement.
                            The merciless judge insisted that the convict had violated the eternal principles of
                            justice, and nothing would satisfy its demands but the vindictive punishment of the offender
                            or his substitute. And said he, young man, if you are sincere and interested in saving that
                            wicked wretch from deserved punishment, you may just take his place and suf- fer the full
                            penalty of law in his room and stead. So that vindictive justice is satisfied, I care not
                            who pays the penalty. The humane, kind-hearted young man replied : Well I am sure that I am
                            in a condition which enables me to bear the punishment much better than my poor offending
                            neighbor, and if you cannot show mercy nor forgive, you may punish me and let him go free.
                            This blind judge could not see that eternal justice would be more violated by punishing the
                            innocent and letting the guilty go free, than to pardon the guilty and let him go free
                            without punishing the innocent; therefore he accepted the good young man's offer, threw him
                            into prison and made him suffer the full penalty of the bad man's sentence. Orthodoxy says
                            the son was killed, sent to hell, staid three days and was then let off and restored to
                            life. Reader, which of these judges do you like best ?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pelham, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. Pelham</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">Good Friends of The Shaker : Look out for the pamphlet soon to be issued, from the pen of J.
                            M.Peebles, entitled: •'Spiritualism. Shakerism and Free Religion,—which ?" There will be
                            hundreds of copies ordered in advance. We want ten. Who feels interested in the approaching
                            centennial anniversary of Shakerism in America ? What do you suggest as a fitting
                            testimonial? How shall the 6th of August 1874 be celebrated ? *</p></div2><pb n="22" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit of intolerance" TEIform="index"/>(From the Mirror of Typography.) The Spirit of
                            Intolerance</head><p TEIform="p">It is a common error to believe that intolerance was abolished when the feudal system was
                            swept away or crushed by the invective of a Calvin, a Luther, or a Knox. It exists at the
                            present time with as much force, and is as practical in its results, as when the bold baron
                            rode forth with his armed retainers to levy and slay with all the gran ferocity of the
                            twelfth and thirteenth centuries; is just as strong as when Rogers, and Ridley, andCranmer,
                            sung their hymns of praise amid the blazing pile and the hootings of their persecutors, or
                            when Salem judges sent innocent women to the stake. The intolerant baron lives still; he is
                            not mounted upon a barbed steed or clad with steel, nor does he hold the lance ready to
                            enforce his demands; his charger is a "hobby," his armor respectability, and his lance the
                            tongue, the pen, or the purse. Unlike his prototype of the twelfth century, the feudal chief
                            of the nineteenth urges on his retainers from behind the barriers of the journal, or the
                            statute book, instead of leading them on in person and showing a courageous example. The
                            same judges, in spirit, that condemned reformers and witches to the stake, still breathe in
                            our midst. Filled with wise saws and armed with glib tongues, they prate of civilization,
                            free speech, free press, and kindred blessings; declare with emphasis that they love
                            mankind, that is, those that love them, and believe as they believe. Precepts so harmonizing
                            and tolerant are scattered broadcast, yet the authors, by their own lives, belie the words
                            they utter. Intolerance is part of tho» human system, as it is also an indication of
                            strength. It drove the Huguenots from France, and the Puritans from England, as did the same
                            elements drive the Quakers from Massachusetts and the Mormons to the desert of Utah. The
                            same story is repeated over and over again through history, sacred and profane, and is being
                            and will be repeated while the human race exists. The strong are born to criifh the weak,
                            unless the growth of the latter be so rapid as to defy the efforts of the former. Keep
                            theology out of the Constitution of the U. S., or this "Spirit of Intolerance" will throw
                            off its mask, give the Constitution a sectarian name, and wage war on those who will not bow
                            down to it. *</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Community of intellect" TEIform="index"/>Community of Intellect</head><p TEIform="p">Come down all ye high, and ye lofty in Mind, And mingle with kindred of lower pretense ; Give
                            each one a share of your wealth, more red ed. And serve each a banquet of love and good
                            sense. Then reach down in mercy, and lift up the lowly, And cause them to feel that you love
                            them indeed : Your mental refreshments, then loving and holy, Will prove a sweet season,
                            from vile passions freed, Then dwell altogether, and mingle your talents, By blessing each
                            other, and each being blest; No one is found wanting when weighed in the balance For each,
                            of this heavenly food is possessed. Then here is the Sisterly, Brotherly kindred— Community
                            holy, that Heaven will own ; The heights and the depths are in harmony blended, Cemented by
                            love, to the heavenly throne.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Beals, Isaac" TEIform="persName"/>Isaac Beals, U. Village, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Practical and the beautiful" TEIform="index"/>The Practical and the Beautiful</head><p TEIform="p">The Divine creations and their attending laws are all in harmony with each other. This is a
                            necessary corollary from the fact of the existence of the Supreme and Infinite Creator. The
                            Infinite must be in harmony with himself. There can be no infinitely disturbing cause.
                            Whatever apparent discord there is, therefore, can be so only to the finite mind. The
                            All-Wise and All-Good is— " From seemingevil still educing good, And better thence again,
                            and better still, In infinite progression.'1 As viewed by the finite mind, there are in-
                            Inite degrees of ascending life. The student of Nature has more than a glimpse of this truth
                            wherever his observations extend. All degrees of life are correlated, having a necessary
                            conj nection with each other, though this connection, in many instances, may not be
                            perceived ay some. There is the same ascending series m human life, all the subjects of
                            which being correlated, so that the apostolic injunction, " Let the strong bear the
                            infirmities of the weak," is of perpetually binding authority. This is in force not only in
                            the Church of | Christ, where the law of love reigns supreme, but wherever human
                            intelligences exist. It aas reference not only to external needs, but also to internal
                            wants. There is an obligation resting upon the entire community to care for all its members,
                            in respect to the means of subsistence, and the development and constant growth of all their
                            God-given faculties. " My Father works hitherto, and I work," was the language of Him who
                            had a clear comprehension of this Divine law. There is the same correlation between all the
                            faculties of the human being; and the law | of general regard that is in force throughout
                            the Universe is binding here. As in the human race nations and individuals are in different
                            stages of advancement, so in the individual man the faculties are not equally developed at
                            once. Often a few sway the whole man, the others being so feeble as to manifest themselves
                            in hardly the slightest degree. The Divine law respecting the latter is, not to neglect but
                            to cultivate them. Though they may appear as fallow ground, yet that is to be broken up,
                            exposed to the air and rains of heaven, and thus be able to bear fruit from seed sown. There
                            are many persons who possess a strong sense of moral obligation ; are strictly conscientious
                            in the performance of whatever, in their regard, devolves upon them as duty, whether to
                            their fellow beings or to the Supreme Being; but from a lack of growth in the faculty of The
                            Beautiful, they do not experience the enjoyment which another does who feels equally the
                            force of moral obligation, and has, at the same time, an ardent love of The Beautiful. To
                            the latter there is a beauty in moral actions; love, as displayed in be- nevolence and in a
                            tender regard for the rights and interests of others, is beautiful; purity is a beautiful
                            condition of both soul and body; regularity, whether in external or internal things, is
                            beautiful. "0, how I love thy law! " he exclaims as he contemplates the All-Beautiful,
                            because he sees it as a golden chain extending throughout all worlds and every species of
                            existence in them, uniting each to the other in one Universe of beauty and glory. To him
                            there is great beauty in harmony, mental and moral as well as musical; in a consistent life
                            of self-denial for the sake of a greater good, and in that symmetrical character which is
                            the result of cultivation of every faculty bestowed upon man. He loves to contemplate the
                            unnumbered worlds in the vast expanse, their relations to each other, and their various
                            movements under the guidance of Sure-Directing Force. Earth's scenery, which presents to his
                            view so grand a variety of hill and dale, lake and river, forest and cultured field, is a
                            source of perpetual charm; and old ocean,— " That glorious mirror where the Almighty's form
                            Glasses itself in tempest,'1 is no less a cause of admiration. He also takes pleasure in
                            viewing the numerous products of earth, whether in the mineral, vege- table or animal
                            realms, as well as in the higher productions of human skill, displayed either in mechanics,
                            in the finer arts, or in science and literature. All these have a prac- tical bearing upon
                            his life, for they serve to fashion his soul to higher conditions, to inspire him with
                            better thoughts, and to urge him on to nobler actions. In the mind of the person in whom the
                            faculties of Moral Obligation and Love of The Beautiful are equally developed, there is no
                            question whether one should be ignored for the sake of the other. They are equally cherished
                            and cultivated, yet, like every other faculty, under the guidance of enlightened reason. For
                            they give strength to each other. Moral Power has more completeness conjoined to the other
                            fully developed, and Love of Beauty has a far wider field of action in association with
                            Moral Force. This is in accordance with the general law that the greater the strength of
                            each faculty, the greater the strength of all combined. "A three-fold cord is not easily
                            broken," much more, a manyfold one. But the one who is aiming at the highest life must, in
                            all things, seek his gratification in that which is highest in its degree. That which has m
                            itself the highest use possesses the greatest beauty. The curve is called one of the lines
                            of beauty; but who that is thoroughly imbued with the Spirit of Christ, can view with
                            satisfaction the death-bearing bomb-shell on its way for the destruction of human life or
                            the useful and beautiful works of man, though the curve which it describes may be of
                            geometrical exactness ? Two armies in battle array, with their divisions, battalions and
                            regiments, may present a scene of wonderful activity and great regularity of movement, in
                            their various marches and countermarches. Many have journeyed miles to view such a sight,
                            but is there any enjoyment to the Christian in its contemplation ? Even the wonderful beauty
                            of earth's scenery must be viewed under favorable circumstances to give satisfaction. There
                            is said to be remarkable beauty and sublimity in the vicinity of the Yellowstone river, in
                            Montana, but Everts, in the thrilling description he gives of his " Thirty-seven days
                            peril," recently undergone there, says: " Seen under favorable I circumstances, this
                            assemblage of grandeur, | beauty and novelty would have been transporting; but jaded with
                            travel, famishing with hunger, and distressed with anxiety, I was in no humor for ecstasy.
                            My tastes were subdued and chastened by the perils which en- vironed me." Wesley once made
                            the remark that " it was a pity the devil should have all the best music;" and some
                            religious people have undertaken to convert a portion of what has been used in his service
                            to sacred purposes. But however sweet its melody and lively its notes, there 22 <pb n="23" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE 8HA.KER. always appears an incongruity in transferring the music which has
                            been used for ages in singing the praises of Mars and Bacchus, to the service of Him whow as
                            in character the exact reverse of those divinities. The fountains of melody are
                            inexhaustible. Let the faculty of music be enlarged and improved by thorough cultivation;
                            let the soul be open to all the highest inspirations, and there will be no lack, in the
                            Church of Christ, of beautiful music, with its correspondingly beautiful poetry, without
                            borrowing anything used in the worship of the deities of the past, however inspiriting it
                            may have been to their "worshipers. The shrill sounds of the clarion, the more melodious
                            tones of the bugle, together with other other instruments used to urge men on to the deadly
                            conflict, may be allowed to remain where they properly belong; yet there are and still will
                            be instruments discoursing the sweetest music that may aid the vocal powers in their effort
                            to chant celestial praises. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, W. H." TEIform="persName"/>W. H. Bussell</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian patience" TEIform="index"/>Christian Patience</head><p TEIform="p">It is impossible, and indeed altogether undesirable, considering the wickedness of the world,
                            that individual Christians should have no enemies. This will be especially the case with
                            those who possess force of character, and feel strongly the truths entrusted to them. The
                            fearless advocacy of right, the zealous persistence in duty, will inevitably produce
                            alongside of much good report, its reward of slanderous evil report. Now it is very desir-
                            able that the Christian should be aware of this, and should know how to meet such circum-
                            stances. The highest state of mind that, in this respect, we can attain to is to feel this :
                            " It matters not at all what envious and cunning individuals may say or do against me. I am
                            conscious of my own rectitude. God sees my heart, and gives me my reward. I feel for those
                            poor persons who try to injure me, nothing but love and pity: how far are they from those
                            gentle feelings of humility and goodness with which I am blest! However they may injure my
                            external reputation, they cannot take from me my internal struggles or the victories I have
                            gained over sin. If any opportunity occurs, I will be very tender to those spreaders of evil
                            reports ; I will heap on their hearts the burning fires of love." When a soul can feel thus,
                            and can act on this principle, it has progressed far. But such is the weakness of human
                            nature that, however well intentioned souls may be, few can help feeling wounded by
                            misrepresentation. But any one possessed of ordinary intelligence and power of will can
                            avoid crying out when hurt, however keen the wound. Nothing will give greater satisfaction
                            to a malicious enemy than to see his malice take effect; and it is a point of prudence, if
                            of nothing higher, to foil malice by patient self-restraint. A soul derives satis faction
                            from self-respect, and it is impossible to feel self-respect if we give wajr to expressions
                            of annoyance at slander, or if we retaliate on the slanderers in any other way than by
                            blessing. But some will say, especially those whose years have not given them experience,
                            that it is impossible to enjoy life, if all their external surroundings are embittered by
                            the malice of enemies, and if they feel in the minds of those about them distrust and want
                            of appreciation. This at once shows a want of deep spirituality. Until a soul feels that
                            real substantial happiness consists only in conquest of the nature of sin, it cannot feel
                            that calm certainty for itself in which alone subsists that peace which passeth
                            understanding. Moreover, it is certain that, in practical life, a steady and zealous
                            pursuance of duty will produce its inevitable consequence of confidence in the minds of
                            those who are really worthy of our esteem. What a satisfaction it is to look back on the
                            difficulties we have lovingly struggled through ! Well-doing is a rock on which the feeble
                            bark of slander will inevitably go to pieces. But the Christian has no right to any enemies
                            except those produced by adherence to Christ principles. The Christian cannot have personal
                            enemies. He hates no one, his heart is full of love; therefore his foes are those only who
                            hate not him, but the life he lives, the truths he advocates; and who would hate that life
                            and those truths in "any one? Let us hunger for such enemies, since, alas ! there must be
                            wicked people in the world ; and since it is better for us that they hate us than that they
                            love us. Again : in the progress of our travail, before the soul has gained a thorough
                            knowledge of itself, the criticisms of enemies are very useful. An enemy discovers a fault
                            of character much more quickly than a friend, and the patient laborer in the overcoming
                            field will gladly note hostile observations, and thus turn to good account malicious shafts.
                            This will be very bitter to the old man in us, yet there cannot be a better exercise : for,
                            the soul will find, when it can patiently listen to adverse words, and can draw therefrom
                            truths pregnant with salvation, that it will possess a divine patience that nothing can
                            shake.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ervin, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna Ervin, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes on Plato" TEIform="index"/>Notes on Plato</head><p TEIform="p">Plato was born B. C. 429 years; and died B. C. 348. His mother, Perictione, was a de-
                            scendant of Solon ; and his father, Aristo, was of an eminent family. He studied eight years
                            with Socrates, and was the youngest of the Senate at the time of Socrates' arraignment; but
                            could do nothing to save his life. Upon the death of Socrates he fled, with others of his
                            disciples, to Italy; where he gave himself to the discipline of Pythagoras, chiefly to the
                            continence, chastity, and knowledge of nature possessed by that school. In his school he
                            thought it all important to accustom j'outh to "take delight in good things; otherwise plea-
                            sures were the bait of evil." " Education should be conducted with a serene sweetness, never
                            by force or violence." His studies did not sour his temper, nor mar his interest in mankind.
                            His ordinary conversation was extremely winning. He lived single, yet soberfy and chastily;
                            temperately; abstaining almost entirely from animal food. He slept alone, and disapproved
                            very much the opposite manner. Of his prudence, patience, moderation, magnanimity and other
                            virtues, all bear good record. He was wont to say: " See to it, youths, that you employ your
                            idle hours usefully. Prefer labor before idleness, unless you esteem rust above brightness."
                            Being asked how long he meant to be a scholar, he replied: "As long as I am not ashamed of
                            growing better and wiser." Being asked what difference there was between a learned man and
                            one unlearned, he replied : " The same as betwixt a physician and a patient." Hearing that
                            some one spoke ill of him, he answered : " No matter, I shall live so that none shall
                            believe him." He owed no man anything. He died on his 81st birthday, of old age, which
                            Seneca ascribes to his temperance and diligence. In his ideal republic he afforded the same
                            chances to women as to men to become its rulers, thus representing the whole interest.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. Webster</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life in God" TEIform="index"/>Life in God</head><p TEIform="p">The English translators of St. John the Evangelist, in the first verse, according to the
                            version of an eminent linguist, have made a wonderful mistake; the Greek word "Logus" has
                            two significations, "mind" and "word." Thomas Jefferson says, the translators by selecting "
                            word " instead of "mind," as the representative of the word Logus, have entirely destroyed
                            the meaning, and made nonsense of the evangelist's context. In accepting Jefferson's
                            translation we have: " In the beginning was Mind or Intelligence, and mind was with God, and
                            mind was God." In thus setting forth the beginning of the Gospel, or Thesis of St. John, we
                            restore the verse to common sense, reason and truth ; for mind must precede word, either
                            spoken or written, as word is only an emanation, whether of the Eternal or finite mind. A
                            right translation might have saved volumes, besides a world of trouble to commentators, and
                            much vexation to the common readers of the sacred volume It would require a Nicene Council
                            to make the Supreme out of a word; and one of more potency, to change the virgin Mary into
                            the mother of God; and the still more potent Ecumenical Council to elaborate the old
                            corpulent Italian into the immaculate Jehovah ! Tn the very penning of these awful
                            blasphemies, we feel a degree of compunction, as having taken the most sacred name of the
                            Eternal in vain. However deplorable and mortifying these black pictures may be to the
                            truthful and pure in heart, the nineteenth century may be in labor and travail, and bring
                            forth a monster, of which the world has no conception, in terrible blackness and deformity !
                            Catholicism may be called to restore the " Holy See " to the government of the secular and
                            religious world; a bloody tragedy may ensue, of which the Crusades to the " Holy Land", are
                            as a mere shadow ! The civilized world may yet learn to its great consternation, that
                            Catholicism is neither dead, nor dying; but lying in an assumed condition, of which we have
                            a specimen in a certain animal of the west, which can die, at will, or pleasure, and again
                            become reanimated, with the same ease and facility ! ! 23 <pb n="24" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHA.KEH.
                            But leaving these hints for future consideration, we find ourselves involved in a labyrinth
                            of theological mysteries ; according to modern sectaries, religion seems to have deserted
                            the souls of men and women, and taken up its abode in Ecclesiastical Mysteries. To evolve,
                            or disentangle and straighten out these knots of their divinity, has engaged the best minds
                            of reformed Catholicism for ages, and called forth many cart-loads of reformed divinity;
                            writer after writer has puzzled his brains, and brought forth gas only; for the whole
                            anti-christian scheme of salvation by proxy is a myth, an oriental speculation of the
                            Brahmins. If any of our readers are yet in doubts, may we ask them to procure the "
                            Bhagvat-Geeta," or the " Dialogues of Kreeshna and Arjoon," translated by the English clerk,
                            Charles Wilkins, of the East India commission; in that sacred volume he will find the whole
                            of the mysteries pertaining to the secular godhead, and many more strange ideas, in
                            conjunction with the triune divinity and incarnation. Also, the corroborative testimony of
                            the Governor General, Warren Hastings, as to the truth of the translation, and the identity
                            of Hindoo mythology and Catholicism. Truth has no place in this matchless chaos of
                            absurdities: still, men are preaching. The disciples of Luther and Calvin, and a host of
                            others, after a collegiate education, study their speculative theology, or Brahminism, under
                            some of their renowned Drs. of divinity, and being duly ordained, according to creed, go
                            forth to teach, and spread paganism through the land; and the poor heathen, as we call them,
                            have to be tortured with this miserable, speculative, rejuvenated sectarian paganism ! How
                            long, before rational men and women will learn, that Salvation is a growth of righteousness
                            in the human soul ? and that this growth in the divine nature, is to con- tinue to the
                            endless ages of eternity ? The Saviour never taught any other mode of salva- tion; he said
                            nothing about salvation by proxy; nothing of "paying the debt in our law, room and stead;"
                            but redemption from a sinful nature was to supervene by a life of self-denial and the cross
                            ; a daily dying to the propensities of a carnal animal nature, by following the Captain of
                            our salvation in the regeneration. In his parable he said, " I am the vine, ye are the
                            branches, my Father is the husbandman ;" thus to grow up in God, and become one with him, in
                            the Divine nature, was the design and intent of the Saviour's mission. This buying and
                            selling salvation on hypothetical capital, seems too much like speculation, or gambling in
                            matters of eternal interest. 0 the folly of a deluded sectarian world ! "The blind leading
                            the blind;" and all in the ditch of ignorance, folly, and superstition :—Paganism reigning
                            triumphant in a supposed Ghristian land; and fanaticism spending millions of money, and much
                            precious time, and many valuable lives; and al for what ? Simply to convert the Orienta'
                            Nations to their own Religion, of more than four thousand years' prevalence; aged anc
                            *rey-headed, long before its advent on the shores of Europe. But there is still hope; the
                            Saviour's Light s again burning and shining, and the nations are turning to its bright
                            illuminations ! Paganism is destined to have an end, and the true God and his Gospel will be
                            known; the gospel will spread to the uttermost parts of the earth; and the heaATenly Father
                            and Mother will be honored and glorified by the redemption of their prodigal children; all
                            in ;heir appointed time.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Redmon, William N." TEIform="persName"/>Wm. N. Redmon Union Village, 0., Dec. 2nd 1871.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Guardian angels" TEIform="index"/>Guardian Angels</head><p TEIform="p">The Shakers do not claim that it is their apecial Mission to take cave of Orphans, although
                            it is said that their conditions in life, and especially those of the Sisterhood, are well
                            adapted to the charge of those little sufferers of earth. O were our eyes unsealed, Glad
                            secrets to descry, What shining hosts would be revealed, Divinely hovering nigh. Bright
                            Angels clothed with love, True Ministers of grace, In hovering circles gently move, To guide
                            the erring race. Their gentle wings expand In truth it may be said; ' The lowliest saint, is
                            rainbow spanned, The child is Angel led. And woman also shows She can be Angel too; The
                            gentle mind reflects on those, Our dim eyes may not view. The garland that she weaves, Would
                            grace the Savior's brow; 'Tis fragrant as the perfumed leaves, That by life's river grow. In
                            dungeons, she is day; In sickness, solace mild; To the maimed, a staff; to the blind, a ray;
                            She soothes the lonely child. And never doth she send More golden rays abroad, Than when she
                            shines the Orphan's friend, And leads the child to God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Benner, Andrew" TEIform="persName"/>Andrew Benner, Shirley. Mass</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Items of Interest</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Debatable land" TEIform="index"/>Debatable land
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"The Debatable Land,'1 by R. D. Owen, is a most remarkable work on Spiritualism. Those
                                who are interested in the progress of Spiritualism will not fail of its perusal. The
                                address to the Clergy is a valuable exhortation to thinking humanity. But let no one
                                read who will not understand, or who fears being persuaded. Carleton, New York, is the
                                publisher. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A man proves himself fit to go higher..." TEIform="index"/>A man proves himself fit to go higher...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A man proves himself fit to go higher, who shows that he is faithful where he is. A man
                                that will not do well in his present place because he longs to be higher, is fit neither
                                to be where he is, nor yet above it. " </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life of Victoria C. Woodhull" TEIform="index"/>Life of Victoria C. Woodhull
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tilton, Theodore" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Life of Victoria C. Woodhull " has been sent us; were it not from the pen of a nature's
                                nobleman— Theodore Tilton—we would incline to the belief that its subject was a myth of
                                the 19th century. Price 10 cents. </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="As long as men continue to worship an exclusively masculine God..." TEIform="index"/>As long as men continue to worship an exclusively masculine God...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> As long as men continue to worship an exclusively masculine God, they will never
                                practically acknowledge the equality of woman. Let women teach their children to pray
                                Mother God, and there will soon be a change in the current of public opinion. Go to the
                                fountain head, it you would purify the stream. The world has inherited its theology from
                                the times when women were considered as the servants or slaves of men—when animal force
                                was predominant, and men's highest conception of God was that of a being capable of
                                executing justice, by force. The higher element of Love they had not realized as a
                                moving power in the Godhead, and hence had not recognized this feminine element in their
                                worship. How long will enlightened women continue virtually to acknowledge their
                                inferiority, by continuing to ignore the representation of their sex in the Godhead? Is
                                this the Nineteenth century, and are the people awake? Who are the heathens to-day?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName TEIform="persName">Moonly Voice</persName>Moonly Voice</byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Among our exchanges, we have found none more radical..." TEIform="index"/>Among our exchanges, we have found none more radical...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Among our exchanges, we have found none more radical on the vital questions of to-day ;
                                none more willing to stand by and build up unpopular, but living truths ; none that are
                                willing to do more good to others than is done to it, than the neatly printed and ably
                                edited ''Crucible" of Baltimore, Md. </p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our Canadian subscribers must send postage..." TEIform="index"/>Our Canadian subscribers must send postage...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Our Canadian subscribers must send postage ; we are required to prepay. </p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One of the happy 'signs of the times'..." TEIform="index"/>One of the happy 'signs of the times'...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> One of the happy " signs of the times'' maybe eagerly observed by every true reformer,
                                in an article on " Husbands and Wives" in "The Herald of Health " for Feb. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Communism" TEIform="index"/>Communism
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Communism.—Christian communism declares, "All that is mine is thine.''
                                        Infidel communism, on the contrary, " All that.is thine is mine."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="World's Crisis" TEIform="index"/>World's Crisis</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christians who wish to retain the spirituality of their religion..." TEIform="index"/>Christians who wish to retain the spirituality of their religion...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Christians who wish to retain the spirituality of their religion, should be very careful
                                how they mingle with the world. He who is pleased with the company of ungodly men, no
                                matter how witty or learned, is either himself one with them, or is drinking into their
                                spirit.— World's Crisis. </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Once virtue stood before knowledge..." TEIform="index"/>Once virtue stood before knowledge...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Once virtue stood before knowledge, in the estimation of the Apostle, for he exhorted to
                                add knowledge thereto. If he lived now, he would, doubtless, advise to add to knowledge
                                virtue.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. Myrick</byline></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bound copies of the first volume of The Shaker..." TEIform="index"/>Bound copies of the first volume of The Shaker...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Bound copies of the first volume of The Shaker, may be obtained by. application to the
                                Resident Editor. Price, Two Dollars ; extra binding, Three Dollars; unbound, 75 cents.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Item for meat eaters..." TEIform="index"/>Item for meat eaters...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Item for meat eaters: An old ox, having done valuable service in one of the Shaker
                                families, was fatted, and brought to the shambles. Walking up to the ring without
                                resistance, he stood, and as if conscious of his past efforts and the impending blow,
                                actually shed tears, until stunned by the butcher! We vouch for this. * </p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="On page 20..." TEIform="index"/>On page 20...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> On page 20, present number, top of third column may be observed, a sentence—"Ye
                                generation of vipers''—very commonly attributed to Jesus. Our reading of this in Matt.
                                3, 7, makes John the Baptist author of this harsh saying. "Search the Scriptures." *
                            </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological Annual" TEIform="index"/>The Phrenological Annual</head><p TEIform="p"> is out. Among other matters, we find a purported portrait of Ann Lee, together with our
                                letter to S. R. Wells. Very few Shakers coincide with the Spirit Artist; but it is very
                                interesting to observe what artists attempt, and phrenologists determine from such
                                attempts.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Members of society" TEIform="index"/>MEMBERS OF SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p">Appointed to answer Correspo?ulerits, among whom are the Board of Editors. Elder F. W. Evans.
                            Mt. Lebanon, Columbia Co., N. Y. " Issachar Bates. Shakers, N. Y. " Calvin G. Reed, Mt.
                            Morris, Livingston Co., N. Y. " Simon Mabee, West Pittsfield, Mass. " Stoughton Kellogg,
                            Thompsonville, Conn., Shakers. " Albert Battles, Tyringhani, Berkshire Co., Mass. " Wm.
                            Leonard. Aver, Mass.. Shakers. " Jonas Nutting, Shirley Village, Middlesex Co., Mass. "
                            Benj. H. Smith, Shaker Village, Merrimack Co., N. H. " Henry Cummings. Enfield, Grafton Co.,
                            N. H. " John B. Vance, Alfred, Shakers, York Co., Me. " Alonzo Gilman. West Gloucester,
                            Cumberland Co., Me., Shakers. " Chas. Clapp, Union Village, Warren Co., O., Shakers. " Ezra
                            Sherman, Preston, Hamilton Co.,* Ohio, Shakers. " Stephen Ball, Dayton, Shakers, Ohio. "
                            Jacob Kul]), Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co., Ky. " J. R. Eades, South Union, Logan Co., Ky. " J.
                            S. Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio, Shakers. 24</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>