<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2506" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">30</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">25</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><date value="18950601" TEIform="date">June 1895</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">121-146</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="25" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
JUNE.
THE
MANIFESTO
PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES.
VOL. XXV.
'' Cast tht bread upon the waters ; for thou shalt find it after many oats."
Ecch XI: i.
East Canterbury, N. H.
1895.
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
CONTENTS.
Special Providences,
June,.....
God is Everywhere,
Social Improvement,
Inspiration,       Among the Rosicrueians,
Letter,Calvin G. Reed,
"     ,Sarah F. Wilson,
Our Mission,      Faith,.....
Faithful in Duty,    Music,Heavenly Pathway,
Notes About Home,
Tribute,Martha Crooker,
Exchanges,        Angels' Foot-Prints,   Joseph of Arimathea,
Spelling Kitten,
So much of the friction, Deaths,
Books & Papers,
THE MANIFESTO.
Page.
121
12-2
123
124
125
128
130
131
132
135
136
142
143
146
144
RELIABLE MEN to sell
our choice and complete
line of Nursery Stock.
'Highest salary and commission paid weekly, paying permanent position
guaranteed and success assured to good men.
Special inducements to beginners, experience
not necessary. Exclusive territory and your
own choice of same given.   Do not delay.
 ALLEN nursery CO.
ROCHESTER, N. Y.
POUR
By Pressing the Lid.
Tea and Cofft e Pots that pour bv the lid without lifting or tipping      bimple bcumd belief.
Prac ti( al md artistic     fee ml for p unphlc t
THE ASBURY=PAINE MFG. CO., Phila., Pa.
This is a good thingEd.
Should have the beautiful 36-pagre Monthly
= ILLUSTRATED HOME JOUXUrAXi =
50 otB. a year.   Sample free.   Agents wanted.
thobkas a. zrswasAir ft sow.
CHICAGO, ILL.
SWEATS.TRADE IUkks:
COPYRIGHTS.
CAN I OBTAIN A PATENT? Fora
prompt answer and an honest opinion, write to
MUNN fc CO., who have had nearly fifty years'
experience in the patent business. Communications strictly confidential. A Handbook of Information concerning Patents and how to obtain them sent free. Also a catalogue of mechanical and scientific books sent free.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice in the Scientific American, and
thus are brought widely before the public without cost to the inventor. This splendid paper,
issued weekly, elegantly illustrated, has by far the
largest circulation of any scientific work in tha
world.   S>3 a year.   Sample copies sent free.
Building Edition, monthly, $2.50 a year. Single
copies, 25 cents. Every number contains beautiful plates, in colors, and photographs of new
houses, with plans, enabling builders to show the
latest designs and secure contracts.  Address
MUNN & CO., New York, 3til Broadway.
WANTED!
Agent to sell our new hook, Dictionary of
United State*- History, by Prof. J. Franklin Jameson. Needed by every: teacher, pupil, and family; indorsed. Agents selling fifty books per week. Successful agents will
be made general agents.   Big: par.
PURITAN PUBLISHING CO., Boston. Mass.
THE SHAKER covenant.
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS    OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION    AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
the same time, afford instruction to all  inquiring minds.    Price 5 cts. each,  postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
Apply to--><pb n="121" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Special providences" TEIform="index"/>SPECIAL PROVIDENCES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>By Hamilton DeGraw.</byline><p TEIform="p">IN dealing with this subject we will apparently be treading on forbidden ground. 1 he
                            infinite spirit does not turn to right or left to favor finite existences. Admitting the
                            truth of the foregoing statement, we are sure that the divine Spirit gives to its children
                            according to their needs, and according to their merits. When in the process of human
                            evolution conditions arise that require a special line of action, instrumentalities arise to
                            meet the demand and the current of events is turned from the course that it had been
                            pursuing. To illustrate;In the upheavals and revolutions that have changed the destiny of
                            nations, individuals have appeared on the scene as prominent actors who before were in
                            obscurity and would have so remained had not the necessity arisen for the use of those
                            mental and spiritual faculties that they possessed. Abraham Lincoln illustrates this
                            principle. He became the heritage of our whole country regardless of party. Reared in
                            obscurity nevertheless his life training and discipline supplementing his inherent faculties
                            fitted him for the ordeal that he was called to pass through in after years. The conditions
                            of human society then existing called for those special faculties to serve his nation and
                            they moved to the front. The question is asked, "Does divine Providence favor some more than
                            others?" We would say that while those laws are unchangeable he who complies with them ;
                            moves in concord and attunes his life in harmony with the Divine, receives special blessings
                            that the violators of those laws fail to receive. JUNE, <pb n="122" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 122 THE
                            MANIFESTO. The old adage "God helps those who help themselves," is true, and those who fail
                            to make exertion in their own behalf do not receive the Divine aid. Without transcending the
                            boundaries of the immutable, unchangeable Infinite, the revelation that the law of worth is
                            one of the Divine attributes, and that merit alone will insure special blessings needs to be
                            understood. "The prayer of the righteous availeth much." If there were no rewards of merit
                            to be given then the efforts of human life for advancement would be useless. The lazy and
                            shiftless, especially in a spiritual sense, would be on equal footing with the industrious;
                            but it is not so, "Whatsoever a man soweth that shall he also reap." By moving in the
                            current of those spiritual forces the special benefits accrue that those who are
                            side-tracked lose. Every intelligent person, who thinks in the line of intellectual and
                            spiritual growth, has at times experienced a necessity for an especial manifestation of
                            providential aid in his behalf and although granted according to a fixed law of the
                            spiritual world, yet to the casual observer, viewing the circumstance from an external
                            position it seems like a changing of Divine law to suit the whims of mortality; but not so.
                            The supplicant realizing his need enters into a labor to bring his spirit into perfect
                            accord with the Divine; and the very fact of its wrestling with the powers of good makes a
                            realization of his desires possible. In the spiritual world there is no such thing as
                            chicanery or sophistry. Each individual must stand for just what he is, and receive just
                            what he has earned and no more. AVhatever has been gained of a spiritual treasure will be an
                            inheritance more lasting than the rock of ages, for it will never fade away neither can it
                            be wrested from him. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="June" TEIform="index"/>JUNE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>By Martha J. Anderson.</byline><p TEIform="p">Oh, now will the queen of summer reign Embowered in bloom of the roses fair, Whose delicate
                            fragrance and shadings rare Will not to our senses plead in vain : She calleth the dews and
                            gentle rain, And, waving the wand of her kindly care Rich beauty blossometh everywhere. O'er
                            meadow and hill, and field of grain, What magical changes unfold to view; The grasses plume
                            and the seed cups fill, And the woodland copse so lone and still Expands in richness of
                            foliage new. 'Tis blessed to trust that the seasons will Each in their turn God's love
                            fulfill. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="123" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God is everywhere" TEIform="index"/>GOD IS EVERYWHERE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/>By Lucy S. Bowers.</byline><p TEIform="p">Beneath the sod what wondrous treasures lie! What substances of beauty and delight! And how
                            man seeks them with his mind and might. Deep beds of gems, so pleasing to the eye ; Diamonds
                            whose brilliance no glitter can outvie, And rubies glowing with a crimson light; Emeralds
                            dipped in spring's new verdure bright, And sapphires decked with drapery of the sky, The
                            topaz blazoned with the golden gleam ; And like the blushes of the morning beam Behold the
                            purple amethyst so fair, Who tinctured this deep hidden dust? who wrought The lucid drop?
                            'Twas God. His power and thought Are truly manifested everywhere. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Social improvement" TEIform="index"/>SOCIAL IMPROVEMENT. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">THE Social Improvement Society of the North family held its regular meeting Wednesday
                            evening, April 10th, which was rendered very interesting by reason of the discussion of the
                            vital question,Will there be a new order in society and if so will the same be communistic
                            .or co-operative? Elder Daniel Offord led the discussion by an able paper in which he held
                            that the long pent up and enslaved powers of mind and soul will of absolute necessity break
                            the fetters that have for so long held them in bondage. The dial of time plainly indicates
                            to all discerning minds that the hour has already struck and a new order of society is being
                            formed. He believes that the higher or celibate order in the coming social regime will be
                            communistic, and the generative order co-operative. Sister Catherine Allen read a paper
                            treating of the same subject in which she claimed that all the movements of the day, for
                            evil as well as for good clearly indicate that in the near future there will be a new order
                            in society. The wide-spread social and industrial troubles, the increasing misery of the
                            masses resulting from the concentration of wealth in the hands of the few are creating the
                            upheavals and overturnings which are shaking our present civilization to its very center.
                            Brother Charles Greaves made a short address on the question under discussion, contending
                            that as land was the seat of wealth, free land would be absolutely essential to any
                            substantial social reform. ' A paper by Brother Ezra J. Stewart advanced the idea that at
                            the close of <pb n="124" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 124 THE MANIFESTO. each century unusual commotion in both
                            business and social circles seemed to be in order and that out of the present movement must
                            accrue communism and co-operation. Brother William Bassett said that in a new social order
                            money would be unnecessary to carry on the business of the world and that this means of
                            commerce would be destroyed. Sister Sarah Burger read a selection on the subject from The
                            Manifesto. The writer was Robert Stevens. Brother Charles J. MacLaughlin followed with a
                            brief address pointing to the fact that biblical prophecy indicates a new heavens and new
                            earth which were about to dawn. Selections were read by Sisters Rosetta Stevens, Lucy
                            Bowers, Julia Lincoln and Mabel Lane touching on the question of social reform. Short
                            original paragraphs were read by all the members of the society. A paper on,Does the press
                            mould public opinion or does public opinion mould the press? by Cora C. Vinneo. The question
                            selected for discussion at the next monthly meeting was, How would a union of Church and
                            state affect our national liberties? The speaking was interspersed with beautiful hymns. The
                            sixth of next August is selected as the date to commemorate the life and work of the founder
                            of the Order of Believers, Mother Ann Lee.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inspiration" TEIform="index"/>INSPIRATION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Theobald, Frank" TEIform="persName"/>By Frank Theobald.</byline><p TEIform="p">OF what use would be a piano without the marvelous touch of a master hand to bring out the
                            sweetness and harmony which it is capable of giving? So is it with the human mind and soul.
                            Unless touched by the inspiring hand of God we would be dead ; it is his Spirit that gives
                            us strength and ability to give to each other our best thoughts, as in the case of all true
                            prophets and sacred writers who, by the influence of the spirit of God, were led to prophecy
                            and write of divine things with a certainty that leaves no room to doubt their supernatural
                            origin. Every thought and word that tends to strengthen our care for each other and for
                            things good and pure, is an inspiration from God ; and all reforms whether in religion,
                            science, art, politics, mechanics, or in any of the various walks of life, if they are in
                            the interest and for the betterment of humanity, the person through whom this work is
                            brought about has received an inspiration from God. We may not all think alike as to the
                            source from which the inspiration comes. For instance we would suppose that all reforms
                            would come through agents especially prepared for the work; mortals whose lives have been
                            filled with good deeds, love to God, and their fellow-men. This is true to <pb n="125" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 125 a certain extent. God works in various channels, and it is
                            not best to judge that of which we are uncertain; but if it is the means of bringing that
                            soul or another to the Christ life, then we can say it is the work of God. I think we should
                            labor for this inspiration, in good fellowship; aspire for an ambition, a purpose in life,
                            by which we can give our best thoughts, words and works, for the good of mankind. We read
                            that the Scriptures are the Word of God, and every thoughtful, intelligent mind would be led
                            to so believe, as they read the sacred writings which have stood the test of time, and are
                            to-day accepted as truth. Jesus was inspired to bring salvation in his time. The inspiration
                            which came through Mother Ann, and her fidelity to.light and truth as revealed to her, gives
                            us the Father and Mother in Christ, as recognized in the natural order of things, and if
                            this union is preserved, in the spirit and teaching of Mother Ann, and the first leaders of
                            our faith, with a kindly regard for the rights and duties of each other, remembering that we
                            are to love our neighbor as ourselves, blessing and prosperity will be our portion. All
                            inspirations which have come from God through man, which have been proved by a practical
                            test, as truth, will forever be accepted as such. The laws of man are changeable, but the
                            laws of God are the same, now and forever. The power for doing good, which has made so many
                            men and women famous, we all have, to a certain degree, and let us use this inspiration for
                            the benefit of all, that God in His goodness, may use us, for His own honor and glory, in
                            whatever way he deems best. Enfield, N. R.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Adventure among the rosicrucians, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>
                            ADVENTURE AMONG THE ROSICRUCIANS, NO 1.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hartmann, Franz" TEIform="persName"/>By Franz Hartmann.</byline><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by William C. Ayer.]
                            (A member of the Theosophical Society, and published in the Society'1 s Magazine.) THE
                            obstacles which arise from the external world are intimately connected with those from the
                            inner world, and can not be separated; because external temptations create inward desires,
                            and inward desires call for external means for gratification. Still, there are many people
                            who do not crave for the illusions of life, but who have not the strength to resist them.
                            Many have a desire to develop spiritually and to gain immortality, but they believe
                            themselves forced by external circumstances, which they dare not resist, to employ their
                            time and energy for the attainment of worthless things, instead of using their strength to
                            dive down into the depths of the soul to search for <pb n="126" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 126 THE MANIFESTO.
                            the priceless pearl of wisdom. Thousands of people have not the moral courage to break loose
                            from social customs, ridiculous habits, and foolish usages, which they inwardly abhor, but
                            to which they nevertheless submit because they are customs and habits to act against which
                            is considered to be a social crime. Thus thousands sacrifice their immortality to the stupid
                            goddess of fashion. Who dares to break loose from the bondage imposed upon him by fashion,
                            and to exchange for it the freedom of eternal life? Who dares to face the calumny and the
                            comtempt of the ignorant, to obtain iu its place the applause of the wise ? Who has the
                            courage to incur the sneers of the imbecile, the ridicule of the ignorant, the laughter of
                            the fool, and gain thereby a light of whose existence those who live in eternal darkness
                            know nothing ? But the vast majority of people drown the voice of reason by the speculating
                            power of the intellect. Rather than have their vanity suffer, they allow the spirit to
                            starve ; rather than be crucified and to resurrect into immortal life, thiy submit to the
                            galling chain; they lose their appreciation of liberty, and, becoming used to their chains,
                            begin to love them and to impose them upon others. I am not a believer in total depravity of
                            the human nature ; I know that man's animal principles, on account of their inherent
                            instinctive efforts for the preservation of their existence, are opposed to the development
                            of his higher principles, because the life of the higher involves the death of the lower ;
                            but I also know that in each human being is contained a power for good, which may be made to
                            develop if the proper conditions are given. There are elements of good and elements of evil
                            in every man, and it depends on ourselves which class we desire to develop. From a
                            cherry-stone nothing can grow but a cherry tree, from a thistle seed nothing else than a
                            thistle ; but man is a constellation of powers in which all kinds of seeds are contained ;
                            you may make him grow to be a hog or a tiger, an angel or a devil, a sage or a fool,
                            according to your own pleasure. The continual rush after more money, more comfort, more
                            pleasure, after we already possess all we require, and which characterizes our present
                            civilization, is not necessarily a sign of greed, viciousness, and moral depravity ; but it
                            is rather caused by the instinctive impulse, inherent in the constitution of man, to reach
                            something kigher and better, which expresses itself on the physical plane. Man intuitively
                            knows that, no matter how rich in money or fame he may be, he has not yet reached a state in
                            which to be contented and to rest; he knows that he must still keep on striving for
                            something, but he does not know what that something is. Not knowing the higher life, he
                            strives for more of those things which the lower life affords, and thus wastes his energies
                            for the attainment of things which are useless to him. Thus we may see a bug or a butterfly
                            falling into a lake, and in its vain efforts to save itself from drowning swimming away from
                            the shore, because it does not know in which direction the means for salvation exist. Thus
                            the curse <pb n="127" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 127 of the world and the root of all evil is
                            ignorance. The curse of man is his ignorance of his essential nature and final destiny, and
                            the efforts of a true system of religion and science should be above ail to remove this
                            ignorance. {To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Elder Henry;--The April Manifesto..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Beloved Elder Henry;--The April Manifesto...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mt. Lebanon, April 1895" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. April, 1895.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Henry ;The April Manifesto for 1895 has quite a sprinkling of conflicting
                                opinions relating to Florida. As every one has an opinion, whether true or false, in
                                regard to this enterprise, which is expressed, and which is being promulgated through
                                some one of the circulating media of communication, I concluded to give expression to my
                                source of knowledge, sincerely hoping not to offend even the least. On the evening of
                                Feb. 7th 1895, having finished writing my journal of the day's proceedings, also some
                                other matters, I prepared myself for a quiet repose in the arms of Somnus. Sleep, sweet,
                                soothing sleep was what most possessed my feelings, but a sudden and unexpected change
                                of mind took the entire possession of me, so.that for two hours not a particle of sleep
                                came to me. Soon after I had extinguished the light, Elder Giles A very placed himself
                                at the east end of my room. I saw him as plainly as though he possessed a material body.
                                At his right hand, but a little behind him stood Elder Daniel Boler. In company with the
                                two Elders were several Brethren and Sisters who were once our companions in the earth
                                sphere. Suddenly they all joined in singing this old familiar song: "O what came we
                                together to do? We'll sing the love of Mother to you, For this will all our spirits
                                renew, And bring New earth and Heaven to view. Pure love so fresh from Mother to me, It
                                makes me feel so happy and free, I never did feel so joyful before; O I want more love,
                                Mother's love more." Having finished singing this piece, they sang the anthem, "Parents
                                Blessing," which commences, "Ho, this is the hour wherein I can rejoice and be glad."
                                The anthem was finished and then Elder Giles, who appeared to be the leader of the
                                company assembled turned to me and said, I want you to say to Elder Joseph, that the
                                Florida enterprise did not originate in the earth sphere, it was ministered from the
                                Spirit world. We inspired those outside of our Community to engage in the prosecution of
                                the enterprise. This has influenced and moved them to accept conditions and work with
                                you for its consummation. <pb n="128" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 128 THE MANIFESTO. We in the Spirit
                                sphere feel in earnest to have you, Elder Joseph, press the prosecution of the work with
                                your untiring energy. We will work with you and bless your earnest efforts. We wish you
                                to be assured that your gospel relation in the Spirit world are with you heart and soul,
                                to strengthen you and to bless you. We can see clearly what to your vision is obscure.
                                Sometime after this interview I fell into a quiet repose which held me until about
                                midnight, when it seemed that some one was pressing on my feet, but not succeeding in
                                waking me, they came to the head of the bed and struck me a heavy blow on the shoulder
                                which suddenly awakened me. So real was the shock, that I turned saying ; "What do you
                                want? " No one answered, and 1 saw no one, but the following stanza was vividly
                                impressed upon my mind as though some one was repeating the words, and I arose, lighted
                                a lamp and sketched them. O work ye my people, O work saith the Lord; Work ye in my
                                Spirit, You will have your reward. A house I am building, 'Tis the Temple of Love, In a
                                land of bright promise, Blessed by heaven above. There are others in our Community who
                                have seen the spirit of the Lord has cast a halo of blessing on our investment in
                                Florida. Those who think that God has especial respect for any place upon his footstool
                                to the exclusion of all other places must upon more mature reflection, blush that they
                                have such poor conception of the wisdom and benevolence of the divine Creator. Even
                                mediums outside of our Community see glory and the hand of God in our Florida
                                plantation. Brother Alonzo Hollister received a letter from a friend in Lancaster, O. on
                                March 11, 1895, as follows; Deak Friend and Brother;I received a communication from the
                                greatest medium in the world. She says that the Society which goes south, will be a
                                spiritual success, and will get the greatest spiritual demonstrations the world has
                                seen. She said the light blinded her eyes. I thought this of so much consequence to you
                                and yours that I send it right along. The name of the medium is Dr. Amy Little.
                                Respectfully, - - - - - - -"In the mouth of two or three witnesses every word shall be
                                established." Matt, xviii., 16. In kindest love now and forever. Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reed, Calvin G." TEIform="persName"/>Calvin G. Reed.</byline></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Not in the environments of the past..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Not in the environments of the past...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Not in the environments of the past, but in the freedom of consciousness that seeks its
                                own expression, do we unfold that divine self-hood that individualizes our existence.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div3><pb n="129" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vincens Hansens, Our Kind Friend..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Vincens Hansens, Our Kind Friend...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, East Canterbury, April 1895" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury, N. H.
                                April, 1895.</dateline><p TEIform="p">VlNCENS HANSENS, Our Kind Friend ;Your letter of Feb. 23rd received and by no means has
                                been forgotten. The remittance also received and the papers sent as requested. Agreeably
                                to your request, one of the Sisters addressed a kind letter to the lady of whom you
                                wrote several weeks ago, hoping thereby to open a correspondence if agreeable to her but
                                we still wait a reply. We are happy to learn that The Manifesto proves a messenger of
                                glad tidings, in your household. We think it should be as a burning and shining light
                                which by its illuminating power and testimony of truth is able both to judge and save
                                the lost. The pure gospel of Christ in the combined excellence of its first and second
                                appearing will, we believe, eventually shake the whole earth; then will the ripened
                                grain fall into the garner of God. The end of the world will come to those by whom the
                                new life in Christ is accepted and lived. How can one who reads the prophecy in Matt,
                                xxiv., 6, and compares it with the signs of the present fail to believe that its
                                fulfillment is near,even at the very door. A powerful manifestation of the increasing
                                wrork of God seems inevitable to meet the moral and spiritual needs of the present. The
                                pioneer Shakers or Believers in Christ's second appearing were accused of breaking up
                                family ties. "Was it the Shakers or the truths of the gospel of regeneration which
                                created this revolution? Making the old commandments of none effect, thus placing the
                                soul in a position where it will be possible to love God with might, mind and strength.
                                Wherever this condition is reached the Savior's word in Matt, x., M, will no doubt be
                                verified. Then "the oue may be taken and the other left." We seem to read between the
                                lines of your epistle a sincere hungering and thirsting for spiritual nourishment, "the
                                bread and water of life" and bid you God speed in your efforts to secure the
                                soul-sustaining food. May you be encouraged to maintain the "everlasting right." As a
                                Church we sincerely cherish the spiritual welfare of all such in our daily prayers. "He
                                that endureth to the end the same shall be saved,"endureth to the end of all controversy
                                with the truth which is to free us from the thralldom of worldly principles. A spiritual
                                Christian Church is established on the earth. The house is set in order promised by the
                                Comforter. That the Christ spirit may be manifest in every individual claiming to be a
                                follower thereof, is our fervent desire ; while our universal prayer is ; "Hasten the
                                time, when the laborers shall be, Many in thy vineyard, Lord, Sowing and reaping the
                                harvest for thee Filled with the power of thy word." We fully agree with your statement
                                that it will be no easier to live the <pb n="130" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 130 THE MANIFESTO. Christ
                                life in a future state. We believe that greater glory will crown such as deny self,
                                while it is in their power to be ruled thereby. No soul c;in be justified in defening
                                the day of salvation, by self-crucifixion, after hearing distinctly the call of the good
                                Shepherd,"Follow thou me." We realize the momentous work of the mission we have
                                undertaken, to represent practically the principles of the Christ life. Whenever you
                                think of our Church and its people you must feel assured that as all good is related,
                                you are entitled by good efforts to a place in our visible kingdom of heaven on earth
                                for we think an entrance thereto may be as accessible in Norway, as in New Hampshire,
                                but we will do our part iu prayer to extend the bond of Christian fellowship across the
                                wide waters, as no distance can saver the union of the spirit. Last but not least we
                                express the kind love and remembrance of our Brethren and Sisters to the worthy mother
                                and children. Respectfully,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilson, Sarah F." TEIform="persName"/>Sarah F. Wilson.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our mission" TEIform="index"/>OUR MISSION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peck, Florence M." TEIform="persName"/>By Florence M. Peck.</byline><p TEIform="p">WHEN we think of our mission, we are naturally inclined to think of it as being in two forms;
                            first the mission of our Church and second the mission of each one individually. The
                            original purpose of the founders of this Church was to establish the mission of our Savior,
                            upon a plan so simple and easy to be understood, that any one of common intelligence could
                            be able to live the life which Jesus taught. Separation from the world, community of
                            interest, confession of sin, and a virgin life ; these vital principles were taught and
                            lived by Jesus and where they have been kept alive in our hearts the real mission of our
                            founder has been established. To-day, as well as one hundred years ago, it is the mission of
                            our Church to obey the ever increasing light that comes to us, and shed this light abroad
                            that others may see some of the beauties of the highei life, and to "glorify our Father
                            which is in Heaven." As our calling is so much above and beyond that of many others, we
                            should be earnest as individuals to raise and keep our standard high and in this way be
                            helping ourselves and those around us. We can not realize how far our influence may affect
                            others or how lonoour mission may live after we think that our part is done. Ruskin tells us
                            that "every noble life, leaves the fibre of it interwoven forever in the work of the world.
                            Life is so short and the good that we might do is so little that all of our life MISSION <pb n="131" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 131 forces must be brought to bear upon whatever
                            talents we may possess. I believe that God will just as surely bless those who have only one
                            talent, faithfully used, as he will those with more talents. Some may say that their mission
                            is to do just whatever they may be called to do; another may say that each one has some
                            especial mission to perform, that in God's great plan, each one has some especial work to
                            do. I love to think that this is true, that our heavenly Father's care is so constant and
                            loving that each one however situated, has a share of divine fore-thought. May my life not
                            be a failure, but may I be given light to see and know what my especial mission is and in
                            the strength that our Father can give, be able to perform it. We know that: "There's never a
                            rose in all the world, But makes some green spray sweeter. There's never a wind in all the
                            sky, But makes some bird's wing fleeter. God gives to us all, a mission small, With which to
                            make earth brighter." Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith" TEIform="index"/>FAITH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><index level1="Stephens, Annie B." TEIform="index"/>By Annie B. Stephens.</byline><p TEIform="p">Into the solemn silence of the night, We lift our hands in calmest trust,not fear, And feel
                            the strength of unseen forces near; A sheltering love encircles with its might, A light
                            shines out upon the inner sight. The outer darkness may be dense and drear Yet even then we
                            feel that God is here. And, with a child-like trust, we seek the light. Until by faith
                            anointed, eyes were dim; We blindly groped the valley's shadowed way, Nor saw the glory of
                            the mountain's rim, Nor blessed the hand that led from night to day; The stars may pale, but
                            Faith's clear flame shall rise, Refulgent as the light of noon-day skies. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Happy is he..." TEIform="index"/>Happy is he...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> is he who curbs his passions and masters his dominant inpulses.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A,</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Flattery may be likened to a clear and sparkling icicle..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Flattery may be likened to a clear and sparkling icicle...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Flattery may be likened to a clear and sparkling icicle, it holds its form in the cold
                            regions of selfishness ; but in the warm interior of the soul under the divine rays of truth
                            and love, it can not exist.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="L., M. E." TEIform="persName"/>M. E. L.</byline></div2><pb n="132" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faithful in duty" TEIform="index"/>FAITHFUL IN DUTY. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">A WRITER of recent date makes this remark, "Aggressive evangelism jLjL is the only thing that
                            will make any religion successful." The above is so very true and so in harmony with the
                            testimony of Jesus the Christ, that it is worth repeating many times for the especial
                            benefit of those who have accepted the cross of Christ. To be aggressive has at first an
                            unpleasant sound for peacemakers, as it indicates an attack, or an assault upon some other
                            party. At first thought it seems much better adapted for the business of the sinner, rather
                            than for tl e saint. By some it has been thought that the Christian should stand only on the
                            defensive, and be able to protect himself again-st any form of enemy that might chance to be
                            manifested, and let all fighting of enemies be done by those who hated each other. Opening
                            the New Testament we at once caught sight of this peaceful solicitation, "Come unto me all
                            ye that are weary and heavy laden, and I will give rest unto your souls." Such a beautiful
                            invitation does not sound very aggressive, and it would require considerable time before
                            either the muscular or the theological fires could be brought into action for either
                            offensive or defensive warfare. The spirit that invades the domestic circle for the sake of
                            arousing religious thought and enquiry, suddenly enters those hearts that are weary of the
                            sins of the world and are anxious to find the promised rest, and yet the still small voice
                            is far more potent in leading souls through the exaltation of divine Love. We have happily
                            learned that God is love, and that the son of God is designated as the Prince of Peace.
                            "Love," says the apostle, "beareth all things," and certainly can harbor no retaliation or
                            even a wish of unkindness. To follow the Prince of Peace would be to discriminate the gift
                            of love throughout the whole world. "Follow peace with all men," is another admonition from
                            the same higher light, and demands of us a personal sacrifice for the blessing of others. In
                            connection with these Christian influences which so thoroughly hold conscience to its duty,
                            there is the strong predisposition in many individuals to submit to almost any disadvantage,
                            rather than to contend for what may be termed their rights. Age also has a strong
                            ameliorating influence over the mind, and anything that savors of contention becomes very
                            disagreeable. A devoted life in the interests of a Christian Community can not otherwise
                            than less- <pb n="133" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 133 en all the contending elements for
                            peace, and develop more fully the better qualities of a religious mind. It is this love
                            which is moving quietly away from the spirit of the world and imparting "peace and assurance
                            forever," in a'beautiful, consecrated home while on the earth, and the anticipated hope of
                            love and joy in the world beyond. All this love and peace and quietness and assurance may do
                            valuable service for the world at large, and make any family or Community the abode of
                            loving and peaceful spirits, giving them songs of joy and gifts of praise that would carry
                            them most lovingly through the gatts into the holy City. Jesus may have thought of all this
                            and held it in anticipation, but his direct work was quite the reverse, as he publicly
                            remarked that he had not a private, selfish abode where he could lie down to rest. With a
                            home, or without a home the soldier of the cross of Christ must battle against the sins of
                            the world, for the protection of his own spirit and for the salvation of others. An
                            aggressive warfare must be continued so long as ignorance and indolence may be found to
                            exist, and any Community or even any individual to maintain a successful prosperity must
                            become actively engaged in this vitalizing work, Tl e zeal that was manifested by the
                            Apostle in his exhortation to the; Ephesians is the lesson for every Christian to have fixed
                            in his own heart. "Put on the whole armor of God, that ye may be able to stand against the
                            wiles of the devil. For our wrestling is not against flesh and blood, but against the
                            principalities, against the powers, against the worldrulers of this darkness, against the
                            spiritual hosts of wickedness in the heavenly places. Wherefore take up the whole armor of
                            God, that ye may be able to withstand in the evil day ; and having done all- to stand. Stand
                            therefore, having girded your loins with truth, and having put on the breastplate of
                            righteousness, and having shod your feet with the preparation of the gospel of peace ;
                            withal taking up the shield of faith, wherewith ye shall be able to quench all the fiery
                            darts of the evil one. And take the helmet of salvation, and the sword of the spirit, which
                            is the word of God." Enough has been left on record for us to become familiar with the
                            course that Jesus pursued. Here is one of his lessons of aggression and yet it is a lesson
                            of love. "Woe unto you Scribes and Pharisees, hypocrites, for ye shut up the Kingdom of
                            heaven against men ; for ye neither go in yourselves, neither suffer ye them that are
                            entering to go in." <pb n="134" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 134 THE MANIFESTO. To be able to use such
                            language as this, a man must, indeed, have on the whole armor of God or his safety would be
                            at a fearful discount, as these Scribes and Pharisees occupied prominent places in the
                            government. In observing the ordinances of their religion they acknowledge no superiors.
                            They believed that God had accorded to them wonderful privileges and made their nation a
                            powerful representative of his divine favor, and they felt assured that no power could ever
                            displr.ee them from their religious, exalted position. That they should be incensed at these
                            remarks of Jesus and denounce him as under the influence of the devil, can not be thought
                            strange, but when he took a still more aggressive position and attacked them in their
                            selfish and sensual lives and made prominent the domestic ciicle, then they were ready to
                            crucify him. Subsequently listening to his exhortations of peace they felt assured that he
                            could do them no special harm, and probably anticipated that he would soon fall from sight.
                            But suddenly they heard from him again ; "Think not that I am come to send peace on earth ;
                            I came not to send peace, but a sword, for I am come to set a man at variance against his
                            father, and the daughter against her mother, and a man's foes shall be they of his own
                            household." This stands as our highest lesson in aggressive evangelism. It was the striking
                            of the ax at the root of the tree. It was the thrusting in of the sharp sickle to reap the
                            harvest of the earth. Paul like Jesus was assured of his spiritual success as he had "fought
                            the good fight of faith,'7 and contended against the principalities and powers, and against
                            all wickedness in spiritual places. He then says, "Our weapons are not carnal, but mighty
                            through power to the pulling down of the strongholds of Satan. To do less for the cause of
                            righteousness than did the apostle, after having more extended privileges, would be very
                            much to our discredit. In accepting the call to be a disciple of Christ, we must accept the
                            life of the Teacher. When he says "learn of me" he evidently means that we must do as he had
                            done, in that he denied himself of all ungodliness and every worldly lust. There can be no
                            compromise with wrono-, and no lukewarmness in the bearing of the Cross of Christ.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian character is not an act..." TEIform="index"/>Christian character is not an act...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Christian character is not an act, but a process, not a sudden creation, but a development.
                            It grows and bears fruit like a tree, and like a tree it requires patient and unwearied
                            attention.</p></div2><pb n="135" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Heavenly pathway" TEIform="index"/>HEAVENLY PATHWAY.</head><p TEIform="p">"I reckon that the sufferings of this present time are not worthy to be compared with the
                            glory which shall be revealed in us."Rom. viii, 18. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Canterbury, N. H. 1.
                            Do we think what a treasure the Gospel will 2. Oh! the joys that we now see will fade from
                            our 3. Oh! then let us press onward, the goal we may be, When our souls from all struggles
                            with nature are sight, As the stars softly melt in the morning's clear win, And our souls
                            may be cleansed from the nature of free ? When the unbounded regions of glory are light; And
                            our spirits made pure by the Gospel's bright sin; By the cross that our Heavenly Parents did
                            ours, And our pathway lies always 'mid heavenly flowers, fire, Will rise through eternity,
                            higher and higher, bear, By watching and meekness, by love and by prayer.</p></div2><pb n="136" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. JUNE 1895. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the "United
                            Society of Believebs" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Okdek and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All communications should
                            be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. .75 .40 One copy per
                            year, postage paid " " six months, " "</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. April. Thermometer. Bain. Snow. 1894. 44.3 1 in. 7 in.
                                1895. 44.44 5 " 0 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 76 above 0 Lowest " . " " " 20 "
                                Number of rainy days " " 10 " " clear " " " 10 " " cloudy " " " 10 C. 6. Meed. May,
                                1895. "So, then, the year is repeating its old story again: we are come once more, thank
                                God! to its most charming chapter. The violets and Mayflowers, are its inscriptions and
                                vignettes." So said Goethe, and so we say. An old story, yet forever new. We never tire
                                of the beautiful freshness of such a spring. After so long and cold a winter we ex
                                pected a tardy spring but like the Dutch man "we can not nearly always sometimes tell"
                                for surprises seem to be in order. On the fifth instant we found that we were but rive
                                days later than the very early spring of last year; and the past warm days make the
                                difference still less. On the 29th ult., we parted with Sisters Minerva Reynolds, and
                                Anna Lane, of our family, and Sister Nancy Dow of the Center family, who will for the
                                present make their home in Florida to care for the Brethren there, and give the
                                essential requisites of "home sweet home" to the nucleus in that southern" land. They
                                were all loved and trusted members of our home, and the parting was sad; yet we hope
                                that by casting our bread upon the waters, there may after many days, be a returned
                                blessing. Charles Preston a young Brother from Canaan also accompanied them, and our
                                earnest prayers were offered for a safe and prosperous journey, which we have since
                                learned was accomplished in four days by steamer from New York to Jacksonville, and by
                                rail from there to their home in central Florida. This includes also a halt of a few
                                hours at Charleston, S. C. We trust that as soon as possible our Florida Community will
                                be represented in the Home Notes. The present health of our family is a kind that has
                                "go" in it. From the eldest to the youngest, all are busy and as far as time and
                                strength will permit, seem to be embued with the "Public Spirit" so clearly denned by
                                our loved Sister Martha J. Anderson, in the February No. We have always observed that
                                the busiest people find the most leisure for making home happy, while the care and
                                worship of self, produces a total eclipse of the comforts of home and friends. Amelia J.
                                Calver. North Family. May, 1895. One swift leap from winter to spring brings high
                                pressure on the few upon whose exertions we are dependent for the good things from
                                orchard and garden. In addition to the usual work of the season TERMS. <pb n="137" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 137 improvements are being made in our kitchen garden by
                                draining the boggy end and arranging for irrigation on the other end. The suddenness
                                with which the seared meadows and bare trees have clothed themselves with fresh robes of
                                beauty, seems indeed a wondrous miracle, and gives our hearts courage to believe that
                                through the long period of spiritual inertia divine powers have been concentrating which
                                before long will burst forth in new spiritual life for humanity. As a people we realize
                                the necessity of this, and the vitality latent within is reaching upward for the warmth
                                and light of a new inspiration. We gladly let fall to earth the shriveled leaves from
                                the tree of more than a century,old customs and forms which served well in their time,
                                but must now give place to those better adapted to the needs of to-day. Any tree which
                                can not renew its foliage and put forth new shoots is in process of decay. We must have
                                fixed principles, but no stereotyped customs or patterns to hinder the future from
                                giving those principles higher and broader expression. "The letter killeth but the
                                spirit giveth life." "Lord send by whom thou wilt," if we may but receive the truth
                                which alone maketh free. The letter printed in The Manifesto of July 1894, from Br.
                                Arthur Dowe, and some later ones from other pens, justly admonish us. We bless the
                                burning words of truth so boldly spoken. As a spiritual people we prosper only by
                                "seeking first the kingdom of heaven and its righteousness,"our own higher interests and
                                those of our fellow beings. Our predecessors who labored so heroically to lay the
                                foundation of our church, though often suffering for the common necessities of life,
                                were never too poor to spend time and substance in spreading the light and truth of the
                                gospel. It is a source of deep regret to us that the earnest appeal for help from
                                California, in starting a society there did not meet with response, but the calls keep
                                coming from others in the same region where there seems to be material p repared. The
                                little colony in Florida have our best wishes for growth and prosperity. Now that
                                something new has been done we hope that by another year some effort will be made to
                                answer the calls from the Pacific coast. We have heard many words of praise for The
                                Manifesto of May. Thanks to all to whom we are indebted for its continuance, especially
                                to the beloved Editor. Catherine Allen.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 1895. "The world is in commotion and human hearts are stirred." The varied emotions
                                that are stirring human society illustrate the development that the individual, society
                                or nation has attained in their intellectual and spiritual growth. "When ye shall hear
                                of wars and rumors of wars, then know ye that the time is at hand." This certainly is
                                applicable to the present. That the time is even at the door for the old heavens and
                                earth to pass away, we fully believe. Not by might or power, but by the spirit of truth;
                                as the work will be one that will call for each soul to enter the temple and see that it
                                is made clean; a fit place for the abiding of the holy Spirit. Our Society meetings have
                                lately been blest with the special ministrations and presence of the veteran souls who
                                have passed over the river, who have made themselves known visibly to our mediums. It is
                                a comforting assurance to know that we can not be separated wherever our earthly
                                habitation may be from their presence and power. The month of May has to date, the 8th,
                                given us some very warm weather. The temperature several times ranging above eighty. Our
                                weather prognostications are an average high temperature for the summer. How correct it
                                will be time will prove. Indications are good for a bountiful fruit year. Hamilton
                                DeGraw.</p></div3><pb n="138" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 1895. Spring, with its multiplicity of duties both in and out of doors, was rather
                                late in its arrival. Large piles of snow were seen on the mountains on the first of May.
                                Still, much has been accomplished by the farmers and by others. Oats are sown and
                                gardens planted. All are busily employed in some way to help make our home pleasant and
                                comfortable. As we see many young tret s set out this spring, and that older trees have
                                been trimmed and grafted, it gives encouragement for new effort. Within the buildings
                                the brooms, mops, and utensils of the busy cleaner, are being almost constantly wielded,
                                so that the spring cleaning will soon be accomplished. A great and much needed
                                improvement has been made in the entrance hall at our Brick dwelling. With a new spruce
                                ceiling, finished with shellac and varnish; a fresh coat of light paint on the walls,
                                and one of varnish on the woodwork, the hall is transformed into a new place. It has
                                been decided to enlarge our Trustees' Office on the west or front side. On May 1st, work
                                commenced on the foundation. Carpenters are also at work on the window frames and such
                                other work as is to be done in the shop. A description of the new addition can be given
                                better at a later date. The State Road surveyors were here last week and surveyed the
                                ground one mile west of us. We expect a road will be built this season. This, with the
                                mile east already commenced will give us two miles of as good road as can be found in
                                the state. On April 20th two car loads of Western cattle, numbering 57 head, arrived at
                                our station, bought by Br. Ira Lawson, in Chicago. Some little trouble was experienced
                                by him in bringing them into the state, caused by the Mass. Cattle Commissioners
                                neglecting to forward the permit to East Albany where they arrived. They came through,
                                however, after a vexatious delay without any extra expense to us. The beloved Ministry
                                left us on the 1st inst. for a sojourn at their home in Connecticut. Our visit with
                                Eldress Louisa Greene of Harvard will long be remembered. We have observed that an
                                acquaintance with a Believer makes each renewal of intimacy a very pleasant and
                                desirable event. We are again proving the truth ot the above assertion by a pleasant
                                visit, of a few days duration with Sister Emily Offord, of Canaan, N. Y. The inmates of
                                our home send loving greetings to all, both far and near. In the early twilight and at
                                other times we like to talk with one another of the various homes of Believers. Not one
                                is forgotten, in Maine, New Hampshire, Massachusetts, Connecticut, New York, Ohio and
                                Kentucky. The little settlement in Florida, and the one in Philadelphia where Sister
                                Rebecca Jackson and her companions are toiling so patiently and faithfully. All these
                                dear friends have our best wishes. May the blessing of Heaven rest upon them. Emoretta
                                Belden.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 1895. "Every man that hath this hope in him, (that is the hope of being like
                                Christ,) purifieth himself even as He is pure." Let us hope on and hope ever. Let us be
                                strong, be brave and manly, believing that, "He doeth all things well." Let us be sure
                                we are sowing good seed in the heart; sure that we ought to do just what we are doing,
                                and all will be well with us. In forming a true Christian character, purity is the chief
                                corner stone. Let us be virtuous and heavenly joy will flow into our hearts. Impure
                                people poison their associates by evil examples and are moral ulcers and plague spots.
                                Let us shun the malaria of vice as we would a pestilence. How sweet are the hours spent
                                in God's service. "Good thoughts are blessed visitors, and should be heartily welcomed
                                and much sought after. Like rose leaves they give <pb n="139" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                                139 out a sweet savor if laid away in the jar of memory." "A friend in need is a friend
                                indeed; but a friend, indeed, is never in need." "The first Bible printed in America was
                                in 1663. It was translated by John Elliot into Algonkin language for the Indians. At the
                                sale of the Brinley library in New York, March 1879 an Elliot New Testament brought
                                $7.00. At the same sale a Bible of 1663 sold for $1,000. At an auction in 1884 a Bible
                                of 1685 brought $950. The Bement copy of the Elliot Testament of 1661 sold in London in
                                1820 for less than a dollar. The same copy at a sale in New York in 1890 brought $610.
                                The total amount of Indian Testaments and Bibles of this period now known to exist is
                                125." "The Chinese not only cultivate their land, but all of their lakes, ponds and
                                marshes are gardens in which aquatic plants, suitable for food are largely raised. Among
                                these the water chestnut is preeminent and is said to be of a very palatable and
                                wholesome nature." Daniel Orcult.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 1895. "The time of the singing of birds has come." In the morning the early shrill
                                notes of the robin awaken us to a sense of gratitude for the blessings of another day.
                                At eventide, poor will takes a whipping; while the mosquito sings his harsh evening song
                                in our ears, which we would prefer not to hear. Yet we are surrounded with beauty on
                                every hand. "This world is full cf beauty, As other worlds above, And if we did our duty
                                It might be full of love," which is the oil of gladness that lubricates the wheels of
                                communal machinery that there need be no friction. Peach, pear, plum and cherry trees
                                are in bloom, while the laborers are dilligently sowing and planting the seeds, in faith
                                looking to the fulfillment of the promise that seed time and harvest shall not fail. We
                                earnestly hope that nature's kindly conditions will be favorable to an abundant harvest.
                                The family who have so lately taken possession of our South family have become quite
                                well settled in their new home, and our centenarian Brother endured the move much better
                                than we had anticipated. Sister Louisa Greene is now on a visit to Mt. Lebanon and
                                Societies of that bishopric. She will be absent through the month of May. We are pleased
                                to send so good a representative and hope she will have a pleasant visit and come home
                                recuperated. Marcia M. liuUard.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 1895. The four seasons as they come and go, each in their regular course, bespeak a
                                powerful force in the law of the universe, of uWondrous truths, and manifold as
                                wondrous." Gladly we welcome the advent of summer with its newness of life. Verily a
                                change in the aspect of nature is productive of varied lessons of thought, beneficial to
                                mind and body. In these days of religious skepticism, reference to rules, creeds and
                                ceremonies of the past fail to benefit mankind, or perpetuate the gospel of Christ.
                                Active Christian works in daily life, speaking words of comfort to the needy if
                                consolation is the leaf needed from the tree of life; educating, if knowledge is the
                                gift necessary from the mind's store-house; these are the practical works of
                                righteousness which are to raise our fellow beings from theological error into an
                                atmosphere of universal love and moral activity. Whatever be our lot, may we be givers
                                as well as sharers of the goodness and mercy of God, thus doing his will and making our
                                lives sublime. We are pleased to add to the list of our blessings of to-day, the
                                pleasure we are deriving from having our reverend friend, <pb n="140" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 140 THE
                                MANIFESTO. Elder Abraham Perkins with us. As he visits the field of his former labors,
                                may he realize that the good seed he has scattered by the way is bearing the fruits of
                                righteousness, and may the golden sunshine of peace bless his life as he glides into the
                                courts of heaven's joys. On the evening of the 24th of April, our North family met with
                                the loss of their mill by fire; cause unknown. Loss estimated at $2,300. No insurance.
                                Farming and gardening progressing finely and usual prosperity throughout the Society. We
                                offer our thanks to both divine and human powers of good for all blessings realized,
                                with renewed prayers for God's children in all the earth. George II. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 1895. Seed-time and harvest will never fail. So says the good Book, and it is a
                                consolation to know that some good things are permanently secured for our happiness and
                                prosperity while on our pilgrimage to the land of souls. The beauties of spring have
                                come to us in abundance, and we will accept the generous and wonderful contribution just
                                the same as though we had ordered it to be prepared for us. Even the honey bees and
                                humble bees are made happy by this early supply of bread and honey, and the trees are
                                made alive with the buzzing of these industrious little workers. But few bees, however,
                                are kept in central New Hampshire, as it is difficult to carry them through the long,
                                severe winters. One of our Brethren rejoiced in the possession of two colonies in the
                                month of April, but for some cause they went out on a strike in the month of May and
                                have not yet returned. A report from the dairy informs us that we have over sixty
                                gallons of milk a day. This more than supplies our large family with butter and allows
                                us to place some upon the market. When we wrote our last "Notes," the only birds to be
                                seen or heard, in tliis vicinity, were crows, blue jays and English sparrows. Although
                                they were not so musical as some birds, they seemed to enjoy their own style of singing
                                and indeed in mid-winter it was not to be despised. Now, at exactly 3-30 a. m. robin
                                redbreast opens the bird concert, and soon the sparrows, bluebirds and bobolinks and
                                others are filling the air witli their beautiful songs. //. C. Blinu.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/> Union Village, o.</head><p TEIform="p">April, 1895. Mabch has come and gone with his big blows and little snows, and snug days
                                and wintry ways, and these we have utilized in sawing fire-wood with our twelve foot
                                geared Air motor; a very economical power, requiring no feed and no fuel and always
                                ready, when the wind blows, for any work requiring more than from one to ten horse
                                power, according to the force of the wind. April is here, with her modest cheer, and
                                gentle showers and early flowers, and corresponding to these, is the flow of life in our
                                fraternal union. Free from extremes or forceful dreams and ever tending toward the
                                settled warmth of fraternal love in the summer Land. The evenings are made cheerful by
                                the long rows of fires in the big cornfields, the farmers burning the cornstalks; having
                                been raked into winrows, and lighted almost simultaneously, the effect is very pretty.
                                Health of Society usually good. Watson Andrews.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">May 5, 1895. May has come, bringing its burdens to the farmer and gardener. Most of the
                                help is engaged at the saw-mill just now, yet the farm work is not neglected. About 350
                                fruit trees have been set out, <pb n="141" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 141 250 apple, and
                                the rest are peach, pear, plum and cherry. A new strawberrybed is also in progress. Our
                                young Brethren have built a greenhouse which is heated with a wood furnace. In it they
                                started about eightyfive dozen tomato plants, also 3,300 celery plants. The tomato
                                plants will mostly be sold to people living in this vicinity. They are raising the
                                celery for the Poland Spring Hotels; the seed was sown in Feb. and the plants are at
                                present seven inches high. Celery is now grown as a common garden crop, yet few
                                understand its cultivation. It has to be thoroughly irrigated during dry weather and a
                                few weeks before taking up it is bleached with hay or earth. The weapons of cleanliness
                                are being wielded, for as John Wesley says "Cleanliness is next to Godliness" we must
                                remove the dust and dirt in order to become godly. Our surroundings will show if we are
                                what we profess to be,a godly people. Though the Sisters have not yet a greenhouse, they
                                have done a goodly amount of seed starting. They have at this time hundreds of seedlings
                                grown in their sunny rooms. Carnation Pinks, Asters, Dahlias, Cosmos, Antirrhinum,
                                Pansies and other flowers which are soon to be transplanted to the garden plots. We
                                often think of the untiring efforts of the Editor and printers of The Manifesto, during
                                these warm, pleasant days, and heartily extend our grateful thanks and well wishes,
                                exclaiming with Dickens, "God bless you every one." Ada S. Cummings.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>-Alfred., Me.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 1895. Afteb patiently waiting, the frosty air of winter and late spring has at
                                length left us, and the genial rays of "Old Sol" are resurrecting the vegetable
                                creation, and clothing Mother Earth with a green mantle. Our days of waiting were well
                                improved, with the duties appropriate to the season, not one day for sloth or indolence;
                                and now comes the seed sowing. Likewise, if we patiently work and wait, the Sun of
                                Righteousness will, in the appointed time, warm the hearts of the children &gt;f men and
                                prepare them to receive the good seed which shall spring up and grow, increasing many
                                fold, if the weeds of sin and selfishness are not permitted to grow and crowd out the
                                plants of virtue. As it would not have hastened the harvest, if we had planted before
                                the earth was warmed and prepared for the seed, let not an unwise impatience cause us to
                                forget that the material world is a type of the spiritual, each having its seasons of
                                sowing and harvesting. Father Joseph, whom Mother Ann esteemed as a wise man, said our
                                Church was to have seven degrees of travel; and the counsel to us has been to keep up
                                with the increasing growth of the Church. But each degree of travel will bring its
                                increasing degree of crossmore denial of self and not less. A wise man of old declares
                                that "God hath made man upright," but they have sought out many inventions. The Shakers,
                                like the Apostle, "Glory not save in the cross of our Lord Jesus Christ," by whom the
                                world is crucified unto us, and we unto the world. Anything that leads away from this
                                cross is but progression like that of a crab. While the farmers are busy preparing and
                                seeding the land, three painters are painting the buildings. One coat of paint every
                                five or six years is cheaper than two coats every ten or twelve years. We have all heard
                                that when the moun tain would not go to Mahomet, he went to the mountain. It is reversed
                                with us, We would not go to Florida, so the Florida climate has come to us. To-day, the
                                10th of May, it is above 90 deg. in the shade, and has been for a number of preceeding
                                days. If I have exceeded the 350 words, will the Editor kindly charge it to the space
                                not occupied last monih. Fannie Casey.</p></div3><pb n="142" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South Union, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>South. Union, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">April 14, 1805. This is Easter Sunday morning, find "behold the lilies of the field" how
                                beautiful they are, as fair and bright and odorous ats they were in the vales of old
                                Palestine m the days of Jesus whose resurrection from the grave we commemorate to-day.
                                This is a day well fitted for oration and sermon, prayer and song: for the sky is so
                                blue and the air so clear, so soft, so refreshing, one feels as if he were in the Better
                                Land. For the birds thrill both air and tree with their warbling song, and the sward
                                beneath our feet is dotted with variegated daisies and yellow dandelions. There is a
                                very good prospect for a fruit crop this year, for the trees are ablaze with a radiance
                                of bloom, unsurpassed in former years. Our corn is planted, and all kinds of work are
                                progressing. New fences are taking the place of old ones; new grasses look more pleasant
                                to the eye than the old broom sedge that has covered some of our pasture fields so many
                                years and the painter too is using his brush with a facile hand. He is making the facade
                                of our buildings to look brighter and better. The prospect of an exodus from this
                                Society is not very promising at this writing. In about four weeks we will have an
                                abundance of bright red, delicious strawberries. How good they are powdered with sugar
                                and covered with cream to eat with cake. James Carr.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute to our sister Martha Crooker" TEIform="index"/>Tribute to our Sister MARTHA
                            CROOKER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stickney, Asenath C." TEIform="persName"/>By Asenath C. Stickney.</byline><p TEIform="p">"For to me, to live is Christ, and to die is gain.'"Phil, v., 21. Dear, cheerful, loving
                            sister, At length, you've earned your lot Among the risen "Marthas,1'1 Where "worldly
                            cares," come not. Now restsweet rest enshrine you, Our precious loyal one; The blessings of
                            the household Receive,for robe and crown. As long you've borne life's burdens With modest
                            grace and care, And long have dealt to others The bounties yours to share, So shall the
                            sweets of Heaven Be multiplied to thee, Her joysin blest fruition Yours,heightened
                            endlessly. We all must miss the friendly smile, The cheery, pleasant tone, But He, the
                            Authcr of all life Now claims what is his own. And thus, no requiem we swell To note your
                            blissful change From thrall of earth,no dismal knell, No dirge will we arrange. But bid you
                            lovingly farewell! While angels", parents sing, "Well done." And friends uncounted, christen
                            you 'lheir "Good Samaritan." As "Carrier dove" from spheres above Oft bear us gifts of
                            peace, And we with you, will strive anew To meet each blest increase, Of truth and light and
                            love, That virgins wise approve. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>EXCHANGES.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Freedom" TEIform="index"/>Freedom
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Freedomis a Weekly paper, under the EditoraJ charge of Helen Wilmans. It is published in
                                the interest of the Mind cure treatment. Mrs. Wilmans is now in Florida building a
                                Colony under the name of "The City Beautiful." </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="American sentinel" TEIform="index"/>American Sentinel
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> American Sentinel is Published in New
                                York and A.T.Jones and C. P. Bollman are the Editors. It is in defense of Liberty of
                                Conscience and opposed to anything tending toward a union of Church and State. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good way" TEIform="index"/>The Good
                                Way
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Good
                                Way comes from Chillicothe, Mo. and is Edited by John P. Brooks. Holiness is one of the
                                leading features of the paper and certainly if all the good words in the "Good Way" are
                                carefully observed, they will assuredly lead to holiness. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield advocate" TEIform="index"/>The Enfield Advocate
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Enfield Advocate which has
                                entered its second year is Published by W. S. Abbott. It is growing in popularity and
                                bids fair to be- <pb n="143" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 143 come a permanent institution.
                                It is replete -with local news, and even visits the adjoining towns in the interest of
                                the public welfare. The paper well subserves the present nee^s and is liberally
                                patronized by those who are engaged in trade.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Teacher's journal" TEIform="index"/>The Teacher's Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Teacher's Journal is a pamphlet of thirty two pages, and under the management of Rev.
                                P. Anstadt and Sons of York, Pa. It is designed for Pastors and Sunday School Teachers,
                                and contains suggestive blackboard illustrations, as well as the "International Sunday
                                School Department. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Church union" TEIform="index"/>The Church Union
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Church Union is Published in New York City by Elizabeth B.
                                Grannis the Editor. It is in the Interest of those laboring for the visible unity of
                                Evangelical Believers.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Angels' foot-prints" TEIform="index"/>ANGELS' FOOT-PRINTS.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">[Contributed by John Ferryman.]  Every little kindness, Every deed of love, Every little action Prompted from
                                    above: E'en a cup of water In His great name given These are angels' foot-prints
                                    Leading up to heaven. Every little sacrifice Made for others' weal, Every wounded
                                    brother That we strive to heal, E'en a word of kindness To misfortune given All are
                                    angels' foot-prints Leading up to heaven. Then let angels lead us Whereso'er they
                                    would; Even let them teach us What is for our good; May they cross our pathway When
                                    from heaven they roam, Let us follow after Foot-prints leading home.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Joseph of Arimathea" TEIform="index"/>JOSEPH OF ARIMATHEA.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Carleton, Will" TEIform="persName"/>By Will Carlton.</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">'And when Joseph had taken the body, he wrapped it in a clean linen cloth, and
                                    laid it in his own new tomb, which he had hewn out in the rock: and he rolled a
                                    great stone to the door of the sepulchre, and departed."Matt. He stood beside the
                                    gate to know His triumph or his doom: "What didst thouforme, there below?" "I gave
                                    The Prince a tomb: I found Him 'neath the foeman's tread; And soon, from strife
                                    apart, I pillowed soft His bleeding head, And staunched His wounded heart. From
                                    hills of pain, His form I bore To chambers cool and deep; With whitest robes I clad
                                    Him o'er, And left Him there asleep. Although, when morns had numbered My Guest had
                                    gone away, [three, Yet still, I come to beg that He Will shelter me for aye."
                                    "Behold, good Heart, in joyful bloom, The seeds so humbly sown: Thou lendest to The
                                    Prince a tomb He gives to thee a throne!"</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Every Where" TEIform="index"/>Every Where.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Russell, Mary" TEIform="index"/>Mary Russell
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mary Russell, at Shaker Station, Conn. Feb. 24, 1895. Age 84 years. Faithful unto death.
                                D. Orcutt. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Parsell, John H." TEIform="index"/>John H. Parsell
                            </head><p TEIform="p">John H. Parsell, at Shaker Station, Ct. April 14, 1895. Age 75 years. Br.
                                John had lived with us nine years and never was heard to speak ill of any one. D.
                                Orcutt. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elam, William" TEIform="index"/>Wm. Elam
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Wm. Elam, at East Canterbury, N. H. April 29, 1895. Age 50. years, 6 mo. and
                                15 days. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Crooker, Martha" TEIform="index"/>Martha Crooker
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Martha Crooker, at East Canterbury, N. H. May 14, 1895. Age 69 years, 9 mo. and
                                24 days. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cameron, John" TEIform="index"/>John Cameron
                            </head><p TEIform="p">John Cameron, at Enfield, N. H. 17, 1895. Age 68 years. May</p></div3></div2><pb n="144" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological Journal and Science of Health" TEIform="index"/>
                                THE PHRENOLOGICAL JOURNAL AND SCIENCE of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">THE PHRENOLOGICAL JOURNAL AND SCIENCE of Health for May contains the lu-ual variety of
                                excellent iratter. The editor, Dr. Beali, gives an interesting and instructive
                                phrenograph of Mary A. Livermore, one of the greatest women of the United States, It is
                                from a personal examination, and will serve as a fine lesson in the art of reading
                                character. "The Great Minority," L&gt;y Alice E. Ives, is a brilliant nd powerful
                                arraignment of the shams in modern social aims and habits. Mrs. Charlotte Fowler Wells
                                continues her illustrated sketch of William Walton, explaining the relations of special
                                talents to poetic composition. "Phrenology in Theory and Practice," by the Rev. N. F.
                                Douglas, is very timely. Anna OlcottCommelin concludes her psychic story, "Mysteries of
                                To-Day." A study of the late Robert Louis Stevenson, the brilliant and eccentric author,
                                with fine portraits of himself and wife, is given by the editor, and is a lesson in
                                character reading from photographs. Dr. H. S. Drayton contributes an erudite, scientific
                                anil historical article. Parents will be greatly benefitted and delighted with Professor
                                Sizer's character sketches of fifty-eight children, with engravings, among which they
                                will certainly see, if not their own little ones, many familiar faces. The Science of
                                Health Department is strong and the editorials are of value for their technical
                                information and wholesome advice to young authors, with a peculiar coincidence regarding
                                Bismarck, Gladstone and Li Hung Chang. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sketches in Wonderland" TEIform="index"/>Sketches in Wonderland
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Sketches in Wonderland is a beautifully
                                illustrated Pamphlet, issued by the Northern Pacific Rail Road Company. A careful study
                                of the life like illustrations is next best to a journey through that land of magic
                                wonders. The Pamphlet can be obtained by forwarding six cents in stamps to Charles S.
                                Fee, General passenger agent, St. Paul, Minn. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="5000 books" TEIform="index"/>5000 Books
                            </head><p TEIform="p">THE 5000 BEST BOOKS. When a woman sends
                                her subscription to The Ladies' Home Journal special privileges seem to go with it,
                                besides getting her full money's worth in the magazine. She can take the fullest
                                advantage of a perfect educational plan by which she can educate her daughters or sons
                                at the best colleges in the country free of charge, and now the Journal has arranged it
                                so that she can buy her bookseven a single book at a timeat prices heretofore obtained
                                only by large buyers. There comes to us from this magazine a very artistically gotten-up
                                illustrated booklet of ovei"250 pages, called "5000 Books," which serves as an easy
                                guide to the best books in any department of reading. This guide is very well done. The
                                best literary experts of New York, Boston nnrt I'hiladelphia were engaged by the Journal
                                to select the five thousand books which it presents as the most desirable fora home
                                library, and their work has been admirably carried out. Very clear, explanatory comments
                                are given by these men of books, and besides there are given not less than 160 portraits
                                of leading authors. No book will, perhaps, do so much to extend good reading as this
                                guide, so carefully gotten up, so beautifully printed, and so generously offered, free
                                of any charge, by the publishers of The Ladies' Borne Journal. "5000 Books" is
                                unquestionably the best and easiest guide to a wise selection of books that has been
                                issued for a long time. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Atheism and arithmetic" TEIform="index"/>Atheism and Arithmetic
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Atheism and Arithmetic. This is a singular combination and we
                                well might ask, Whs't has Atheism or Christianity to do with Arithmetic? The author H.
                                L. Hastings, however, is quite at home in the illustration of his subject and has called
                                our attention to the "Arithmetic in Plants and Planets." "Mathematics in musical
                                Science." "Number in Vital Action." He has even illustrated the wonderful work of God by
                                noticing the "Arithmetic in a Corn Field." Books like this of such careful, useful and
                                correct representation are valuable in any home, and could be read with profit by either
                                young or old. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fourteen nuts for sceptics to crack" TEIform="index"/>
                                Fourteen Nuts for Sceptics to Crack
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Fourteen Nuts for Sceptics to Crack. This little book of sixteen pages
                                contains fourteen very pleasant articles and although written especially for those who
                                stand outside of the church, they might be a good accompaniment to the hymn book or even
                                the prayer book, for many who sit in front of the pulpit. The articles are all
                                interesting and instuctive, but the illustration of "The hen and the Egg" is just cute.
                                Published by H. L. Hastings, 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cosmopolitan" TEIform="index"/>The
                                Cosmopolitan Magazine
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> LATE LITERARY NEWS. Rudyard
                                Kipling to Revisit India. Much interest will be felt by the public in the return of
                                Rudyard Kipling to India. He has just agreed to furnish a regular contribution to The
                                Cosmopolitan Magazine for the coming year, beginning his work upon his return to India.
                                India has never been critically considered by such a pen as Kipling's, and what he will
                                write for The Cosmopolitan will attract the widest attention, both here and in England.
                                Perhaps the most beautiful series of pictures ever presented of the Rocky mountains will
                                be found in a collection of fourteen original paintings, executed by Thomas Moran for
                                the May Cosmopolitan. To those who have been in the Rockies, this issue of The
                                Cosmopolitan w ill be a souvenir worthy of preservation. This number contains fifty-two
                                original drawings, by Thomas Moran, Oliver Herford, Dan Beard, H. M. Eaton, F. G.
                                Attwood, F. O. Small, F. Lix, J. H. Dolph, and Rosina Emmett Sherwood, besides six
                                reproductions of famous re- <pb n="145" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 145 cent works of art,
                                and forty other interesting illustrationsninety-eight in all. Though The Cosmopolitan
                                sells for lout fifteen cents, probably no magazine in the world will present for May so
                                great a number of illustrations specially designed for its pages by famous illustrators.
                                The fiction in this number is by F. Hopkinson Smith, Gustav Kobbe, W. Clark Kussell,
                                Edgar W. Nye, and T. C. Crawford.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Standard dictionary" TEIform="index"/> THE STANDARD DICTIONARY. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Corning, Charles B." TEIform="persName"/>A Beview by Charles B. Corning.</byline><p TEIform="p">We do not hesitate to pronounce this work as the most useful, the most comprehensive and
                                the Best ever placed before the English speaking people. In every point of view this
                                dictionary merits the highest consideration and praise and the name given to it by the
                                makers is happily appropriate for The Standard marks an epoch in the intellectual
                                advancement of the world. Abreast, even in advance, of the critical and scholarly
                                researches of the age; especially when compared with two and perhaps three of our late
                                dictionaries, the Standard has planted itself in a position whence it may safely await
                                not only the judgment of its rivals but the verdict of the world. The public at large
                                have little or no knowledge of what the making of a dictionary means but the public will
                                understand the measurement of time and the expenditure of money. Five years and a
                                million of dollars are surely clearly intelligible and this, the publishers tell us has
                                been the cost of making the Standard Dictionary. In the preparation of the work nearly
                                300 office Editors and specialists have found constant employment, and in addition to
                                these there have been twice that number engaged in reading proofs, collecting
                                authorities and in defining the meaning of words. Not only this country but all
                                countries have contributed the ripest thoughts of their most distinguished scholars to
                                the making of this really wonderful work, and if, by any possibility any thing has been
                                omitted, it has been because of the utter impossibility of securing it. The Excellence
                                of his dictionary is beyond dispute, it is an enduring monument to the persistence, the
                                liberality and, we do not hesitate to say, to the patriotism of its publishers. IT. One
                                of the potent charms of liufus Choate's oratory consisted in the richness of his
                                vocabulary and his marvellous choice in the use of words. It was due to his profound
                                knowledge of the exuberance of the English language that he achieved such high
                                distinction in tiie forum and on the platform. His was the master hand whose touch
                                brought forth the exquisite beauties of the good old mother tongue.. Choate was free to
                                acknowledge the debt he owed to the dictionary and its constant study, and it was this
                                that caused Mr. Justice Wilde of the Massachusetts Bench to exclaim, when some one told
                                him that Webster had just published a dictionary containing 10000 new words, "For God's
                                sake don't tell Choate of this." Ten thousand new words made an epoch in Choate's time
                                but here is a dictionary which contains many fold more words than the best of
                                dictionaries fifty years ago. But this would be saying a trifling thing by no means
                                creditable to the present age which has been prolific of so many good and substantial
                                lexicons, if comparisons as to size of the respective lexicons is to be made between the
                                more recent works on this common subject. Assuming that the vocabulary is the principle
                                test of a work of this kind, it is interesting to see just where the Standard stands in
                                relation to its rivals. It occupies the first position and is many lengths ahead of its
                                nearest competitor. Its collection of words exceeds that of the six volume Century by
                                the thousands and the Century holds a most distinguished position among scholars. Within
                                the past ten years a remarkable quartet of lexicons has been published in the United
                                States, namely; Worcester, Webster International, The Century and The Standard. And the
                                last shall be first. The vocabulary terms in Worcester are 105,000; in Webster Inter-
                                    <pb n="146" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/> 146 THE MANIFESTO. national 125,000; in The Century (six
                                volumes) 225,000, while in The Standard are 301,865 besides 47,469 entries in the
                                appendices. Why this is so needs no explana lion. How often we have searched for the
                                definitions of electrocution and of appendicitis, and searched in vain until The
                                Standard came to our relief. Now we find these current terms and countless others for
                                the makers of this work have been to indefatigable care to gather and define all the new
                                words and expressions which the advancement of science and of general knowledge have
                                brought into every day use. III. No English lexicon ever devoted so much space to
                                synonyms as The Standard has done and no lexicon that we ever saw contained a list of
                                autonymes arranged so admirably as in this dictionary. To discriminate between the
                                shades of mean ing is the sine qua non of a good writer, but how to arrive at precisely
                                that point of selection has always been a most difficult thing for the writer to do. Now
                                comes The Standard to his assistance and lays him under a debt of everlasting gratitude.
                                To this important department the Editors have given immense labor and made it the
                                leading feature of a work replete with features. All English literature from Chaucer to
                                Kipling has been ransacked and more than 100000 volumes have been studied in order to
                                bring about the desired result. As in the vocabulary so in the synonymes, The Standard
                                surpasses its rivals an arrows flight. We need not speak of the more purely scientific
                                departments comprised in this marvelous work, each is complete and leaves nothing to be
                                added; it is one grand whole, a magnificent master piece of research and learning; a
                                magnificent mosaic of the beauties, the richness and the strength of theEnglish
                                language. Nothing is more necessary to the completeness of the table than tea or coffee;
                                if that does not begin the repast it must either end or accompany it. (See "adv."J</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spelling kitten" TEIform="index"/>SPELLING KITTEN.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A dear little girl, With her brain in a whirl, Was asked the word "kitten" to
                                    spell. "K-double i-t T-e-n," said she; And thought she had done very well. "Has
                                    kitten two I's ?" And the teacher's surprise With mirth and patience was blent. "My
                                    kitten has two," Said Marjory Lou; And she looked as she feltquite content.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Ladies' Companion" TEIform="index"/>Ladies' Companion.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="So much of the friction..." TEIform="index"/>So much of the friction...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"So much of the friction, the pain, the disorganization of life is due to lack of truth; so
                            many of us lie passively, keeping silence when truth demands speech clear and free. The
                            majority of us would resent the charge of cowardice with indignation, but often we are not
                            above defending silence by calling it reticence, which we feel is a word that involves the
                            possession of a strong character. It is an element in a strong character if it does not
                            overbalance equally desirable traits. How much courage it takes to speak when speaking
                            involves disagreement with one whose opinion we value or whose displeasure we dread! Yet how
                            can we hope to keep a place in a friend's estimation, unless we have the courage of our
                            convictions? Being truthful involves being brave. Spiked guns never won a battle, and never
                            will. But being truthful does not mean rattling shot, nor sharp-shooting. It means a fair,
                            open field, a face-to-face encounter. Silence, we say, is golden. It is if speech is
                            unnecessary; but it becomes the basest metal if truth demands speech. Life is too short to
                            waste it in useless encounters. Meet each obligation as it comes, and peace and respect, the
                            foundation of confidence and love, will be the natural outcome."</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Each well-born soul..." TEIform="index"/>Each well-born soul...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Each well-born soul must win what it deserves.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilcox, Ella Wheeler" TEIform="persName"/>Ella Wheeler Wilcox.</byline></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p29"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
with large type  and on excellent paper.
It contains  130 pages and has
ILLUSTRATIONS
of the Shakers and their
The  work  gives  quite an extended account of the  Several SOCIETIES, their
organization and general management.
Price  in cloth 75  cts;   in boards 50 cts.
Address   H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
AUTHORIZED RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY.
The religiousjbasis of the Obdee must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the  individ
ual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
A Visit to the
of EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
 . CHANDLER. U. S.HT
Liberally Illustrated with half tone
pictures of persons and places.
The Tillage of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the lovliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price 15 cts.
3MHUND CONCENTRATED       8
SYRUP of SARSAPARILLA,
With 1 oz. Hydriodate of Potassa to 12 Bottles.
PREPARED AX
# Sbafcer ISillage, Merrimach En., R.
This medicine has proved to be most
valuable in the following diseases :
Chronic Inflammation of the Digestive
Organs ; Dyspepsia, or Indigestion; 'Weakness and Sourness of the Stomach; Rheumatism ; Salt Rheum ; Secondary Syphilis;
Functional Disorders of the Liver; Chronic
Eruptions of the Skin, and all Scrofulous
diseases and disorders arising from impurities of the blood. It is also an excelUm remedy for the Erysipelas, Asthma,
Dropsy, Dysentery, and Diarrhoea, and
for the complicated diseases of females,
so apt to end in consumption.
Dose.For an adult, a teaspoonful
four or five times a day, with or without
a little water, which may be increased to
a tablespoonful, as best suits the patient.
To guard against counterfeits, observe
the signature of the inventor on each
label and on each wrapper.
HUMAN NATURE
is an illustrated Monthly, now only 50 cts.
per    year,    devoted   to   PHEEN0L0GY,
PHYSIOGNOMY.  HEALTH,   MEDICAL
& SOCIAL REFORM.
Would you like a copy?
Send 5 cts. for Sample to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Francisco, Cal.
<pb n="" id="p30"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cream of  tartar   baking   powder
Highest of  all in  leavening strength.
Latest   United  States   Government
Food Report.
Royal Baking Powder Co.,
106 Wall St., N. Y.
The Self-Pouring Pot looks like anyother and is made of various materials
and patterns. Its peculiarity is that it
stands all the while in its place on the
tray and is neither lifted nor tipped. The
handle is only to carry it to the table.
How then?
The cover is made so it can slide up
and down a few inches within the body of
the pot, and has on its top a small knob
of non-conducting material, with a small
hole through the center. Take the knob
by the thumb and second finger and lift
the cover, close the small hole with the
forefinger, then press down and the liquor
is forced by pneumatic action through the
spout into the cup. The spout is turned
downward, always pointing to the bottom
of the cup. The instant the fingers relax
their downward pressure on the knob the
flow stops. The pressure regulates the
flow; there is neither slopping nor dripping.        (See "adv." on another page.)
HOW I CAME
TO   BE
Price 5 cts.
This is a genuine American "Watch..
It is made for service and is the Best low
priced Watch for the rich man or poor
man, or for their sons or for any one who
wants a
Good Time Keeper.
It is a work day as well as a Sunday
watch. It has a patent winding attachment and weighs 4j/o oz.
It is open face, with heavy,
For $1.50 we will send the Watch, and
also a copy of The Manifesto for one
year, to any address in the U. S.
Address,
The Manifesto,
East Canterbury, N. H.
THE  ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley,
2 N. Fourth St.,  St. Louis, Mo.
A    SHAKER
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>