<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2609" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">26</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><date value="18960901" TEIform="date">September 1896</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">137-152</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="26" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
1896.
A Visit to the
of EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
LLOYD H. CHANDLER. U. S. N
Liberally Illustrated with half tone
pictures of persons and places.
The Village of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the lovliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price,   15 cts.
Address   H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
AND
SHAKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the United   Society   of   Believers   in   Christ's
Second Appearing.    Illustrated.
By Giles B. Avery.
Price,  15 cts.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF  TEE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS
Price, 10 cts.
the shaker covenant.
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS   OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES  and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION     AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
the same time, afford instruction to all  inquiring  minds.    Price 5  cts. each,  postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
SEPTEMBER,
BY
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
A new, enlarged and beautifully illustrated
edition of "The Wonderful Law" has just been
issued from the Repository Press at 47 Cornhill, Boston. The book now contains almost
300 pages. This excellent work from the pen
of that interesting writer, the venerable H. L.
Hastings is now sent abroad into the world.
It will, no doubt, become the able instructor
of thousands of readers. They will study with
pleasure that "Wonderful Law" which Moses,
the servant of God, was led to write. Its
special mission was for the better guidance of
the Hebrew nation during their wilderness
journey of some forty years. Pub. at 47 Cornliill, Boston, Mass.   Price, 30 cts.
The Journal of Hygeio Therapy for July
lias the sixth chapter on "The Science of Life"
and much valuable information may be obtained by its careful perusal. The Science of
Phrenology treats of the Temperaments with
the several combinations. Indigestionits
Cause and Cure. The person who can come
forward with a cure for that almost universal
malady would certainly merit the title "Good
Physician." Other interesting articles to be
found in this same number. Pub. by Dr. T. V.
Gifford & Co., Kokonio, Ind.
A fine book of Poems, Mount Lebanon
Cedar Boughs, by the North family of Shakers. Pub. by the Peter Paul Book Co., Buffalo, N. Y. 12mo, $1.00. This is a collection of
original poems by the Shakers from which
may be gained a glimpse of their inner life,
which seems both simple and sweet, yet incomprehensible to the world generally. Their
belief is a strange one, yet they are a sincere
and unpretending people who labor with
hands and with hearts to maintain what they
consider "higher conditions" of happiness,
and generously offer this good to all who care
to receive and can appreciate it. These poems
embrace, odes to Nature, Sonnets, Memorial
Tributes, poems on Duty, Patriotism and
Progress. There is a department giving the
post office addresses of a number of the different communities, together with a brief citation of the regulations governing the society
of Shakers, which is interesting.The Magazine of Poetry.
Word and Works for August, has a very
significant title over its first article"Stars
and Storms." The stars as a general thing
seem to be fixed quite securely on high, but
the storms and fearful ones are growing altogether too familiar. As things are moving we
shall soon begin to wish that our Rev. Etlitor
was not quite so "sartin." However, it is well
to be forewarned that we may also be forearmed.
Many interesting and instructing articles
may also be found in the August Word and
Works, quite unlike what we may read about
the stars, and yet essential for our prosperity
on life's journey.
Published by "Word and Works Co., 2201 Locust St., St. Louis, Mo.
The Pulpit for July has five very valuable
sermons and all on subjects that come quite
near to the human heart. Christ, Humanity's
Magnet by Rev. W. L. Pickard, of the Baptist
church.
Israel's Golden Fruitage by Rev. J. B. Whitford of the Methodist church.
Sermon to Business Men by Rev. J. A. Ecob
of the Presbyterian church.
Saving, a Sacrifice by Rev. J. A. Wilson a
Prof, in a university of Cal.
A Flower Sermon by F. W. Farrarof London,
Eng. All are interesting and well worthy of a
careful perusal. Pub. by G. Holzapfel, Fredericksburg, Pa.
pecially will be very much interested to know
what Prof. Sizer has to say about those who
are anticipating a move toward the White
House.
Article No. 2 on Phrenology and Psychology
by John W. Schull. Phrenotypes and Side
Views of several persons now prominently before the public.
Fits and Misfits by V. S. Wisner with this
prominent question "How to be successful."
Child Culture has some very fine illustrations, and shows the growing interest that is
being manifested in the bringing of children
into this world. Being born right the first
time may go a long way toward a successful
second birth, etc , etc. Fowler and Wells Co.,
27 East 21st St., New York City, N. Y.
The last thing written by Mrs. Harriet
Beecher Stowe, only a few days before her
death, was a loving acknowledgment to the
public for fond remembrances and tokens and
expressions of affectionate esteem, on her 85th
birthday, which she sent to Tlie Ladies' Home
Journal. In tha next issue of this magazine it
will be published in fac simile. It reflects the
beautiful nature of the gifted authoress, and
by her death has become her last message to
the American public.
From the newsboy on the street to Commander Ballington Booth, people are familiar
nowadays with the "Moody and Sankey" Gos
pel Hymns. Twenty-five years ago it was different. It was with fear and trembling that
Mr. Sankey made his first attempt at using
these hymns publicly in Scotland, one evening in November, 1873. Public denouncement
had been made there of his "human hymns,"
and "kist o' whistles," as his small cabinet
organ was called by the Scotch. The outcome
of this and subsequent meetings, and a laughable incident in connection with the "kist,"
are to be told by Mr. Sankey himself in the
forthcoming issue of The Sunday Schojl
Times.
John D. Wattles & Co., 1031 Walnut St.,
Philadelphia, Pa.
"Cuba's Struggle for Liberty" is the subject of a fully ilhistrated article in Frank
Leslie's Popluar Monthly for August. It is
written by Fidel G. Pierra, one of the leading
spirits of the Cuban Delegation in New York,
and contains portraits of Generals Gomez,
Maceo, Marti, Carillo, Sanchez, Garcia, Rodriguez and Palma, and some interesting views.
Another feature of this number is an article
on the Christian Endeavor Society, by Rev.
Francis E. Clark, its president and founder,
with many attractive illustrations. The great
Lee Series is continued with the first of two
papers on General Lee's part in the battle of
Gettysburg, by Colonel John J. Garnet, Confederate Artillery. "The Making of a Piesident," by Rufus R. Wilson, tells about nominating conventions, cost of electing a President, etc., and gives portraits of William MeKinley. President Cleveland, T. B. Reed W
C. Whitney, W. E. Russell and W. L Allison.
There are papers on Anarchism, Montenegro,
Salisbury and Wells Cathedrals, and a particularly  well illustrated article on Nashville
The Phrenological Journal for August
has beautiful Notes of Mr. William McKinley
and Mr. Garret A. Hobart.   Republicans,  es--><pb n="137" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes referring to the early history of the shakers in the United States, no. 3" TEIform="index"/>Notes Referring to the Early History of the Shakers in the United States. No. 3.</head><p TEIform="p">I WAS now hurrying on my way home and felt measurably released, as I thought I never could
                            become like the Sisters. Distinctly I heard Mother's footsteps and then her voice. She was
                            looking for me, and said, "AVhere is that young woman ?" The Sisters in the kitchen
                            replied,She has just passed out. "Call her back," said Mother, "that she may bid me
                            good-bye." I stopped involuntarily and turned around, and saw Mother at the door. The
                            Sisters then told me what Mother had said, and I went back to excuse myself as I could not
                            bear to be other than polite to so beautiful a woman. I told Mother I could not stay,
                            although I liked them all very much. I knew I could not be like them and I could not remain
                            as I knew my people were waiting for me to take breakfast, at my father's house. "0," said
                            Mother, "then you thought you would not come again." As these were my thoughts I hardly knew
                            what to say, but excused myself as best I could for the present. Not long after this I found
                            myself in the house with Mother Ann, where we enjoyed a very pleasant conversation. While
                            busily engaged Mother asked me, "Do you not want the people of God to pray for you?" I
                            replied that I did, and in an instant her arms were around me, and we were both on our
                            knees. After this I thought no more of going home. Four weeks passed away and found me most
                            of the time engaged in attending the meetings. The Sisters who worked in the kitchen were
                            busily employed. A great SEPTEMBER, 9. <pb n="138" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 138 THE MANIFESTO. many persons
                            who came to the meetings were provided with dinner, and it was not uncommon to have as many
                            as two hundred. When such large numbers were in the house, some feared that the timbers were
                            not strong enough to bear the strain. At one time Mother Ann called the children under
                            fourteen years of age and sent them to their homes, accompanied by some responsible person.
                            She then asked the young Sisters to accompany her into the door-yard, and soon half the
                            assembly went with Mother. At times there would be an intermission of thirty minutes, when
                            some would return to their homes, and others would come to attend the meetings. After
                            several weeks it was thought best for me to return home, which I did, but was at the
                            meetings nearly every evening. If it was stormy, or if I was weary, Mother would have me
                            remain in the Square House till morning. Mother often kneeled and prayed to God for me, and
                            then I felt a perfect freedom to talk with her. The second time Mother went to Petersham I
                            went with her. Mother wore a small cotton neckerchief and Mother Hannah Kendall offered her
                            a nice silk one, but Mother Ann said, "Nay, I do not think it is best for me to wear it. The
                            young folks may wear the silk and if I need another I will have a cotton one." Mother rode
                            in a carriage, as did several others, who accompanied her from Harvard and Shirley, I rode
                            on horseback. While we were assembled in meeting, some rough characters came to the house
                            and discharged their pistols at the windows. These were evidently the same characters who
                            came the day previous and so cruelly beat Aaron Wood, that they feared he would die. The mob
                            became frightened through fear that they had mortally injured Brother Aaron and suddenly
                            dispersed. Brother Aaron, however, recovered from the abuse. While at this place my sleeping
                            room was adjoining that of Mother Ann. One night after all had passed into deep sleep, I
                            heard Mother sorrowing to God, with such fervent cries, that I felt very sad and could not
                            sleep. As Mother wept I heard her say, "O God, I am but a poor woman, help thou me to
                            fulfill my mission." We remained at Petersham over three Sabbaths. Previous to leaving
                            Harvard for Niskeyuna, Mother Ann arranged for a company to visit the Believers at the last
                            named place. The next winter three Brethren and three Sisters, myself one of the party, left
                            home in an open wagon, on a very cold day. In the afternoon as we suffered so much with the
                            cold, we called at a public house to be made more comfortable by the fire. The Brethren had
                            decided to go six miles farther, but the landlord thought if we cared for our lives we
                            should remain in the house. We however, went on and were protected. On the last part of our
                            journey we rode all night. We called at one house <pb n="139" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. lSd
                            in the evening but they could not entertain us on account of a sick child and there was no
                            other way but to drive on. Early in the morning we reached Watervliet and were met by Mother
                            Ann and Father Calvin Harlow. Mother said, "These are the very people that I have borne on
                            my heart and soul all night." We were all made welcome, and soon after we entered the house
                            were comfortably provided with nice places to rest. Our dear friends thought it a miracle
                            that we were not frozen. After a rest of two hours wo were called to breakfast and ate
                            thankfully the food that was provided. Soon after this we went into the meeting, which, with
                            several intermissions continued till two o'clock the next morning. As we took our breakfast
                            on the second day, Mother Ann and the Elders walked around the table and waited upon us.
                            Mother said, "These Brethren and Sisters were very kind to us while we were at Harvard. They
                            always made us welcome to anything they had in the house." As there were large companies
                            constantly calling, some of us offered to assist the Sisters in the kitchen prepare the food
                            while we were there. {To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thoughts" TEIform="index"/>THOUGHTS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>By Abraham Perkins.</byline><p TEIform="p">IS there any Scriptural authority for communistic life and community of interest ? This is an
                            important question to which every member of our religious faith ought to be able to give an
                            intelligent answer, and a reason for such faith and the hope that is in them. In the early
                            days, which we believe to be the opening of the dispensation of Christ in his second
                            appearing, there were in many places and among many people great religious revivals and a
                            wonderful outpouring of the spirit of God. Among those greatly gifted and spiritually
                            baptized, was Joseph Meacham, an Elder of the Baptist church of New Lebanon, N. Y. He was a
                            man of extraordinary talents and extraordinary light and conviction of Christian duty.
                            Hearing of a marvelous spiritual work among a strange people denominated Shakers, at
                            Watervliet, N. Y., he visited them for the purpose of learning their character, and of
                            weighing and comparing the degree of the light of God they had received, with that found in
                            his own soul. Mother Ann directed Elder James Whittaker to open the testimony of Christ to
                            him. The labors were lengthy, arduous and of a most thoroughly searching character. At
                            length Elder Joseph said to Father James,How do you reconcile <pb n="140" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 140 THE
                            MANIFESTO. woman's speaking and having government in the Church of Christ, with the
                            Apostle's doctrine, which forbade it? ^ In answer to this and to the Messiahship, Mother Ann
                            told Father James to say to Elder Joseph, that the order of man in the natural creation is a
                            figure of the order of God in the spiritual creation. Man and woman standing in their proper
                            order are both required to lead and take the government of their family. If the man, the
                            father, is not present, the right of government belongs to the woman, the mother. It is the
                            same in the family of Christ." Marriage in the natural order constitutes the twain, one
                            flesh; the union and relation in the spiritual order produces one spirit,no more twain, but
                            one spirit. The natural order as the figure of tla spiritual in its perfection, embraces
                            both father and mother. Thus the spiritual creation, as the antitype, requires both father
                            and mother, Jesus, the father being absent; and Ann, the mother being present, (it being
                            evident she had the anointing,) the .power and authority of Christ on earth was committed to
                            her and to her was given the power to lead and govern her spiritual children. This answer
                            opened to Elder Joseph a vast field for contemplation and gave him a clear sight and great
                            understanding concerning the spiritual work of God. He saw the answer was incontestable and
                            could not be refuted, and accepted it as satisfactory. Is there proof from the bible of any
                            example, of the necessity of Community of interest for the Christian church. It seems like
                            consummate ignorance of the Scriptures, to affirm otherwise. In the 2nd chapter of the Acts
                            of the Apostles, we are told that the disciples of Christ, when the day of Pentecost was
                            fully come, were with one accord in one place, filled with the holy Spirit; that by them the
                            first Christian church was established at Jerusalem, on communistic principles; that all who
                            believed were together, and had all things common; that they sold their possessions, and
                            parted them to ah1, as every man had need. The 4th chapter tells us, that the multitude who
                            believed were of one heart and soul, and neither said any that ought of the things which he
                            possessed was his own, and that they had all things common. It certainly would seem that the
                            foregoing testimony is proof sufficient to exemplify the foundation on which to build a
                            Christian church. I believe it is generally conceded by the candid, and by persons of the
                            best intellect, that such a basis must be destructive to self and the vile passions of the
                            human heart, and without this crucifixion, there can be no perfect salvation. East
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is not enough..." TEIform="index"/>It is not enough...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is not enough that we have once swallowed truths; we must feed on them as insects on a
                            leaf, till the whole heart is colored by their qualities and shows its food in even the
                            minute fiber.</p></div2><pb n="141" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Contributed in answer to the question, 'when to speak, and when to keep silent?'" TEIform="index"/>Contributed in answer to the question," When to speak, and when to keep silent?"</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, Isabella" TEIform="persName"/>By Isabella Russell.</byline><p TEIform="p">There are moments, wh ui silence is golden, There are times, when the thought unexpressed, Is
                            productive of blessings unlooked for And we see and acknowledge 'twas best, Considering the
                            time and occasion, Our judgment to wisely suspend, For we do not, we can not see clearly,
                            Our way, from beginning to end. And we know there's a power overruling, A wisdom, we can not
                            control, Safely leading us onward, and upward, To the unexplored realms of the soul. Then
                            why should we pause, on life's journey, Or repine at the trials we meet When perchance it
                            may be, that without them Our heaven, would have been incomplete? There are moments, when
                            words fitly spoken Are worth more, than silver, or gold; There are great and momentous
                            occasions, When the unvarnished truth must be told ; There are errors and evils to conquer,
                            By the use of the tongue and the pen; There are times that demand earnest action On the part
                            of brave women and men. No sluggards, nor cowards are wanted To stand in the van of the
                            fight, 'Tis firmness, and courage, and daring, That win in the battle for right. Already
                            these times are upon us, There are dangers on every side, Requiring our utmost endeavor, To
                            lessen the incoming tide Of sensual and selfish indulgence Enslaving both body and mind, The
                            source, and the root of all evil, The bane and the curse of mankind. <pb n="142" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/>
                            U2 THE MANIFESTO. All honor and praise to the workers Engaged in the glorious strife,
                            Fulfilling the law of the Master, Resurrecting from death nnto life. These are the seers and
                            the prophets Foretelling the time yet to be, When knowledge shall fill the whole earth, As
                            the waters now cover the sea 1 The desert so lonely and barren, With beauty and grandeur
                            shall teem; God's world in His Infinite Goodness From sorrow and sin will redeem. Already
                            the harvest is ripening, And 'tis time for the reapers to go, In the power, and the
                            strength, and the wisdom Which only God's love can bestow. But those who would benefit
                            others, Must stand on the rock that is sure; From the fountain corrupt and unholy Proceed
                            not, sweet waters and pure. The freedom obtained by our Savior At the cost of his own
                            selfish life, Is ours, if we're willing to suffer, And endure to the end of the strife.
                            Sweet purity now, and forever, Our time-honored motto should be, Till we reach the fair
                            portals of heaven, And stand in the ranks of the free. Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thoughts on character" TEIform="index"/>THOUGHTS ON CHARACTER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barrett, Andrew D." TEIform="persName"/>By Andrew D. Barrett.</byline><p TEIform="p">IT is said "Out of the abundance of the heart, the mouth speaketh." As the spring-time is the
                            season for sowing seed for material aid, so is youth the spring-time for sowing the seeds of
                            a virtuous life that will form those principles that mark the perfect man or woman, In order
                            to form these principles there is something higher than the mere gaining of earthly fame or
                            power to be considered. There are victories over self to be won; treasures of immortal
                            inheritance to be gained, which will brighten and adorn the spirit. If this happy con- <pb n="143" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 143 dition can be attained by self abnegation, it will
                            be well worth the labor. How true it is that humanity needs to pass through a spiritualizing
                            process, needs to cultivate a devotional spirit which will lift the soul above the narrow
                            confines of the exclusive circle of me and mine, into a condition of harmony and purity,
                            where they may claim a relationship to the angels. Habits that are formed in early life,
                            generally make a lasting impression. Much of our education is taken from books and it is
                            very necessary that we select the right ones. Books and papers help to determine the mental
                            tastes, and to form the character. Then how important it is that the mind be directed
                            aright. The perusal of stories that are filled with scenes of strife or with reports of
                            wrong doing on the part of their heroes is not calculated to awaken very deep thought
                            concerning the duties of life* "Faith without works is dead." It had better be "Hands to
                            work and heart toward God," agreeably to the teaching of Mother Ann Lee. It is evident that
                            "Without the vision the people perish." And without a spiritual ministration the people will
                            sink into infidelity. "As the twig is bent so is the tree inclined." So with habits formed
                            in early life. If formed aright they will lead in the path of virtue, and will point upward
                            to the goal of perfection. A bad resolution is better broken than kep ; but it is still
                            better not to make a bad resolution. My dear young friends, to you belongs the successorship
                            of this great inheritance. You must study well the duties of life, make yourself an
                            interested worker in the social, moral and religious interests that are around you ; have
                            your principles thoroughly based on truth if you become an heir of this eternal kingdom.
                            Narcoosee, Fla.</p></div2><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Fred Aitkin and Brother..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Fred Aitkin and Brother...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Scotland, Glasgow, June 1896" TEIform="index"/>Glasgow, Scotland. June, 1896.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Fred Aitken and Brother :What a shame of me, but writing is a very weary job;
                                "better late than never." When yours came we were at tea on a Saturday afternoon and I
                                was saying how glad I would be if you could walk in. I keep missing you and wondering
                                how you are getting on, so you guess yours was gladly received. We all three wanted it
                                at once, still it was short and just like you. A few days after I received your face on
                                paper, it was good of you to remember me with one. Glad you had a good time crossing. Am
                                much wondering how you are getting on now and often try to send a wave of kindness out
                                to you. I do miss you, there are so few I am in close touch with. Well now do you find
                                it easier to serve one Master where you are, than <pb n="144" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 144 THE
                                MANIFESTO: you did to try to, here? To serve in the struggle for djiily bread and at the
                                same time live according to oiir light toward all ami toward our own uplifting, in the
                                heat of discord felt and unseen. I find, at times, a severe serving of two Masters,
                                which He said could not be done. Mammon we need, God I can not do without. What then is
                                to be done? Something within me says, "Be patient child, "man does not live by bread
                                alone." "Life is more than meat." Will you be so kind as to let me know how you feel
                                inwardly and outwardly with the Shakers. Try and spare me time for a long account of
                                yourself and what you think of me having thoughts of setting sail for Mount Lebanon.
                                Have you felt homesick? Have you made friends? Do you feel at rest and peace and gaining
                                ihOre knowledge? I would so like a report of the land. I hope you can send grapes like
                                those of Eschol. Your sincere friend and sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mackie, Isabel" TEIform="persName"/>Isabel Mackie.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Mrs. Mackie..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Mrs. Mackie...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mt. Lebanon, July 1896" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. July, 1896.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Mrs. Mackie :From your letter I judge that you want me to give you an account of
                                myself and my manner of life here. Well, I wrote Mr. Wilson, quite, a long letter,
                                giving him that sort of information, and asked him to acquaint you with the substance of
                                it, hoping that he would give it to you to read intoto. So I must just repeat myself. My
                                first experience here was a week in the visitor's room. In this room, those who come to
                                inquire into Shakerism live, until such a time as they have satisfied themselves and the
                                Elder and Elflress that they wish to become a member of a Shaker family. While I was
                                there I was visited frequently by the Elder, and various Sisters, and by the Eldress,
                                Anna White, to whom I carried a letter of introduction from James McNish, as. you may
                                remember. As usual with strangers I was very reserved and shy, but in my own way, I was
                                observing and drawing my conclusions. Before being admitted as a member of a Shaker
                                family, you are required to "confess" or give some account of the mental, moral and
                                spiritual journey you have come through, which has led you up to coming to them. This
                                was pretty hard for me, for I am not in the habit of unbosoming myself to acquaintances
                                of a week's duration. However I gave the Elder, (in your case you would tell the
                                Eldress) some account of my moral struggles, and found myself installed as a Brother
                                that evening, sitting down to supper with the family and sharing a room with the others.
                                The first thing I was set to do was to learn to milk cows, and for a week, morning and
                                evening I wrestled three quarters of an hour with an old brownish, black cow in the
                                attempt to get half a pail of milk. At the end of the week it was still a struggle for
                                me, and in pity for the cow, or for me, I'm <pb n="145" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 145
                                not sure which, I was taken off milking, and set for ni}T morning duty to groom an old
                                horse, which I continue to do until this day. This is done before breakfast, which is
                                served at six o'clock. After breakfast I do whatever is set for me to do; sometimes it
                                is to hoe corn,- again weed onions, paint wagons and sleighs, (I have done much of this
                                work since I came here,) or anything that needs doing.' We had spring's cleaning soon
                                after I came here, and I helped some in this line, whitewashing, and doing anything to
                                help those who had the work in hand. The Sisters' work is quite as varied. They look
                                after the clothing of the Brethren, darning socks, sewing on buttons and in a general
                                way keeping their wardrobe tidy. Duties they have without number, cooking, baking and
                                housekeeping, and in spare times, we have eight sewing machines where shirts are made
                                for a firm in the city. Under the direction of the Deaconesses all the Sisters take a
                                regular turn at these various duties. In the summer there are berries of various kinds
                                to be gathered; currants, cherries, gooseberries and in the fall there are apples to be
                                stored for the winter. This the Sisters do with aid from the Brethren as their work will
                                allow. And now, do I like, it? No and yes. My old man, the personal, egotistical self,
                                does not altogether enjoy it just yet. Ho does not get much to feed him, is hungry and
                                kicks accordingly. For the ordinary natural man, there is but little here to make him
                                feel comfortable and a good deal to make him feel very uncomiortable; which is good. But
                                for that part of you which is upper, for the real me, the higher self, the Christos, the
                                Christ, call it what you like, it is my honest belief that if there be anywhere on the
                                face of the earth where he can find a substantial environment to grow in, it is here.
                                Now I do not want to indulge in any "high falutin." In all circumstances one can have an
                                ideal and work towards it; but here you have the help, which comes from the
                                companionship of others who are on the same road as yourself, and where you can get the
                                opportunity to bring your whole life from rising in the morning to lying down at night,
                                into harmony with the best you know of what you ought to be. Here you have the
                                opportunity, step by step, of steadily eliminating from your character, the dross and
                                rubbish. The influence of the place helps you to do this, nay, drives you to do so,at
                                least to try. You could not stay here, and be comfortable without making some attempt to
                                get farther on the road to holiness. You would have to leave. Endeavor is in the very
                                air. This is at least how I have felt. I find the struggle hard at times but I shall
                                stick to it like grim death. "Tasks in hours of insight willed Can be in hours of gloom
                                fulfilled," says H^tthew Arnold; and in my hours of depression, here, (and I've had
                                some, I can tell you) I try to remember the resolution I came to in a better <pb n="146" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 146 THE MANIFESTO. moment, and go stumbling on, in the dark as it may be,
                                but knowing that the day cometh. So it is more than likely that I shall stay here. May
                                be I shall have the pleasure of seeing you here also. I think you would find a real home
                                here ; find soul-fellowship with the sisterhood, and I believe some would find
                                fellowship with you. I read your letter to them, and-they think this is just the place
                                for you; still, weigh it well before you decide to sell up and come. I remember that you
                                were once in this country before, and left it again in hurry and disgust. You might, do
                                the same again ; or want to. Perhaps I have spoken rather too highly of the Shakers of
                                the North family at Mount Lebanon, for I can only speak of what I know best; so I will
                                add that you are not to expect a very Kingdom of Heaven here, but you may expect to find
                                an honest attempt to form the nucleus of such a thing. Shakerism has progressed a good
                                deal since it was first founded by Aun Lee, but it is the hope and belief of this
                                family, that it will progress still farther, uever cease progressing in fact. We are
                                thorough believers in the continuous unfoldment and evolution of the human spirit and
                                along side of that runs all other progress. From a few pamphlets which I enclose, I hope
                                you will gain all the other information you may desire, as to the present day aspect of
                                Shakerism, and after reading, perhaps you might pass them on to such as may be
                                interested in the subject. Good bye for the present.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Aitkin, Fred" TEIform="persName"/>Fred Aitken.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Influence" TEIform="index"/>INFLUENCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Belden, Emoretta" TEIform="persName"/>By Emoretta Belden.</byline><p TEIform="p">A ROUND each person is a subtle atmosphere in which he lives and ./TV moves. It is a part of
                            himselfit is his personality, and whether it be weak or strong it leaves an impression on
                            his associates. This power, when exerted to sway the feelings or conduct of another, is
                            called influence. An influence for good, like the sunshine is cheering, lifegiving,
                            invigorating; while its opposite could better be compared to a poisonous vapor, blasting,
                            deadening to soul-life and growth. It is very subtle in its action working gradually to its
                            culmination. We can hardly estimate what our influence means to another. It is not only felt
                            to-day, to-morrow, or next week, but it reaches forward even to eternity. On every page of
                            history we see the effect of conditions and events of the past. We read of what powerful
                            minds have done in bringing order from chaos at the time when we were without a settled
                            government,we see the degrading effect of slavery upon the people and the country, and later
                            of the influence of the Civil War. All this is felt by us to-day, though we may not be aware
                            of the fact. <pb n="147" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFES TO. 147 Paul said, "None of us liveth to
                            himself and no man dieth to himself." He also admonishes us to put no stumbling block in
                            another's way, but rather to "Bear the infirmities of the weak," and seta noble example to
                            our brethren who are weak in the faith. "If meat make my brother to offend, I will eat no
                            flesh while the world standeth." Doubtless these words have influenced thousands of earnest
                            souls, and will many more. Evidently it becomes the duty of all Christians to resolve,If an
                            unpleasant and wrong act, look, word or manner will cause my friends to fall, I will deny
                            myself of them, "While the world standeth." Not only great apostles like Paul; great
                            preachers like Beecher; great generals like Grant, or great men and women in other vocations
                            wield a powerful influence, but every one, has a mighty power for good or evil in the circle
                            in which they associate. There is nothing of so much value as the human soul and it is a
                            very solemn matter that we are accountable for the influence of our example in the sight of
                            all men. "If any little word of mine May make a life the brighter; If any little song of
                            mine May make a heart the lighter; God help me speak that little word And take my bit of
                            singing, And drop it in lonely vale, And set the echoes ringing." West Pittsjield, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Charity is indeed a heaven sent messenger..." TEIform="index"/>Charity is indeed a heaven sent messenger...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Charity is indeed a heaven sent messenger; she goeth forth as an angel with consolation on
                            her tongue, love in her heart, pity in her eyes and relief in her hands; she inclines her
                            ear to the suffering and the poor; she seeketh out distress, nor ceases from morning to
                            evening her mission among the homes of the sorrowing; she heeds not the scorn of the proud,
                            the shrinking of the fearful, the eyes of the inquisitive, nor rain, nor wind, nor the
                            bitter frost, but keeps on, and her way is compassed about with gladness. The hungry, the
                            ill-clad, the sick and despairing rejoice at her approach. She shuns ostentation; she has no
                            set time for her labors, but worketh always for want, suffering and grief are ever in her
                            path. She pities the afflicted and is ever mindful of what she owes herself in her duty to
                            others ; her motto,"Love God with all thy heart, and thy neighbor as thyself.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Seneca" TEIform="persName"/>Seneca.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The highest form of Christian experience..." TEIform="index"/>
                            The highest form of Christian experience...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The highest form of Christian experience, is always in harmony witn present duty ; does all
                            things right and well, first, by estimating all things in themselves, and their relations
                            just as they ought to be estimated, and then corresponding to this just estimate by an
                            equally just conduct.</p></div2><pb n="148" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. SEPTEMBER, 1896. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the
                            "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all
                            communications to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. TERMS. One copy one
                            year, postage paid. .50</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. July. Thermometer. Bain. 1895. 67.62 4.75 in. 1896.
                                71.19 3.125 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 90 above 0 Lowest " " " " 48 " " Number of
                                rainy days " " 7 " clear " " " 13 " cloudy" " " 14 C. G. Meed. Soutn Family. Aug. 1896.
                                ''Bless the Lord, O my soul, and forget not all his benefits." We have read with
                                interest the pages of the last Manifesto, and pronounce them all good, but find the
                                article by Grace A. Brown especially inspiring. The summer has been made joyous by the
                                presence of a party from Enfield, N. H., who passed one day with us. We were also
                                delighted to. meet our mutual friends and former neighbors, Dr. Hellen I. Woodworth and
                                mother, who spirit a couple of weeks visiting acquaintances in this Community. While
                                this section represents a marked fruit famine, the mountains have generously furnished
                                us with an abundance of the healthful and refreshing blueberries, nearly thirty bushels
                                having been gather-, ed by the family who, early and late, considered the berries of the
                                mountain, how they grow. Peace and quiet reigns throughout our home, with occasionally a
                                ripple of excitement induced by a wrecked bicycler who always finds here the "good
                                Samaritan." Brother Wm. Thrasher, the good man of centenarian fame is still an
                                inhabitant of earth. One hundred year's acquaintance with physical life finds him
                                wonderfully attached to terrestrial scenes. We believe with Dr. Talmage "to those who
                                are fitted for sailing to the Summer land, theirs will be not a landing on a rockbound
                                coast but a pulling of their boat amid cacti and groves of orange." Such will be the
                                welcome home of our Brother. Genevieve DeGraw. North Family. Aug. 1896. "Beautiful and
                                lovely are thy courts O Zion." Glory rests upon thy hills and peace within thy valleys.
                                "If our home is so beautiful here, what must it be in the world to come?" Our beloved
                                sister Emily Offord, might now give us an answer. On Aug. 2nd p.m. a number of dear
                                friends from Hancock and a large attendance from all the families of Mt. Lebanon met at
                                Canaan where her memorial meeting was held. Rich in tributes of affection and praise,
                                sweet in inspiring song and strong in the living testimony that appreciates the present
                                good while recognizing the need for future increase, more than twb hours were pressed
                                full of heavenly ministrations. Special note was made relative to the superior mentality
                                of the departed."A student of rare ability whose deepest les- <pb n="149" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                MANIFESTO. 149 sons were learned from her own heart." With courage undaunted and a grasp
                                of principles of which only strong minds are capable, she lived and ministered the faith
                                of the Gospel, worked in its present, and for its future unfoldment. Her soul atmosphere
                                was courage and helpfulness to all around her. None name her but to bless. Some earnest
                                souls prepared by the Spirit are finding with us their only true home. Our worthy Sister
                                G. A. Brown is spreading the light among many interested friends on Long Island. The
                                army worm attacked several fields of fine grain consuming about one third; higher ground
                                escaped. Berries are abundant and early apples bring a good price in market. General
                                health prevails. Catherine Allen.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Aug. 1896. Veky acceptable is the endorsement of those New York physicians, as given in
                                the previous Manifesto, that a life of chastity is the best remedy to annihilate
                                existing evils. What better declaration could be given in favor of our doctrine, from
                                those not of our Order: "Be ye therefore perfect even as your Father in heaven is
                                perfect." The great, generous Creator of all good, freighted this world with mineral,
                                wood and floral wealth for the benefit of mankind; and as we appreciate the products of
                                the earth, surely the grander gifts of the Infinite should be desired, to obtain which,
                                the cultivation of the virtues of Christ must be given thought to, as readily as the
                                educational, domestic or mechanical work entered upon, if satisfactory results in
                                spiritual growth would be obtained. As usual at this season of the year, a walk through
                                our village would reveal to the observer the Sisters busy with domes tic and educational
                                affairs, also the making of fancy work for sale. Brethren con cerned with mill work,
                                business, trading and gardening. Quite a heavy and very creditable job has recently been
                                done at our Office horse barn, wholly by the young brethren, in the relaying of the
                                floor, and the rebuilding of the stalls for the horses. All, we trust, are especially
                                concerned about the sacred responsibility entailed upon us as a Church to let our light
                                so shine that others seeing our works may know that there are joys of the Spirit unknown
                                to the selfish or sensual and duties of life which only a God-loving mortal-loving and
                                service-loving soul can perform. George H. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. Aug. 1896. The editorial in August Manifesto has the true tone in the
                                sentiments expressed. Just such testimony should be constantly kept before the minds of
                                religionists of all schools and degrees of thought to remind them that the Church of
                                Christ, does not use the weapon of persecution to enforce its views upon mankind. We
                                have lately finished the perusal of "The History of the Reformation;" a work of some 800
                                pages. To view the depth of spiritual degradation and superstition to which the human
                                mind at that time had sunken, it is not to be wondered at that in its efforts to burst
                                the fetters that bound it the zeal and enthusiasm manifest should at times be paramount
                                to its wisdom. We would like to have some one who possesses greater insight into the
                                workings of the human soul tell us why it is that of all the commotions among mankind,
                                the one waged in the name of religion, so called, has been the most heartless and
                                vindictive. On the 21st of July we had a pleasant call from M. C. Schofield, of Guelph,
                                Canada; a mutual friend of the family and an old subscriber to The Manifesto who spent a
                                week very pleasantly with us, studying communistic life in its various phases. <pb n="150" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 150 TEE MANIFESTO. On the 28th ult. a party of young people with
                                dinner basket and tin pails started for the huckle-berry swamp where we spent the day
                                very pleasantly in gathering the fruit. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Aug. 13, 1896. What a fearful mortality this midsummer hot wave has created. Cities and
                                villages and even the farmers' homes on the hills and mountains have all been invaded If
                                it is the work of the planets, and some think it is, then it must be a celestial hot
                                wave, and the force that sends it is quite beyond our control. The hay crop that has
                                been secured is of good quality, and even in quantity has no disappointment. The corn
                                for the silo promises to be an excellent crop.* Some of it has already a height of 12
                                feet and is still moving upward. We may now anticipate a limited crop of apples for the
                                winter hut the prospect is not at all flattering. The sweet and favorite blueberries
                                have been quite abundant and some twentj bushels have been gathered for winter use.
                                Including all the heat that has been poured upon us, and the free use of green corn,
                                green peas and green cucumbers, with an occasional dish of ice cream, it is a wonder to
                                see how few have fallen victims to some of the ills in the long list for summer. Let us
                                give thanks that our stomachs are so wonderfully, if not fearfully made. Henry C.
                            Blinn.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoossa, Florida" TEIform="index"/>Narcoossa, Florida</head><p TEIform="p">July 28, 1896. A rainy season commenced with the first of May and continued until the
                                second week in July. From Feb. 28, until April 28, there was no rain, but two or three
                                light showers. We again desire rain Our watermelons have amply supplied us; peach trees
                                have put forth three, four and five branches, two feet and over in length, with an
                                overstock of latterals we took off, and all these since Dec. 25th. The blossoming pine
                                with its great bayonet green leaves reaching to your shoulder is a marvel of beauty when
                                the thick scarlet bud begins to peep into the light and spread out the strong leaves
                                like a vase. There are about fifty apples, and one hundred and fifty young plants; these
                                plants are worth thirty cents apiece. Before this greets you the increase will be five
                                fold. Let me seepotatoes, peaches, melons, pineapples, rice, milk, and eggs are already
                                a success under our care and by the blessing of God. Climate is perfect, and our health
                                in a general way corresponds with our courage and hope. We are all, in a sense, exiles
                                and feel the sepaiation from associations that were dear and pleasant, but on the whole,
                                this land is a "Promised Land" and no mistake. One other, and the greatest blessing we
                                have, is a knowledge of the Gospel of Christ. Andrew Barrett.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Aug. 1896. Since last we met for our chat about home, summer's rains and suns have
                                nourished and warmed the seed entrusted to keeping, and we find harvest time approaching
                                with its treasures of mellow fruits and sweet flowers, given for the comfort and
                                enjoyment of man. Not an over supply, we think, will be meted as our portion this ysar,
                                in the line of fruits, but enough for the comfort of our family. Berries have been very
                                abundant. Huckle-berries especially plentiful. For five weeks the hills of ''Old
                                Berkshire" were constantly having the "Blues." Troops of laughing children, eager for
                                the pleasure of picking, and older children, equally anxious for the result of such
                                labor, flocked to them daily, returning well loaded with the berries, nearly six hundred
                                quarts gathered. Black-berries are likewise plentiful. <pb n="151" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                MANIFESTO. 151 On the evening of the 6th inst. we were visited by a terrific thunder
                                shower. The thunder and lightning were both violent and continuous and the rain beat
                                upon the dry earth with fury. It lasted for about three hours. Many fires occurred
                                around us, there being seven within a radius of four miles, most of them were the
                                burning of barns, loaded with newly gathered hay. We, escaped without the least harm,
                                even the oats, then enduring the threshing process, were all safely under shelter, owing
                                to the wise forethought of Brother Ira, who apprehended the threatened storm. Our
                                friends at the Canaan family, whose joys and sorrows we always share, invited us to
                                attend the farewell meeting of Sister Emily Offord. At such seasons how closely we
                                approach the pearly gates, catch a glimpse of the glory within, the reward awaiting
                                every faithful worker here below. Our flowers are in blossom delighting the eyes of
                                every beholder. Their beautiful tints and sweet fragrance, cause them to be loved by
                                all. Arranged in handsome bouquets, they find their way around the house, like
                                messengers of love, telling of an All-wise Power constantly caring for, not only the
                                needs, but the pleasures of his children. Fidelia Estabrook.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute of love to our sister Emily Offord" TEIform="index"/>Tribute of Love to our Sister
                            EMILY OFFORD.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>By Eldress Anna White.</byline><p TEIform="p">An invisible world of intelligence "Lies around us like a cJoud, A world we can not see; Yet
                            the sweet closing of an eye May bring us there to be." Our Sister has entered upon this new
                            stage of existence; she has forded the river that separates time from eternity; she has
                            passed the pearly portals all must pass, and vanished from mortal sight. Having been
                            thoroughly impregnated with the principles of our Order, and living in conformity thereto,
                            she has before this been made a welcome guest by members of the Order, constituting the
                            Church of Christ, or, the Mother Church in the Spirit world. The change commonly called
                            death, is to her a most happy change, a joyous realization of the faith she loved above all
                            other. In early life she took upon her the sa-' cred vow of consecration; a consecration
                            that means the relinquishing of the old life of nature for the new life of the Spirit; the
                            demolishing of the me and mine system, and the adoption of the principles of equality, which
                            entirely dethrone selfishness and give the largest possible scope for the rounding out of a
                            beautifully exalted character; a character of which she was a fit representative. In the
                            atmosphere of her life there was health, peace, happiness. Her brightness of spirit
                            overshadowed the suffering of body. For many years she fought with unrelenting energy
                            against physical disease, which was mainly inherited. Sister Emily believed in the dominance
                            of mind over matter, and through this faith kept the latter at bay to a wonderful extent.
                            The subject of mind controlling matter is one that is now being investigated and accepted by
                            a large class of thinking men and women. Upon those lines we have all had our experiences
                            and can witness to the fact that there is far more truth than fiction in the doctrine. When
                            we allow faith the pre-eminence, our possibilities will be greater. We are yet children in
                            the rudimentals, and it is well for us to keep there, that we may enter fully into the
                            kingdom of heaven state before we aim to ascend to loftier heights or are called there by
                            travail and experience. The least in this kingdom are greater than the wise and learned of
                            this world, because they have a knowledge of the spiritual worldthe world of causationand
                            apply that knowledge to the practical things of this life, thereby creating a heaven below,
                            preparatory to entering a heaven above. OFFORD <pb n="152" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 152 THE MANIFESTO. No
                            one is without his spiritual experience. I am not without mine. The night after Sister
                            Emily's ascension she 3ame to me. I recognized her at once ind said, "Emily, I know you are
                            here; you have kept your promise; come to me often." Again I was aroused by hearing most
                            angelic singing, I thought surely every one in the house must hear it, and said aloud to my
                            room mate, "Do you hear that heavenly music? it is Emily singing." She said, she did not.
                            After this we both heard the sound of voices in earnest conversation. One verse of the
                            stanza ran thus; Oh, joyous, joyous happy thought! From pain and death set free, On wingo of
                            love I soar aloft Away, oh earth from thee; Away from thee,still not away, The heavens and
                            earth are blended, When from the night into the day The Spirit hath ascended. Showing that
                            though here on earth we have the power to rise in the resurrection and life of Christ by the
                            maintenance of the pure, gospel testimony of our Mother. In one of her "many mansions" we
                            find our beloved Sister like a caged bird set free, decorated in garments bright and
                            shimmering, the garments she has woven thread by thread, by kindly thoughts, by loving words
                            and good deeds. There we shall meet her. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The strong animals that do the world's work..." TEIform="index"/>
                                The strong animals that do the world's work...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The strong animals that do the world's workthe elephant, horse, mule, ox etc., eat only
                                vegetables. No one thinks of f eeding them flesh to add to their strength or fleetness.
                                No wolf or other predatory animal can catch a deer, antelope, caribou or moose on a fair
                                run, but by stealth, sly cunning, watching and springing or hunting in packswhere the
                                fugitive doubles an his tracks and they cut across. So of the hounds and hare.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="O'Leary, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. O'Leary, M. D. in Human Nature.</byline></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bread and fruits..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Bread and fruits...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Bread and fruits, in the larger sense of the term, contain all the essentials of a
                                correct human diet, whether for flesh, blood, brain or bones. Unripe fruit proves more
                                or less injurious to every one. Currants, gooseberries and apples gathered before they
                                are half ripe and stewed or made into pies, are common. These cooked fruits contain all
                                the noxious ingredients that the raw ones do. The sun in the process of ripening may
                                change them to healthy ingredients, but cooking does not and can not do it. In this way
                                a world of unripe fruit, so to say, is eaten and a world of disease and premature death
                                is the consequence.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Alcott" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Alcott.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Appeal of Alexander M. Nicol..." TEIform="index"/>Appeal of Alexander M. Nicol...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Appeal of Alexander M. Nicol,Look up. We are his chosen people. We belong to a God raised
                            movement. Men die, men fail, men falter, men surrender, but God lives and his work goes
                        on.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What God wants of us..." TEIform="index"/>What God wants of us...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">What God wants of us is that out reaching bigness that ignores all littleness of aims, or
                            love, or creeds, and clasps all Earth and Heaven in its embrace.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilcox, Ella Wheeler" TEIform="persName"/>Ella Wheeler Wilcox.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dillon, Judith" TEIform="index"/>Judith Dillon
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Judith Dillon, at South Union, Ky. July 8, 1896. Age 93 years, 5 mo. and 26 days. Sister
                                Judith is the last of the children of the first settlers in this Society. She has spent
                                eighty-six years here, during which time, she held several offices of trust, and was
                                respected by all who knew her. J. C. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Offord, Emily" TEIform="index"/>Emily Offord
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Emily Offord, at Canaan, N. Y. July 30, 1896. Age
                                48 years and 8 months. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Evington, Ann E." TEIform="index"/>Ann E. Evington
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Ann E. Evington, at Pleasant Hill, Ky. Aug. 9, 1896. Age 61 years
                                and 1 mo. She entered the Community in 1849 and was beloved by her many friends. For
                                several years she took charge of the little girls, who sadly mourn their loss. J. W.
                            S-</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
and the Tennessee Centennial by Charles T.
Logan. The fiction in this number is particularly good, as is also the department for
young people, which contains contributions
by Horatio Alger, Jr., Edward S. Ellis, Minna
Irving and others.
The July Magazine Number of The Outlook
contains two illustrated articles in the nature
of character-sketches of the Republican and
Democratic candidates for the Presidency.
The article on Mr McKinley is written by Mr.
Murat Halstead, a personal friend of Mr. McKinley. The article on Mr. Bryan is written
by Mr. Richard Linthicum, a successful Chicago journalist. Both articles are illustrated
in an original and striking way. The feature
of the number is an article on the author of
"Uncle Tom's Cabin," the late Mrs. Harriet
Beecher Stowe, written by Mr. John R. Howard, who has intimate knowledge of the personal and literary history of Mrs. Stowe.
Fourteen illustrations will accompany the
article. Mr. Talcott Williams writes on -'The
Higher Life of Philadelphia." This is perhaps
the most finely illustrated of all the articles
printed in the series on "The Higher Life of
American Cities," and the article itself is of
unusual interest. Educational matters receive especial attention. An able article, and
one sure to provoke discussion, is that on
"Tendencies in Collegiate Instruction." by
Professor F. H. Stoddard, of the University of
the City of New York. In the scries on "The
Founders of Great Movements," there is printed an article on Dr. Francis E. Clark, founder
of the Christian Endeavor Society, which has
ust held its great annual meeting in Washington. The author is Mr. J. W. Baer Secretary of the United Society. There are many
pictures. ($3 a year. The Outlook Company, 13 Astor Place, New York.)
In commemoration of the fifty years of ex
istence of the firm, the proprietors of the  Sci
entific American, Munn   & Co.,  have   issued  a
special number of the Scientific American    We
have the number before us, covering 72 pages
with very numerous illustrations, sot e of e\
ceeding  interest as   being   reproductions of
what  were  scientific  notabilities of   former
days, others relating to subjects of modern or
immediate interest.   The first page of the paper contains a reproduction of sample pages
of early issues, veritable curiosities in a way
In one early issue, for instance, the Morse telegraph  is   spoken of, "a wonder of the  ige
which for some months has been in operation
between   Washington   and   Baltimore and is
likely   to  come into general use."   Another
page   gives   an  illustration  of an improved
railway car, while the Smith Electro magnetic
Machine  figures on  another page; all inter- 
eating scientific   thought of fifty yeais   ago
The text of the paper consists of series of   sn
tides on   leading  mechanical and   scientific
subjects; Electrical Engineering, Progress of
Printing, Bicycles, Telescopes, Photography,
Locomotives and the like.   These are all liberally illustrated.   It is, of course, impossible
to suppose that the advance of the last half
century, almost worthy  to be called greater
than the progress of all preceding ages, could
be presented within the limits of an encyclopedia; but the work on this issue of the Scientific American appears to have been very carefully done and no pains  seem  to have been
spared to make it cover its ground.   Some of
the   portraits  of   distinguished inventors, of
which quite a number are given, are exceedingly interesting; and the other illustrations,
as showing the transactions of the past fifty
yearsthe curiosity of  engineering and the
achievements of science and invention of the
same epochare exceedingly interesting. If
published in book form, it would represent a
volume of 442 ordinary sized puges. Price, 10
cents.   Mnnn & Co., Publishers, New York.
A LESSON FROM AFRICA.
Sometimes valuable information about ourselves comes from unexpected sources. Here
is something interesting about American baking powders all the way from Africa.
Rev. Bishop Win. Taylor, for several years
Methodist Bishop of Africa, says that the red
label of the Royal Baking Powder is famliar
to every housekeeper in America, is quite as
well known and the powder as highly prized
in every part of that continent to which civilization has extended. The Royal Baking Powder was taken to South Africa a great many
years ago by Mrs. Robinson, a missionary.
But its use soon spread beyond the Missions,
and it came to be 1 egarueu as a necessity by all
classes. It was found particularly valuable in
the mines and upon the rancii.es, and frequently sold at interior stations lor a dollar a pound.
Especially has it conduced to the comfort and
health of the missionaries, who would find
bread-making a sorry business without it.
A SUMMARY VIEW
 church,
OB
"United   Society   of  Believers,"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price, 50 els.
Another interesting fact is that no other
baking powder will stand service in that
country. Rev. Ross Taylor, the agent for African Missions, says: "During the past ten
years we have shipped Royal Baking Powder
regularly to our African missions, and for the
last four years to the exclusion of all other
brands, because of the testimony of our missionaries that it maintains its strength, freshness and purity in the tropical Ciimi: te, which
others do not. For instance, the superintendent of our mission in Angola, a work ih;:t is financially maintained on commercial lines, reported that lie could not hold his trade with
anything else but the Royal. We are Using it
in forty mission stations in Africa."
Here is a suggestive fact of value to American housekeepers. Though the presence of
this keeping quality in the Royal and the lack
of it in other powders is developed more conspicuously in the hot, moist climate of Africa
it exsists in the Royal and is deficient in the others as they are sold in this country in exactly
the same ratio. This natural test demonstrates more forcibly than a chemcial analysis
could the wide difference that exsists between
the different baking powders in their combination and actual practival value. The maintenance of its strength and freshness under
all climatic conditions is evidence that the
Royal powder is more accurately made and
composed of purer and better ingredients
such a powder only will give uniform results
in perfect foods and prove of the greatest economy in the saving of flour, butter and other
articles used in their production. N. Y. Christian Advocate.
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
AUTHORISED   RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY.
The religious basis of the Order must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
Scientific American
Aaency for 
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cream of tartar  baking   powder.
Highest of all in leavening strength.
 Latest   United   States   Government
Food report.
Royal Baking Powder Co., New York.
For Information and free Handbook write to
MUNN & CO., S6X Broadway, New York.
Oldest bureau for securing patents in America.
Every patent taken out by us is brourrht before
the public by a notice given free of charge in tiie
Largest circulation of any scientific paper In the
world. Splendidly illustrated. No intelligent
man should be without it. Weekly, 3.00 a
year; 1.50 six months. Address, MTJ-VN & CO,,
Publishers, 361 Broadway, New York City.
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
with large type  and on excellent paper.
It contains  130 pages and has
ILLUSTRATIONS
of the Shakers and their
The work gives  quite an extended account of the Several SOCIETIES, their
organization and general management.
Price, 50cts.
The New York
Dispatch.....
Oldest      and      Best     Recognized
Weekly     Paper     in   the    United
States.
Improved        Management,        and
Methods up to date.
A   Family   Journal
Of Morals and Public Interests,
Newsy, Literary, Scientific,
Humorous, Useful, Entertaining. Also G. A. R., Masonic
and Society News.
One Copy,  One   Year,   $2.50.
Post yourself on what is going
on in  New York.      Address
The  New York  Dispatch
15O Nassau Street, N. Y.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>