<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1104" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><date value="18810401" TEIform="date">April 1881</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">73- 96</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                    <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> APRIL, 1881. MANIFESTO. G. A, LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, N. Y. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT
                        CANTERBURY, N. H. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony: 4'Go 'preach the Kingdom of God!" ADDRESS ALL
                        COMMUNICATIONS TO G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1881. Vol. XL No. 4. L 60 Cents Per Annum. The Shaker " The Shaker
                        Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
--><pb n="73" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Resurrected flowers" TEIform="index"/>RESURRECTED FLOWERS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>CECELIA DEVYR</byline><p TEIform="p">Seek not within the darkness of the earth, Thy friends nor flowers; For lo ! their spirits
                            have a radiant birth Through death's dim hours. Ask for the mystery hidden in the light, For
                            eyes are blind. Seek for the veil that screens all mortal sight And heaven thou'lt find.
                            'Tis but the olden root the sod conceals, The fiowers are new. A recreative power the spring
                            reveals, Through heat and dew. The simplest blossom of the mountain pass, A marvel seems;
                            When 'neath the magic of the wondrous glass, Its beauty beams. And yet within this
                            revelation hides A marvel still; A life, a presence, calmly there abides, That makes us
                            thrill. Only the eye clairvoyant can behold The spirit flower Gathering its robes of purple,
                            pearl and gold, In dying hour. And yet, the eye clairvoyant, like the lens, A limit finds;
                            The infinite creation so transcends Our girded minds. Thronging the air with fragrance,
                            grace and bloom, Are unseen flowers; We feel their influence through the glow and gloom, Of
                            life's strange hours. They put their impress on the flake of snow; The penciling frost
                            Catches their outlines when the whirlwinds blow, And clouds are lost. The sun, that gives to
                            us this fertile ball, Has jealous light, That shuts out with a golden roof and wall, The
                            stars of night. And thus, the life external wraps the soul In fervid beams'; Conceals the
                            glories that around it roll, Beyond its dreams. Death waves his hand, all outward things
                            retreat; Then angels sing, Blest words wherein life's holy mornings meet; " Wake it is
                            spring." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peace" TEIform="index"/>PEACE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p">BY Peace is a word, whether written or spoken that seems to possess a charm, and is like balm
                            to the spirit ; but when carried into practical effect, it is done by self sacrifice at the
                            expense of pride, ambition, hatred and revenge. If we take counsel of unperTHE <pb n="74" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. verted reason, it will always decide as did one of the
                            wise men of olden time, that "Anger resteth in the bosom of fools," and ask in the name of
                            all that is good and true why it is that contending armies meet in hostile array clad in
                            habiliments of war under the influence of heated passion, to fight and slay each other,
                            under pretext — real or imaginary — of some wrong done, without being able to offer one
                            intelligent reason for so doing ? Individual, society or national wrongs can never be justly
                            settled by inflicting pain and suffering and committing a still greater wrong. Must we
                            continue to think, that, in this enlightened age, the nation's honor is dependent upon the
                            use of the sword ; and that there are no better means of settling disputations and
                            dissensions other than by the practice of grossest inhumanity, and turning all the powers of
                            mind and body to hate and revenge, and like wolves rend and devour those who should be our
                            friends and brothers ? Is it not far better to suffer and patiently endure a wrong than to
                            retaliate and render evil for evil ? Thus thought and thus taught Jesus, our great exemplar
                            and elder brother. War is wrong in principle and in practice. Let the. maxim " In time of
                            peace prepare for war," be changed ; and the principle be inculcated of peace and good will
                            to all nations and kindreds of earth. Let those influential positions in society as
                            teachers, leaders and rulers denounce war and show its hideousness and dark side, and cease
                            to justify wholesale murder, and glorify the abettors of war and its chieftains, while they
                            condemn and punish crime on a smaller scale committed by individuals. Tell us not that there
                            is honor and dignity in retaliation and revenge whether perpetrated by one individual, by
                            few persons or by many. It matters not if an army goes forth to battle, under cover of a
                            nation's flag, towering high, and with martial music and a chaplain in attendance to do the
                            praying, war is war, and neither priests nor people can change its nature, nor the effects
                            produced thereby. We repeat, let the adage " in time of peace prepare for war," be
                            discontinued and discountenanced by the rulers of the people who are placed in positions to
                            shape the destiny of nations, who by different codes of laws are forced to subserve their
                            purposes, and obey their behests, irrespective of their own convictions of right or wrong —
                            or rebel. And let such rulers and magistrates feel the weighty responsibility that rests
                            upon them, and remember that they hold the lives in their hands that will uplift humanity to
                            higher and better moral and social conditions, or to the opposite. The rulers of nations
                            have it in their power to render war disreputable by denunciation, and showing a better way
                            to redress wrongs. Let calm legislation, pointing to arbitration and mediation between
                            contending parties in lieu of the sword, take precedence in the national councils, and
                            instead of satiating the ambitions of vain mortals, by laudation, and crowning them with
                            laurels such as they seek, and men can bestow, ask them when the din of war has ceased, the
                            camp fires have died out, the sword lias been sheathed, and the cool of the day has
                            overtaken them, and reason has returned, to visit the widow and orphan, .whose home — if
                            they are fortunate enough to have one left to them — has been made desolate, by being bereft
                            of fathers, sons and brothers slain in battle; and to place their eyes upon maimed and
                            wounded soldiers, whose lives have been shorn of peace and happiness by the war demon, and
                            see if they will not be persuaded to bring all their weapons of war and lay them down at the
                            feet of the Prince of Peace, and doff the warriors' crown, and all the honors connected
                            therewith, and enrobe themselves in garments of peace, which they will have confidence to
                            appear in before recording angels. This the devotees of war and its principles, cannot do,
                            for the reason, that, by continuing to advocate war in principle and practice, they are not
                            " doing unto others as they would that others should do unto them." The readers of the "
                            Manifesto," will patiently bear with us, if we often refer to the subject of War and Peace.
                            It is a momentous question, and is one of the living issues of the present time, and demands
                            thought and attention. I think the public will pardon us, when we confess that we 74 <pb n="75" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 75 are slow of comprehension, and utterly fail to
                            understand how the high sounding professors of the Christian religion practiced by Jesus of
                            Nazareth, who by the Christ spirit plainly taught, that " they who take the sword shall
                            perish with the sword," as also the professed ministers who claim to preach the gospel of
                            peace and salvation, and at the same time, and from the same pulpits advocate war, and hold
                            up its champions as worthy the nation's praise and honor. We cannot see the propriety, if
                            any there be, in making marked demonstrations of loyalty to Jesus, and to the principles
                            which he boldly and fearlessly announced as the rule and guide of the Christian life and
                            character, by celebrating Christmas day and claiming to uphold and advance the cause, and at
                            the same time uphold and approve a cause diametrically opposite. Let those who name Christ
                            and claim to be his ambassadors, return blessing for cursing, and teach others to do the
                            same. Then they can consistently adore the character which Jesus formed by being identified
                            with the truth; and understanding^ join with angels in the song, " Peace and good will."
                            Such will prove that there is no " mystery in godliness," but mystery is' found in false "
                            theology." All hail the Prince of Peace ! and all joy to his true followers !</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Physical resurrection" TEIform="index"/>PHYSICAL RESURRECTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, W." TEIform="persName"/>W. PERKINS</byline><p TEIform="p"> It is widely known that Judge Comegys and his grand jury in Delaware, propose to indict and
                            punish as a criminal, R. G. Ingersoll, should he ever again lecture in the State. Their fear
                            is that persons may be led to doubt the orthodox dogmas of that Book. Some years ago it was
                            forbidden by a woman in Iowa to tell her daughters that our earth was round, since the
                            scriptures said it had four corners (Rev. 7, 1). So soon as her daughters took up their
                            geographies and gave heed to the evidence of stubborn facts, they would inevitably believe
                            in the spherical form of the earth, and disbelieve their mother's Bible. This is but a type
                            of a class numbering thousands who understand and administer the Bible against facts and the
                            rights of man, honest infidels result. Comstock &amp; Co. have made more infidels by
                            putting D. M. Bennett to prison for thirteen months, than he could have made in double that
                            time with his pen and tongue. Judge Comegys has done likewise in Delaware as to Ingersoll,
                            and he significantly thanks him for it. Honest, truth-loving men cannot follow orthodox
                            absurdities. Hence the Bible must be reasonably interpreted in conformity with facts and
                            science, or common sense will disbelieve it. This universal principle applies forcibly to
                            the dogma of bodily resurrection. If the scriptures literally assert this, stubborn facts
                            literally assert the contrary. Even were it possible for the bodies of the countless
                            billions of our earth to lie waiting for Gabriel's horn, in a state of preservation like
                            Egyptian mummies, it were an absurd miracle to re-spiritualize them. More than half gave up
                            the ghost, emaciated to skin and bones, or maimed, halt, blind, deaf, dumb, rickety and
                            bodily deformed. Are these to live again, as they died ? Such is material, identical
                            resurrection. Moreover, where hi the long meantime have been their spirits ? Have the good
                            been in the bliss of heaven, and the bad roasting in the orthodox hell ? If so, where is the
                            reason or scripture for ejecting them. Don Quix. oting them back to their miserable bodies
                            on earth and under command of Gabriel's horn, to be retransported whence they came ! Yet
                            still more absurd in the face of the fact, that there can be found no such bodies to
                            resurrect. For the greater part have for centuries disintegrated into countless forms of
                            vegetable and animal bodies. Their elements have, in a train of almost endless succession,
                            gone into weeds, grass, grains, bugs, worms and every species of animals. Were it therefore
                            possible for the bodies, yet in form of dry bones to reanimate and walk through the streets
                            of Jerusalem at the Crucifixion of Christ, it is utterly impossible, now or hereafter, to
                            find even the dust of one out of the billions of bodies once living and dying oh our earth.
                                <pb n="76" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 76 THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. To preach that they are in esse waiting"
                            for Gabriel's horn, is to assert startling falsehoods, occasioning1 wide-spread infidelity.
                            Is not the Shaker interpretation of spiritual resurrection into a new and higher life, the
                            more reasonable and true ? South Union, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Discord—concord: no. 2" TEIform="index"/>DISCORD-CONCORD: No. 2</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p"> There is in the individual human soul the same discord, originally, as in the human society,
                            passion warring with passion, and the light of truth and reason, as it enters, in the
                            conflict with native brutality and stupidity. We have this statement from an English poet:
                            '¦ Devils with devils damned, firm concord hold." But this is attributing to the diabolic
                            that which belongs exclusively to the divine. All that we know of the diabolic, whether
                            obtained from the records of human history, or by the observation of our individual selves,
                            shows a state of things the exact reverse of concord. The reader of history cannot avoid
                            being struck with the facility with which nations that have combined their forces for the
                            purpose of attacking some other warlike power will often dissolve that connection for some
                            apparent or fancied cause and turn their weapons against each other. Mere self-seeking or
                            self-glorification invariably engenders discord, whether in a nation or in the individual
                            soul. For this reason Jesus declared selfdenial to be the sole test of discipleship, this
                            being the only means by which the grace is obtained which assures union between different
                            persons, and harmony in the soul of each. " God is Love," is the fundamental doctrine of
                            Christianity. 'Love is harmony; In finite Love is therefore Infinite Harmony. This is
                            discoverable by the astronomer in the grand movements of worlds, but when we come to our
                            individual globe, the geologist and the historian speak of earth's upheavals, of the
                            clashing of elements, of continual conflicts arising among all peoples that have ever
                            inhabited the earth. How is this to be reconciled with the idea of Infinite Harmony? Some
                            have undertaken to solve the difficulty by supposing an existant principle, all of whose
                            acts tend to discord. Others opposed to this the idea of progress from original, lowest to
                            the highest conditions both in the physical and mental worlds, The geologist maintains that
                            there are abundant evidences on the surface of the earth itself of a condition of things in
                            the earliest ages, when it was unadapted to life, either vegetable or animal, but by gradual
                            changes it has become what we now behold it. So, the intellectual optimist assures us. it
                            has been with human society, in its first stages but little above the condition of the
                            brute, but gradually tending to higher and better things. The Christian believer who rejects
                            what has been styled orthodox Christianity, ficds nothing in this latter view inconsistent
                            with the teachings of Jesus. In the language of the poet Thomson, God is "Prom seeming evil
                            still educing good, And better thence again, and better still, In infinite progression."
                            But, to turn from theory to practice, how is one to assure himself that God is love, and
                            that the discordant feelings, appetites and passions inherent in human nature may be
                            removed, and something infinitely better take their place ? Let him test it for himself,
                            just as he would test the value of any thing that has been recommended to his attention.
                            Nothing can be simpler than the method of testing that Jesus himself has given, "Ask, and it
                            shall be given you." " But let him ask in faith." One has the proof within himself of the
                            harmony of the Divine Nature, when he has asked and received the inspirations of Divine
                            Love. The tendency of these inspirations is to harmonize all within him. His warring
                            passions cease their conflict, at least for the time being; his peace is like a river,
                            gentle in its flow, whose sediment is not so mixed with it as to prevent clear seeing. He is
                            satisfied of its divine origin, just as he is satisfied with the proofs of any truth
                            presented to his understanding. He needs then only to apply to the same source of inspira-
                                <pb n="77" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 77 tion until he has satisfied himself that
                            all within is harmony, peace and love. When all persons shall have done this, each for each,
                            we shall have a harmonious world. Earth will then have become heaven.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Human progress" TEIform="index"/>HUMAN PROGRESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p">Wake! pulseless muse, to throbbing life again, 'Till quickened currents course through every
                            vein, And inspiration thrills the heart, and brain, With glowing thoughts of fire. Thy voice
                            seems mute as winter's icy streams, Thy wings lie folded in oblivious dreams; Wake! and
                            ascend amid the glittering beams, And tune thy heavenly lyre. Touch the deep chords that
                            thrill the inner soul. Swell the grand song that brings complete control, 'Till symphonies
                            in rapturous waves shall roll, Uplifting hearts to heaven. Lo ! while time's lengthened
                            shadows fall apace, The history of past and present trace, Behold, how men of every clime
                            and race For life divine have striven ! Religion, latent in the human heart, Has of its life
                            forever been a part; Not fashioned by the skilful hand of art, Immortal germ so fair. Like
                            precious seed the husbandman hath sown, Who, patient waits until the harvests grown, So doth
                            the Father all His planting own, And nurtures it with care. The good sown broadcast by His
                            bounteous hand, From Asia's desert to Columbia's strand, Hath borne abundant fruit in every
                            land Where cultured soil was found. The swelling song of immortality, Hath rolled from
                            mountain, vale and restless sea ; From hearts of bondman, and from spirits free, The
                            circling globe around. Old are the scenes that first gave life and birth To seed, that
                            peoples now this glorious earth ; Seed, tliat contained the growth of highest worth, Grand
                            possibilities ! In man's crude state, and undeveloped sphere, Strange thoughts of God, in
                            stranger forms appear; The mirrored objects of His awe and fear He worshiped, but to please.
                            God works through laws for man's eternal good; His laws are love—when rightly understood.
                            They lead from idol forms of stone and wood, To worship that is real. Up through-
                            progressive steps in every age, Earth's perfect seed produced the seer and sage; A war with
                            cherished sins of times to wage And teach truth's high ideal. The opening mind by slow
                            degrees is taught, By forms objective to its senses brought; And thus expands in loftier
                            realms of thought, By education's rule. Experience gathered in the ages vast Is through the
                            mold of human progress passed, And nobler types of manhood are recast, As teachers in life's
                            school. ¦ Thus darkened blots of superstition's blight, The reign of ignorance and error's
                            night, Will by the glory of fair reason's light Pass like a funeral pail. And poor religion
                            struggling for its life, Shall rise above dissension, feud and strife, With blessed fruits
                            of summer harvest rife, Dispensing good to all. 0, prophet martyrs ! ye who lived of yore,
                            And gleamed as signals on time's rocky shore, While tempest, storm and surge, ye bravely
                            bore, Your light shone not in vain. The truth has sped its way through currents strong, By
                            rocks and quicksands of opposing wrong; And still pursues its glorious course along, With
                            sure and steady gain. Material science to its place assigned. Philosophy, the intellective
                            sphere of mind, With intuition's inner sense combined Shall cease to be at strife ; These
                            are to man the body, spirit, soul, Which form in truth, the grand and perfect whol e, The
                            balance force, that holds in full control The varied powers of life. And man by man in labor
                            shall be blessed, No man by title deeds of hate oppressed, But all his wrongs by love shall
                            be redressed, In true equality, <pb n="78" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 78 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. For freedom
                            rises in her sacred might, To break earth's shackles, and proclaim the right, To rend the
                            veil that screens the glorious light Of heaven-born liberty. Lo ! words of peace are passed
                            from shore to shore, Beneath old ocean's waves and billows roar, Hushed be discordant sounds
                            forevermore, When nation's counsels meet. And as the years of swift revolving time, Bring to
                            our land the gifts of ewery clime, May all mankind blend in the hallowed chime, Of
                            brotherhood complete. Mt. Lebanon.</p></div2><div2 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dairy, kindness as a preeminence" TEIform="index"/>THE DAIRY, KINDNESS AS A PREEMINENCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p"> On the 26th of December, 1880, we visited one of our Shaker families in New Lebanon. In the
                            course of conversation we questioned the leader of the family rel ative to the condition of
                            the dairy, the herd of cows, etc., was informed of a very great improvement in the condition
                            of the cows, and the remarkable increase in amount of milk from the herd which had been
                            received during the short space of about two weeks. We inquired for the cause of the same.
                            Had not the cows in milk been increased in numbers? Not any! Had there not been a change of
                            feed, some roots or grain, bran, or shorts been dealt out to them? None at all ! Did they
                            not have better hay, and were they not treated to warmed water, and warmer stabling? No
                            change had been made in any of these things. What, then, could be the cause of so marked a
                            change, such an increase of milk, being about one-half ? Well, the only assignable cause
                            that could be rendered was more kindly care in management in handling, milking, feeding, and
                            universal treatment, by a change of herdsmen. The secret was thus revealed. Cows in milk
                            give milk, if plentifully and properly fed, largely in accordance with the flow of their
                            affections ; this is nature's wise provision. If roughly handled so as to produce constant
                            fear, excitement and irritation they hold up their milk as a result; and holding it up a few
                            days in succession, the milk is reabsorbed into the system, and the cow gradually dries oft,
                            and, if long continued, is liable to remain so until a change of feed, of treatment, or some
                            important beneficial change of conditi@ns. If kindly, tenderly and affectionately treated,
                            they yield their milk freely and fully, and, under the same circumstances of food,
                            temperature, etc., greatly increase it : add to this, a little improvement in feed, for
                            instance, some steamed hay, stalks, etc., sprinkled before steaming with say, one quart of
                            corn meal, ©r two quarts of shorts, or, in place of this, a peck of roots, as beets, turnips
                            at a feeding, or half that amount of carrots or parsnips, and their milk would be more than
                            doubled, especially, if, added to this care they are warmly stabled, and, in cold weather
                            their water a little warmed, even this, itself, would benefit them much. For years, before
                            this interview we had been cognizant of the fact that kindness was essential in the
                            management of cows in order to have a good dairy, but never before had we a conception of
                            the immensity of effect that kindness would produce. Why, according to statistics presented
                            us this day, the difference in amount of milk rendered between kindness gentleness and
                            tenderness, and rough boisterous behavior manifested to a herd of fifteen cows, would be
                            sufficient to pay the wages of a herdsman. Thus wondrously are the laws of God manifest in
                            the lower orders of creation. What, then, is the magnitude of influence of kindness and
                            tenderness in the human family. And how intensely powerful is sympathetic affinity between
                            souls in the mortal casement and those liberated from its cumbersome shroud inhabiting the
                            immortal spheres. Let us be Kind. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mental photography" TEIform="index"/>MENTAL PHOTOGRAPHY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/>CATHARINE ALLEN</byline><p TEIform="p"> The fact that every action, thought, and motive of one's whole life is indelibly inscribed
                            on the memory, and that the mind only needs to be brought under certain con- <pb n="79" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 79 ditions to render these all as distinct as those of
                            the present moment, is affirmed by many testimonials of those who have been resuscitated
                            from drowning, or other cases of imminent danger. Probably the real science of photography
                            exists and operates in the mind, reflecting there the unseen realities of mental origin,
                            representing the exact hue, depth, weight and quality of every emotion, thought and motive,
                            even more perfectly than scenes of the outer world are reflected upon the metallic plate of
                            the photographer. The more we comprehend of the science and laws of the visible creation,
                            the better we can understand the originating forces and soul life of which the exterior is
                            but a reflex, aad the more we learn of our own curious dual life; because man is a complete
                            microcosm of the universe, body, soul, and spirit. There is not one substance of earth
                            element, of the animal or spiritual creation, principle of science, or attribute of Deity,
                            but has a germinal existence in the human brain. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let us reason together" TEIform="index"/>LET US REASON TOGETHER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p"> It is written, that in the long ago, the Lord, by His prophet Isaiah, said to the people, "
                            Come now and let us reason together." And the ministry of the Apostle Paul was marked by his
                            habitude of reasoning with the people of his time. Jesus, the first baptized Jew and
                            expounder of the Christian religion, spake more in parables to the unbelieving, and by
                            intuition and inspiration, to his followers, and to those who were prepared to understand
                            him. At one time when speaking to certain of his disciples concerning the order of his
                            spiritual kingdom, of its faith and principles, he gave them to understand that there would
                            be no limit to its growth and increase, and no diminution of power when he had finished the
                            work that was given him to do, and he had passed from their visible presence into interior
                            spheres. And while he gave pledges that he would be with them in spirit to assist them in
                            their ministrations after his departure, and that they should be blest with still greater
                            spiritual power than himself had possessed while in mortal form, he also laid them under
                            great responsibilities concerning the use they should make of delegated powers conferred
                            upon them as leaders and directors, and in regard to the faithful performance of duties
                            which would bring them to occupy the position of servants as well as rulers. The greatest
                            must also be least in the kingdom that he came to inaugurate, which would embody the
                            substance of all the hopes and predictions of God's true prophets.through past shadowy
                            dispensations. Law and order are a necessity in all of God's creation; without such law, all
                            would be chaos. It is evident to our senses, that the Creator of the Universe had a design —
                            a perfect plan — that He purposed to carry to its ultimate in the fulfillment of times and
                            seasons. How many ages it will take for the growth, development and ripening process, before
                            that purpose be effected, the rolling cycles of time and events must determine. If we would
                            reason with God — according to our limited capacity — we must begin at the substratum; and
                            rise upward from the base. The lower forms of mineral substances have their place and uses,
                            as do also all kinds of vegetable and animal life. Each, and all were designed to subserve
                            the higher purposes of man and woman, under guidance and direction of superior intelligence
                            and reasoning powers — a God-given endowment, placed upon man as a distinguishing mark
                            between the higher and lower orders of animal existences — to be used and not abused, nor be
                            misplaced by converting them into gods, and worshiping them as such. We reason that man is a
                            duplex being in his nature and in his desires and attainments. It is requisite while we are
                            in a rudimental state of existence ; and are dependent upon the material products of the
                            earth for subsistence, that we enter into rapport, and form a union with material
                            substances, and seek to discover and develop the hidden sources of supplies which have been
                            held in <pb n="80" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 80 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. reserve for ages, by a wise and
                            beneficent father and mother, for the benefit of their children ; and in so doing, if we
                            would cooperate with the divine will respecting us — we should be very careful to maintain
                            moral integrity, and learn to commune with God's creation, as revealed in the exterior,
                            visible world of matter, and strive lawfully and earnestly through that medium, to compre
                            hend something of the interior world toward which we are all journeying of which it is said
                            by many who claim to be spiritually illumined that the visible world is but a reflex. What
                            benefit might accrue to each and all, if, while we are placed npon middle ground, and have
                            it within our power to honor the creative power that spake all worlds of mind and matter
                            into being, if we would maintain our rectitude ; by holding each and all in their proper
                            sphere ; use them as needful for our own subsistence and the good of humanity. By so doing,
                            we might hold unbroken communion with the angel world, through pure ministering spirits, who
                            would grasp, and hold us in their loving embraces, and guide us in safety to our heavenly
                            home, where all our needs will be supplied without the aid of malerial substances. By
                            maintaining just and proper relations with the two worlds, we might unfold and perfect our
                            duplex natures, the natural and spiritual, the earthly and heavenly — and better understand
                            the significance of the ancient scripture, which is recorded as the voice of " Wisdom "
                            claiming co-relation to, and affiliation with the creator ; when He formed His plans and
                            executed His decrees concerning the hills and valleys, the sea and dry land ; that she was
                            as one brought up with Him, was His delight and counselor. And we should learn to comprehend
                            more fully that " the earth is the Lord's, and the fullness thereof ; that the gold and the
                            silver and the cattle upon a thousand hills belong to Him; and are ours in usufruct only. We
                            can develop the godlike attributes of our being the most effectually by being in strict «ind
                            harmonious accord with the well-devised and executed laws, placed to guide intelligent
                            manhood from rudimental, earthly conditions to higher destinies in the great beyond. Thus we
                            shall be able to see God in the tiny leaf, in the unfolding fragrant flower in the towering
                            oak ; also in the little streamlet which courses its way through meadows and valleys onward
                            to mingle with the waters of the great ocean ; and in all we shall recognize the impress of
                            the Divine originator and dispenser of blessings for humanity's weal. " God is not slack
                            concerning his promises, as some men count slackness ;" neither is He angry or impatient,
                            because the race makes slow progress. He awaits the growth and advancement of sentient
                            beings and the fulfillment of times and seasons ; knowing that in the sequel, justice will
                            prevail: Tiiuth will be victorious. His work will be accomplished, and wisdom will be
                            justified of her children !</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sacred scriptures, revised and boiled down" TEIform="index"/>SACRED SCRIPTURES, REVISED AND
                            BOILED DOWN</head><p TEIform="p">' PRENTICIANA. Exordium.— Liberally educated in all the theological issues of the past, and
                            having made the sublime discovery that the Sacred Scriptures as graciously vouchsafed by the
                            learned council of " The most High and Mighty Prince James, King of Great Britain, France
                            and Ireland," is behind the age, we patriotically resolved our honorable self into an
                            Ecclesiastical Council, and with much pious labor, care and diligence bring forth the
                            following : OLD TESTAMENT. Fond parents, wishing to establish a colony in a new country,
                            clear a spot, plant it with trees, and make it like a garden. They put two of their children
                            there, one of each persuasion — mere youths they were — and say to them, " You see we have
                            given you all the needfuls for horticultural purposes, and an instrument of a thousand
                            strings. When arrived at mature age, once in twenty-six moons, when you have a teleram from
                            us, with anthems of adoration and praise, you may touch the chords of that instrument, and
                            we will send you a lit- <pb n="81" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. 81 tie angel — and thus
                            shall your number be increased until you become a great nation. But see that you make no
                            unhallowed use of the instrument. This shall be the test of your integrity, your worthiness
                            to receive the rich blessings we have in store for you." Wisdom is not a birthright
                            inheritance. It is a plant of slow growth, some times through sufferings. Itching curiosity
                            to try the chords of the mysterious instrument drew the youthful colonists into a youthful
                            indiscretion. They see the blunder, they feel it. He tries to lay it to her. Bad chivalry
                            that. She lays it to turtium quid. They do have an accession, and say, "We have gotten a man
                            from the Lord." The sequel demonstrates that they " have gotten " him too far from the Lord,
                            entirely. This youthful indiscretion demoralizes the colony, and now the question arises,
                            how shall humanity be cleaned up, the Church be cleaned up, the Rev. the Clergy be cleaned
                            up ? NEW TESTAMENT. Holy Eternal Parents plant a second colony like unto the first, same
                            outfit, just this slight variation in the instructions — "The use — the sole and only use of
                            the Harp of a thousand strings, is to be let alone, not meddled with, manner nor shape. This
                            is the test of your aspiration and selfcontrol, your fitness for our mansions of eternal
                            brightness." This second enterprise is a success. Now are the New Heavens, so long existing
                            in prophecy only, being actualized in this, our day. The "New Earth, wherein dvvelleth
                            righteousness," is forthcoming. It will furnish better material for the "New Heavens" than
                            is now lying about loose. In the "New Earth" children can be born in good shape, physically
                            and mentally, no pre-natal nor subsequent insult nor abuse, no lack of the affectionate.
                            Peroration.— To all who make Scripture, expecting others to read, we respectfully suggest,
                            wait till you are sure you have an idea, an idea that will interest somebody besides vour
                            own dear self. When sure you have an idea, put that idea in the fewest possible words, put
                            the words together mechanically, in pursuance of the laws of language. Let your sentences be
                            short ; don't send your readers away back to hunt for your nominative or antecedent. In this
                            fast age, with such deluge of would-be reading matter, if writers would have readers they
                            must write, not wholly, for their own edification. Nothing personal intended.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Open letter" TEIform="index"/>AN OPEN LETTER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>Giles B. Avery</byline><p TEIform="p">To the Board of Directors and Officers of the Federation of Reformers in the spheres of
                            Governmental Polity ; Social Organization ; Priestly Thraldom; Theological Cant; Sectarian
                            Bigotry ; Religious Pedantry ; and Female Disfranchisement, which met in Brussels, Belgium.
                            Friends of Truth — Permit us to present to you through the kindness of the editor of a noted
                            American periodical, the facts that there are seventeen societies of religionists and
                            radical reformers in the United States, of North America, embracing, in all about
                            fifty-three families, or communities varying from twenty to one hundred and twenty, or more
                            persons in a family or commune, each holding all its real and personal property in common,
                            as a substance consecrated to the service of God, the development, reform and protection of
                            human society in the freedom of conscience ; republican government; female suffrage and
                            equality ; universal abandonment of international wars and bloodshed ; peaceful settlement
                            of national difficulties by arbitration through a congress of nations; ransom from all kinds
                            of human slavery recognizing the right of property in a fellow human being; banishing popery
                            and all priestly aristocracy; demanding the positive and eternal separation of Church and
                            state. Recognizing no religion in mere sectarian theology. Denying that the Christian bible
                            is the word of God, but claiming that portions of it are a more or less faithful record of
                            that word! And of Heaven inspired truths recognized by the enlightened and inspired sages of
                            the ages, and received <pb n="82" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 82 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. by Jesus Christ and
                            His faithful followers, as the vicegerents of God. Sons and daugh ters of God, to reveal a
                            new phase of human evolution for humanity into a spiritual and heavenly New Creation of God.
                            A Christian dispensation. A character of Christianity. With the Jews we deny the generative
                            divinity of Jesus, except in the capacity of sonship, and understand this relation to the
                            Father to have been the fruit of a new and spiritual birth by baptism of the Holy (ihost and
                            obedience to its behests ; and, in this capacity he became the "Elder Brother," as St. Paul
                            expresses it, of a family of Christ. Younger sons and daughters of God. " The first born of
                            many brethren." We believe in God as a bisexual duality of creative power, wisdom and love,
                            the human equality as regards a natural right to the earth and its fruits as a means of
                            support and equality of burden bearing for human weal and protection of life and liberty and
                            the God-given inheritance of liberty of conscience. We believe in a present as well as a
                            past, and continuous revelation of spiritual and scientific truth to the human family ; in a
                            future state of the soul's existence ; in the extension of probation to the spirit life ;
                            that the election to heaven or happiness is the performance of deeds of goodness,
                            righteousness, love and mercy; that reprobation is equally and only the fruits of
                            unrightness — the result of violated laws. We believe in monogamic marriage as a worldly
                            institution to be used as an adjunct of sexual organism, simply and exclusively for the
                            propagation of the species and the maintenance of those fraternal and paternal affections
                            necessary for the family relation in the order of nature, but do not recognize it as a
                            Christian institution. We protest against marital slavery and bondage in cases of sexual
                            abuse and incongenialities of physical, social, psychical, religious or secular temperament
                            or developments. And we hereby present our Communal Institutions and their principles as
                            iconoclasts upon the humanly instituted theologies and creeds of sectarians that teach
                            vicarious atonement, an angry God ; justification by faith without accompanying good works.
                            Accepting the life, character, examples, and precepts of Jesus Christ as our life guide and
                            preceptor; and believing that a new baptism of the Christ spirit, may, should, did and does
                            as really descend upon the female sex of humanity as it did upon Jesus, we accept the advent
                            of this baptism now at hand, as manifest by the fruits of Christianity, and in no other way.
                            We discard the idea of a physical resurrection of Christ and understand that resurrection to
                            be of the soul, from a death, the fruit of sin against God's laws, to a life, the fruits of
                            obedience thereunto. We believe that all the claims we justly have to earthly substance is
                            in usufruct only, and that we, and our services of life belong to God in the evolution of
                            human character and conditions until Heaven is inaugurated upon earth, and love is ruling
                            power in governments, bearing upon her dove-like wings of peace, the ensign love,
                            righteousness, charity, mercy, goodness and truth, and peace and good will to all mankind.
                            Our prayer to the powers that rule in the government of nations, ministered through human
                            intelligences as agents for the execution of God's laws are, may Heaven inspire their soul's
                            power, their minds with wisdom to institute such reforms as may contribute to make earth an
                            Eden, the vestibule of Heaven. Your Friend for Truth, , In behalf of the Shaker Communities
                            of North America. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Speaking of the contest between infidelity and Christianity..." TEIform="index"/>Speaking of the contest between infidelity and Christianity...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Speaking of the contest between infidelity and Christianity the Herald makes this strange
                            assertion : " It is not for secular newspapers to take sides in these questions." And why
                            not? We do not so limit the functions of a newspaper. It ought by all means to take and to
                            defend its side. And the side of The Sun is, first and last, genuine, practical
                            Christianity. Against that no infidel arguments will avail.</p></div2><pb n="83" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editor Manifesto:" TEIform="index"/>Editor Manifesto :</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>Abraham Perkins</byline><p TEIform="p">I am so frequently receiving letters like the following, which so very much demonstrates
                                the spirit which is at work in the hearts of many, I thought it might not be out of
                                place to forward the following extracts which you are at liberty to publish with my
                                earnest desire that still brighter vision may be developed for a clearer understanding
                                of the great work of God; the seeds of which are planted in the earth and so far
                                germinated as to produce fruitage and to give indubitable evidence of a power that
                                purifies the heart and prepares it for an abiding habitation for the Most High. In much
                                love, your brother, Enfield, N. H., March 25, 1881. </p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boston, Mass., March 20, 1881" TEIform="index"/>Boston, Mass., March 20, 1881</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="N., S." TEIform="persName"/>S. N.</byline><p TEIform="p">Boston, Mass., March 20, 1881. Elder Perkins : Dear Sir.— Assured that it would not be
                                considered unwarrantable presumption to address you, I do so, and feel honored in being
                                permitted to enjoy the privilege of interchanging thoughts and sentiments with one whose
                                life for half a century has been so strictly in conformity with that life of
                                selfsacrifice which the Master enjoined upon all those who would be his disciples. Your
                                worship and home lives impress me deeply ; the atmosphere of which has a restful
                                influence and the repose and severity of your lives seem enviable. I cannot express how
                                tenderly such lives, so quiet and unsophisticated, appeal to a heart thoroughly satiated
                                with the frivolities and hollow pretensions of friendship, which are the inevitable
                                accompaniments of a society life, in which my position compelled me in some degree to
                                mingle, though always with reluctance. In my acquaintance with your people, I now feel
                                that I have come into a higher, a purer atmosphere, and that " old things have passed
                                away and all things have become new." Living as I have in the vortex of society, subject
                                to constant fluctuations, my naturally quick susceptibilties were being constantly
                                wounded by attrition with coarser uncongenial natures ; and ^1 do not think a day passed
                                so happily that I could have desired to have the next its counterpart. It is different
                                now ; your acquaintance, your letters have to me become perpetual soul feasts, and each
                                morning brings the certainty that this day will be more abundantly blest. Purity of life
                                I am seeking. It is my highest conception of godliness. The greater the purity of soul,
                                the fitter its abode for the indwelling Deitjr ; and if to attain to that purity we must
                                walk through the fiery furnace of affliction, our reward will be commensurate with our
                                sufferings. With Ann Lee, of blessed memory, I believe " tribulation brings our souls
                                near to God." We must tread the wine-press with bleeding feet, even as he did whom we
                                love to call our elder brother. If we suffer with him, we shall reign with him ; if we
                                bear our cross here, there is laid up for us a crown hereafter. The position of many
                                Christian teachers burdens me. They stain their robes by assuming connubial obligations,
                                and thereby fail to follow their Lord, who was without spot or blemish. I do not
                                understand you to be creed-bound. Your liberal sentiments, your recognition of Christian
                                principles wTherever found, is one of the cords that attracts me and binds me to your
                                people. In this we are united by that illimitable love that knows no creed. Although my
                                standing may be outside your fold, I crave admission into your hearts ; I have that
                                degree of confidence in your honest lives ; I ask that I may have its benefits of your
                                counsel and ripened wisdom ; nor would I have you feel misgivings in presenting your
                                ideas, fearing they may collide with favorite opinions of mine. If truths wound because
                                of false hope 1 may have hugged, let them wound, and let those wounds be probed that
                                they may be the sooner healed. With regard to the strong ties of friendship for you as a
                                religious body, too high an estimate cannot be placed of their value to me. O ! that I
                                may have not only faith, but that I may be able to act in accordance with that faith
                                which is germinating in my soul ; and as I comprehend it, I realize that it does<pb n="84" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 84 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. not teach that 1 can enter the gates of
                                the city, only as you have been blest to find an entrance. 0 ! how precious the oneness
                                of sentiment existing between us, and comforting the realization of the sympathetic
                                chord which vibrates in unison with our emoti nal natures ! Yet you seem so far above,
                                and beyond me in spiritual attainments, I can never dare expect to reach your altitude,
                                but shall be most thankful to sit at your feet and receive nourishment from minds richly
                                blest with gifts of the Divine, I mean no flattery, nor would I be so understood. 1 am
                                now drawing toward the setting sun ; the greater part of my life is behind me ; and what
                                of life remains for me, I wish to improve, that I may secure an 1 hold that which will
                                unite my spirit with the just made perfect, that which will give the friendship of your
                                body, that which has opened to me * fountain most, alleviating to the distress of a
                                burdened soul, that which refreshes me with a balm most restful and enables my spirit to
                                take on wings that carry me heavenward, and thus ally me to the Infinite. May I be
                                permitted to continue the friendship so happily formed, a friendship which I would for
                                no consideration be willing to lose. Yours with sentiments of high regards.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editor of the manifesto" TEIform="index"/>Editor of the Manifesto</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>Abraham Perkins</byline><p TEIform="p">Realizing as I do that I stand upon the brink of eternity, that to the longest, a few
                                short years only remain in which to close my earthly labors, I am instinctively led to a
                                review of what has passed before me, what have been my aims, what has fallen to my lot
                                to meet, what have been my conflicts in the operations of the vicissitudes of life, how
                                I have met these varied phases, and how I have treated society and conditions as I have
                                found them. The days of childhood are those of iguoranee and innocence; they are also
                                the days which most thoroughly educate the mind ; the period of life most impressible,
                                in which principles are more firmly established and character is generally formed. Hence
                                the importance of children being situated where no blighting or corrupting influence
                                should reach them, where example is both moral and Christian, and where they may be
                                intelligently educated in those principles which have their foundation in truth. The
                                dignity and honor of the future man and woman, his or her success in life, depend almost
                                wholly upon early guardianship and discipline. The seed then sown usually finds soil
                                which ministers nourishment, produces growth, and yields fruit in all the seasons of
                                after life. As the period of youth develops the natural instincts of the mind, among the
                                developments is conspicuously unfolded the disposition to canvass the attainments of
                                other minds, to stuiy the manners and habits of those with whom they come in contact;
                                the result of which is, that those emanations, opinions and notions the most palatable
                                are those which bring no restraint, no checks upon the downward tendencies, the lower
                                animal passions of the human heart. The events of early life in my experience are so
                                vivid, they are before me as the scenes of yesterday ; many of which being fruits of
                                sound principles bring unsullied joy ; while others produce pain and sorrow., from the
                                fact that the fountain was foul from which they were brought forth. Manhood succeeds,
                                habits are formed and character established. Whatever the acquirements, they become as
                                second nature ; the correct and true require comparatively little effort to sustain
                                them; while habits and principles which are false and tend to immorality are difficult
                                to eradicate or change. In the retrospection of the aims of life, it is a pleasant
                                reflection, that the decision of judgment weighs favorably in the balance of justice,
                                crowning the soul with a good degree of justification. Although in the journey of life
                                much imprudence and error are apparent, that failure has often been the result of
                                earnest toil, that bright hopes have been baffled; yet, knowing that the object was
                                legitimate and the enterprise honest, feeling that underlying those labors, truth and
                                right was the operating power, the contem- <pb n="85" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKES MANIFESTO.
                                85 plation is peaceful, especially when the verdict is, that our trials have been met
                                manfully and with moral courage. The walks of life are labyrinthian. None can discover
                                at the commencement, the solution of its problems. We must trust, or we never
                                accomplish; and in subjecting our selves to discipline, to the instruction of the wise
                                and experienced, we are positively and practically fulfilling a law established by Him
                                who set in order the systems of the universe, the lower subordinate to the higher, every
                                part of creation subservient to a relative power, which finds its source in the great
                                Creator, the motive power, the ruling intelligence. In the economy of creation, no such
                                thing existed as independence. All created things are linked together in one vast chain,
                                each having its respective capacity and order, and each its legitimate relation to the
                                other, centering in the Great First Cause. Hence the necessity of obedience to the law
                                of light, the attribute of reason ; the necessity of our dependence upon each other,
                                which gives a connection of the two worlds, by which we have a union with those guardian
                                spirits who have ministered to our necessities by which we are granted a reunion with
                                our gospel parents and beloved kindred who have passed on before us. In view of our
                                fellowship with the saints of God, with the just made perfect in Christ, I realize the
                                necessity of the greatest care in regard to the manner and spirit entertained in earth
                                life ; that under no circumstance, with Christian profession, can we in justification
                                tolerate unkindness, hardness of heart, revenge or malice; if reviled, we are not to
                                revile ; if unkindly or uncharitably dealt with, we are not to take on the same spirit
                                in return. Such disclosures evince want of culture and Christian education —it is the
                                fruit of an unsubdued heart, which in such condition has no place in the Kingdom of
                                Heaven. . Enfield, N. H.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There is nothing certainly more unreasonable..." TEIform="index"/>There is nothing certainly more unreasonable...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mansfield" TEIform="persName"/>Lord Mansfield</byline><p TEIform="p">'' There is nothing certainly more unreasonable, more inconsistent with the rights of human
                            nature, more contrary to the spirit and precepts of the Christian religion ; more iniquitous
                            and unjust, more impolitic ; than 'persecution. It is against natural religion, revealed
                            religion and sound policy."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian essentials" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN ESSENTIALS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">It is by the " line upon line, and precept upon precept " now, just as ever in the past,
                                that truths are enunciated over and over again. There is no truth now, but agrees with
                                all the real truths of the past. Supposed truths of the past—-many of them— are to-day
                                proven to be errors then, even as they are errors now. The saying that " there is
                                nothing new under the sun," has a significance, when attached to the essentials of an
                                effectual Christian's life. That there should have been sprung upon the people, through
                                Jesus of Nazareth, such an immense and perfect display*of the true Christian, is and
                                will remain the wonder of many ages. The ouly real possible reason we have for supposing
                                that Christianity was not a sudden apparition in the man Jesus, lies in the fact, that
                                the culmination of the laws of Moses—the highest and most perfect embodiment in any
                                one's life—would introduce a higher plane; a better model than Moses; a superior life
                                than the school of Judaism had ever dreamed of producing. If " Moses was a schoolmaster
                                to bring souls to Christ," then we can easily see the perfection of the graduate of that
                                school, beginning in the essential elements of Christ's superior life, although of
                                apparently opposite teachings. In Moses's early teachings we find the people restricted
                                from miscellaneous reproductions, to a crude, but orderly arrangement of the same. The
                                same rule applied in the retaliation of injuries — one life for one liie, etc.— and so
                                on in the entire scale of Jewish<pb n="86" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 86 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. human
                                life economy. If the student of ecclesiastical history will, while wondering at these
                                unchristian regulations, read back to previous history, he will easily perceive how
                                great were these, as improvements, upon the worse than heathen practices that preceded
                                them, when there was no law to regulate either the propensities of lust nor
                                retaliations. Arriving at the beginning of the Christian annunciation that what Moses
                                taught was right to date; but "Behold / give unto you new commandments" and that these,
                                though bringing a cessation of those of Moses, are simply one grand step higher for all
                                who are able to take the step, the simplicity of the mission of the first Christ is
                                apparent. " I come not to destroy laws " of the past; but I come " to f ultill " the
                                higher laws for human progress. Until humanity acknowledged the practical renunciation
                                of Jewish practices, made by Jesus, as correct Christianity, it is far preferable that
                                Judaism have and hold control. The selfdenials of Jesus, which are our Christian
                                lessons, were illustrated in the renunciation of marriage ; of war and retaliations; of
                                selfish interests and private property, and of mingling with worldly clans for worldly
                                popularity and, applause. However right Jesus admitted these to be among the Jews
                                —however right, we his followers in self-denials and renunciations, admit these to be
                                among the worldly—Jesus, and those living to proclaim the testimony of the Christ to be;
                                " Come ye out from such practices "—not because of their wickedness as Jewish
                                permission—but because, in comparison to the higher and better life taught by the
                                self-denials and renunciations of the Christ, they become wickedness for Christians to
                                practice. If the honest, earnest, devout disciple of Jesus would know in what and of
                                what the essentials of Christianity consist, he needs not wrangle with any other sect to
                                fully determine what these truths are. Let such draw up the simple, but wonderful
                                contrast between the best life under Judaism and the lovely self-denying examples of
                                Christ, and the whole truth appears. In this contrast appears the call of Christian
                                duty— " Follow rne !" and in the following is fully experienced those practical
                                Christian essentials, which the children of the world are as yet unready to accept and
                                adopt as a life practice. Let none then charge upon us, Shakers, with being innovators,
                                not of Christ. If Shakerism permits practices which Jesus did not engage in, and deny
                                those which He proclaimed to be the credentials demanded to possess discipleship, then
                                let the churches and the people shake the Shakers. But if the churches are not blinded
                                by the lusts of the people ; if the people are not beguiled into the dullness of dead
                                creeds and unchristian churches; then let us have an awakening to the facts, that
                                however displeasing to our selfish, sensual natures, Christ is best, even amid all the
                                selfdenials, renunciations of the world and its unchristian permissions, the essentials
                                of Christ are better and best. -fa</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Can Shakers respect infidels?" TEIform="index"/>Can Shakers Respect Infidels ?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">EDITORIAL NOTES. It has been wondered at by many, why a people so deeply imbued with a
                                    <pb n="87" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 87 love of Christianity, that rigid
                                selfdenials without stint are practiced by them, as a necessity, to bring them into a
                                conformity with Christianity, could have any respect for the so-called scoffing infidel.
                                But we can see good reasons for a large admiration amid all their jeering at creedal
                                formalities. These do not profess Christianity as their creed, and therefore do not
                                practice it. Professedly Christian churches hold as their head and Lord, Jesus, the
                                Christ, while in the lives of their communicants, they differ not at all from the
                                professed infidels. Christianity is a life, not merely a creed. As a creed only,
                                unaccompanied by the life of Christ, it is a sorry and ridiculous farce. Infidels, from
                                Paine to Ingersoll have never ridiculed honesty, integrity, nor sincerity in the
                                practice of virtue, but they have and do ridicule the want of practice among church
                                people of what they profess. They ask with good reason, why call yourselves Christians,
                                and Jesus your Master, yet fail to obey the demands of your faith and Captain? Such
                                contrasts as exist between the practices of nearly all professedly Christian churches,
                                and those of the Christian Master, that no one can blame any for shaming and shunning
                                such churches. It is singular that Ingersoll never has ridiculed the Shakers. And yet it
                                is not so singular after all. Professing Christ as a life pattern, the Shakers can only
                                be consistent, by trying as accurately as possible, to follow in the footsteps of the
                                Master's life-practice. Prom a failure to do just this, professing, but unpracticing
                                Christians give infidels all desirable opportunity to ridicule, if such is desired. They
                                will not believe Christians, so-called, love Jesus, unless they will live like Him. They
                                will not admit they believe in His doctrines of renunciations.and self-denials unless
                                they will enter upon them as a practice. There are very few testimonies, which are put
                                forth against the undutifulness of Christian communicants, ourselves included, that come
                                home with more force, reason, and in which the point so well taken, as from these
                                so-called infidels. If we are better than they are by profession, let us show it in our
                                practice; by more exoellent charities for one another; by a purer life than theirs; by a
                                nearer semblance, in our lives, to the model we have accepted as our great exampier.
                                Infidels, from Voltaire to Bennett, have had more respect for the Shakers, than have as
                                many of the brightest lights of the popular churches, and the reason is plain— that the
                                Shakers are trying to practice in particular, what Christ both preached and practiced.
                                The popular churches have ever ridiculed the Shakers ; while they have ever been very
                                distant admirers of the Christ, who lived very much as do the Shakers, and so very
                                different from the popular churches and their creeds. For the reason that the Shakers,
                                in believing in radical Christianity, and practicing it as they do, the javelins of
                                infidels have broken at their feet. The ridicule of the churches has been more than
                                harmless to those, who professing, have the nearest practiced Christ. We claim that the
                                popular churches make a sorry figure at genuine, Christian imitation ; that they render
                                themselves as very open to the reasonable attacks of ridicule and reprehension of honest
                                    <pb n="88" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. men and women ; that they encourage
                                infidelity by making of Christianity an impossible creed, impossible to believe in
                                reason, and by the want of a love and fellowship for neighbors taught by the
                                acknowledged Christ. So long then, as Paine or others honestly differed from the models
                                of Christ's life, yet whose " religion is to do good to our fellow-men ; " so long as
                                Ingersoll shall love, admire and practice the " Golden Rule"and " Sermon on the Mount,"
                                we are not only forced, but can ardently respect them, even more than we can those who
                                cry, " Lord, Lord," but do not the things which I say—live not the life which Christ
                                did.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Is Christianity a questionable assertion?" TEIform="index"/>Is Christianity a
                                Questionable Assertion ?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We wish it distinctly understood that we do not enter Shakerism upon the attention of the
                                people as an aggression of their rights to think and live other than it inculcates; but
                                we simply hold it up as radical, unperverted "Christianity, which every one has the
                                right to choose or refuse. We claim Celibacy as most Christian; We claim iMarriage as
                                not Christian. We assert Community of Interests to be the bounden duty of all professing
                                Christianity ; that they fare and share alike. We hold the opposite personal, private
                                interest to be unchristian- We hold Peace, and nonresistance, and charity to be very
                                Christian, while their opposites cannot be so. We hold abstinence from sensual
                                pleasures; temperance, in all that Christ was temperate ; and freedom from worldly
                                ambitions to be very Christian, while their opposites never were nor can be. Is it a
                                question in any one's mind which are the Christian features in the above assertions ? Is
                                it questionable how any Christian should live ?</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Letter to Jesus" TEIform="index"/>A LETTER TO JESUS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eddy, Grace" TEIform="persName"/>GRACE EDDY</byline><p TEIform="p">BY A postman stood with puzzled brow, And in his hand turned o'er and o'er A letter with
                                address so strange As he had never seen before, The writing cramped, the letters small,
                                And by a boy's rough hand engraven, The words ran thus, "'To Jesus Christ," And
                                underneath inscribed, " In Heaven." The postman paused; full well lie knew No mail on
                                earth this note could take, And yet 'twas writ in childish faith, And posted for the
                                dear Lord's sake. With careful hand he broke the seal, And rev'rently the letter read;
                                'Twas short, and very simple, too, For this is all the writing said : " My Lord and
                                Saviour, Jesus Christ, I've lately lost my father dear, Mother is very, very poor, And
                                life to her is sad and drear; Yet thou hast promised in Thy Word That none can ever ask
                                in vain For what they need of earthly store, If only asked in Jesus' name. " So I am
                                writing in his name, To ask that Thou wilt kindly send Some money down; what Thou canst
                                spare, And what is right for us to spend. I want so much to go to school. While father
                                lived I always went, But he had little, Lord, to leave, And what he left is almost
                                spent. " I do not know how long 'twill be Ere this can reach the golden gate; But I will
                                try and patient be, And for the answer gladly wait." The tidings reached that far-off
                                land, Although the letter did not go ; And straight the King an angel sent To help the
                                little boy below. 88 <pb n="89" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 89 Oft to his mother he
                                would say, " I knew the Lord would answer make When he had read my letter through Which
                                I had sent for Jesus' sake." Ah ! happy boy, could you but teach My heart to trust my
                                Father's love, And to believe where aught's denied, 'Tis only done my faith to
                            prove.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the spelling class" TEIform="index"/>TO THE SPELLING CLASS</head><p TEIform="p">Stand up,.ye spellers, now and spell, Spell Phenakistoscope and Knell; Or take some
                                simple word as Chili, Or Ganger or the Garden Lily. To spell such words as Syllogyism,
                                And Lachrymose and Synchronism, And Pentateuch and Saccharine, Apocrypha and Celandine,
                                Lactiferous and Cecity, Jejune and Homoeopathy, Paralysis and Chloroform. Rhinoceros and
                                Pachyderm, Metempsychosis, Gherkins, Basque, Is certainly no easy task. Kaleidoscope and
                                Tennessee, Kamtschatka and Dispensary, Diphthong and -Erysipelas, And Etiquette and
                                Sassafrass, Infallible and Ptyalism, Allopathy and Rheumatism, And'Cataclysm and
                                Beleaguer, Twelfth, Eighteenth, Rendez vous,Intriguer, And hosts of other words are
                                found On English and on Classic ground. Thus Belmn&gt;&gt;- Straits and Michaelmas,
                                Thermopylae, Cordilleras, Suite, Hemorrhage, Jalap and Havana, Cinquefoil and
                                Ipecacuanha, Rappahannock Shenandoah, And Schuylkill and a thousand more, Are words some
                                prime good spellers miss In Dictionary lands like this, Nor need one think himself a
                                Scroyle If some of these our efforts foil, Nor doom himself undone forever To miss the
                                name of either river, The Dnieper, Seine or Guadalquivir.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pray what can this little  bird be?" TEIform="index"/>PRAY WHAT CAN THIS LITTLE BIRD
                                BE?</head><p TEIform="p">It's strange how little boy's mothers Can find it all out as they do If a fellow does any
                                thing naughty Or says any thing that's not true ! They'll look at you just a moment,
                                Till your heart in your bosom swells, And then they know all about it — For a little
                                bird tells ! Now where the little bird comes from, Or where the little bird goes, If
                                he's covered with beautiful plummage Or black as the king of crows, If his voice is as
                                hoarse as a raven Or clear as the ringing bells, I know not—but this I am sure of— A
                                little bird tells ! The moment you think a thing wicked, The moment you do a thing bad,
                                Are angry or sullen or hateful, Get ugly or stupid or mad, Or tease a dear brother or
                                sister— That instant your sentence he knells, And the whole to mamma in a minute That
                                little bird tells ! You may be in the depths of a closet Where nobody sees but a mouse !
                                You may be all alone in a cellar, You maybe on the top of the house; You may be in the
                                dark and the silence, Or out in the woods and the dells— No matter ! Wherever it
                                happens, The little bird tells ! And the only contrivance to stop him Is just to be sure
                                what to say— Sure of your facts and your fancies, Sure of your work and your play. Be
                                honest, be brave and be kindly, Be gentle and loving as well, And then you can laugh at
                                the stories 'The little bird tells !</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What might have been" TEIform="index"/>WHAT MIGHT HAVE BEEN
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lawrence, Kate" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">WHAT MIGHT HAVE BEEN. Kate Lawrence. It might have been that the sky was
                                        green, and the grass serenely blue; It might have been that grapes on thorns and
                                        figs on thistles grew; It might have been that rainbows gleamed before the
                                        showers came; t It might have been that lambs were fierce and bears and tigers
                                        tame; It might have been that cold would melt and summer heat would freeze ; It
                                        might have been that ships at sea would sail against the breeze; And there may
                                        be worlds unknown, dear, where we would find the change From all that we have
                                        seen or heard, to others j ust as strange — But it never could be wise, dear, in
                                        haste to act or speak; It never could be noble to harm the poor and weak; It
                                        never could be kind, dear, to give a needless pain ; It never could be honest,
                                        dear, to sin for greed or gain; And there could not be a world, dear, while God
                                        is true above, Where right and wrong were governed by any law but love.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl">in <index level1="Wide awake" TEIform="index"/>Wide Awake</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><pb n="90" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sizer, Charles" TEIform="index"/>Chas. Sizer</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bowns, Charlotte" TEIform="index"/>Charlotte Bowns</head><p TEIform="p">At Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., --------; --------.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Allard, Daniel" TEIform="index"/>Daniel Allard</head><p TEIform="p">At Enfield, N. H., deceased, Feb. 3, 1881, , aged 88 years.</p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Received" TEIform="index"/>Received</head><p TEIform="p"> : Chas. Clapp.......................$24 00 Albert J. Battles................... 5 00
                                Irene George...................25 20 Amelia Lyman..................18 00 Benj. H.
                                Smith.................... 12 00 George Wilcox.................... 2 00</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Removal of stains and spots" TEIform="index"/>Removal of Stains and Spots</head><p TEIform="p">[The following recipes for the removal of stains and spots, we copy from the German
                                Muster Zeitung. If they are as reliable as sug gestions heretofore coming from this same
                                source, they will be worth dollars to many households.-—Ed.] Gum, Sugar, Jelly, etc.—
                                Simple washing with water at a hand heat. Grease.— White goods, wash with soap or
                                alkaline lyes. Colored cottons, wash with lukewarm soap lyes. Colored woolens the same,
                                or ammonia. Silks, absorb with French chalk or fuller's earth, and dissolve away with
                                benzine or ether. Oil Colors, Varnish and Resins.— On white or colored linens, cottons,
                                or woolens, use rectified oil of turpentine, alcohol lye, and their soap. On silks, use
                                benzine, ether and mild soap very cautiously. Slearine.— In all cases, strong, pure
                                alcohol. Vegetable Colors; Fruit, Bed'Wine, and lied Ink.— On white goods, sulphur fumes
                                or chlorine water. Colored cottons and woolens, wash with lukewarm soap lye cr ammonia.
                                Silk the same, but more cau tiously. Lime and Alkalies.— White goods, simple washing.
                                Colored cottons, woolens, and silks are moistened, and very dilute citric acid is
                                applied with the finger end. Alizarine Inks.—White goods, tartaric acid, the more
                                concentrated the older are the spots. 'On colored cottons and woolens, and on silks,
                                dilute tartaric acid is applied cautiously. Blood and Albuminoid Matters.—Steeping in
                                luke warm water. If pepsine, or the juice of Caricapapaya, can be procured, the spots
                                are first softened with lukewarm water, and then either of these substances is applied.
                                Iron Spots and Black Ink.— White goods, hot oxalic acid, dilute muriatic acid, with
                                little fragments of tin. On fast dyed cottons and woolens, citric acid is cautiously and
                                repeatedly applied. Silks, impossible. Acids, Vinegar, Sour Wine, Must, Sour Fruits.
                                —White goods, simple washing, followed up by chlorine water if a fruit color accompanies
                                the acid. Colored cottons, woolens and silks are very carefully moistened with dilute
                                ammonia, with the finger end. [In case of delicate colors, it will be found preferable
                                to make some prepared chalk into a thin paste, with water, and apply it to the spots.]
                                Tunning from Chestnuts, Green Walnuts, etc., or Leather.—White goods, hot chlorine
                                water, and concentrated tartaric acid. Colored cottons, woolens, and silks, apply dilute
                                chlorine water cautiously to the spot, washing it away and reapplying it several times.
                                Tar, Cart Wheel Grease, Mixtures of Fat, Rosin, Carbon and Acetic Acid.— On white goods,
                                soap and oil of turpentine, alternating with streams of water. Colored cottons and
                                woolens, rub in with lard, let lie, soap, let lie again, and treat alternately with oil
                                of turpentine and water. Silks the same, more carefully, using benzine instead of oil of
                                turpentine. Scorching.— White goods, rub well with linen rags dipped in chlorine water.
                                Colored cottons, redye if possible, or in woolens raise a fresh surface. Silks, no
                                remedy.— Muster Zeitung for Faerberei, Druckerei, etc. Wouldst know Fresh Eggs.—Les
                                Mondes gives the following old recipe for testing the age of eggs, which, it thinks,
                                seems to have been forgotten. As Nature thinks so<pb n="91" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE
                                MANIFESTO. 91 too, we may reproduce the recipe for our younger readers, and also as
                                having other possible applications. Dissolve 120 grammes of common salt in a liter of
                                water. An egg put in this solution on the day it is laid will sink to the bottom ; one a
                                day old will not reach quite to the bottom of the vessel; an egg three days old will
                                swim in the liquid ; while one more than three days old will swim on the surface,
                                Colored Inks for Stamping.— The following are commended for the colors most frequently
                                wanted for stamping purposes: Red. Dissolve £ oz. of carmine in 2 oz. of strong water of
                                ammonia, and add 1 drachm of glycerine and f oz. of dextrine. Blub. Rub 1 oz. of
                                Prussian blue with enough water to make a perfectly smooth paste ; then add 1 oz. of
                                dextrin, incorporate it well, and finally add sufficient water to bring it to the proper
                                consistence.—111. Sci. News. Leghorn hats are whitened (otherwise than with the fumes of
                                sulphur) as follows : Immerse in a strong aqueous solution of sulphite of soda or
                                bleaching powder (chloride of lime), and then in dilute sulphuric acid (acid 1, water
                                5). The bleaching powder treatment requires much subsequent washing, or the use of an
                                antichlore dip, hyposulphite of soda dissolved in 20 parts of water.—Ditto. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Use of the lemon" TEIform="index"/>Use of the lemon
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> The Use of the Lemon . — There are three ways of making lemonade : To squeeze the juice
                                into cold water—this is the short est way; or to cut it in slices and soak it in cold
                                water, or to cut it in slices and then boil it. Lemonade is one of the best and safest
                                drinks for a person, whether in health or not. It is suitable to all stomach diseases;
                                is excellent in sickness. The pips, crushed, may also be mixed with water, and used as a
                                drink. We advise every one to rub the gums daily with lemon juice, to keep them in
                                health. The hands and nails are also kept clean, white, soft and supple by the use of
                                lemon instead of soap. It also prevents chilblains. Lemon is used in intermittent
                                fevers, mixed with strong, hot black coffee, without sugar. Neuralgia may be cured by
                                rubbing the part affected with a cut lemon. It is valuable, also, to cure warts, and to
                                destroy dandruff on the head by rubbing the roots of the hair with it.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Table</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Preacher's Cabinet" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Culture and Religion" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">The enterprising publishers, I. K. Funk &amp; Co., 10 and 12 Dey street, New York,
                                quite outdo our power or space to do full justice. Volume after volume of the most
                                healthy literature issues almost daily from this house. Among the most recent
                                publications are The Preacher's Cabinet, containing 335 verbal illustrations of almost
                                as many topics. It is a multum in parvo, and will be carried in the pockets of many, who
                                cannot better spare 20 cents than purchase an immense encyclopedia. Also, Culture and
                                Religion — an excellent work, clearly showing that there is no antagonism, but a genuine
                                relationship, between them. Price, 15 cents. Also, by the same, Standard Hymns, with
                                historical notes of their authors. A pretty little work. Price, 6 cents</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Illustrated scientific news" TEIform="index"/>THE ILLUSTRATED SCIENTIFIC NEWS</head><p TEIform="p">One of the handsomest of publications is the Illustrated Scientific News, published by
                                Munn &amp; Co., New York. Every number contains thirty-two pages, full of engravings
                                of novelties in science and the useful arts. Ornamental wood-work, pottery, vases and
                                objects of modern and ancient art are finely shown. The March number contains, among
                                various other subjects illustrated, a full description of the manufacture of paper
                                hangings, with engravings; how the deceptive curve is produced in casting the ball by
                                the baseball pitcher, his attitude, how he holds and handles the ball, all fully
                                illustrated. The number before us also contains engravings of Captain Eads' proposed
                                ship railway across the isthmus, and a novel hydraulic railway locomotive. In addition
                                to all this, it contains many valuable recipes for artisans and housekeepers.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Revised new testament" TEIform="index"/>THE REVISED NEW TESTAMENT</head><p TEIform="p">Shall we have a Cheap Official Edition? —• The Help of our Readers asked to secure it. It
                                is believed that the English Oxford Press (the official publishers) would be willing to
                                issue a cheap popular edition of the<pb n="92" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. New
                                Testament, provided they can be convinced that the demand for such an edition in this
                                country is great enough to warrant it. To test the extent of this demand our readers are
                                requested to send at once to I. K. Funk &amp; Co., 10 and 12 Dey street, New York,
                                their names, stating how many copies they are willing to take for themselves and
                                friends, provided the price per copy be not more than 25 cents, postage free. These
                                would be the official copies, printed in Oxford, England, from the original plates, and
                                would be delivered in America simultaneously with the high-priced edition.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canterbury Shakers" TEIform="index"/>THE CANTERBURY SHAKERS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Winkley, Francis and Sanborn, Israel" TEIform="persName"/>Francis Winkley, Israel Sanborn</byline><p TEIform="p">[Copied from a New Hampshire Gazeteer, published in 1815, by Rev. Eliphalet Merrill, of
                            Northwood, N. H.] " On the S. E. side of the town near Loudon, is the Shakers' Village ; and
                            as the head of their family has furnished the compilers of this work with a particular
                            account of their concerns, we take pleasure in giving it in his own words. " The believers
                            (or people commonly called Shakers), in Canterbury, have been in the faith we now profess
                            upwards of thirty years, and have had one Lord and one baptism, which is a crucifixion and
                            death to the nature of sin, and unites the soul in the spirit and power of the resurrection
                            of life. " We have united our temporal interest for more than twenty years ; except some,
                            who have since misbelieved, or those who did not choose so to do ; as there is no compulsion
                            with us in such a case. We live together in love and union, as brothers and sisters in the
                            spirit and not in the flesh. * * * As to marriages, we are all married to one, even to
                            Christ who is in, and is the head of, His body, the Church. "Death.— The souls who are in
                            Christ do not die ; and to the faithful soul who departs this life there is no sting. Within
                            thirty years, thirty persons, old and young, have departed this life in our society here,
                            for whom we do not mourn, believing they have the fruits of their labors. " We have
                            generally consisted of from two hundred to three hundred souls in this village. We have one
                            meeting-house, open at all times for public worship for all civil, discreet, candid and
                            well-behaved people ; but those who are otherwise minded, we wish them in better employ than
                            to come among us. We have seven dwelling-houses, one deacon's office, and a number of
                            workshops, both for brethren and sisters, and several mills, etc., on an artificial stream.
                            " We occupy upwards of one thousand acres of land, which is consecrated to the Lord, to all
                            of which we hold a lawful and constitutional right to govern and protect from all abuse ;
                            and in that we are assisted by the ministers of the good civil authority to which we have
                            respect, and from whence we derive support. " We manufacture many articles for sale, which
                            we endeavor to make worth what the purchaser gives for them, such as linen and woolen
                            wheels, measures, sieves, candlesticks, brooms, wooden ware, boxes of wood, whips, cooper's
                            set work, cards for wool and cotton, rakes and snaths, leather of different kinds, etc. We
                            also raise garden seeds, in which we take pains to propagate the best kinds. " For several
                            years we have not made use of spirituous liquors except for sickness or infirmity, seeing
                            the evil it brings on the human race. And to escape another obvious evil, we have not made a
                            practice of trusting or being trusted. "We believe the above sketches to be supportable in
                            truth ; and if it answer your purpose ye will insert it without varying the sense. Ye are
                            also welcome to our names. " In union with and behalf of the people called Shakers, in
                            Canterbury. (Signed.) " " P. S.— Our beloved brethren and sisters at Enfield, in this State,
                            are nearly of the same number, and are in the same faith and kingdom, and in similar
                            circumstances. " F. W. " I. S."</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When evil days come, as evil days will, no man deserves the title of gentleman..." TEIform="index"/>When evil days come, as evil days will, no man deserves the title of gentleman...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">When evil days come, as evil days will, no man deserves the title of gentleman if he does not
                            take honest work to do, regardless of social influences.</p></div2><pb n="93" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Minister's daughter" TEIform="index"/>THE MINISTER'S DAUGHTER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whittier, John Greenleaf" TEIform="persName"/>JOHN GREENLEAF WHITTIER</byline><p TEIform="p">In the minister's morning sermon He had told of the primal fall, And how thenceforth the
                            wrath of God Rested on each and all. And how, of His will and pleasure, All souls, save a
                            chosen few, Were doomed to the quenchless burning And held in the way thereto. Yet never by
                            .faith's unreason A saintlier soul was tried, And never the harsh old lesson A tenderer
                            heart belied. And, after the painful service On that pleasant Sabbath day He walked with his
                            little daughter Thro' the apple-bloom of May. Sweet in the fresh green meadows, Sparrow and
                            blackbird sung; Above him their tinted petals, The blossoming orchards hung. Around, on the
                            wonderful glory The minister looked and smiled, '" How good is the Lord who gives us These
                            gifts from His hand, my child ! " Behold in the bloom of apples, And the violets in the
                            sward, A hint of the old, lost beauty, Of the garden of the Loi'd." Then up spake the little
                            maiden, Treading on snow and pink : " 0 Father ! these pretty blossoms Are very wicked, I
                            think. " Had there been no Garden of Eden, There never had been a fall, And if never a tree
                            had blossomed God would have loved us all." "Hush, child !" the father answered, " By His
                            decree man fell ; His ways are in clouds and darkness, But He doeth all things well. " And
                            whether by his ordaining To us cometh good or ill, Joy or pain, or light or shadow, We must
                            fear and love him still." " Oh, I fear Him ! " said the daughter, " And I try to love him
                            too ; But I wish he was good and gentle, Kind and loving as you." The minister groaned in
                            spirit As the tremulous lips of pain, And wide, wet eyes uplifted, Questioned his own in
                            vain. Bowing his head, he pondered The words of the little one ; Had he erred in his
                            life-long teaching ? Had he wrong to his master done ? To what grim and dreadful idol, Had
                            he lent the holiest name ? Did his own heart, loving and human, The God of his worship shame
                            ? And lo ! from the bloom and greenness, From the tender skies above, And the face of his
                            little daughter, He read a lesson of love. No more, as the cloudy terror Of Sinai's mound of
                            law, But as Christ in Syrian lilies The vision of God he saw. And as when in the clefts of
                            Horeb, - Of old was his presence known, The dread Ineffable Glory Was Infinite Goodness
                            alone. Thereafter his hearers noted In his prayers a tenderer strain, And never the gospel
                            of hatred, Burned on his lips again. And the scoffing tongue was prayerful, And the blinded
                            eyes found sight, And hearts, as flint aforetime, Grew soft in his warmth and light.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progression: a sonnet" TEIform="index"/>PROGRESSION: A Sonnet</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p"> Eternal rounds ! the cyclic periods meet In grand succession, all replete, And in
                            procession, spiral tower, Moved forward by an unseen power That veils the secrets of a plan
                            Which moulds the destiny of man. This earth from fires chaotic rolled, And, by unchanging
                            laws controlled In form symmetric borne through space 'Mong other worlds assumed its place.
                            Thus, from the old evolves the new, From darkness light, from false the true, And life
                            progressive onward tends 'Till infinite with finite blends.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Scotch clergyman, whose habit was to preach hell-fire to his congregation..." TEIform="index"/>A Scotch clergyman, whose habit was to preach hell-fire to his congregation...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> A Scotch clergyman, whose habit was to preach hell-fire to his congregation in large doses,
                            had occasion to visit a poor, sick parishioner. After enlarging with considerable unction on
                            his favorite topic, he said to her: "Now my dear woman, did you ever appreciate the tortures
                            of the damned before?" . " Nae, nae; never till you came here."</p></div2><pb n="94" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Divine afflatus" TEIform="index"/>DIVINE AFFLATUS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>James G. Russell</byline><p TEIform="p"> Moderate Enfield, N. H. 1. All hail thou glorious light, Shining on Mount Zion's height, 2.
                            Behold, thy kingdom come! Father now thy will be done, Casting out all shades of night,
                            Thy "divine afflatus" run, That righteousness may reign. Thro' earth and heav'n the
                            same. CHORUS. Zion's inmates one and all, Heed ye now the spirit call. Let thy light so
                            shine abroad, That sin-sick souls may cease to plod <pb n="95" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 95 The way no eye can see. But viewing on Mount Zion's height, The fullness of
                            thy glory bright, May gather home to thee.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lucretia Mott" TEIform="index"/>LUCRETIA MOTT</head><p TEIform="p"> A radical and thorough advocate of the peace cause — a mother to her people — has departed
                            to her home in the better land. Her struggles for peace will be better appreciated in af't»r
                            years. Her fame as a reformer will spread with increasing luster. She dedicated herself to
                            the cause of righteousness in the early dawn of womanhood, and her whole life bloomed with
                            heavenly fragrance. The fruits thereof made the world rich with its blessings. Hope, faith
                            and labor made her precious life a perfect melody. No matter how steep the ascent, she went
                            up into the mountain and blessed the multitude. She was born January 3d, 1793, and quietly
                            closed her mortal career on the 11th of November, 1880. Among her sayings we record the
                            following : " We must not admit that war is right under any circumstances. We must take
                            higher grounds than this. Bible authority in favor of war should not blind us. In the Bible
                            we have accounts of Israel's God beingwarlike. We have divine tuitions and a higher standard
                            than this. It is not in man's higher nature to fight. Long before Jesus there were advocates
                            of peace. Even Buddh ists are surprised to find what a warring people we are. Moral power is
                            found to be all-sufficient to go/era children. It is wrongto bring up boys of the Girard
                            College as soldiers." Thefe admonitions were always spoken by her in tenderness and
                            decision. May her wise teachings be long remembered, and may more of her sex lift their
                            voices for Christian love, purity and peace. Amen.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good for houses" TEIform="index"/>GOOD FOR HOUSES</head><p TEIform="p"> A good thing to give a horse after he has been driven is a quart of oat-meal stirred into a
                            pail of water. It refreshes and strengthens him, relieves his immediate thirst, and prepares
                            his stomach for more solid food. It is like the plate of soup before dinner— satisfying and
                            appetizing to gether. [We copy the above from an exchange. We purpose to use the same good
                            hint in the heated harvest fields for our help • and would urge it as a superior beverage to
                            beer or spirituous drinks for hard- working, over-heated, thirsty men and women. — Ed.]</p></div2><pb n="96" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Crooked paths" TEIform="index"/>Crooked paths
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stuttle, L." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">CROOKED PATHS. Mrs. L. Stuttle. Cold and dark was the Wintry sky, Black were the
                                    clouds as they hurried by; Veiled were the stars; and the moon so bright Shed not a
                                    flickering ray of light. Is it the voice of the winds I hear? Waileth the storm in
                                    my shrinking ear ? Is it the shriek of the angry blast, Tossing the trees as it
                                    rushes past? Hark! 'tis the cry of a sinking form, Lost in the pitiless blinding
                                    storm. Slower, and slower the poor feet go, Round and round, through the drifting
                                    snow. Oh, how crooked the paths he makes! Oh, how many the sad mistakes! Joy, oh,
                                    joy! Through the dreary night, Far away shines a welcome light. "Wow, at last, he
                                    can surely go Straight ahead through the blinding snow; Now he can follow his
                                    shining guide; Why should he falter or turn aside? But the tired limbs are benumbed
                                    with cold, And the form is feeble and weak and old, And the poor feet wearily climb
                                    the hill, But the path is crooked and winding still. By-and-by, when the goal is
                                    gained, When the longed-for rest is at length attained, When the glorious light of
                                    the new-born day Scatters the darkness far away, The old man smiles through his
                                    grateful tears, To see how crooked his path appears. 'Tisthus through the toilsome
                                    night of life, Vexed and worn with its ceaseless strife, Oh, how many the vows we
                                    break! Oh, how crooked the paths we make! Yet, how oft with an eye of pride Scorn we
                                    the lost one turned aside! Oh, how oft from the weak we turn, Uttering words that
                                    are cold and stern! Ah, how little we know the smart Buried deep in our brother's
                                    heart! Little we know of the grief and cares, Little we know of the earnest prayers.
                                    Little we dream of the foes he hath — Naught can we see but the crooked path. Not on
                                    man, with a cruel frown Looketh the pitying Saviour down ; But as a Father, kind and
                                    true, Sheddeth his mercies ever new. But when the morn of eternal day Driveth the
                                    darkness far away Oh, how crooked will then appear The winding paths we are making
                                    here!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl">in <index level1="Advent review" TEIform="index"/>Advent Review.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hard pan aphorisms" TEIform="index"/>HARD PAN APHORISMS</head><p TEIform="p">Any kind of an honest job is better than no job at all. Take a dollar a day for your work if
                            you can get no more. A man's best friends are his ten fingers. When,, country boys come to
                            the city, if they will hold on to the old sweet ways they can defy the world. Keep your grip
                            on the hard pan of principle and good conduct, and you will be men of good name and good
                            fortune. When a boy fills a house with bugs, he is all right, provided he don't run after
                            humbugs. He has the makings in him of a great naturalist. A good farmer is better than a
                            poor doctor, and a good horse-shoer is better than a bishop who preaches sermons that nobody
                            wants to hear. A good day's work of what you can best do is the hard pan to which all must
                            come. Society says one thing, and nature says another. Work is good medicine.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Judge religion by their fruits" TEIform="index"/>Judge Religions by their Fruits</head><p TEIform="p">That old Catholic woman, of whom Mr. Stevensori tells in his "Travels with a Donkey," who
                            said to him that there was no difference between Protestants and Catholics "save that '
                            wrong was more wrong for the Catholic' who had more light and guidance," came very near
                            telling an important truth. That was all the difference that the good old saint herself
                            knew, and if there were other distinctions whose import she did not quite grasp, who shall
                            deny that she clearly stated the only lawful claim that one religion can have for
                            pre-eminence over another ? If my neighbor's religion makes "wrong more wrong" and right
                            more right for him than my religion does for me, then his religion is for him a better
                            religion than mine is for me. A religion that does not deepen the moral convictions and
                            strengthen the moral purposes is good for nothing; and all religions are to be valued in
                            proportion as they bring forth in their votaries this fruit!</p></div2><!--
                     <pb id="p29"/>
                     <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>