<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1302" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">13</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><date value="18830201" TEIform="date">February 1883</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">25-48</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="13" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb n="t.p." id="p1"/>
                    <p> VOL. XIII. FEBRUARY. NO. 2. SHAKER MANIFESTO. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT
                        HARVARD, MASS. "Blessed are those that hear the word of God and keep it." SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H.
                        1883. </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>
                        </head>
                        <p> [Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="25" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><!--
                    <div2 type="note">
                        <p> CONTENTS. Page . Greatness,....... 25 Invitation, ...... 26 Never Mind what "They" say, 27 Rapid Eating,......
                            Shirley Village, Middlesex, Co., Mass. 28 Asceticism, ...... 31 '•'Charity thinketh no Evil," 32 The Reliable
                            Character, In Remembrance of our First Parents, 33 A Goodly Example, - - Truth, - - -* -. - - - - 34 Joy of
                            Liberty, ..... 35 Perseverance, ...... " Doing Good,...... 36 Thy Best, ....... 37 Where There's A Will There's
                            A Way, Zeruah Clark, ..... Life is Brief,...... Pain, ....... Consistency....... Letter Box, .....
                            Notes,........ Vegetable Diet, .... Weak Lungs, ..,..-. Never, ...... Kind Words for the Year 1882, House and
                            Earm, - Books and Papers,..... Di:at::s,....... Music;—Petition,..... Vol. XIII. FEBRUARY, 1883. Page. 39 42 18
                            44 45 4G 47 No. 2. </p>
                    </div2>
                        [Needs pb codes filled out and needs to be re-scanned]
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Greatness" TEIform="index"/> GREATNESS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/> ELIJAH MYRICK.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Inherent greatness and endowments, unsupported by virtue, benevolence and humble service to
                            humanity, is but a vast and barren waste. . Great possessions are a desert, unless
                            complemented with these active elements. Position is a trust, a garment worn today, which
                            may be put upon another tomorrow. The wheel of fortune may turn up opportunities for great
                            achievements, and too many wait for such events, heedless of the very things which
                            constitute greatness. In reply to the question "Who shall be the greatest," our exampler
                            said, "He who does the greatest service to all." True greatness consists then in the merit
                            of humble service. According to this maxim, the highway to greatness is open to all, and in
                            degree is only measured by the improvement of opportunity. "Subtract from a great man all
                            that he owes to opportunity ; all that he owes to chance, and all that lie has gained by the
                            wisdom and folly of others, and the giant will often be left a pigmy." Greatness is too
                            often eclipsed by selfish conceit and egotism, an incubus on greatness, as sure as
                            gravitation ; while deference and a heedful care of that which is least, is as sure to carry
                            one up to a just estimation of true worth, as the ascent of flame. All cannot be great ia
                            the sense in which the world esteem greatness, but all can greatly do the little duties and
                            obligations which contribute to the happiness of our fellow beings. Faithfulness "in a few
                            things,"— small things insures a trust in "many, greater things." True merit.can never <pb n="26" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. hide from the appreciative eye. Strive for useful
                            service rather than greatness. Reputation may shine like a meteor; but character is a fixed
                            star. The vast ocean is composed of drops. The great mountains are only associated particles
                            of matter. The suspension bridge is supported by thousands of small wires, the accumulative
                            strength of ¦which bears hundreds of tons safely over it. So with us in our relations to
                            each other, it is the countless every day attentions to little things which make up •the sum
                            total of greatness. It matters nothing what the particular duties are to which the
                            individual is called, how minute or obscure in their nature. Greatness lies not in the
                            extent of the sphere that is filled, or of the effect which is produced, bat altogether in
                            the power of virtue in the soul; the impelling motive, the love of goodness. "We call him
                            great who does some deed That echo bears from shore to shore,— 33oes that, and then does
                            nothing more, Yet would his work, earn richer meed, When brought before the King of Kings,
                            Were he but great in little things." Harvard, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Invitation" TEIform="index"/> INVITATION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>OLIVER C. HAMPTON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "Come unto me all ye that labor and are heavy laden and I will give you rest. Take my yoke
                            upon you, and learn of me for I am meek and lowly and ye shall find rest to your
                            souls."—Matt. xi: 28. We are fully aware that sorrow and unrest are the bitter portion of
                            very many of Earth's denizens at the present time. Mercy, forgiveness—above all, charity,
                            seem to have taken their flight from earth, and cruelty and oppression, treachery and
                            betrayal of friends have taken their place. Now we say most fervently and sincerely, to all
                            who are weary of these conditions, that we have something better to offer themr even an
                            asylum of peace and contentment where the elements of enjoyment, both now and hereafter may
                            be practically laid hold of and appropriated by all who are ready to exchange a selfish life
                            in the world, for an unselfish life "Hid with Christ in God ;" and capable of increasing
                            felicity Ad Eternum. We know whereof we affirm, by practical experience, and we know we live
                            the life which Jesus the Christ lived and taught, because we constantly experience the
                            fruitions and beatitudes which he declared to be the inevitable results of such a life.
                            Would you not be glad to be ushered into a society of practical Christians ignoring all
                            private, selfish habits and indulgences, and living for the good of each other? Whose
                            Comfort and blessing were augmented exactly in proportion to their interest and zeal in
                            promoting the comfort and blessing of others ? It cannot be otherwise than you should enjoy
                            such a life and be. happy in a community leading it, provided you are "weary and heavy
                            laden" with the sins and shams of this present evil and adulterous world, and ready to take
                            a glorious step higher. How many have trespassed against the faithful and sincere
                            admonitions of conscience and wept bitter tears of repentance over their short-comings,
                            resolving to amend their lives, and wishing they might be able to live free from future
                            temptations and be once for all emancipated from the slavery of sin ; even as the Judean
                            Leader said to Isra26 <pb n="27" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE el's Host on one occasion, "The Egyptians ye
                            have this day seen, ye shall see them no more forever." And yet for want of the power and
                            heavenly magnetism of an organized sinless Christian Church from which to gather daily food
                            and the strength of heavenly manna, have fallen again into sin and despair, almost wishing
                            they had never been born, rather than to be the sport and mockery of such painful,
                            unendurable relapses. Now we testify to you sincerely, joyfully ; we are living in just such
                            a Christian Church as is able to afford you immunity from actual sin, and open to you the
                            gates of a sinless Paradise which no man shall be able to shut, so long as you adhere to its
                            holy ordinances and are willing to be guided by its love and disciplined into the saving
                            efficacy of its wisdom. Once legitimately joined in spirit to .this Christian Church of
                            Believers, by a sincere confession and repentance of every recollected sin and derilection
                            from right, you need go no more out forever or be left to stumble and fall among the gloomy
                            crypts of sin and despair. Your pathway will continue to shine umore and more unto the
                            perfect day" and your progress be upward and onward into more and more peace and felicity
                            forever. We are well persuaded that could mankind see these things as they really are, great
                            numbers would choose this life and its purity, unselfishness, and felicity—and so we
                            continually and lovingly hold out the hand oi invitation, to all who feel ready for
                            something better than the pleasures of a rudimental plane of existence, and a fugitive,
                            perishing world ; in the same spirit and words of Jesus which begins this article. Union
                            Village, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Never mind what 'they' say" TEIform="index"/>NEVER MIND WHAT "THEY" SAY </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Don't worry nor fret About what people think, Of your ways or your means, Of your
                                    food or your drink. If you know you are doing Your best every day, With the right on
                                    your side, Never mind what "they" say. Lay out in the mmorning Your plans for each
                                    hour, And never forget That old time is a power. This also remember, 'Mong truths
                                    old and new, The world is too busy To think much of you. Then garner the minutes
                                    That make up the hours, And pluck in your pilgrimage Honor's bright flowers. Should
                                    grumblers assure you Your course will not pay, With conscience at rest, Never mind
                                    what "they" say. Then let us, forgetting The insensate throng That jostles us daily,
                                    While marching along, Press onward and upward, And make no delay, And though people
                                    talk Never mind what "they" say. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Domestic Journal" TEIform="index"/>Domestic Journal</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rapid eating" TEIform="index"/>Rapid eating
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is a mistake, says the Lancet, to eat quickly. Mastication performed in haste must be
                            imperfect, even wit the best of teeth, adn due admixture of the salivary secretion with the
                            food cannot take place. When a crude mass of inadiquately crushed muscular fibre, or
                            undivided solid material of any description, is thrown into the stomach, it acts as a
                            mechanical irritant, and sets up a condition in the mucous membrane lining that organ which
                            greatly impedes, if it does not altogether prevent, the process of digestion.<pb n="28" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> When the practice of eating quickly and filling the stomach with unprepared
                            food is habitual, the digestive organ is rendered incapable of performing its proper
                            functions. Either a much larger quantity of food than would be necessary under natural
                            conditions is required, or the system suffers from lack is required, or the system suffers
                            from lack of nourishment. Those animals which were intended to feed hurriedly were either
                            gifted with the power of rumination, or provided with gizzards. Man is not so furnished, and
                            it is fair to assume that he was intended to eat slowly. We must apologize for reminding our
                            readers of facts so familiar; but we do this in the hope that any who may chance to have
                            influence with the managers of large hotels, where dinners a la table d'hote are in vogue,
                            will take measures to bring about a much-needed reform in the manner in which these
                            entertainments are conducted. At the best and most frequented establishments in places of
                            fashionable resort, where at this season multitudes of health-seekers are wont to
                            congregate, the hurried dinners are not only causes of annoyance, but actually go far to
                            prevent the benefit which should be derived from a change. No sooner is one course served
                            than another is introduced, without giving the guest time to digest, or even swallow the
                            first. The eagerness to secure good dividends takes a particularly mischievous form when it
                            piles food on the plate of a customer, and compels him to consume it breathlessly. The
                            matter may seem a small one, but it is not so. Just as a man may go on for years with
                            defective teeth imperfectly masticating his food, and wondering why he suffers from
                            indigestion, so a man may habitually live under an infliction of hurried dinners, and endure
                            the consequent loss of health, without knowing why he is not well, or how easily the cause
                            of his illness might be remedied. </p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shirley Village, Middlesex Co. Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>
                            Shirley Village, Middlesex Co. Massachusetts
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wetherbee, William H." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The Illustration of "Our Home at Shirley" given in this No. is a street view of the Church
                            family of the Shirley Shakers. The Community at this place is pleasantly located in the
                            southerly part of the Town, one mile from the Station, on the Fitchburg R. R. The street
                            running north and south, is lined with beautiful shade trees on either side, and a short
                            distance from the center both north and south, are excellent watering places, supplied the
                            year round with the best of water ; which, during the warm season, are greatly appreciated
                            by both man and beast. Here lies about one thousand acres of land owned by this community.
                            The soil is good and easily tilled, and with judicious management a good living can be
                            secured by farming. Here devoted workers, both men and women have toiled incessantly for a
                            century of years, to upbuild and sustain one of the Shaker communities, now known throughout
                            the nation. The testimony and sketches of the life and character of Elijah Wilds have been
                            published and need not now be repeated. He occupied and owned a homestead in this place,
                            previous to the time that the Shakers started a community, and his hospitality was shared by
                            Mother Ann Lee and others of the founders of Shakerism in* this country. His ancient
                            dwelling with two stately Elms in front have stood the winds and tempests of more than a
                            century. Nathan Willard, Oliver Burt, Amos Buttrick, and Ivery Wilds, were prominent men,
                            with corresponding able and devoted women forming the brother and sisterhood, were among
                            tlie early settlers in this place. By faithfulness, industry, and economy these early and
                            devoted veterans were enabled to enlarge, beautify and secure "Our Home at Shirley." While
                            toiling to accumulate a substance of the needful things of this life, they were not
                            unmindful of the spiritual welfare, both of themselves and of the generations to come after
                            them. Uppermost in their pursuits was a practical illustration of the principles of purity,
                            honesty and righteousness. The Christ life and salvation from sin, being their motto. These
                            principles, have been handed down and kept intact, while some errors, and some superstitions
                            and prejudicial customs are giving way, and the watch-word now is, Progression, holding fast
                            to the truth, and to fundamental principles. The present number of able and devoted workers,
                            is small, and they are watching, working, waiting. Shirley, Mass.</p></div2><pb n="29" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="figure" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Church family, 'Shakers' Shirley, Massachusetts, looking north" TEIform="index"/> CHURCH
                            FAMILY, "SHAKERS" SHIRLEY, MASS., LOOKING NORTH. </head><p TEIform="p">[figure]</p></div2><pb n="30" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/><pb n="31" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Asceticism" TEIform="index"/> ASCETICISM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/> MARTHA J. ANDERSON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Not all earth's denizens,—the human race— To sensual life their noblest powers have given; '
                            On history's page this glowing truth we trace, That souls for high and glorious aims have
                            striven. In all ages, and in every clime, the golden chain of heavenly principles has been
                            ontwrought, in individual life and character. They, who in their mental development,
                            expressed the highest unfoldment of the spirituality of their time, have ascended above the
                            basic plane of animal desire and indulgence, to the cerebral region of inner consciousness
                            the God-life of the soul, where they could enjoy the blessedness of spiritual communion
                            untrammelled by vvorldliness and exterual temptation to sin. "Virtue, forever frail as fair
                            below, Her tender nature suffers hi the crowd, Nor touches on the world without a stain."
                            The oriental doctrine that matter was the origin of evil, hence the body was an enemy to the
                            soul, influenced many in earlier ages, to withdraw from all human society, and abide in
                            seclusion. Such uniformly adopted austere rules of action and rigorous abstinence from all
                            the pleasures of the senses. Ancient Egypt, Hindostan, and Arabia, abounded with recluses,
                            who voluntarily chose an ascetic habit of life, counting earthly things of little importance
                            compared with the joys of that higher spiritual state, attainable by contemplation of God,
                            and communion with the invisible world. The climactic conditions of the Orient seemed
                            especially adapted to the development of that peculiar temperament and mentaality which
                            naturally tend to exclusive meditation, and extreme fervor. Hence when Christianity was
                            introduced into Egypt and the adjacent countries; it assumed in many cases, the form of the
                            most rigid asceticism. So spiritual and yet so practical was the nature of its principles;
                            that many unbalanced minds, conjoining the purely religious element, with the notion that
                            all materiality was in its nature evil, and detrimental to spiritual growth, carried the
                            idea of celibacy to extreme results, which tended to create abnormal physical conditions,
                            and rendered the spirit while under mortal bonds, incapable of acting out its highest
                            convictions of right. Extravagances of asceticism were usually more apparent among those who
                            were termed anchorites, who dwelt alone in dese ts, on mountains or in caves, with nothing
                            to regulate them but the wild fantasies of their own fevered imaginations, wrought up by an
                            intensified nervous state induced by protracted fasts. In many cases there came a
                            reactionary state of mind, and individuals plunged in the depths of sin, under a pretext
                            that their souls were too holy to be contaminated therewith. Religious institutions
                            established at later periods, for the protection, accommodation and regulation of the
                            religiously inclined; were blessed with the salutary influence of labor, which proved
                            beneficial in checking the visionary tendencies of the enthusiastic devotee. There were
                            various phases of cenobite life among those who embraced Christianity, and measurably
                            comprehended the grand principles of the virgin life and community of property. Saint Martin
                            acted under the idea that all mercenary employment detracted from the sanctity of the monk's
                            life ; hence, his disciples lived in holes cut from the <pb n="32" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                            rocks, or built narrow wooden cells, which they inhabited and worked just enough to barely
                            raise a meagre subsistence. Ashamed of the necessities of the body, the religious devotee
                            paid but little attention to its actual needs ; and, from the uncleanliness of his habits,
                            was often the object of loathing and disgust. Extraordinary acts of mortification and piety,
                            alone ensured his salvation. Many of the holiest of these solitaries were believed to be
                            invested with miraculous power, which enabled them to perform great wonders ; these the
                            common people sought with superstitious faith ; and it has been asserted that many
                            miraculous cures were performed, in their presence. (To BE CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reliable character" TEIform="index"/> THE RELIABLE CHARACTER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Danforth, Nancy G." TEIform="persName"/> NANCY G. DANFORTH.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The person of unflinching integrity is respected by all; the friendship of such is
                            universally desired, and in such times as try men's souls their aid is sought after by those
                            who, in days of prosperity, ridicule and despise them. That person whether man or woman,
                            rich or poor who will be firm for the right, regardless of present consequences is of
                            estimable worth. Though he may be clad in rags and beg his daily bread, yet his virtue is of
                            more value than re"¦al robes or golden crowns. To whom do we. look when burdens press
                            heavily upon us, when troubles assail, or afflictions overtake us? Do we turn to the vain
                            and fickle for help, expect succor or even sympathy from the inconstant? Nay, but the true
                            and upright alone we would enlist on our side, knowing that there will be found strength and
                            firm support. Then who can tell the value of such a character? The true friend in all the
                            relations of life, who rejoices with the upright, loves and pities the erring, without
                            stooping to their vices ; who stands alone, bearing reproach and scorn, from the multitude
                            of evil-doers, rather than yield to do that which conscience forbids. Such are as pure gold,
                            the salt of the earth ; around such all good clusters. They are the basis of good society,
                            without them it could not exist. This being true in the moral, how much more in the
                            spiritual life? The soul that is fully consecrated to do the will of God, will never
                            complain at the cross or seek to shun it; but rather inquire : ilow can I do more good, be
                            more devoted to the .cause of Truth? How are such beloved by their companions on earth !
                            With what love and admiration are they beheld by ministering angels ! Through the mediumship
                            of such souls they are enabled to make known the will of God to those dwelling on the earth.
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Charity thinketh no evil" TEIform="index"/>"CHARITY THINKETH NO EVIL." </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, Amelia J." TEIform="persName"/>AMELIA J. CALVER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Blest Charity is e'er inclined, To view with loving eye; Nor seeks to move Time's drapery, A
                            blemish to descry. For life with all its battle grounds Its fearful odds of fate, Gives each
                            its measurement of grief, Its cares of burd'ning weight. O we are blind to spirit strife!
                            Its conflicts cannot know, Nor trace the winding labyrinths Where some sore feet must go,
                                <pb n="33" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> To meet upon the road of life, Companions of the way, Who found an
                            easier pathway up; Nor met so much delay. Too apt are we of finite gaze, To measure by one
                            span; And credit due oft lies beneath The weight of Censure's ban. But when we drop this
                            mortal coil And rise to higher spheres, The stature we've attained by toil In bold relief
                            appears. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In remembrance of our first parents" TEIform="index"/> IN REMEMBRANCE OF OUR FIRST PARENTS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sampsom, Rachel" TEIform="persName"/> RACHEL SAMPSOM.</byline><p TEIform="p"> While a youth I had the privilege of living with those who have been termed our "First
                            spiritual parents." I was not able at that time to appreciate the blessing which I was so
                            freely enjoying, but as I advance in years, and bear their lives and deeds in cherished
                            remembrance, I realize more fully the care and kindness which were proffered to roe at that
                            early age. Many times have I heard them relate the incidents of their deprivations and
                            hardships, which they experienced as the society was being gathered into order. It was to
                            them the cross of Christ, the self-denial of the increasing gospel work as revealed by
                            Mother Ann, and it was indeed, the New Creation of God. New Lebanon at that early date, was
                            but very sparcely inhabited. Many of the settlers were quite poor and lived in houses made
                            only of logs, and from this an idea may be obtained of their general surroundings. There
                            were many families however, who accepted the faith, and joined the society in New Lebanon
                            that were abundantly blessed. On entering the order and becoming members of a joint
                            interest, all shared equally in every temporal blessing. For several years the Believers
                            were obliged to work very hard, having land to clear, houses to build, food to raise, cloth
                            to make and to obtain by their own skill and industry nearly everything that was demanded
                            for their aintenance. It is surprising to learn how nuch they were able to endure. After
                            toiling all day in their several occupations for a temporal sustenance, they, it the close
                            of these duties spent several hours in religious exercise, which on some occasions would
                            carry them far into the night at the expense of their hours of sleep; and t'et they lived to
                            enjoy their homes and to see a prosperous Community established upon the place where they
                            had consecrated their lives to God. Our first parents, were in the strict sense of the word,
                            self-sacrificing. They were of that order that could freely lay down their selfish lives for
                            the increase and prosperity of the Avork of God. All who were accepted into the society
                            shared bountifully and freely of the blessings which these faithful pioneers had earned.
                            Their care and attention over all whom they accepted was constant, affectionate, and so much
                            in advance of the selfish relations of this world, that they were in truth, parents in the
                            Lord. Day and night they watched and prayed that the protection of our Heavenly Father might
                            bo upon the whole household of faith. As it was toward themselves, they anxiously sought
                            that it might be to others; the way of life and salvation. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Goodly example" TEIform="index"/> A GOODLY EXAMPLE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/>LUCY S. BOWERS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> In all our intercourse and association, one with another, how necessary it is that we
                            manifest justice,' and a goodly example; that we forget not the law of righteousness, nor
                            the blessedness of self-control; especially is this incumbent upon us when brought in
                            contact with others. None of us can become so isolated from or independent of each other
                            that our influence will not reach and affect those with whom we are associated; neither can
                            we avoid through this means being more or less operated upon; and according to the
                            teachings, surroundings, and the quality of the food ministered to the mind, the formation
                            of character will largely depend; and this we shall be apt to indicate <pb n="34" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/>
                            34 THE Mi through our manners, words and general deportment. In the young, the animal powers
                            are the strongest; a desire to please the senses and and any thing tending in that direction
                            ¦will give that part of their being increased strength, which without a balance of the
                            superior, would create a deformity ; the better must be encouraged, trained rightly, and it
                            will finally crown the human intelligence with eternal beauty. Children are not taught from
                            text-books alone; neither by what is often reiterated to them; but very much from the
                            example of others, the motions, manners, and manifestations of the spirit as they are
                            exhibited, the tenderness of love, and gentleness of instruction ; the mercy of forgiveness,
                            and beauty of courtesy, have much effect upon all toward whom they are exercised; and it is
                            better that we fail not to have these constantly controlling our spirits; for in due time we
                            shall "reap just whatwe have sown.'' As the earlier impressions of life are usually the most
                            vivid in memory, and bear the most potent influence on the mind, we can scarcely be too
                            careful lest in unguarded moments we manifest that to minors which may be the ground work of
                            future thoughts, motives, and actions which it will be difficult for them to overcome. "Love
                            begets love; it is the fulfilling of the law," and proves a gift of good to the giver, and
                            the receiver. There is a responsibility resting upon every one, a sacred duty necessarily
                            done to all of less years or experience than themselves, if they would have them become
                            patterns of true uprightness. Purity of heart is manifested in unfeigned love; and purity of
                            life has no better index than is shown in Christian courtesy, which is always exemplified in
                            honesty, submission persuasion, gentleness, love, forbearance and kindly condescension ;
                            these never bniise the heart, grieve the spirit, blight the beautiful, dwarf the good, nor
                            in any way injure the tender feelings of the soul. Thus the sacred and religious sentiments
                            that will ever increase in loveliness, proves to both giver and partaker a blessing of
                            inestimable worth. This is the work of resurrection; of lifting from the Ioav to the high;
                            of turning the current of life from the false to the true; the ennobling things of a better
                            condition; and an example which has power over precept; a spirit that inspires confidence
                            and affection, and will bring a glorious recompense to all who fulfill this duty, to each
                            succeeding generation. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth" TEIform="index"/>TRUTH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., A. E." TEIform="persName"/>BY A. E. P. </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Roll on, thou mighty tide of truth, And deluge all the land; Sweep error from
                                    those honored posts, Where now it holds command. Roll on, roll on, nor cease thy
                                    flow, Till every seed shall die, Of worthless tares and bitter fruit, Sown by the
                                    enemy. Too long already has this tide Set back upon its source; Still it is gaining
                                    added strength, And a resistless force. And when the rains from heaven descend,
                                    'Twill swell a torrent deep, And foam and dash impetuously, And every barrier leap.
                                    . Then raise the flood-gates, free its course, And let it onward go ! The thirsty
                                    earth will drink it in, And better fruits will grow. Why should we spend our
                                    precious time In beating back the truth? And see grim want and famine gaunt Still
                                    stalking o'er the earth. Why not set free this blessed stream, To irrigate the land?
                                    Why not go into all the world, Obeying Christ's command? Such arc the thoughts
                                    tumultuous, Now surging in my soul; But which I'm vain endeavoring To keep in my
                                    control. You know, to wakeful watching eyes The night seems very long; And should we
                                    work when darkness reigns, It might be all done wrong. But some bright rays are
                                    beaming through, Upon my darkened way, <pb n="35" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 35 And
                                    streaks of light are glancing in, Betokening the day. We'll throw the shutters open
                                    wide, Admit the sun's bright rays. For see the eastern firmament With light is all
                                    ablaze! Now hope revives within my soul I will no longer fear, Since there's a Power
                                    above myself, That silent prayer will hear. For I seem to hear this answer , Come
                                    floating now to me ; "Fear not, fear not, who watch and wait, The truth shall yet be
                                    free. It soon shall have a channel made, I will the gates unlock, And force for it a
                                    passage-way, Though chiseled through a rock."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/> Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Joy of liberty" TEIform="index"/> JOY OF LIBERTY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catherine" TEIform="persName"/> CATHARINE ALLEN.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The records of history, which acquaint us with the conflicts between Science and Religion in
                            the past, forcibly remind us of the great cost by which the radiant dower of civil and
                            religious liberty, now bequeathed to us, has been obtained, and causes us to rejoice in that
                            glorious gift of faith, established by divine revelation, and reaching upward to the eternal
                            hills of progression, and in which science with religion peacefully unites in the strength
                            of that immutable law, which links cause with effect, forever. This beautiful faith is,
                            indeed, "the substance of things hoped for," the wealth for which the past has toiled. It
                            emancipates us from narrow, dogmatical creeds which cripple the mind, fetter hope, and
                            detain within their prison bars, the soul that yearns for liberty, that longs for the
                            divinity which gave it birth ; and feign would take its flight on aspiration's wings, to
                            find its native element, a home in Truth. This liberty wre may attain, and soar with
                            strength of eagle's wings until we reach that sunny home where God is life, and light. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Perserverance" TEIform="index"/> PERSEVERANCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/> DANIEL ORCUTT.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Perseverance is essential to success. "A constant dropping wears away the stone." Don't
                            forget this proverb. If you would discard evil, be in earnest. Let your motto be,
                            "Persevere." Failure to overcome shows that more firmness and resolution is needed. Don't
                            expect to conquer with one blow. Stroke by stroke is the secret of success Jn the Christian
                            wrarfare. Strike now. "Step by step, one goes very far." A great many steps must be taken,
                            all in the right direction—onward and upward. Arm yourself with a steadfast purpose that
                            will repel all hindrances, or your efforts will be unavailing. A doubting, wavering mind
                            gains nothing. Don't "give up" at slow progress. Slow growth is often sure growth. Pray
                            heaven for firmness. Look on the heaven side of life. God's promises will not fail. Trust in
                            Him. Choose wisely, resolve firmly, then execute your purpose with inflexible perseverance,
                            and you will advance to high attainments. "Faithful in that which is least." Apply this
                            motto in every day life. You cannot afford to be unfaithful. There are too many half-doers.
                            We all admire faithfulness in others, and those who are diligent in duty according to their
                            ability, are sure to command <pb n="36" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 36 THE MANIFESTO. respect. If a piece of
                            work is to be done by you, persevere, by all means, and master it. Some persons commence the
                            self-denying work, and with such earnestness that we would suppose they were "determined to
                            persevere to the end." But, a*las ! after "doing well for a season," the work is abandoned ;
                            they "give up;" and thus time rolls on, showing only a blank record, and sad must that be to
                            all who experience it. One proverb, if heeded, would help them; it is this ; "Holdfast what
                            you have gained and add thereto." Perseverance is all-important; practice it and you will be
                            convinced of it-1 value. What has been done, can be done again, and it is only those who
                            persevere that win. Remember the Lord's declaration, "Them that honor me I will honor." Fill
                            with usefulness each moment of time. Don't be put out of heart by trials : they test the
                            material you are made of, and if rightly borne, will do a world of good. The more trials you
                            bear, the sweeter will be the "Peace be unto you." Begin early in life to practice
                            perseverance. Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Doing good" TEIform="index"/> DOING GOOD.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Chandler, Olive F." TEIform="persName"/>OLIVE F. CHANDLER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The source of happiness is found in doing good to humanity; in striving to sweeten, with
                            Christian love and charity, the bitter cup of life. Jesus went about doing good wherever
                            opportunity presented. He carried the spirit of forgiving love and healing sympathy,
                            imparting to the diseased soul and body the elements that made whole. For this He was
                            maligned by those who conceived evil, and scorned by the jealous and bigoted Pharisees. In
                            this opposition came growth to the divine nature. Hence, without friction there can be no
                            deep thought or heroism. Life is not wasted unless it ends in sloth, dishonesty, or
                            cowardice. Success is not worthy of the name unless won by honest industry, and bravely
                            breasting the waves of fortune. Through conflict to victory, is the motto for every human
                            soul; and this is acheived in ways as diverse as our several lots. Our foes are manifold,
                            they are within, around and about us ; they are veiled spectres, whose hiss we hear; whose
                            grip we feel: If not in immediate activity, we know they are gathering, and that combat is
                            at hand. Daily life is vital with influence. The most insignificant act may .set in motion a
                            train of eternal consequences. Our unconscious word may decide a destiny. Some odors abide
                            indefinitely ; so grand sayings and silly acts become photographed and are garnered for
                            worth or. ridicule. We can all do some good in this world, without money, which may prove a
                            happy reflection when we have gone into new fields of labor, or when the frosts of years
                            have whitened our locks. Great conquests, startling events, extraordinary inventions,
                            surprise the world ; but little kindnesses, words of truth and love, sweeten existence, and
                            hold us firmly in fraternal bonds. Milton said : "To understand the common things of life
                            was prime wisdom." Ayer, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Forgiveness" TEIform="index"/> FORGIVENESS.</head><p TEIform="p"> Let me forgive though no forgiveness asked; Tis best to feel my heart free from all blame.
                            The Father doth not wait repentance named, But seeth it, forgiving all the same.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><pb n="37" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thy best" TEIform="index"/>THY BEST. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Newton, Agnes E." TEIform="persName"/>Agnes E. Newton. </byline><p TEIform="p">The best thy heart can offer God Is all that He requires, The perfect living sacrifice • The
                            off'ring He desires. Se&gt;rve God, in life's bright sunlit hours Ere evil days draw nigh; . .
                            Bilek first the Kingdom of our Lord, The priceless jewel buy. Go sow with care the waiting
                            field' Though other hands may reap, And as their labor may present . Thy sheaves of ripened
                            wheat. Go in the Master's Vineyard now; The idle are unblest; Where duty mills, there nobly
                            toil And give to God thy best. Though far removed from mortal view Reward the Father gives;
                            How sweet the inward peace of one Who in His service lives. Then give thy best, an off'ring
                            free, And thy reward is sure; The treasure earned-It crown of life Which ever will endure.
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Where there's a will there's a way" TEIform="index"/>WHERE THERE'S A WILL THERE'S A WAY. </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Though troubles perplex you, Dishearten and vex you, Retarding your progress in
                                    sombre array; To shrink with terror Is surely an error, For where there's a will
                                    there's a way. The task may be teasing, The duty unpleasing, But-he- who confronts
                                    it will soon win the day; Half the battle is over When once we discover That'wher~
                                    there's a will there's a way. Misfortunes, uncounted Are often surmounted, If only
                                    we quit not the field in dismay; Then once more endeavor,' Remembering ever
                                    '.TlUWwhere there's It will there's a way. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Domestic Journal" TEIform="index"/>Domestic Journal</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Zeruah Clark" TEIform="index"/>Zeruah Clark. </head><p TEIform="p">I was born on the 15th. of June, 1755, in the town of Norwich, Ct. My father, Peabody
                            Mosely, was, an Elder in the Baptist church. He was very particular in teaching his family
                            the principles of morality and reo ligion, according to his understanding: and at times, he
                            appeared to be in great exercise of mind for the.spiritual welfare of his children. He would
                            often weep over his children with great tenderness of feeling, while he endeavored to
                            impress their minds with a sense of his religious instructions. Being young, these
                            impressions were not very durable while I was surrounded by the snares and allurements of
                            the world, and the natural growth of youthful vanity' gained the ascendancy over my mind .
                            At a subsequent date, however, I began to be exercised about religion, which increased upon
                            me, so that I was unable to conceal it and finally aj;qtlainted my father and others of the
                            fact. ,{;hey thought that I had been converted, and that it was expedient for me to be
                            baptized: baptism soon followed and I joined the church. At the age of twenty I was married
                            to Rufus Clark, a member of the same church. With a family of three children, and a kind
                            husband, under prosperous circumstances, I found I was in a situation to take comfort in the
                            world. But all this did not make me happy. I had not yet obtained salvation from sin and I
                            found my' consciencc bearing witness against me. I was assured that the nature of sin was
                            growing stronger and stronger in. me, and I cried out, alas! what shall I do? where shall I
                            go; or where shall I look for relief? I could not see any who, I thought, lived in
                            accordance with the doctrine of Christ and the -apostles as laid down in the New Testament.
                            I prayed before God in the best manner I was able, that he would open some way for my
                            salvation. In the month of May 1780, we heard of a very remarkable people who lived a few
                            miles above Albany, and who had a new kind of religion. Prom this account, which greatly
                            affected me, I felt a desire to visit them. Inthis state of mind, Rufus and myself left <pb n="38" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/>home to make them a visit, and took with us, our infant chilli. For the
                            first time, I now found a people professing the religion of Jesus Christ, who did not find
                            it necessary to use "un tempered mortar," and to cry peace and safety where there is none.
                            Here I also heard that soul quickening word of God which I had never heard .bcforo, and felt
                            the force of that divine light and searching ~.ower which I had never, till this time,
                            experienced I felt myself us in the presence of God, and my whole life was open before me,
                            as a book. Mother Ann conversed with us freely upon the subject of a religious life, and
                            told us that we could not love and serve God while in our sins, but that we should honestly
                            confess our sins to God. Elder William Lee spoke to me npon the same subject, "Remember,"
                            said he, "if you confess,your sins, yon confess them before Godund the holy angels, and we
                            are his witnesses .. " Rufus accepted tilt' confession first. I then confessed the wrongs of
                            my life, one by one, as in the presence of God and before his witnesses. 'Mother then said,
                            "N ow you may return to your home, and serve God; you could not serve God while Iivirg in
                            sin." Mother and the Elders imparted to us much good counsel concerning our future conduct,
                            and the relation which we should sustain toward each other. Husbands should love their
                            wives, even as Christ loved the church, and gave himself for it, that he might sanctify and
                            cleanse it; and then referring to me. Mother said, "you must be subject and obedient to
                            your husband and bring up your children in the admonition of the Lord." "If you are
                            obedient," said she, "to what we have taught you, the promise of God is to you and your
                            children; yea, if you continue in obedience, sin will a:'pei\r hateful to you, and you will
                            have no more feeling to return to the works of darkness than the infant in your arms." At a
                            subsequent date we visited Mother and the Elders while they were i~ Harvard. Mother invited
                            us into the room where she was engaged in spiritual labors with several persons who had been
                            the followers of S'f\adrach Ireland; and though they had embraced the present testimony of
                            the gospel, they still retained their faith in some of Ireland's WIio peculiar principles.
                            One of these was, that, the bodies of the faithful would never die. Mother seemed to feel a
                            great anxiety for them, and endeavored to show to them darkness they were under, and the
                            inconsistency of such a principle. "Already, you are aged people," said she, "and yet you
                            think you shall never die! One after another is passing away, from among you: yet you charge
                            it to a secret cuuse---to something which they may have done. You say, if they had been
                            faithful, it would not have occurred. Look at yourselves; you carry abou"t you all the marks
                            of mortality that are on other people. Your' hair is becoming white and falling from your
                            heads: your sight is failing; your teeth are decaying, and your bodies are growing
                            decrepit. . How very inconsistent it is for you to think that you shall never die! These
                            mortal bodies must all return to the earth and turn to dust." , Mother's instruction to ns
                            was, that we should take' up a full cross against all manner of sin, all forms of deceit and
                            falsehood, and against every evil that proceeds from a selfish lind sinful nature. She
                            taught us the necessity of crucifying the flesh with all its affections and lusts, and to
                            right all our' wrongs, by making restitution to those whom we had, in the least degree,
                            injured. She taught us to be neat, cleanly, prudent and industrious. While on one of these
                            visits with Mother, I asked her counsel about some articles of fashionable clothing which I
                            had purchased. Without making any direct reply to my question, she said, "You should not
                            dress yourselves -in rich and costly apparel; but use that which is modest, lind which
                            becomes the holy women of God." Mother taught us to love God and serve Him faithfully, and
                            to live honestly, righteously and godly in this world. I am fully persuaded that she was
                            endowed with the spirit. of wisdom from God; for she taught as never woman taught before.
                            (To be continued.) </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is profitable to take an active interest..." TEIform="index"/>
                            It is profitable to take an active interest...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is profitable to take an active interest in all laudable enterprises, and even join in
                            innocent amusements.</p></div2><pb n="39" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life is brief" TEIform="index"/>LIFE IS BRIEF. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Anna R." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">I walked through a garden all verdant and fair, The flowers were in fullness of bloom;
                            Methought as I gazed, they live not for themselves, For the)' fill nil the nil' with
                            perfnme. But feelings of gloom over.shadowed my mind, Which caused me deep sadness and
                            grief; Tiley witheI' and die 'neath the cold touch of time, Their beautiful life is too
                            brief. The spring•time comes laden with opening buds, A.nd Summer soon fans them to bloom;
                            And whll« I'm enjoying their beauty so rare, ' Tiley're bJiglJtedand fall to earth's tomb;
                            But, there are .fays that time cannot touch, That tilde uot with floweret or leaf; In glory
                            they brigbten in regions beyond, Where life is unending, not brief. So unto tile spirit of
                            goodness I turned, To jO)'S that wi!lnever wax 01U; Where pleasures celestial, of angelle
                            birth With heavenly beauties unfold. The spirit immortal exclaims with new hope, Toil on
                            th"ough all sorrow and grief! .Thy existener, shall last through etel'llity's day, But time,
                            and this earth.life, are brief. Then come loving angels with wisdom endowed, :My be'ing with
                            power embne! Give light to direct me in luty's straight path Awl faith that is stendfnst and
                            true. And while I am climbing the highway of truth At times oyersh,\dowed with gl'ief--'
                            Your sweet hallowed presence each' day may I feel, Through the journey of life that's so
                            brief. And when time hns folded its wings over me, And death opes the bright pearly gate,
                            Maya substance etcrnnl untarnished by sin, Be the treasure my soul shall await. 0, then may
                            I list to tho glad welcome sound, Of angels who've brought me relief! "Enl'th's toils are
                            all ended, Jour work is wen dour, Through tho life that was trunslent and brief." Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pain" TEIform="index"/>PAIN. </head><p TEIform="p">Written for the Manifesto. Oh Pain! Oh Pain! What canst thou be? A chastening agency of Fate
                            Sent to inflict a penalty Upon our frail mortality, And bring us caution all too late? Or
                            dost thou come Death's votary, To frighten us and aggravate; Or art thou the supposed
                            sequence Of N ature and Necessity? The will divine of Providence To silence mortal will and
                            sense? Or art thou horn of sympathy? Which suffers nameless woe immense, Nameless, because
                            too sweet to be Called pain, or rather miseR Iled so. Or-as an Angpl comest thou To teach us
                            well to brave and bear Our griefs and trials here and now, This crown of thorns upon the
                            brow, Teach patiently this crown to wear, To all thy mandates meekly bow, And without
                            protest take our share? Ere we subscribe to this we pause, And criticise thy origin, The ill
                            effects of some bad cause, ' By violation of life's laws, Through iguorance or folly vain;
                            No less a penalty, because Of ignorance, 0 Conqueror, Pain! The sour grapes our fathers ate,
                            Still set the children's teeth on edge; And then the case to aggravate, The children also
                            try the bait Ignore Life's laws nor deign to pledge To seck the right, thus change the fate
                            But still perpetuate the dregs. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Consistency" TEIform="index"/>CONSISTENCY. </head><p TEIform="p">It has been said, that "consistency is a jewel;" which is no doubt owing to the fact, that
                            inconsistency is the rule. To prove this, it is not necessary for any of us .to go far, as
                            each one in taking a retrospect of his, or her life, will perceive in most cases that the
                            inconsistencies predominate. We are composed of the same materials as are people in
                            general, and whatever advantages our system may possess over other systems, consistency is
                            no more a marked characteristic of us, either individually or collectively, than it is of
                            others. The aim of 'our life is to become pure and refined; to cultivate the better
                            elements of our being, while we seek to retain and extinguish what we consider our inferior
                            propensities. It must bc potent to any person of intelligence, that perfect purity of life
                            is impossible apart from courteous manners, and a refined cultured intellect, Noone would
                            think of associating absolute <pb n="40" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/>purity of thought, word, and ,deed, with
                            a rough, boorish, illiterate person. It being admitted therefore, that gentle manners and a
                            cultured intellect are essential stepping' stones to perfect purity of life, is it not
                            highly inconsistent to oppose anything conducive to that end? Much has been said pro and
                            con 'conce~ning the influence which music" pictures, and flowers have upou themind, Some
                            even suppose that their tendency is to draw our minds from spiritual duties. ' 'Yhat are our
                            spirituul duties? If our surroundings are uncongenial, we shall be more or less unhappy;
                            aud to alleviate this unhappiness, and render life pleasant is, indeed, a spiritual duty.
                            The most conservative person would view a beautiful landscape with pleasure, and consider
                            the effects everyway beneficial: and a copy of that same landscape, whether on canvass or
                            paper, affords a corresponding pleasure. A beautiful rose may be admired while on the bush:
                            and it is uo less beautiful when taken into our dwellings, nor its fragrance less
                            acceptable. Many quote from the Bible "Tho~ shalt not make unto thee any grave~ image." But
                            the Bible contains many commands highly inapplicable to our day and civilization: and
                            anyone who should be reckless enough to attempt to p.tt them in practice, would soon
                            discover his mistake: and among the first to rebuke him, would be those who always qnote it
                            so glibly, whenever they have a hobby that needs propping up. The questions of today must
                            necessarily be settled upon their merits, and in accordance with the intelligence and reason
                            of today; and not by the opinions and prejudices of past generations. Our right to usc our
                            reason is as clear as that of our ancestors: and we are not bound to believe what experience
                            has proved to bl' an-error because they did. "A thing of beauty is a joy forever.' Never was
                            truth more fitly spoken. The Apostle says ; "By the things which are seen, we know of the
                            things which are not seen." If we were blind, we should know very little either of the
                            "things .whieh are seen, or the things which are not seen;" and a thing of beauty could be
                            no joy to us. But as we arc not blind, and as we are promised all things beautiful in
                            another world, and as the same God is supposed to rule all worlds, why should we be denied
                            the limited enjoyment of that here, of which we are to enjoy such a superabundance
                            hereafter? As we reserve our best clothing for the Sabbath, why should we not have our
                            bestrbooka, papers, pictures, or whatever may conduce to make us more like the sons and
                            daughters of God, where we can enjoy them .on the Sabbath? May not our fine clothing
                            detract as much from our spiritnality as 'ourbooks&gt;iahd pictures? Let us be consistent. If
                            we are to stop at the verge' of bare necessity, then is every pleasurable emotion aside
                            -frorn those felt in the exercise of religious duties'wrong; and every thing not counted
                            among the absolute necessaries of life ought to be withheld. A philosopher once said..
                            "L\lt me make the songs of a nation, and I care not who makes its laws." Thus showing the
                            importance of art in civilization. We can scarcely do with less than has been found
                            necessary to civilize and elevate, mankind either in the past, or present, . If the basic
                            principles of our system are correct, we ought to be the happiest people in the world; and
                            consistency would demand that we reject nothing not in conflict with those principles, that
                            would tend to increase our happiness or better our condition. We fully agree with Br. Thomas
                            Smith when he says that "In logic as in Christ, we all are one." We would also call
                            attention to this fact, that the final verdict of leading authorities Upon all matters
                            pertaining to our well being, as a people, can be our only criterion. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Longfellow's creed" TEIform="index"/>LONGFELLOW'S CREED
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">My work is finished; I am strong In faith and hope and
                                    charity; ForI have written the things 1 see, The things that have been and shall be.
                                    Conscious of right, nor fearing wrong; Because 1 am in Jove with Love, And the sole
                                    thing I hate is Hate; For Hate is death; and Love is life, A peace, a splendor from
                                    aboye; And Hate a never ending strife, A smoke, a blackness from the abyss •• Where
                                    unclean serpents coil and hiss I Love is the Holy Ghost within; Hate the
                                    unpardonable sin, L, Who preaches otherwise than this Betrays his Master with a
                                    kiss. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="41" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My Dear Young Friends;—The subject of..." TEIform="index"/>
                                My Dear Young Friends;—The subject of...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Shaker Village" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Village,N. H.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> My Dear Young Friends;—The subject of Prayer has so fully occupied my mind today that I
                                undertake to pen my thoughts, mentally addressing my youthful companions that you may
                                meditate with me upon this beautiful theme. How many pure and sacred desires are
                                suggested by the word Prayer as it breathes forth an inspiration which it seems might
                                not only be realized by professing Christians, those best acquainted with the gift, but
                                the poor wayward child who has wandered from virtue, and perhaps never prayed, could
                                feel ts sweet forgiving influence, and through numble prayer return to the Parent's fold
                                of love and charity. Prayer is a sincere desire unuttered or ex/ pressed; a means
                                through which the soul seeks the blessing and protection of God and attending Angels, as
                                we meet with the troubles and perplexities consequent to life, or when our path lies
                                amid thorns instead of flowers; when our portion is a severe trial and disappointment,
                                or our lives in peril ; how natural it is then to flee to prayer as a refuge ; and who
                                at such seasons has not almost heard in answer a gentle "Peace be still," calming the
                                troubled spirit? Prayer was the Savior's watch-word, and I have sometimes thought that
                                this beautiful ?ift must have been breathed upon us by his spirit. Among the many
                                teachings to his bllowers we read these beautiful lessons, "Watch and pray, lest ye
                                enter into temptaion." "Pray for them which despitefully use you and persecute you." And
                                even in the bitter hour of his betrayal, surrounded by enemies, his prayer was, "Father,
                                forgive them, for they know not what they do." Although uttered eighteen hundred years
                                ago are they less needed now than they were then? From mjr earliest recollection I have
                                been taught to pray. Many young persons tell the sad experience of an irreligious home,
                                not so mine: for my childhood days are hallowed by praying Parents. The obedience
                                rendered to that teaching has ripened into a knowledge of the worth of prayer. It is a
                                shield against temptation, and as the call to forsake the natural ties and order of
                                life, and enter the new angelic way, requires greater selfdenial,—deeper, purer prayers
                                should be offered, lest in an unguarded moment the blessing be lost through neglect of
                                this gift. In the happy New Year that is before us, may we all realize a growth of
                                fervent, sincere prayer; and may the recording Angel of our lives, bear many to the
                                throne of all good, in which we have been able to say, "Not my will, but thine, O Lord,
                                be done."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Liscomb, Mabel" TEIform="persName"/> Your Sister, Mabel Liscomb.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="About rabbits" TEIform="index"/> ABOUT RABBITS.</head><p TEIform="p"> I think rabbits are very cunning little creatures. I will tell you what some of their colors
                            are; some are dark red in summer and white in winter ; they are found in forests. I had a
                            dark red rabbit once, I fed it with clover, but after a while it ran away, and I felt real
                            bad. Rabbits are plenty in Canada where I used to live; they are more harmless than other
                            wild animals are that have claws. People can handle them when wild, the same as a kitten,
                            without being bitten by them. They live on the same kind of food that sheep do, and their
                            meat makes good stews. Once while clearing a piece of grass-land that had a lot of old logs
                            on it, my Father found a nest of five rabbits in a thick patch of grass. They were too small
                            to run, and he gave them to some Frer.ch children that lived near our house. My Father used
                            to catch a great many wild rabbits in a box trap he caught one once that had four little
                            ones and he made a pen for them and was going to tame them but after they were a little more
                            than a week old, a big cat came one night and killed them all; so my Father set a large wolf
                            trap and the next morning we found the old cat caught fast in the trap. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Jenny" TEIform="persName"/>Jenny,—10 years old.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="An Oxford student, being examined..." TEIform="index"/>
                            An Oxford student, being examined...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> An Oxford student, being examined in sacred history, was asked, "who was the first king of
                            the Jews?" At a venture, he replied, "Saul" then encouraged by the assent of the examiner,
                            completed the answer as follows : "Saul of Tarsus, sometimes called Paul." </p></div2><pb n="42" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes" TEIform="index"/>NOTES. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Ask and you shall receive, Seek and you shall find, are equally as true and as potent in
                            their influence, at this day as when they were first uttered. Those who do not ask are very
                            likely to remain ignorant, and those who neglect to seek will in all probability become a
                            burden upon the world. It is no less true in religious matters than it is in the acquisition
                            of a temporal interest. The active man asks, when, where and how and then diligently seeks
                            for the place and opportunity, that is best to acquire wealth. Day and night, through
                            sunshine and storm, he forces his way that he may accomplish the desire of his mind and
                            accumulate to himself the treasures of this world. He has learned most assuredly, that "God
                            helps those who help themselves." On a certain occasion, Jesus was led to say, that "The
                            children of this world are wiser in their generation, than the children of light." The first
                            ask and seek persistently to acquire worldly treasures ; the latter are very willing to
                            allow God and the holy Angels to call men to repentance, while they sit by and see the work
                            go on. It is indeed wonderful what a soothing influence this religious anodyne has upon the
                            mind. Zealous in prayers, and in church ceremonies and yet look on with indifference while
                            the world inarch by to certain destruction. "Fear not," said Moses, "Stand firm and see the
                            salvation of the Lord that he will do for you this day." Excellent counsel of 3000 years ago
                            ! and yet how very much, we are, like the tribe of Reuben in standing firm to see what will
                            be done for us.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The great desideratum for our paper..." TEIform="index"/>
                            The great desideratum for our paper...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The great desideratum for our paper is to heighten and make solid, spicy and unanswerable its
                            tone. It should contain the most searching, clear, sound ringing tones of any in the
                            Universe. Let us strive for this-. We certainly have access to the most abundant fountain of
                            noble truths from which to store a periodical, on moral, religious and highly spiritualized
                            subjects.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. Avery. </byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Salvation army" TEIform="index"/>Salvation Army
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Salvation Army. Wm. Booth or Gen. Booth was formerly a Methodist Minister, who began his work
                            17 years ago in the streets of London, England. He has to-day an army of 15000 privates, 760
                            officers, 320 corps, and an annual income of $350,000. They hold over 6,000 services weekly.
                            The army is molded after that of Loyola, and renders unconditional obedience to its
                            commander. The Salvation Army publishes two papers. The, War Cry for adults, and the Little
                            Soldier for children. It is said that they circulate 360,000 copies per week. </p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A society for the promotion of 'early rising'..." TEIform="index"/>
                            A society for the promotion of 'early rising'...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A society for the promotion of "early rising" has existed in England for four years. The
                            object was to gain time for the study of Sunday school lessons. There are fines for the
                            violation of the rules. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Speak as you mean..." TEIform="index"/>Speak as you mean...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> "Speak as you mean, do as you profess, and perform what you promise."</p></div2><pb n="43" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vegetable diet" TEIform="index"/> VEGETABLE DIET.</head><p TEIform="p"> "Gunshot and other wounds never heal as quick in flesh-eating nations as in
                                vegetableeating nations. Flesh-eaters are especially subject to inflammatory diseases,
                                particularly fevers and dysentery. Over-indulgence in animal food gives an unnatural
                                life, leads to sensuality, sensuality brings on exhaustion, exhaustion demands
                                stimulation, ending in sickness, insanity and death. A vegetable diet, based on
                                physiological principles, with a sound mind in a sound body, may be considered an
                                absolutely certain safeguard against fevers, bowel complaints, cholera, small-pox, and
                                similar diseases. Abstinence from animal food, tobacco, snuff", alcoholic and fermented
                                beverages is conducive to piety, moral goodness and long life."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ruttley, J. H." TEIform="persName"/> J. H. Ruttley, M. D.</byline></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Weak lungs" TEIform="index"/> Weak Lungs.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Weak Lungs.—One important principle to be remembered is that pure air is as
                                        needful for the lungs as food is for the stomach, pure air day and night. While
                                        it may not be well for the patient to be exposed in stormy weather, certainly
                                        not unless most fully clothed it is still of the utmost importance that no
                                        impure air shall be breathed at such a time, remembering the fact that moist air
                                        is not at all unfavorable, to the lungs, at least, so long as the body is warm
                                        and comfortable. Another important idea is that the skin and the lungs are in
                                        intimate sympathy, as may be seen when the pores of the skin—7,000,000 in
                                        number—are closed by what we call a cold, the re-opening of these by a sweat—the
                                        Turkish bath or its equivalent at home, the vapor bath—is the first thing to be
                                        done, by which most of the usual results are avoided. In addition, if there is
                                        special tightness, a wet cloth on which mustard has been sprinkled, may be worn
                                        over the whole chest, causing "counter-irritation," and diversion. It is safe
                                        also, for the victims of weak lungs to use the flesh-brush daily, as a
                                        substitute for the bath or wash of the body, which is often too violent and
                                        chilling for the sensitive—the brush to be used night and morning in winter or
                                        in cold weather. Never.—Never go to bed with cold feet. It is better to sit up
                                        for an hour, if need be, to warm them, rather than to lie awake suffering for
                                        three hours, and then have a violent cold for a long time, as the result. Never
                                        eat any article of food simply to save it, as the stomach can not well afford
                                        .to do extra labor just for the sake of saving a few mills. It is better economy
                                        to throw such things to the swine or the birds. Dyspepsia implies a loss far
                                        greater than could possibly result from the loss of a little food, which,
                                        ordinarily, might be kept till .the next meal. Never eat in haste, in
                                        consequence of a want of sufficient time. It is far better to take one-half of
                                        the usual amount of food (that might be enough, even), than to render the meal
                                        indigestible by improper haste. What is gained in time is lost in the amount of
                                        nourishment appropriated. It is emphatically true in this case that "haste makes
                                        waste." Never imagine that the more you eat the more you will be nourished, for
                                        the opposite is often true. We are nourished by what we digest, and not simply
                                        by what is taken into the stomach. In some cases the labor of digestion destroys
                                        more strength than the amount of nourishment will afford. There is more
                                        practical starvation from eating too much than too little.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="City and Country" TEIform="index"/>City and Country.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">Kind Words for the Year 1882. Shaker Village, N. H. I think the January No. of the Manifesto
                            an improvement on former numbers. The general tone of the paper is good. The printing is
                            nice and on paper good enough for such a work. J. S. Kaime. Enfield, N. H. The March No. is
                            the best this year. A. Perkins. Shakers N. Y. The April Manifesto is the best No. this year.
                            G. B. Avery. Shaker Village, N. H. I think the May No. real good. Mary Whitcher. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y. I think the June No. of the Manifesto, aa exceptionally good one. A. G.
                            Hollister. 43 </p></div2><pb n="44" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>House and Farm</head><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Winter feeding and digestion" TEIform="index"/> WINTER FEEDING AND DIGESTION.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">WINTER FEEDING AND DIGESTION. The following is an abstract of a paper read
                                        before the meeting of the Massachusetts Board of Agriculture, at Bridgewater, by
                                        Dr. Bowen of Connecticut: He remarked that for generations fertility had been a
                                        general waste. In times past farms had everywhere been running down in
                                        condition, but now a change for the better was noticeable. Science was shedding
                                        its light upon the practice of agriculture. The farmer of the future will be
                                        the, man who can give a good and sufficient reason for everything he does.
                                        Plants and animals stand upon the same respects, particularly so in the matter
                                        of food. The waste of animals depends upon their condition, the working oxen
                                        wastes more than the steer in the stall, being fed for the market; the
                                        race-horse wastes more than the dray horse and the deer more than the bear.
                                        Young animals require more food than older ones, and animals are developed as to
                                        size and form in some degree from the food they consume. The evolution of heat
                                        is not confined to animals ; plants share with them to some extent the same
                                        power. The temperature of animals is higher in the Arctic regions than in the
                                        temperate or torrid zones. Only one kind of food is perfect in its character and
                                        that is milk. It contains a large amount of water which is requisite for holding
                                        the elements in solution. Fat is an essential requisite, in the animal economy.
                                        It tends to round up the form and improve its appearance. It produces heat so
                                        essential in the animal economy, Common salt is an important factor, in the
                                        production of milk, so also is phosphate of soda, the latter producing chloric
                                        acid, a very important element in the gastric juice of the animal. Salt in
                                        limited quantities should be regularly fed. The organs of digestion in the
                                        animal are the teeth and the stomach. The oesophagus is a canal to conduct the
                                        food into the ditfer ent stomachs. Horses and pigs have simple stomachs, while
                                        those of the sheep and cattle are compound in their nature. Gastric acid is
                                        found only in the fourth stomach of the ruminant; this latter constitutes the
                                        rennet in the calf. The action of the gastric juice is strictly chemical. Chyle
                                        formed from the food by the action of the gastric juice is taken up by the
                                        lacteals. The colon of the horse is larger in proportion than that of any other
                                        animal. Heavy draughts of water should never be given to the horse after a full
                                        feed, because the water forces itself through the intestines and colon,
                                        frequently producing scours. Milk stock should be fed all they will eat twice a
                                        day, while the horse * should be fed three times per day. Horses are frequently
                                        dyspeptic. Pigs should be fed three or four times a day, and in the care of
                                        young 'pigs five times. Cows should be watered immediately after feeding. Grain
                                        should be fed, if at all, after the ration of hay. . Where more than two quarts
                                        of grain are fed at a time it should be mixed with the hay before being placed
                                        before the cow, yet all grain so fed does not assist in forming a cud, but
                                        passes at once into the first stomach. Farmers can easily ruin the digestive
                                        organs of their domestic animals through improper feeding. Such animals are the
                                        creatures of habit, and the best results are secured only through regularity in
                                        feeding. The wealth of the New England farmer must consist in his live stock,
                                        which demands the same care and vigilance as other varieties of stock, whether
                                        of bank, railroad, mine or factory.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Tribune and farmer" TEIform="index"/>Tribune and Farmer.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In setting hens, it is very important..." TEIform="index"/>In setting hens, it is very important...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">In setting hens, it is very important to pro vide dry earth, or some good substitute, in
                                the bottom of the box or barrel. Quantities of chickens are counted on that never hatch,
                                every spring, for want of a little common sense in this very thing. A simple nest of hay
                                or shavings on the bare floor will not answer. The hen who steals her nest knows how to
                                do it, and hatch ten out of every dozen eggs. Provide something to hold the heat under
                                the eggs while the hen leaves the nest to feed, and make it easy for the hen to supply
                                her want without absenting herself too long from the nest.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There are thousands of acres..." TEIform="index"/>There are thousands of acres...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">There are thousands of acres of almost worthless rough, stony, and poor sandy lands in
                                the Eastern and Middle States, which, if <pb n="45" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/>properly planted with
                                forest trees, would in It few years become highly .valuable from their growth. Among
                                those most certain at present to give the largest profit are the red' cedar, yellow
                                locust, sugar maple, hickory and black walnut. The timber of this last is now the most
                                valuable of all grown in Amer-: ica, as single large trees are, worth from $20 to over,
                                $100 each, according to their size and facility of getting them to market. The maple is
                                not only valuable for timber, but still more so for the, production of sugar. The black
                                walnut and hickory yield excellent nuts as' well as timber, and on one sort of the
                                latter we know they are grown with. shells as tender as the almond, and their meat is
                                of the richest quality. These nuts sell at a high price. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Swallows" TEIform="index"/>THE SWALLOWS. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES S. PRESCOTT. </byline><p TEIform="p">Called the community swallows: because they build their nests in communities, joined
                                together, made of clay and mud. I counted eighty of these nests under the eaves of our
                                barn sixty feet long on one side. These swallows are pretty birds, not so much on
                                account of their plumage as in their dornestio habits. They are about the size of the
                                English sparrow-imported-brown on their backs and their breasts white. They make their
                                appearar ce annually about the first of May, and leave us about the 20th or last of
                                August, and seem more numerous than when they came. What a paradise this world mi~ht be
                                if the human race would keep the law of nature in the reproduction of their offspring
                                as well as these swallows; and is it so, that the human race are the only cxception who
                                do not keep the law of reproduction? North. Union, Ohio. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Merits of large and small cattle" TEIform="index"/>Merits of Large and Small Cattle. </head><p TEIform="p">-In ordinary cases, cows of small breeds yield more butter than those of larger breeds,
                                and the smaller individuals of a particular breed give richer milk than the large
                                specimens of the same breed. The larger animals and breeds, however, produce more
                                cheese. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Classic literary mystery" TEIform="index"/>The Classic Literary Mystery
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The mystery of the authorship of -the famous , "Letters of
                                Juuius" is still uusfllved.The author surrounded himself with so impenetrable..: veil of
                                secrecy that all the efforts of enquirers, political and literary, failed in dispelling
                                the orlginal darkness. Attributed to Burke" Wilkes, Horn Tookc, Lord Littleton, Lord
                                Shelburne, Sir. Philip Francie, and others, they have never been proved to be the,
                                product of either. Their remarkable compression, point and brilliancy of language,
                                their unrivaled sarcasm, boldness and tremendous invective, not only drew, at the time,
                                such public attention as never before was given to letters of political controversy,
                                but have won them a place at the head of the acknowledged classics in literature. If
                                indeed one's home . library can be considered respectably complete without .thern, they
                                certaiuly greatly enrich any in which they find place. In the exceedingly beautiful and
                                wonderfully cheap (cloth, 45 cents, half-Russia, red edges, 60 cents) ELZEVIH edition,
                                in which they arc just issued by The Useful Knowledge Publishing Company, New York, they
                                will be a temptation to which' thousands of bookbuyers will gladly yield. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological Journal and Science of Health" TEIform="index"/>
                                PHRENOLOGICAL JOURNAL AND SCIENCE OF HEALTH
                            </head><p TEIform="p">. January. ,The first nnmber for the New Year comes filled
                                with good things. The Commissioner of Agriculture, Geo.B. Loring, is the subject of the
                                leading article; Rcad it. W m. Penn and the city he founded, g-ives a very interesting
                                account of what once was the I'City of Brotherly Love." The subject is fully
                                illustrated; A day in a Portrait Gallery, has many illustrations, and introduces the
                                read erto the favorites of the court of Charles II. king 'of England ; An extended
                                notice of Spurzheim, having reference to the somt.centennlnl, as commem orutive of the
                                lifc of th.-t celebrated man. Several other articles equally as interesting as the above
                                arc to be found in' this number. Yule Time ill Sweden; Algte or Plants of the Deep;
                                Cultivation of Beauty ; Fourth International Congress of Hygiene; A Remarkable Surgical
                                Operation, ete., etc. Fowler Wells, Publishers, 753 Broadway,N.Y. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>THE HERALD OF HEALTH
                            </head><p TEIform="p">January; Contents:.A Model and Healthful Tenement House; Herbert Spencer's
                                Views on overworked Americans ; Marringe in Germany and America; A, Pessimist.;
                                Muscular training; Health of the Brain, Kerosene Lamps; Influence of Food 011
                                Civilization; Health of American Women ; About bad Colds'; Deep Breathing, etc., etc.
                                M.L. HOLBROOK, M. D. Publish", 13 Iii Laight St., N.)". $1. pel' year.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Never too old to improve..." TEIform="index"/>Never too old to improve...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Never too old to improve while intellect remains unbroken. </p></div2><pb n="46" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Colburn, Ann Eliza" TEIform="index"/>Ann Eliza Colburn
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Ann Eliza Colburn, Dec. 20. at Second Family, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Age 62 yrs. 1 mo. and
                                22 days. The torch of hope with flickering light Burnslow,-which once was bright and
                                clear, The truest mourners earth hath known Repine for thee, our sister dear. Our hope,
                                our stay, our joy, our pride, So rudely taken from our sight We almost doubt the trials
                                worth, And question-Is the suffering right? o Father, throned in power on high, In
                                pleading thought on suppliant knee We ask for strength to bear the shock, And turn not
                                from our trust in Thee; But patient in the strife for right Endure life's trials as they
                                come, 'Till wrapt in death's calm drapery, we Shall enter our Eternal Home. Mt.
                                Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vedder, Angelic" TEIform="index"/>Angelic Vedder
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Angelic Vedder, Dec. 21. at Church Family, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Age 86
                                yrs, 6 mo. and 13 days. Ah! 'tis the ripened sheaf, death garners now, A mind replete
                                with gains of heavenly worth. Earth's law can measure not the growth of soulj. Its
                                fetters oft may check the action here Of noble feelings, which inspire the heart; But
                                from its clamps set free, the spirit's COUrse By true desire is marked in yonder sphere;
                                Where pain and sickness ne'er our efforts blight. O! 'tis with joy the angels sing this
                                morn And our dear .sister joins' the-strain divine, While swiftly gliding through the
                                realms of space, Possessed of wealth w hlch gains admittence there, Assembled hosts
                                proclaim the Welcome strain : ,V ell done, thou SCHaut true, entcr the joy Prepared for
                                thee. The price is fully paid Which gives thee passport to Eternal.Life That life which
                                finite power can measure not Else would it lose its hold on gems, which fade Like
                                floating clouds before the morning light. Thy soul shall meet response in growing power,
                                To all, thy eager mind would blaim of God. For all that hearts appropriate for use,
                                In our celestial home, is free for all. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wheeler, Olive" TEIform="index"/>Olive Wheeler
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Olive Wheeler, Dec. 24, at
                                South Family Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Age 80 yrs, 2 mo. and 2 days. For many years a faithfnl
                                and toiling laborer, in the 'cause of truth. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Buzby, Ann F." TEIform="index"/>Ann F. Buzby
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Ann F. Buzby, Dec. 26, at Second Family,
                                IMt. Lebanon, N. Y. Age 66 yrs. and T mo.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Justice, Elizabeth" TEIform="index"/>Elizabeth Justice
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Elizabeth Justice, Dec. 3, at Second Family,
                                Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Age 78 yrs. 5 mo.'" and 16 days. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Solomon Rankin" TEIform="index"/>Solomon Rankin
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., H. H." TEIform="persName"/>H. H. H. </byline><p TEIform="p">"Happy are they 'Who die in the Lord." "Death loves a shining mark" was never, perhaps, more
                            fully demonstrated than in the death of the Subject of this sketch, for he was pre-emmently
                            a man of God, as a l6ng' and eventful life consecrated to his Mastel's will fully attests.
                            He knew the paths laid out by the "Divine Law Giver," and with an unerring step walked
                            therein having ever in view "the pearlof great price." No wonder then that death was robbed
                            of its terror when his calm and peaceful spirit wended its flight "over the River" there to
                            join in sweet anthems of praise with loved ones gone befote. Yea, dear brother, we miss
                            thee, and in yielding thee up we drop a silent tear to thy memory yct we have the
                            consolation feft, if we but heed thy pious counsels we will some day meet thee in that
                            "Sweet Bye-and Bye." The deceased was a believer from youth to old age and died in, the
                            faith; was a tower of strength to this Society, with an eye single to its every want; was
                            one of the first Settlers here consequeutly shared its adversities and . prosperities alike;
                            held many offices of trust, all of which he fllled with dignity and with a christian spirit;
                            was by nature possessed of a strong will and was firm as the "Rock of Gibraltar" in what he
                            conceded to be right. If charity can be claimed as one of the christian graces then to him
                            must be awarded a double share, for his was the very soul of charity, as hundreds-yea,
                            thousands could testify and no eulbgy, though wefe it from the most gifted pen, could do
                            ample justice to this venerable old Patriarch, who has now gone to reap the reward of a
                            life well spent while here. Sonth Union, Ky. </p></div2><pb n="47" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Petition" TEIform="index"/>PETITION
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Enfield, N. H. 1. Heavenly Father, 2. May that living Heavenly Mother, inspiration May we feel thy From the heavenly presence near, Realize thy love and blessing,
                            Flowing worlds descend, That will work complete salvation, Peace in waters clear. knows no
                            end. Give, O give us strength and power Heavenly Father, Heavenly Mother, To renew our May
                            we feel thy lives to watchful thee, care; Conse crate each Bless each earnest passing hour,
                            To the cause that soul endeavor, Hear, O hear our maketh free, humble prayer. down like
                            Christ that </p></div2><pb n="48" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unfortunate accident" TEIform="index"/>AN UNFORTUNATE ACCIDENT. </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mt. Lebanon" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Dec. 21, 1882. </dateline><p TEIform="p">Gospel Friends ;—We write, at this moment to apprise you of a most sorrowful calamity which
                            occurred at our Second Family on the eve. of the 19th. at 5.30 P. M. Our beloved sister, Ann
                            Eliza Colburn, having been using an oil stove to heat some tea for her sick sister, put out
                            the stove lamp and before it got cool filled it again with oil, having a lighted lamp at
                            some distance. She unfortunately dropped a trifle of oil on the stove, it took lire at once,
                            ran down into the stove lamp, exploded it, and set the Office on fire. The building was
                            destroyed, but most of the goods, books and other articles were saved. Sister Ann Eliza in
                            going back into the building, to secure some articles of value, was so dreadfully burned
                            that she died at 11.15 A. M. on the 20th. As the supply of water was very limited, it was
                            all that could be done to preserve the surrounding buildings. Your Brother, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B" TEIform="persName"/>" G. B. Avery. </byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Happiness" TEIform="index"/>HAPPINESS. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Heber" TEIform="persName"/>BY BISHOP HEBER. </byline><p TEIform="p">One morning in the month of May, I wandered o'er the hill; Though nature all around was gay,
                            My heart was heavy still. Can God, I thought, the just, the great, These meaner creatures
                            bless, And yet deny to man's estate The boon of happiness? Tell me, ye woods, ye smiling
                            plains, Ye blessed birds around, In which of nature's wide domains Can bliss for man be
                            found? The birds wild carolled overhead, The breeze around me blew, And nature's awful
                            chorus said No bliss for man she knew. I questioned Love, whose early ray So rosy bright
                            appears, And heard the timid genius say His light was dimmed by tears. I questioned
                            Friendship : Friendship sighed And thus her answer gave :The few whom fortune never turned
                            Were withered in the grave. I asked if Vice could bliss bestow? Vice boasted loud and well,
                            But, fading from her withered brow, The borrowed roses fell. I sought of Feeling, if her
                            skill Could soothe the wounded breast; And found" her mourning, faint and still, For others'
                            woes distressed. I questioned Virtue : Virtue sighed, No boon could she dispense ; Nor
                            Virtue was her name, she cried, But humble Penitence. I questioned Death,—the grizzly shade
                            Relaxed his brow severe; And "I am happiness," he said, "If Virtue guides thee here." </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peace" TEIform="index"/>PEACE. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER.</byline><p TEIform="p">Peace, peace my soul, commands the whole Whatever earth's commotion; The day is fair in toil
                            and care, And joyous in devotion. When peace is won, the world moves on In peaceful, kind
                            endeavor; And those we .meet we kindly greet As sister, friend avid brother. Hear lies the
                            strife for human life, For peace within our border : Put sin afar, we know no war, As Christ
                            becomes our Savior. </p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">Moses was wise in forbidding the eating of swine's flesh. It is coarse, impure, scrofulous
                            food, often containing trichina?. The graceful reindeer of the polar reigons is a standing
                            proof against the necessity of animal flesh for food even in the frigid north. In the year
                            2000 our advanced race will look upon a meat-eater very much as we now look upon a cannibal.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/>—Dr. J. M. Peebles, in Banner of Light. </byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There can be no defeat in that spirit..." TEIform="index"/>There can be no defeat in that spirit...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">There can be no defeat in that spirit which is moved at all times by the largest, purest
                            purposes of which it can conceive.</p></div2><!--
                        <pb
                        id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]<pb id="p30"/>
                            <pb id="p31"/>
                            <pb id="p32"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>