<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1307" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">13</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><date value="18830701" TEIform="date">July 1883</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">145-167</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="13" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb n="t.p." id="p1"/>
                    <p> VOL. XIII. JULY. NO. 7. SHAKER MANIFESTO. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME A.T
                        SHAKERS N. Y. "Blessed are those that hear the word of God and keep it.' SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H.
                        1883. </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p> [Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="145" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><!--
                        <div2 type="none">
                        <p> CONTENTS. The Pole Star of Faith, Reply, No. 1, Rest, .... Life is Progress, EzEKIE,L
                            MoRBILL, A Prayer, Charity, - - - Letter from Helen T. Our Petition, Shakerism, Watch and
                            Pray, do not have the blues, The Present Era, Woman, - - - Letter from Eld. F.W.E. Letter
                            from J. K. Jones, Page. - 145 148 - 149 150 151 152 - 153 153 - 155 156 157 Caution,
                            Experience, Freedom of the Human Will, Repentance, Letter Box, . . - - Notes, - ....
                            Sanitary, House & Farm, Abuse of Lemons, Select, This Life is what we make it,
                            Trust, - - Music—Purest Blessings, Deaths, Books and Papers, - - Kind Words, - - - Page. -
                            158 159 160 161 162 164 165 166 167 168 Vol. XIII. JULY, 1883. No. 7. </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pole star of faith" TEIform="index"/> THE POLE STAR OF FAITH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/> ALONZO G. HOLLISTER</byline><p TEIform="p">Where God has established an order to accomplish a certain work, that work cannot be
                            performed one side of the order appointed. Jesus Christ was the first foundation pillar of
                            the new creation. He was the beginning, the germ thereof, as Adam was of the old, and he
                            received a revelation to effect a certain order of work therein. If a successor may set a
                            part of that foundation aside, supposing it of no account, then another coming after may set
                            the innovator aside with a new innovation, and so on indefinitely, in which case what better
                            would the foundation be than shifting sand? Jesus said he would build his church upon a rock
                            ; but if one coming after may contradict Jesus, both cannot be right. If the father of the
                            new creation taught error for truth, either by precept or example, where is the assurance
                            that his offspring will not be more imperfect? As he was the primary branch, and all
                            subsequent growth must proceed from him as originator, even as defects are transmissible
                            from parents to offspring, what assurance have we that error will not multiply itself and
                            extend, unless we are guided by a fixed standard, and trim from ourselves all that cannot be
                            brought to this standard ? If our standard varies so as to conform to individual ideas, is
                            not this the same as to be without a standard, or without a reliable guide to the formation
                            of opinions, and for testing our revelations, and then, what do we know ; and what becomes
                            of the ground of unity for faith and practice in the body ? <pb n="146" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 146 THE
                            MANIFESTO. God has placed the Pole Star in the natural heavens where every eye can see it,
                            and beyond the reach of mortals to change it. And are the spiritual heavens less securely
                            established than the natural ? Are they less adapted to promote unity of faith and opinion
                            on subjects relating to our highest interests, among the truly honest and pure in heart, who
                            wish to know the will of God that they may do it? Every spiritual eye shall see him, that
                            they may learn of him who is the way, the truth and the life. And they shall see eye to eye
                            when the Lord shall bring again Zion. Is not the character and testimony of the first
                            witnesses of the new creation, the Pole Star of our faith, and the visible lead like a
                            compass to which we turn for counsel when clouds obscure our spiritual sky and for direction
                            how to work the present work of God in union with the visible body of Christ? And are we
                            censurable for distrusting a compass needle that does not point steadily to the pole, when
                            allowed to adjust itself, free fr&gt;m extrinsic perturbations? Jesus testified, "I and
                            my Father are one." If he was not perfect, how could he be one with the perfect, and how can
                            his followers be perfect? "I speak wisdom to them that are perfect," said the Apostle. If
                            perfection is not attainable, why the injunction, "Be ye perfect even as your Father in
                            heaven?" "I am the vine, ye are the, branches," "Ye have not chosen me, but I have chosen
                            you and ordained you, that ye should bear much fruit." The perfect ones, who properly
                            improve the talents confided to them, become one with the anointing spirit, and that which
                            is one cannot be divided, "The disciple is not above his master, but every one that is
                            perfect shall be as his master." If the Father judgeth no man but hath committed all
                            judgment to the Son, and the Son rises up and disputes whom he wills, and the judgment of
                            truth invariably proceeds from above downward, so that those who taught us the gospel are to
                            be ou judges, what judgment is that which proceeds from below upward ; and of what account
                            is it except to those whom it may mislead ; Is the judge arraigned by his dependent whom he
                            appoints and sustains in office ? Is not the less invariably judged by the greater ? We
                            begin in the same place where Jesus began, by bringing our lives to judgment—we travel in
                            his steps through the same degrees and order of succession that he traveled. Have we
                            traveled swifter and advanced beyond him, and are we able to teach him a knowledge of
                            heavenly things? Is the increased light he has given us to combat the growing evils of the
                            world, designed to constitute us judges in that wherein he was not condemned? Are we more
                            prudent, more self-denying than he was ? Do we use the things of this world as not abusing?
                            And did he not do the same, gaining much from little, and performing large service with
                            small means? Will increasing light make a perfect thing imperfect? Will ripe fruit
                            contradict the green ? Is not the foundation of our trust in a present visible lead, due to
                            our faith in a revelation which preceded them ; so that if our confidence in the truthful
                            integrity of the first witnesses be destroyed, we would have far less ground for confiding
                            in those present with us ? If we build our faith upon persons, and they fail, we fail also ;
                            but if, as <pb n="147" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 147 our first Mother taught, Ave build our
                            faith upon the gift and power of God in the gospel, we must have a light which transcends
                            individual opinions by which to know the real from the seeming, the substance from the
                            shadow. And that light, or test, must be the revelation of the beginniug, supported by
                            concurring testimony of all true witnesses, who are one in spirit, though testifying ages
                            apart. We may call this light principle, but it was manifested to us through witnesses ; for
                            principles are not self-actors, but modes of action that require organization to be made
                            apparent. Mother taught that she received her light and power through Jesus Christ, and that
                            he was her head and Lord. She and her co-laborers were careful not to injure the oil nor the
                            wine, nor controvert the testimony of preceding witnesses. Hence their testimony all
                            witnessed in her favor ; just as the law and the prophets always turned for a testimony in
                            favor of Jesus and his disciples, whenever their opposers attempted to make out a
                            contradiction, upon the foundation Avhich was laid in revelation by the first witnesses of
                            the new creation, is room for endless growth, and increase without limit, and if it be said
                            that we are laboring to support a theory, we answer it is not a theory of man's devising,
                            and man cannot alter it. Human theories are too contracted, and involve too many
                            contradictions to apply to the things of the Spirit, and they leave their advocates in a
                            wilderness. Hence it is well to try ourselves by the revelation of Christ, which is compared
                            to a rock for firmness, durableness, and immutability, and reject from our belief whatever
                            contradicts the acknowledged testimony of the first witnesses, who stand nearest the
                            fountain. The Apostles saw the spiritual things of a future dispensation obscurely, but this
                            did not prevent their seeing clearly to perform the work of their day, perfect in its order
                            and time. When the mind is polarized by a false idea or desire, the reasoning power is
                            liable to strengthen the delusion, because the first principles of reason, and of revelation
                            are not then the test of evidence, but the test is the leading theme in the mind. For
                            example ; a certain materialist formed a train of reasoning which satisfied his mind of the
                            nonexistence of the spirit after death. A spiritual man reasoning from superior premises,
                            refuted every argument in the series, so that the materialist was able to see and
                            acknowledge his error ; yet his mind would revert to his previous train of argument, and say
                            "It must be so," though, being honest, he finally discarded the notion as false. This was
                            mental polarity to an idea. Impure desires still more effectuslly color, and obstruct the
                            light of understanding. H?nee the importance of absolute purity of heart in order to a clear
                            perception of truth. For without holiness no man shall see the Lord. Holy means set apart
                            for a godly use. If both reason ers were correct when tested by the pole star of the
                            heavens, or the primary principles of rational intelligence, then may all distinction
                            between truth and error, virtue and vice be obliterated, and the abominable doctrine of
                            "whatever is, is right," be logically sustained. In this day of chaotic views and opinions,
                            struck like sparks from the clash of elements and dissolving systems, when so many theories
                            are urged as valuable revelations or important principles seeking recogntion, it may be well
                            not <pb n="148" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/>&gt; 148 THE MANIFESTO. to trust to colored glasses, nor be led astray
                            by transitional ideas however plausible, that have no foundation of permanence in
                            themselves, and therefore constitute no part of the gospel plan. Should we not rather
                            preserve a distinction between the revolutionary element which is disorganizing the false
                            systems of the world, removing debris, and which is therefore transient in its character,
                            and the new creating word which is building up a permanent Order that will increase forever?
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reply, no. 2" TEIform="index"/> REPLY, NO. 2</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ervin, Anna" TEIform="persName"/> ANNA ERVIN</byline><p TEIform="p"> God loved him as a Son; the spirit was given him without measure. John iii, 34. He was thus,
                            the "first born of many brethren." Rom. viii, 29. In obedience to the Divine will he leaves
                            the narrow sphere of his parent's home to labor for the good of others, and to form a body
                            of followers into a nucleus, to discipline them into the principles of the resurrection. But
                            his sympathies have not yet passed beyond "the lost sheep of the house of Israel." Matt, xv,
                            24. Only under protest does he move out of this sphere of action. Yet he realizes that God
                            is kind to the unthankful and to the evil. Luke vi, 35. Here we see the beautiful germ of
                            the universal sympathies, of the greater works he foretold for his followers. Jno. xiv 12.
                            He was developed in these principles as far as a Jew could be, and thus became the spiritual
                            father of the human race. In him was manifested in the highest degree possible at that time,
                            the masculine Christian qualities. He was truly the Second Adam of whom the first Adam was
                            the Archetype. But there is something lacking in the ministrations of our dear spiritual
                            Father. The power of his divine commission is undoubted, his resignation to the divine will
                            complete, his comprehension of divine purposes sublime. But he has received no aid from the
                            heavenly mother : Wisdom yet has failed to make her mark. The woman is quite ignored. Seeing
                            himself, the end from the beginning, he hesitates not to urge his disciples to forsake their
                            houses and kindreds for the sake of the gospel, without providing any other protection than
                            dependence on the Divine will and proposes a paralyzing inactivity, in providing for the
                            needs of the body. He sends his disciples through the country and instructs them to shake
                            off the dust of their feet as a testimony against those who do not receive them. He curses
                            an innocent fig tree ; he takes ropes to drive business men out of the temple; he almost
                            recommends his disciples to use the sword after his death; the burden of his testimony is
                            "woe unto you, scribes and Pharisees, hypocrites, ye vipers, ye shall receive condemnation."
                            He thus violates in the most glaring manner the eternal principles of the meek and lowly
                            spirit that he was born into. There is a hardness, a lack of the softening influence of
                            home; notwithstanding the energy, the divine afflatus, the brilliant spiritual successes
                            that marked his career. He and his immediate followers were doing the rough work for Ann
                            Lee. As you well know the Church, which his immediate followers established on the earth,
                            fell away, according to prophecy, ii Thess. ii. 3. It was prophesied that Christ should
                            "appear a second time without sin unto salvation." Heb. ix. 21. But the Apostles profess
                            their ignorance of the nature of that appearance, i Cor. xii. 9. 10. i Peter i. 5. i John
                            iii. 2. Thus these divinely inspired men acknowledge their ignorance respecting the nature
                            of Chritt's second appearing. Now the reason of the falling away of the first Church was
                            from that very incompleteness, which has been mentioned. The Bridegroom had come; but where
                            was the Bride? His were only "children by adoption." Rom. viii. 15 Could a permanent
                            spiritual organization be founded without a Mother? Impossible! Whence, then, comes the
                            Bride? She comes out of the agonizing throes of nearly 1800 years. The vast preparatory
                            leaven of Jesus had done its work. All creation groaned and travailed together, in vain ef
                                <pb n="149" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 149 forts to find its God, until the Mother is
                            manifested by Ann Lee. We do not here recount her history; that may be found in the
                            accompanying tract. But it will be enough to say that out of her sufferings she became as an
                            innocent child, and was born into the universal sympathies ; and that from her labors and
                            and teachings has emanated a social organization, permanently founded on the principles of
                            equality of the sexes, virgin purity, unworldliness, the confession of sin, and com" munity
                            of property; the practical fruits of which are pure love, industry, meekness, unselfishness,
                            innocence and all good Christian qualities. And it may safely be said that all the modern
                            improvements in the condition of women in civilized Society, date subsequent to the
                            establishment of these principles ; and that the final result of these principles will be
                            the establishment of universal justice. Thus Ann Lee is the Second Eve, just as Jesus is the
                            Second Adam. Herein is completed the marriage of the Lamb and Bride. Rev. xxi. 9.; a
                            spiritual marriage, producing spiritual children. And as the earthy Adam and Eve peopled the
                            earth with fallen human beings, so do the second Adam and Eve, the spiritual Bridegroom and
                            Bride, beget, bring forth and nourish those fallen beings into the principles of the
                            resurrection, by which they gain eternal life, iu themselves, by patient continuance in
                            well-doing. I have thus thrown out a few hints; but the subject will richly repay a closer
                            examination. Your Friend, A. E.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rest" TEIform="index"/>REST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witham, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>MARIA WITHAM</byline><p TEIform="p"> How precious to the weary one is rest, A solace to the heart by grief oppress'd, A place, a
                            shelter from the burning sur, When all our weary, heavy tasks are done. Rest for the mind,
                            and for the tired brain, Eest for the nerves from anxious toil and strain; The throbbing
                            brow is on the pillow press'd, Sweetly and tranquilly, we sink to rest. 0 sweetest rest of
                            all, is rest from sin, When cleans'd from all the crimson stains within, With calm ineffable
                            repose of mind, In Heaven's peaceful home, we rest may find. Dear Mother hear, O hear, my
                            spirit cry, List to my faint petitions when I die, And take my weary head upon thy breast,
                            Near thee, 0 let me take my last long rest. Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life in progress" TEIform="index"/> LIFE IS PROGRESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Collins, Elvah F." TEIform="persName"/> ELVAH F. COLLINS. </byline><p TEIform="p"> From the seed bud to the blossom,— From the blossom to the fruit, We perceive the growth of
                            nature, So, for good, the soul's pursuit, Starting on the stage of action, With the inward
                            germs of good, We're continually unfolding, Standing not, where once we stood. Never
                            resting! Life is onward !! That "the grave is not its goal;" Still is sung by Bard and Poet,
                            Still is felt within the soul. For the evidence of further, And still further op'ning
                            spheres, Strongly urges us to action, Now, a« for a thousand years. And from thence through
                            time unmeasured. By the sun's revolving light, On and on, where toil and recompense, Shall
                            never meet a blight. Who can comprehend the ending, Or beginning of our life? Of the powers
                            of good and evil, Which, when meeting cause the strife? Or a God whose laws and statutes,
                            Stand as fixed in earth and heaven; We may reason, think and wonder, But to whom is
                            knowledge given? Of a future we are certain, And of soul's immortal wealth ; Knowing too,
                            through lives of virtue, Wisdom yields us joy and health. And while 'biding in these
                            shadows, Of a substance yet to be, We can strengthen one another. In our faith's leaiity.
                            Then, let love reciprocated, Draw us near in union's bond, Which assures us of re-union, On
                            the shore that lies beyond. Mount Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><pb n="150" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ezekiel Morrill" TEIform="index"/> EZEKIEL MORRILL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/> ABRAHAM PERKINS</byline><p TEIform="p"> Ezekiel Morrill was born in South Hampton, N. H. Nov. 15, 1747. In the days of his
                            childhood, his father moved with his familv to Canterbury, N. H., where Ezekiel lived more
                            than forty years, when he was called to the Eldership of the church at Enfield, N. H. in
                            the establishment of the order of that Society in 1793. He was reared under the influence of
                            the principles of Calvinism, was early religiously impressed and deeply concerned for the
                            salvation of his soul ; yet, having but faint hope of being one of the small number elected
                            to salvation, he resolved to pursue a worldly course, and also equally determined to listen
                            to the voice of the spirit and embrace its testimony, if it spake to his understanding. Thus
                            he lived until over thirty years of age, when a great religions revival pervaded Canterbury
                            and neighboring towns and he was mightily wrought upon and deeply convicted of his loss from
                            God. In his worldly pursuits, he seemed to be completely arrested, ".nd in that element his
                            interest was lost. Under this conviction, he united with a body called Free-will Baptists,
                            believing that the church of Christ must be a pure body. Realizing as he did his remoteness
                            from God, that his inward corruption, as he expressed it, was not removed, by which he was
                            brought into captivity to the spirit of darkness, he felt unable to live to the light of his
                            conviction, nor was he able to discover the cause of weakness and want of power in the
                            church, lie therefore conceived the idea that it could not b3 found short of a new
                            revelation, which would give travel to the soul in regeneration. Still he could not see in
                            what the cross consisted which would give birth to such travel. For four years he labored
                            and struggled in deep tribulation and agony of'soul, often encouraged by bright
                            manifestations and visions., which served to Mipport and hold him, until he found
                            deliverance through messengers commissioned by Ann Lee, to go forth and proclaim the
                            testimony of Christ, the genuine resurrection, a life out from the order of the old creation
                            into the spirit and baptism of the new heavens. Through the labors of these ministers, his
                            eyes were opened, the mystery of iniquity, the man of sin, was revealed. His reason was
                            convinced that the lust of the flesh was the vail that darkened the soul; that he must make
                            confession of his sins unto God, in the presence of his witnesses, slay his carnal life and
                            consecrate all his powers of his soul and body, with no reserve, and live to God. True to
                            his convictions and to his vows, he made the sacrifice, with a firm determination that
                            nothing should come between him and his God to change his purpose, though the heavens fall.
                            He often visited Mother Ann Lee and the first Elders of the Shaker church, and found them to
                            be genuine Christians, just such a people as he had sought after, whose life and testimony
                            bore witness to the truth of the purity of heart which the baptism of the Christ spirit
                            gives. Ezekiel's worldly prospects were flattering and his marital relations were of the
                            most agreeable character ; yet, when compared with the riches of the gospel and the angel
                            life, they were secondary considerations. He felt that no earthly <pb n="151" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 151? tie should be a snare or an obstacle in his way to prevent his obedience to
                            his religious faith, which demanded a life of celibacy, chastity and purity in every sense
                            of the word. His wife at the same time received faith in the testimony of Christ's second
                            appearing without sin unto salvation, and rendered him great support in his early strife for
                            victory over the nature )f sin. She was a talented, strongminded Christian woman, ever true
                            to her profession. She was a daughter of a deacon of an orthodox church from one of the most
                            honorable families. She with Ezekiel occasionally visited her parents where they openly
                            declared their faith and demonstrated their Christian life and character. Her father become
                            so deeply convicted of the truth of their testimony and the emptiness of his Christian
                            profession, that he refused to serve as a deacon in his church. Consequently his pastor
                            commissioned his other deacon to make labors with him and cause him to return to the forms
                            of their service, when he also seemed to become convinced there was more formalism than
                            substance in his profession and he refused to serve. The duty then devolved on the pastor to
                            make labors to reclaim his deacons, whose reasons for refusal were such as to bring their
                            pastor to the realization of the absence of the spirit of Christ in his mission work. He
                            therefore fell into despair, pronounced his profession a sham, that he was unworthy of
                            longer existence and died from starvation. Ezekiel lived to the age of eighty eight years,
                            loyal to the principles of truth as revealed to his understanding from the heavens,
                            respected and honored by his faithful gospel kindred, sternly exact and fearless in all the
                            duties of life, despite opposition or the friendship andi honor which a worldly life
                            offered.. Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/> A PRAYER. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lewis, Polly C." TEIform="persName"/> POLLY C. LEWIS</byline><p TEIform="p"> 0 righteous Father ! We pray fervently, and in humility for the sake of thy Zion and the
                            good of her inhabitants that she may not fail to honor thy holy way. In thy mercy, Heavenly
                            Father, do visit her people and make them pure in thy sight. Let thy power roll until not
                            one stone is left unturned, nor one twig left leafless. We know, Heavenly Father, thy
                            goodness and mercy is great, therefore we pray that the remnant of Israel may prosper, that
                            the aged ones may be crowned with peace and their few remaining days be to us a life long
                            blessing. We pray, earnestly, that wisdom may lead and direct those that are young ; that
                            they may walk in thy holy way. Lead them by the hand of thy love. Water them with the sweet
                            dews of repentance. O righteous Father, bless them with firmness, and with fortitude in
                            life's battle, and shield them from the snares of sin. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Charity" TEIform="index"/> CHARITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/> MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p"> Charity, love, mantled, the greatest of all virtues, ever recurred to the mind of Paul, the
                            grave spiritual teacher, as he recounted the many gifts that should uplift and benefit those
                            who had taken upon themselves the name of Christ. Through all his discourses and epistles to
                            the people, so fraught with wisdom,, <pb n="152" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 152 THE MANIFESTO. admonition,'
                            holy precept and earnest faith ; this beautiful spirit runs like a silvery thread, and binds
                            all the graces in one. '"And above all these things put on charity which is the bond of
                            perfectness." Souls imbued with this principle of love to God, and good will to man, delight
                            in deeds of kindness and mercy¦; such are slow to anger, patient and forgiving ;
                            interpreting things doubtful concerning others in the best sense ; striving to look on the
                            noble side of human character for the angel presence, which may perchance but dimly shine
                            through the cloud and darkness of obscuring error ; but, it is there in every human soul,
                            and can only be developed and brought to light by the action of the higher law of love.
                            "Charity covereth a multitude of sins ;" yet, not in the sense of tolerating wrong. Having
                            the love of God uppermost in our hearts, we may correct the faults of others in the
                            gentleness and meekness of a subdued spirit, and not in a censorious and overbearing manner.
                            Love responds to love ; ' The Lamb of God takethaway the sins of the world." "Let us not
                            therefore judge one another any more, but judge this rather, that no man put a stumbling
                            block, or an occasion to fall in his brother's way." Evil judging and uncharitable censure
                            are detrimental to spiritual growth, as is clearly seen in those who allow this spirit to
                            rule their conduct toward others "Charity suffereth long and is kind, charity envieth not."
                            One great cause of evil-speaking, is the harboring of an envious, jealous disposition ; it
                            is the canker that destroys the peace of souls, and mars the joy of association. "In honor
                            preferring one another," is the law of heavenly relation. Whoso obeys this law, enjoys the
                            kinship of unselfish souls, and is prepared to share the communion of angels. "Now abide
                            Faith, Hope and Charity, these three, but the greatest of these is Charity. Though I speak
                            with the tongues of men and angels, and have not Charity, I am become as sounding brass or
                            as a tinkling cymbal." This God-like attribute, springing from divine love in the soul, is
                            indeed above the knowledge, power and wisdom of the earthly mind. Let us all, especially
                            those who are young, assiduously cultivate this precious gift, and study with observation,
                            its beneficent effects in society. Then, and not until then, shall we know of the doctrine,
                            life and mission of Christ, or be in full membership with His living, growing church, where
                            "Love is the seal of discipleship, and Charity the bond of perfectness and peace." ML
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My Kindly Remembered Aunt C. : On my return from Providence..." TEIform="index"/>
                            My Kindly Remembered Aunt C. : On my return from Providence...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Shaker Village" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, N. H.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> My Kindly Remembered Aunt C. : On my return from Providence, I superscribed this envelope to
                            my cousin, I use it at this time as I hardly know your present address. My dear, dear Aunt,
                            can you feel why I cling in fond remembrance to your hand and heart. Others may love you for
                            daily good deeds witnessed, but your niece H., loves and regards you for the one act of your
                            life, which placed her when a giddy and nearly irresponsible girl, in a good situation to
                            choose a course in life which has budded and blossomed into so much joy and peace that she
                            comes with an offering, a hymn of thanksgiving. Though the poetry of my gift is written in
                            prose, I am <pb n="153" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 153 sure your motherly heart and spirit
                            will accept my tribute. Ever and always, rest in peace, my kind aunt, when you think of your
                            niece with the Shakers. She is happy, she loves and is loved by the friends of her adopted
                            home, and her aspirations for a pure life, and to aid in the Christ mission of doing good,
                            especially to girls of her own mental type, is the waking song of her living soul. Should
                            you reach the immortal shores before I see you again, carry the fragrance of this offering
                            with you, and if you find it practicable to visit earthly friends, come as near as possible,
                            and learn why I have chosen as I have to conclude my life, so unlike the life taken up at
                            the beginning. I am sorry that I have never been able to share my beautiful home with one
                            from my native city, whom I could teach, and thus be able to present a practical evidence of
                            my confidence in the life I have chosen. I could speak of the comet, of an earthquake, of
                            beautiful sunrises and sunsets, but perhaps too long a story at this time, may not be good
                            for me, and not particularly desirable by her whom I am anxious to please. Our Sister J. J.
                            B. with another sister was in Providence a short time since, but did not call upon you. I
                            would express the kindest love to ray cousins. I have only a tablet of good deeds to their
                            account. "Virtue brings its own reward." Love from all my dear Friends, Your Favored Niece</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tabor, H." TEIform="persName"/>H. Tabor.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is a lively spark of nobleness to descend in most favor to one when he is lowest in affliction" TEIform="index"/>
                            It is a lively spark of nobleness to descend in most favor to one when he is lowest in affliction
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> It is a lively spark of nobleness to descend in most favor to one when he is lowest in
                            affliction.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sidney, P" TEIform="persName"/>Sir P. Sidney</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our petition" TEIform="index"/> OUR PETITION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hillsgrove, Elmira" TEIform="persName"/>ELMIRA HILLSGROVE</byline><p TEIform="p">O lead us to the fountain Whence living waters flow; Help us ascend the mountain, Or walk the
                            valley low; Whatever be our portion, Wherever Thou dost guide, Divine and holy Spirit, O
                            there may we abide. It may not be our measure, To find the burden light, It may not be thy
                            pleasure To open to our sight The reason of thy dealings ; Yet give us trust, we pray, A
                            heart that's undivided, A love for thy pure way. Not selfishly, we're asking The favor of
                            thy care; Thine every gift of blessing, We would with others share ; And may the hours
                            passing Be fraught with deeds of love, May truth our hearts be moulding, Till wholly raised
                            above The elements of Sodom, Its false and fickle strife, To find in Thee a service, More
                            worthy of our life. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakerism" TEIform="index"/> SHAKERISM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Field, Floyd C" TEIform="persName"/> FLOYD C. FIELD.</byline><p TEIform="p"> What are the future prospects for Shake rism? This is a question which agitates the mind of
                            many true Believers. This subject has a tendency to cause uneasiness or partial unhappiness
                            to many of the old and well tried heroes and heroines who have, stood for scores of years
                            upon the solid rock of Christian purity. They feel sad when they see their beloved brothers
                            and sisters passing away, who once labored so zealously in the grand work of regeneration.
                            As they look around them now, they observe only a few of their original number. It is true
                            others have come to the fold, but only a few wave the banner of purity and proclaim the
                            truths with the zeal and fer- <pb n="154" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 154 THE MANIFESTO. vor that
                            characterized those who built our homes and turned the wilderness and forests into a garden
                            of Eden. Is it a wonder that they sometimes feel sad and occasionally tears glisten in their
                            eyes as they look back to the time when multitudes of sinners flocked to the altar of mercy,
                            eager to confess their sins, and live the Christ life.? At times the scenes are brought so
                            vividly before their minds that they seem to be living wholly in the past; they can see the
                            sparkling waters of purity flowing in their midst, and containing such a healing balm that
                            even the silvery ripples gave strength to hundreds that nocked to the brink of the holy
                            waters. They imagine they are young again ; they hear words of wisdom spoken with a power
                            that sends conviction to the heart, they confess their sins, and rejoice over their great
                            victory; joy fills their soul, and it is seemingly impossible for them to sit down and wait
                            for the world to come to them ; but they go out and labor; preach plain practical truths ;
                            success crowns their efforts, large accessions follow; they labor with their hearts rilled
                            with divine love. But soon the spell is broken and they realize that they are living in a
                            different age, an age of lukewarmness and worldliness, associated with some who care not for
                            real spiritual growth; but they are waiting : patiently waiting; hoping, that, ere long the
                            power of God will manifest itself as it has in days that are past. We are still living in an
                            age when only plain practical truths can reach and penetrate the hearts of those who are
                            hungering and thirsting for new light to beam upon their famishing souls. Knowledge in
                            metaphysics, discussing on the personality of God, worrying our minds on such subjects as
                            spontaneous generation, and having contentions over issues that are wholly irrelevant to all
                            Christian virtues, can never bring the success that crowned the efforts of the early
                            Believers. There is enough truth in the teachings of Jesus and Mother Ann to save all that
                            desire to live a higher, nobler and purer life! If we had as much zeal and enthusiasm and
                            loved humanity, as well as the early founders of our organization, we would soon be under
                            the necessity of forming new societies, and angelic bands would be in our midst, then we
                            would not be under the necessity of telling what the Lord did for his people nearly a
                            century ago, but we could realize a present blessing, and an out-pouring of the spirit of
                            God, for if there ever was a time when the world needed Shaker principles it is now ! "Say
                            not ye, there are yet four months and then cometh harvest? Behold I say unto you, Lift up
                            your eyes, and look on the fields for they are white already to harvest." I believe a better
                            day is dawning, the world is beginning to realize the terrible influence and prevalence of
                            sensuality. All classes of society feel the great power that the animal nature hath over
                            them, and thousands would willingly separate themselves from the world if the testimony of
                            Jesus could be fairly presented to them. Those principles which Jesus taught must always
                            have followers, for they are founded upon the Hock of Ages, and the gates of hell shall not
                            prevail against them. At times the prospects may look dark, but a glorious morn soon comes.
                            "Watchman what of the night? The watchman said, the morning cometh, and also the night, if
                            ye will inquire, inquire- ye, return, come! 1" So let us gird on the armor of purity, wave
                            the weapon of love, striving to assist all, by showing them the way of life, by so doing and
                            trusting in God and working for his cause, our hopes and anticipations will be more than
                            realized. Furthermore, these principles will continue to shine as a halo of glory, ages
                            after our bodies have crumbled back to mother earth ! Principles founded upon Infinite truth
                            can never die ! God will triumph. May we labor for those principles which Christ taught; may
                            we have the same spirit of meekness and humility that characterized his life; may we have
                            the charity and the love for mankind that Jesus had, and live a pure life, and we will
                            ultimately become more han victors, and conquerors in the grand work of the re-generation !
                            "Awake, awake, put on thy strength 0 Zion, put on thy beautiful garments O Jerusa- <pb n="155" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 155 lem," the holy city—"With the voice togeth er
                            shall they sing, for they shall see eye to eye when the Lord shall bring again Zion !'
                            South, Union, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watch and pray" TEIform="index"/>WATCH AND PRAY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="York, Elsie B." TEIform="persName"/>ELSIE B. YORK</byline><p TEIform="p">"Watch and pray lest ye enter into temptation." Jesus said this to his disciples, -when he
                            found them sleeping. If this injunction of our Savior was regarded more than it is, there
                            would be less sin in the world ; tor in our own strength we can do little or nothing. We
                            need to pray to a higher power, and watch ourselves in order to guard against wrong. It is
                            supposed that all Christians pray, but do we pray sincerely and earnestly r Kneeling for
                            prayer in a custom in all Christian countries, but form and custom avail nothing if the soul
                            is not there. We should pray in joy as well as in sorrow, and really regard the injunction
                            to "Pray without ceasing." When engaged in our secular duties, we should remember the
                            counsel of Mother Ann Lee "Hands at work and hearts to God."</p><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Canterbury" TEIform="index"/>Canterbury, N. H.</dateline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Do not 'have the blues'" TEIform="index"/>DO NOT "HAVE THE BLUES"
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bush, Belle" TEIform="persName"/>BELLE BUSH
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> What if thy day be dark and drear, And
                                    cheerless seems the sky? Yield not thy soul to doubt ox fear, Heave not the bitter
                                    sigh. Though earth may wear her sablest hues, 'Twill naught avail to "have the
                                    blues." Though friends may prove unkind to you, And faithful ones depart, Still let
                                    thy course be up and on, Bear thou a fearless heart. But do not all the fates abuse—
                                    'Twill naught avail to "have the blues." Be firm, be strong, thy purpose high, Stay
                                    not thy upward flight; True courage wears the strongest shield Amid the shades of
                                    night. Then wear not melancholy hues— We're weakest when we court "the blues. Though
                                    fortune prove a "fickle dame," And wealth "a fleeting show," Still from the
                                    treasures of the mind The purest joys may flow. Then cast aside those sable hues—
                                    The brave will never seek "the blues." If thou wouldst win a deathless fame, Bear
                                    well thy weight of years. The priceless treasure of a name Was never bought with
                                    tears. Then cast aside those sombre hues— Toil on, and wait, but shun "the blues."
                                    If thou wouldst nobly live and die, Fear not the passing gale. Know thou that to the
                                    valiant soul There's no such word as fail. Then cast aside those sable hues, And bid
                                    farewell to all "the blues."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Present era, no. 2: not a dream, but a solemn reality" TEIform="index"/>THE PRESENT ERA.
                            NO. 2. Not a Dream, But a Solemn Reality</head><p TEIform="p"> WRITTEH FOR THE MANIFESTO. THE PRESENT ERA. NO. 2. Not a Dream, But a Solemn Reality. I
                            dreamed of the future scarce twelve months ago,— An era seemed dawning with beauty aglow. Of
                            dream, or its subject, I did not complain; But soon to reality wakened again. As high
                            soaring bird on free pinion would go, I left far behind me the regions of woe, In thought,
                            or prospection, I saw the ideal, And Oh! what a shock when I came to the real. The shackles
                            and bands that I saw then unclasp, Are wound around men with tenacious strong grasp And
                            tyrants, who've wielded control at their will, Instead of relapsing, remain tyrants still,
                            In our grand republic, Columbia's free soil, A class are still destined to drudg'ry and
                            toil; While sharpers so shrewdly monopolize wealth, If not by fair dealings, by fraud and by
                            stealth. Our gorernmcnt offices all filled by men, Of whom it is said, some can scarce wield
                            a pen, And some scruple not, as we learn, to defraud, While brother officials their cunning
                            applaud. In this noble land "equal rights" how abound? The claim is just nominal—farce,
                            empty sound; For sisters right loyal to country and cause, As yet are in bondage to lords
                            and their laws. <pb n="156" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 156 THE MANIFESTO. No place is conceded for them at
                            the helm Where they should be active to honor the realm, Help purify politics, morals
                            sustain, And dignify labor of hand, and of brain. The symbol of Justice, with scales in her
                            hand, Would show that equality reigns in our land,— A beautiful emblem, if only 'twere true;
                            Such is not the fact, there is much yet to do. Now avarice wields a strong scepter, and
                            wide, And for love of power and place, is denied To virtue, the part she should act in the
                            play, To conquer the passions with absolute sway. While vice and corruption are rife in the
                            land, And crimes of deep hue, and of satanic brand ; Cells, prisons and jails are in
                            constant employ, And yet some elude, and their freedom enjoy (?) Foul dens of debauchery,
                            coverts of shame, And gambling resorts beastly passions inflame; E'en licensed iniquity
                            finds a retreat; Which truth so abhorrent,—'tis sad to repeat. The mind and the body
                            corrupted and low, No innocent childhood our children can know; And youth so precocious,
                            distorted become, By use of bad morals, tobacco and rum. The manhood that follows we will
                            not portray, But from the sad picture would fain turn away. The bright side of life, for
                            there is one to show, We'd bring to the foreground and hold it to view. We know that
                            reformers are striving with main Whose efforts for goodness will not be in vain, True souls
                            of integrity, minds of great worth, Who work to establish,—reform on the earth. There's much
                            that is lovely, and beauty appears Where darkness and error and false slavish fears Have
                            yielded to light, and the truth that makes free; The dawn of more brightness we already see,
                            Still hope for more victory,—right over wrong. May those now in strife for this purpose be
                            strong, More laborers call, and the conquest increase, With triumph and gladness, win
                            trophies of peace. In this grand encounter where volunteers work, I'll not remain dreaming',
                            lest I seem a shirk; But labor with patience, in duty be found; While prayer and
                            thanksgiving shall ever abound. Shirley, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Woman" TEIform="index"/> WOMAN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Chandler, Olive F." TEIform="persName"/> OLIVE F. CHANDLER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Woman must stand on that platform oi love supreme which has the power tc compass man, as did
                            Mother Ann Lee. That power shall be restored to Mount Zion, that shall make the vile and
                            unclean tremble before it; and the arrows of conviction shall pierce the heart o: the
                            sinner.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Andrew Barrett—Much beloved Brother..." TEIform="index"/>Andrew Barrett—Much beloved Brother...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, May 13, 1883" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, May 13, 1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> 
                            AndrewBarrett—Much beloved Brother; I un impressed to write you this morning, thinking it may be a
                            good time to express the ove of the North Family. You are moving from Lebanon to Harvard,
                            lave made a beginning. In all the years of your experience in Lebanon, you have acted the
                            part of a good substantial Believer—have been a pillar in Zion. Your presence at the Meeting
                            house was always welcome—your word of union acceptable. We shall miss you when we meet. How
                            you can be spared is an unsolved problem. As &amp; peacemaker, in the Society you were a
                            most invaluable element. As a standing, living protest against heretical ideas, you have
                            done great honor to yourself and the Family favored with your membership. You was blessed
                            with a strong, bold Faith, a great Gift of God to you. If but the five Believers, of which
                            Father Joseph spake, had been all who were left, Andrew Barrett would have been one of them.
                            The Rock of Revelation remains, upon it as an exponent of true Shakerism, your house is
                            built, and the Gates of Hell have not prevailed against it, or ever will. Peace be your
                            portion, love your treasure and assurance forever your inheritance. May you form a nucleus
                            around which the faithful seekers after righteousness may gather. Let the weak say "/am
                            strong'," and press into the kingdom. Let the lame and halting be restored, the soul sick be
                            healed, and the sinners in Zion, who work iniquity in the land of uprightness, be reproved,
                            reformed, and the aged Warriors, who are putting off the harness, boast of their deeds of
                            progress in the battles of the Lord, to their heart's content, and may they be greatly
                            comforted. Ann Lee prepared her vessel by washing in the waters of confession and
                            repentance, until she stood as the king's daughter, "all glorious within," transparent as
                            theT * t. So must her followers become. Harvard, M <pb n="157" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 157
                            Be it yours to build up the waste places, repair the broken-down walls of protection, that
                            they may effectually separate between the precious and the vile, between the worshipers of
                            God and the worshipers of self. Beloved Brother, having the Gospel, you can minister it, and
                            can say to the mourners, ''Be of good cheer for I have overcome the world." You have blest
                            God in your Brethren and Sisters of the North Family, and now the North Family bless y.ou,
                            and you will be blessed. Elders. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="S. Mabee.—Dear Friend..." TEIform="index"/>S. Mabee.—Dear Friend...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Leadville, April 23, 1883" TEIform="index"/> Leadville, Apr. 23, 1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> S. Mabee.—Dear Friend ;—March number of S. M. duly received with thanks. My opinion of it,
                            (so far meeting your request,) is, that it is all that it purports to be, Christian in its
                            tenor and effect, its object being to inculcate and develop the divine principle innate with
                            all, by inheritance, differing only in degree. This principle of goodness to which I refer,
                            is eminently characteristic with those known as benefactors in all ages, of whom Jesus of
                            Nazareth stood prominent. To deify Christ the crucified, as the "very God" "before all time,
                            the redeemer of the world" etc., is a matter ot education.—His crucifixion a result, not a
                            necessity. Bigotry crucified him and many thousands of his disciples, even as it persecuted
                            the earnest, god-like Quakers of Salem. I am much opposed to organized creedal power. I
                            believe in practical religion, which simply means, do good deeds, not creeds will save us,
                            self redemption therefore is imperative. "Work out your own salvation" is incumbent/upon
                            all, by good works, inasmuch as "faith without works is dead." I am what may be termed an
                            independent Spiritualist, have lived twenty three years in the Rocky Mountains, am an
                            advocate of anti-creedism, regard all men as brethren, and God the Creator, as our father.
                            Yours Truly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Jones, James K." TEIform="persName"/> Jas. K. Jones.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The great man loves the conversation or book that convists him, not that which soothes and natters him" TEIform="index"/>
                            The great man loves the conversation or book that convists him, not that which soothes and natters him
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> The great man loves the conversation or book that convicts him, not that which soothes and
                            natters him.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Emerson" TEIform="persName"/>Emerson</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Caution" TEIform="index"/> CAUTION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Horton, Lewis" TEIform="persName"/> LEWIS HORT0N.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "He that does not provide for his own household hath denied the faith." This may be strong
                            language, but nevertheless true. To take it somewhat to our own household, a brief
                            explanation may be necessary, namely; they who do not take wise precaution in regard to the
                            physical and moral wellbeing of those who are dependent upon their care, fail in some degree
                            in the faith and calling which they have espoused. If there are mistakes in this line of
                            duty, charity reminds me they are unintentional, errors of the head, not of the heart. Those
                            who were sent out into the world in olden times to preach the gospel, were cautioned to be
                            wise as serpents and as harmless as doves. Can we not be wiser than serpents, and as
                            harmless as doves? We should have a care, the world is teeming with contagious diseases, as
                            alarming as the vices of a cultured and an uncultured civilization, especially in cities and
                            other crowded localities. By one false step, sometimes years of labor and exertion are lost,
                            the doors of the household are left ajar, the destroyer creeps in, and sorrow follows the
                            gaunt figure through the aisles of the sanctuary. Isolation is a strong rampart of defence ;
                            watch well upon its towers and if we must needs go beyond put on the whole armor that we may
                            be safe from the physical and moral malaria of the world. Within lies our spiritual gardens,
                            blooming, if we will, with the fragrance of heaven, bright with divinest love. May His
                            Kingdom come in all sanitary <pb n="158" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 158 THE MANIFESTO. measures, pure air,
                            pure water, cheerfulness, health and happiness. Stanc by the ship now and forever.
                            Canterbury,N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Experience" TEIform="index"/> EXPERIENCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tatterton, M. J." TEIform="persName"/> M. J. TATTERTON</byline><p TEIform="p"> While meditating upon the happiness enjoyed in living the true Christ life, the idea
                            occurred to us that we might perhaps do a little good by writing our thought upon this
                            subject. Having been nurtured from infancy under the holy ministration of Christian
                            teachers, our soul over flows with gratitude ; we are led to exclaim,—Blessed relation which
                            has always been ours to enjoy ! As we grow to understand more and more the depth and breadth
                            of pure and jindefiled religion, how highly we value the means of grace within our grasp ;
                            would that all others could be blest with the same knowledge and surrounded with the same
                            strength. We have had no personal experience in what are termed the sinful pleasures of the
                            world ; but judging from a knowledge of our inheritance, they are sensual and full of
                            vanity, leading the mind afar from holy and noble purposes. It is enough for us to accept
                            the warnings given by those who have had (his experience, and as we understand, obey; thus
                            preserve the purity of soul which it is our sweet privilege to cultivate. 0 that we might be
                            able to impress some little one with the unspeakable beauty and loveliness of the virgin
                            character! thus engage the faculties so inclined to earthly loves and selfish pleasures, in
                            the pursuit of spiritual graces. The question sometimes comes to us, Where is the power to
                            convict souls of the inestimable value of a privilege to preserve soul and body unspotted
                            from the world ? Have we sufficiently wrestled in prayer for "the knowledge of the Lord to
                            cover the earth" that the many whom circumstances bind to worldly relations, the many who
                            are needy, watching and waiting, may feel the drawings of the Father, receive a baptism of
                            the Holy Spirit, and become virgin sons and daughters in the Lord's House ? Canterbury,
                       N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Freedom of the human will" TEIform="index"/> FREEDOM OF THE HUMAN WILL</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Know then that ev'ry soul is free, To choose his life and what he'll he ; For
                                    this, eternal truth has given, That God will force no Man to Heaven. He'll draw,
                                    persuade, direct him right, Bless him with wisdom, love and light, In nameless ways
                                    he good and kind, But never force the human mind. Freedom and reason make us men,
                                    Take these away what are we then? Mere animals and just as well, The beasts may
                                    think of heaven or hell Then let no one their powers abuse, But ways of Truth and
                                    Goodness choose; Our God is pleased when we improve And seek for grace and win his
                                    love. It's my free will for to believe, ¦ 'Tis God's free will, me to receive; To
                                    stubborn willers this I'll tell, It's all free grace and all free will. Then if they
                                    take the downward road, And make in hell their last abode • Our God is clear and
                                    they will know, They plunged themselves in endless wee. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Repentance: an allegory" TEIform="index"/> REPENTANCE. AN ALLEGORY</head><p TEIform="p"> A hermit was conducted by an angel into a wood where he saw an old man cutting down
                            &gt;oughs to make up a load. When it was arge he tied it up and attempted to lift it on
                                <pb n="159" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 159 his shoulders and carry it away, but finding
                            it too heavy he laid it down, cut more wood and heaped it on, then tried again to carry it
                            off. This he did several times, always adding something to the load after trying in vain to
                            raise it from the ground. In the mean time the hermit astonished at the old man's folly
                            desired the angel to explain what this meant. "You behold," said he, "in the foolish old
                            man, an exact representation of those who, being made sensible of the burden of their sins,
                            resolve to repent, but soon grow weary and instead of lessening their burden increase it
                            every day. At each time they find the task heavier than it was before and so put it off a
                            little longer in the vain hope that they will, by and by, be more able to accomplish it.
                            Then they go cm adding to their burden until it grows too heavy to be borne, and then in
                            despair of God's mercy, and with their sins unrepented of they lie down and die. Turn again
                            my son, and behold the end of the old man whom thou sawest heaping up a pile of boughs." The
                            hermit looked and saw him in vain attempting to remove the pile which was now accumulated
                            far beyond his strength to raise. His feeble limbs tottered over the burden; the poor
                            remains of his strength were fast ebbing away: the darkness of death was gathering around
                            him ; and after a convulsive and impatient attempt to lift the load, he fell down and
                            expired.—Selected.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Motives" TEIform="index"/> MOTIVES</head><p TEIform="p"> It is the motive that, more than anything else, renders an action' good or bad. However fair
                            the look of an action may be, if the right motive be wanting, the action is hollow ; if the
                            motive be a bad one, the action is rotten at the core. Who cares for an outward seeming, or
                            show of friendship or affection, unless the heart be also on the same' term%? Who does not
                            prize a rough outside, when it covers an honest inside, more than the most fawning fondness
                            from a heart that is cold and false? Thus it is right to insist on the principles for their
                            own sake, because the principles give their value to the actions, not the actions to the
                            principles, for they are but dross. The principles are the gold on which is to be placed the
                            stamp, and if the gold is not good, the stamp, though it often deceives the people, gives it
                            no real worth.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Letters" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Editor;—Wishing to become useful in Society we..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Dear Editor;—Wishing to become useful in Society we...</head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="June 18, 1883" TEIform="index"/> June 18, 1883</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Editor;—Wishing to become useful in Society we thought we might improve our ability
                                and set a good example to our companions by writing a few thoughts for the Letter Box,
                                on this wise : Be yourself—even if you are naturally a little serious or thoughtful, and
                                perhaps might think you would be preferred by many acquaintances if you were more genial
                                and pleasant. Why, some persons really demean themselves in the estimation of their
                                friends, by trying to assume the manners and ways of another, instead of being true to
                                themselves. There is a class of persons who boast of the great amount of individuality
                                they possess, but if you notice their habits, you will see but very little that is
                                natural, without affectation; and should you by chance read their letters or
                                compositions, one would find them pretty much all made up of quotations, without a
                                single original idea. Now we believe that every responsible being is intended to have a
                                character of his own, and to be what no other person is, or ever can be, by strictly
                                obeying the monitor which our wise Father has given to all, that we might each act for
                                ourselves, regardless of the praise, applause or blame of those around us. We do not
                                mean by this that one should be haughty or self-sufficient, for these errors belong to
                                the list of evils indulged in by the ignorant and foolish. "Be what ycu seem to be, and
                                seem to be what you really are," was the advice of our good Father James Whittaker, one
                                of the first leaders of our church, and we can plainly see by this that to "be one's
                                self," means simply to be honest. If we always act truthfully ourselves though we may be
                                far from perfection, we will never lack love, beauty, companions or friends. We have
                                tried to write our simple thoughts and hope to make the impression that we will be
                                thoroughly true to our convictions of right, and will seek the union and companionship
                                of such who are likewise honest. That we may be vessels of honor in our beautiful Church
                                relation. Faithfully,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="L." TEIform="persName"/> L.</byline></div3></div2><pb n="160" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes" TEIform="index"/>NOTES </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">There may be other duties, imperative duties, some, seemingly, claiming our attention through
                            all the hours of the day, all the days of the week, and through every week in the month. Our
                            lives ! precious probationary moments in which to establish a claim for a more glorious
                            reward ! ! Something to eat? Shall this be first? It, indeed, has a strong claim and cannot
                            be passed over carelessly. We may ask in all confidence, "Give us this day our needful
                            bread," and for even this the mass of mankind are obliged to contend bitterly against the
                            world. They do not and cannot accumulate stores to hide away, and yet they make this a first
                            duty- ' If we would obtain this, our daily bread, we must not only ask, but we must seek and
                            seek diligently till we find it. With this seeking comes our homes and lands, so that we may
                            have a comfortable habitation on the earth. And what should we be able to do without them ?
                            It would be folly to even anticipate such an idea. As Believers, we are anxious to have more
                            and by having more be able to do more good. We have a right to anticipate an hundred fold of
                            every blessing agreeably to the promise. Having obtained it we can then hold it only in
                            God's name, and, certainly, these treasures of the earth should be wisely used for the good
                            of God's Kingdom on the earth. Shall this be our first duty ? or shall we in looking after
                            this hundred-fold of houses and lands accept the same course that is and has been from time
                            immemorial the practice of the children of this world ? Accumulate selfishly and selfishly
                            spend. If Believers should prove able to amass the wealth of a Croesus, what then ? Does
                            this insure a right into the Kingdom of God? Really, the only answer to all these inquiries,
                            is and must be that which has, already, been so wisely proffered. "Seek first the Kingdom of
                            God and his righteousness." This becomes our first duty, and having secured this, all
                            needful things will be added in proportion to our faithfulness in duty. Mother Ann very
                            wisely taught the Believers, "Put your hands at work and your heart to God." With this gift
                            we become permanently established and no "gates of hell" can ever prevail against us, while
                            without it our homes and lands or whatever we may claim as an inheritance in this life, will
                            certainly prove to be of the least consequence. If we think we have already, in our
                            possession this inestimable treasure and the assurance of "Eternal Life" then it should
                            become our first and imperative duty, to let our "light shine," to do all that lies in our
                            power to turn souls into the path of righteousness and peace. It is no less our duty than it
                            was the duty of the apostle "to preach the gospel, not with wisdom of words," but by '"the
                            cross of our Lord Jesus Christ, through whom the world has been crucified unto us and we
                            unto the world." Every Believer should bear in mi:.d the parable of the servant who so
                            carefully folded his treasure in a napkin and lid it in the earth. He very well knew that he
                            had in possession something precious, so choice that he did not even wish <pb n="161" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 161 to run the risk of making it better or o( obtaining more
                            of the same kind. He knew that this valuable treasure belonged to his Lord and that it was
                            among the best gifts. Just as we know that we have a precious treasure, the power of God
                            unto salvation. To keep this unharmed, and away from the dirty hands of a crowd of
                            worldly-wise-men, he would just hide it away, and on the return of his Lord give it to him
                            exactly as he had received it. Six out of eight persons would quite naturally think that
                            this was the best thing he could have done under the circumstances, and yet it did not seem
                            to be quite right. It is an easy matter for us to determine the "first duty" of this man,
                            and we wonder how he could have been so stupid in neglecting to increase his temporal or
                            spiritual interests. Can we at this time as readily determine our "first duty" to God and to
                            humanity? </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Simple remedies for emergencies" TEIform="index"/> SIMPLE REMEDIES FOR EMERGENCIES</head><p TEIform="p"> Very few persons are able to control their nerves so completely as to keep from being
                                startled when confronted with a cut finger with dripping blood, and the loud cries which
                                announce a catastrophe. Sometimes they cannot collect their thoughts sufficiently to
                                recall any of the good remedies with which they are acquainted. One way to avoid this is
                                to write out a list of help in trouble, and tack it upon the door of your room, after
                                the manner of hotel regulations. There is nothing better for a cut than powdered rosin.
                                Get a few cents' worth of rosin, pound it until it is fine, and put it in an empty,
                                clean pepper or spice box with perforated top; then you can easily sift it out on the
                                cut; put a soft cloth around the injured member and wet it with cold water once in a
                                while. It will prevent inflammation and soreness. In doing up a burn, the main point is
                                to keep the air from it. If sweet oil and cotton are not at hand, take a cloth and
                                spread dry flour over it, and wrap the burned part in itIt is always well to have some
                                simple remedies in the house where you can get them without a moment's loss of time; a
                                little bottle of peppermint, in case of colic; chlorate of potash for sore throat,
                                pepsin for indigestion, and a bottle of brandy. Have them arranged so that you could go
                                to them in the dark and reach the right remedy, but be sure you never do it, even if you
                                know they have not been disturbed; always light a lamp or the gas, and make sure you
                                have what you are after. Remember that pistols are always loaded, and that poison may be
                                put in place of peppermint.—Amer. Agri.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Liver complaint" TEIform="index"/> LIVER COMPLAINT</head><p TEIform="p">For your torpid liver go without grease in your food, bathe your skin every morning on
                                rising and follow the bathing with sharp friction with the roughest towel, and, if you
                                can bear it, with a flesh-brush also. Beating the body in the region of the liver with
                                the flat of the hand or with the fist is excellent. General gymnastic exercises are
                                always advisable in what is known as liver complaint. Attacks of bilious colic would be
                                prevented, I believe, by a little care in eating. I think an avoidance of all desserts,
                                and eating but two meals a day, the last one somewhere in the middle of the day, would
                                prevent all return of the trouble.-—Dio Lewis.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Don't" TEIform="index"/>DON'T
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="E., F. W." TEIform="persName"/> [Contributed by F. W. E.]</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Don't sleep in a draught. Don't go to bed with cold feet. Don't sleep
                                        with insecure false teeth in your mouth. Don't stai't the day's work without a
                                        good areakfast. Don't sleep in a room without ventilation of some kind. <pb n="162" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 162 THE MANIFESTO. Don't stuff a cold lest you be next
                                        obliged to starve a fever. Don't try to get along without flannel under-clothing
                                        in winter. Don't sleep in the same under-garmentyou wear during the day. Don't
                                        toast your feet by the fire, but try sunlight or friction instead. Don't neglect
                                        to have at least one movement of the bowels each day. Don't drink ice-water by
                                        the glass; take it in sips, a swallow at a time. Don't try to keep up on coffee
                                        and alcoholics when you ought to go to bed. Don't eat snow to quench thirst; it
                                        brings on inflammation of the throat. Don't strain your eyes by reading or
                                        working with an insufficient or a flickering light. Don't use the eyes for
                                        reading or fine work in the twilight of evening or early morn. Don't try to
                                        lengthen your days by cutting short your night's rest; it is poor economy. Don't
                                        take some other person's medicine because you are troubled somewhat as they
                                        were. Don't blow out a gas-light as you would a lamp; many lives are lost every
                                        year by this mistake.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Dr. Foot's health monthly" TEIform="index"/>Dr. Foote's Health Monthly.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Measles" TEIform="index"/> MEASLES</head><p TEIform="p"> This infectious disease, with ordinary care is not fatal, as a general rule.
                                Symptoms.—The child appears as if it had a cold in the head sneezing, cough, running at
                                the eyes and nose, itching of the face, the eyes are red, and very sensitive to the
                                light. On the fourth day small red spots appear on the face, generally in clusters, and
                                then spread. If you examine them carefully, you will find they are not round, but
                                crescent or half-moon shape. In measles the fever increases as the rash comes out. When
                                it has been out three days it turns brown, and the skin crumbles off like bran. The
                                common saying with regard to measles is "It is three days out and four days in," that
                                is, the patient is ill four days before the eruption appears, and that it remains three
                                days. At this state diarrhoea frequently occurs. Let the child be in a room shaded from
                                any strong light. Keep the chest particularly well protected from cold. Give plenty of
                                warm weak drinks, such as tea, arrowroot, etc., and if the breathing is difficult, put
                                on a mustard and oatmeal poultice to the chest, and give a small dose of purgative
                                medicine, if needful. In general this is all that is required, if you only protect the
                                child from getting cold. But if the disease is not running its usual course, and more
                                than this is needful, you will need good medical advice. Housekeeper's Friend.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>House and Farm</head><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Save the bones" TEIform="index"/> SAVE THE BONES</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> While purchasing bone-dust, and fertilizersinto which bone-dust largely
                                        enters, do not forget to be sure and utilize all the bones that can be gathered
                                        about home. Bone-dust bought in the market costs about two cents a pound. Coarse
                                        fragments of bone dissolve very slowly, and for that reason are not so valuable
                                        as fine ground bone. Still, if buried near grape-vines or fruit trees, the
                                        numberless mouths at the ends of the roots will, in a. few years, eat up and
                                        appropriate every particle of plant food they contain. In setting some apple
                                        trees, a few years ago, we buried a bushel of bones under each tree. The thrift
                                        of the trees and the beauty and size of the. fruit we attribute in a great
                                        degree to the bones. A few years ago, we buried some bones near a Flemish Beauty
                                        pear tree. The tree bore for the first time during the past season. For size,
                                        color and quality of fruit we have seen nothing equaling it in this vicinity.
                                        This we attribute mainly to the effect of the bones, though there may be other
                                        causes. If one does not care to save and use the bones in this way, they may be
                                        burned in the stove and left in the ashes, which will thus be greatly increased
                                        in value. Save and utilize the bones.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Vermont farmer" TEIform="index"/>Vermont Farmer</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Abuse of lemons" TEIform="index"/>ABUSE OP LEMONS</head><p TEIform="p"> Is it not a correct principle to use the things of this world as not abusing them? <pb n="163" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 163 How can this be done except by observation,
                                meditation and reasoning together, until we can discriminate between the precious and
                                vile, between that which is, and that which is not useful? I have long been of the
                                opinion that vegetables and fruits indigenous to, or acclimated in a country, were the
                                most natural food for the people of that section. The fruits of the temperate zone,
                                apples, pears, cherries, plums, currants and berries of various kinds, contain the
                                saccharine and acid elements in just the proportions promotive of health to the
                                inhabitants of their native zone. Is it not natural to use these? Let the children
                                answer. And is it not unnatural, unhealthy, to use exotics? Would it not be better, by
                                "temperance in all things," to avoid the "intermittent fever and lemon juice with strong
                                black coffee without sugar?" Is it not a safe scientific conclusion that if Lemons, or
                                anything else will not grow and ripen in our climate, it is because nature forbids their
                                being used by our people? If it be said they will grow exceptionally; then let them be
                                used exceptionally, as exotics, a luxury, not to be used "daily in rubbing the gums,"
                                washing the hands and nails to keep them clean, soft and supple, instead of using soap."
                                The "warts, dandruff and roots of hair, are a doubtful justification for drinking
                                Lemonade in preference to all other drinks.'' Water is decidedly more natural. In the
                                hot Summer months, when we have Lemon weather Lemons may be used with but little damage,
                                by those who can afford luxuries. But even then, our own acidulous fruits are safer in
                                my opinion. Workmen catering for daily bread, may not be necessitated M daily wash their
                                heads and hands in lemon juice in order to enjoy good health. When lemons cost $S5. to
                                $15 per box, the poor may console themselves with the reflection that tropical fruits
                                have to be picked in a green, unripe condition, and that tropical people would not eat
                                the Oranges, Lemons, Pineapples and Bananas exhibited for sale in our Northern markets.
                                They are dear bought and far fetched in more than the pecuniary meaning of these terms.
                                I would say of Lemons as the Poet puts it of other things. "The gems within the ocean
                                deep, And the wealth her caverns bear, Let the Ocean and her caverns keep, In darkness
                                hidden there. But 0 Almighty Parents send, Your Angels from above, To kindle in our
                                hearts a fire Of purity and love."—F. W. Evans, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To make pickles" TEIform="index"/>TO MAKE PICKLES</head><p TEIform="p"> For 1 gall, cucumbers, take 1 qt. salt, with cold water sufficient to cover them. Let
                                them remain in this brine three days, then remove from the brine, and pour over them
                                weak vinegar, scalding hot. After four days, remove from this liquor, and pour over them
                                good strong vinegar, heated, adding pepper, spice, mustard, &amp;c, to your
                            taste.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tomato preserves" TEIform="index"/>TOMATO PRESERVES
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Take the yellow variety as soon as ripe, scald and peel;
                                        then to seven pounds of tomatoes add seven pounds of white sugar, and let them
                                        stand over night. Take the tomatoes out of the sugar and boil the syrup,
                                        removing the scum. Put in the tomatoes and boil gently fifteen or twenty minutes
                                        ; remove the fruit again and boil until the syrup thickens On cooling, put the
                                        fruit into jars and pour the syrup over it, and add a few slices of lemon to
                                        each jar, and you will have something to please the taste of the most
                                        fastidious.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="South and West" TEIform="index"/>South and West</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fruit stains" TEIform="index"/> FRUIT STAINS. </head><p TEIform="p">In the season of fruits, the napkins used at the table, and often the handkerchiefs and
                                other articles, will become stained. Those who have access to a good drug store can
                                procure a bottle of Javelle water. If the stains are wet with this before the articles
                                are put into the wash, they will be completely removed. Those who cannot get Javelle
                                water can make a solution of chloride of lime. Four ounces of the chloride of lime is to
                                be put into a quart of water, in a bottle, and after thorough shaking allow the dregs to
                                settle. The clear liquid will remove the stains as readily as Javelle water, but, in
                                using this <pb n="164" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 164 THE MANIFESTO. one precaution must be observed. Be
                                careful to thoroughly rinse the article to which this solution has been applied, in
                                clear water, before bringing it in contact with soap. When Javelle water is used, this
                                precaution is not necessary: but with the chloride of lime liquid it is, or the articles
                                will be harsh and stiff.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sheepskin Mats" TEIform="index"/> Sheepskin Mats.</head><p TEIform="p">Wash while fresh in strong soapsuds, first picking from the wool all the dirt that wilt
                                come out. A little kerosene, a tablespoonful to three gallons of water, will aid in
                                removing the impurities. Continue to wash the skin in fresh suds till it is white and
                                clean. Then dissolve a half pound each of salt and alum in three pints of boiling water,
                                put into it water enough to cover the skin, which should soak in the solution twelve
                                hours, and then be hung on a line to drain. When nearly dry nail it, wool side in, on a
                                board, or the side of a barn to dry. Rub into the skin an ounce each of pulverized alum
                                and saltpetre, and if the skin is large double the quantity. Rub ior an hour or two.
                                Fold the skin sides together, and hang the skin away for three days, rubbing it every
                                day or till perfectly dry. Then with a blunt knife clear the skin of impurities, rub it
                                with pumice or rottenstone, trim it into shape, and you have a door mat that will last a
                                lifetime. If it is to be dyed, have a shallow vessel as large as the skin in which to
                                prepare the dye, so that the skin can be laid wool-side down smoothly into the vessel
                                that all parts may be equally immersed in the dye. This should not be more than an inch
                                deep, otherwise the skin might be injured by the hot dye. After coloring again stretch
                                the skin to dry, and then comb with a wool or cotton card.—For "D." </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Select</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Righteousness" TEIform="index"/> "RIGHTEOUSNESS."</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"What we need is to write the word 'righteousness' on the play-grounds where
                                        the children go to school; write it over every open door through which young men
                                        enter upon their lifework; write it on every carriage in which men ride to
                                        business, and women to their shopping; write it on the walls of ev,ery bank,
                                        counting-room and public building; write it over every entrance of church, that
                                        every man may see it when making a public confession of his faith in Christ;
                                        write it so plainly that he that would make haste to be rich and great, may
                                        learn that there is but one road to real success in this world, and this is the
                                        road of strict integrity. God has not given a promise of His favor in this or
                                        any other world to any but the righteous man. The man who lives righteously is
                                        the only man that need apply for admission to the heavenly kingdom. 'Not every
                                        one that saith unto me, Lord, Lord, shall enter into the kingdom of heaven; but
                                        he that doeth the will of my Father which is in heaven.' " —</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="S.W. Presbyterian" TEIform="index"/>S. W. Presbyterian</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We do not think" TEIform="index"/>WE DO NOT THINK</head><p TEIform="p">[Written for <cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Pomeroy's democrat" TEIform="index"/>Pomeroy's Democrat.]</bibl><quote TEIform="quote">WE DO NOT THINK. We do not think when slightingly We speak of one another,
                                        That just a passing breeze may fan The spark we ought to smother; For spoken
                                        thoughts, are apt to grow— Like buds when fairly started— We seldom dream what
                                        form they'll take When from our lips they've parted. We do not think when envy
                                        rules, And tongues begin to wander O'er cruel things— which were they heard,
                                        Might make our neighbors ponder. They may be wrong—we may be right, But should
                                        we try to measure Their lives and actions by our own, Their feelings, at our
                                        pleasure? We do not think, that hearts are crushed And brows are madly burning,
                                        By just an idle word, which gains A hundred while returning. The pleasure's
                                        brief, let conscience reign, How proudly then, we'll own it— That when a
                                        slanderous thought steals up, We'll think—-and just postpone it.</quote></cit></p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is right to be contented with what we have, never with what we are" TEIform="index"/>
                                It is right to be contented with what we have, never with what we are
                            </head><p TEIform="p">It is right to be contented with what we have, never with what we are.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mackintosh" TEIform="persName"/></byline></div3><pb n="165" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dr. Johnson's prayer" TEIform="index"/>DR. JOHNSON'S PRAYER</head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by Anna Ervin.] DR. JOHNSON'S PRAYER. O Lord, my maker and protector, who
                                hast graciously sent me into this world to work out my salvation; enable me to drive
                                from me all such unquiet and perplexing thoughts as may mislead or binder me in the
                                practices of those duties which Thou hast required. When I behold the works of thy
                                hands, give me grace always to remember that thy ways are not my ways, nor thy thoughts,
                                my thoughts. And while it shall please thee to continue me in this world, where much is
                                to be done, and little to be known, teach me by thy holy spirit to withdraw my mind from
                                unprofitable and dangerous inquiries ; from difficulties vainly curious, and doubts
                                impossible to be solved. Let me rejoice in the light thou hast imparted: let me serve
                                thee with active zeal and humble confidence; and wait with patient expectation for the
                                time in which the soul which thou receivest shall be satisfied with knowledge. Grant
                                this, O Lord, for Jesus Christ's sake. Amen.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A busy broker's battle with lunch" TEIform="index"/> A BUSY BROKER'S BATTLE WITH LUNCH</head><p TEIform="p"> For quick eating go down into the Wall street neighborhood, is the advice of the
                                experienced scribe of the Pittsburg Commercial-Gazette. The busy brokers don't waste
                                minutes over their mid-day bites That was why an exception excited my interest. I saw an
                                unusually hurried stock gambler in Delmonico's down town restaurant. He sat at a small
                                table on which were a mutton chop, fried potatoes, bread and butter and a glass of ale,
                                altogether making a meal of moderate size. His watch lay beside his plate with the case
                                open, and he glanced at its face between mouthfuls, and yet, instead of hurrying he was
                                eating with unusual deliberation, though his anxious regard for the flight of time was
                                plain to be seen. "I am not trying to eat fast," he explained, stopping and leaning
                                back. "I am trying to do it slowly. My best record for a lunch of this size is six
                                minutes. I was proud of it. I could pop out of my office, fill up, and be back at my
                                desk inside of a quarter of an hour; but just as I got my system trained down to that
                                point my doctor said I had got to throw away the profits of my skill or get measured for
                                my coffin. You see this hurried why of eating brought on indigestion, and he ordered me
                                to spend half an hour every day over my lunch. I sat down here at 12.20 and I musn't get
                                up until 12.50. A great waste of time, isn't it? But it is a choice for me between time
                                and eternity, and I am not ready for the latter yet."</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="This life is what we make it" TEIform="index"/> THIS LIFE IS WHAT WE MAKE IT</head><p TEIform="p"> Let's oftener talk of noble deeds, And rarer of the bad ones, And sing about our happy
                                days, And none about the sad ones. We were not made to fret and sigh, And when grief
                                sleeps, to wake it; Bright Happiness is standing by— This life is what we make it. Let's
                                find the sunny side of men, Or be believers in it; A light there is in every soul That
                                takes the pains to win it. Oh ! there's a slumbering good in all, And we perchance may
                                wake it; Our hands contain the magic wand— This life is what we make it. Then here's to
                                those whose loving hearts Shed light and joy about them ! Thanks be to them for
                                countless gems We ne'er had known without them. Oh ! this should be a happy world To all
                                who may partake it; The fault's our own if it is not— This life is what we make it.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Quietude" TEIform="index"/> QUIETUDE</head><p TEIform="p"> Convene thyself to little space In this wide world of many, And quietly resume thy place
                                When once assigned to any. The deepest streams roll gently on, • Acid timely reach the
                                ocean ; While babbling brooks that leap and foam Oft spill their given </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div3><pb n="166" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="At the Annual Meeting of the New England Woman Suffrage Association..." TEIform="index"/>
                                At the Annual Meeting of the New England Woman Suffrage Association...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At the Annual Meeting of the New England Woman Suffrage Association held in Tremont
                                Temple, Boston, in Anniversary week, the following resolutions were adopted :— Resolved,
                                That we reaffirm the principle of representative government for all classes of citizens,
                                and demand its application to women. We arraign the political aristocracy of sex as
                                contrary to nature, reason, justice, expediency and common-sense; we denounce the double
                                standard of morals as at war with domestic purity and public virtue; and we pledge
                                ourselves to continued effort for the establishment of republican government and true
                                democracy in New England. Resolved, That an active Woman Suffrage Society in every New
                                England State is essential to the efficient prosecution of our movement, by circulating
                                petitions and appealing to the Legislatures. We congratulate Rhode Island and
                                Massachusetts upon the activity of their State Associations; we invite the State
                                Societies of Maine, New Hampshire and Connecticut to renewed effort ; and we especially
                                urge the formation of a State Society in Vermont as an important work for this
                                Association during the coming year. Resolved, That we welcome the "well descended"
                                Remonstrants as new and effective allies in our great work of arousing women to their
                                political duties ; we see in their recent expression of adverse political opinion an
                                indication of the increasing interest of women in public affairs, which is of the very
                                essence of suffrage ; and we regard their opposition as a powerful additional argument
                                for the suffrage which they deprecate. Resolved, That we respectfully invite the
                                opponents of Impartial Suffrage to meet us before the people in a free and full
                                discussion of this great question, and we request our executive committee to arrange for
                                such discussions whenever and wherever practicable. Resolved, That Woman Suffrage should
                                be made a political issue, irrespective of party lines, in the nomination and election
                                of legislators and governors, and that no antisuffrage candidate for these positions
                                shoul 1 ever again receive the votes of the Suffragists of New England. Resolved, Tllat
                                the recent movements by the governments of Canada and Italy to extend suffrage to women
                                is a subject of hearty congratulation. Resolved, That the good results of woman suffrage
                                wherever established, in the old world or in the new,—in England, Scotland, Holland, and
                                Wyoming, and in the School Suffrage of twelve States,—are the pledge and guaranty of its
                                final triumph everywhere. Resolved, That the Suffragists of each and every State in New
                                England should concentrate their labors upon securing full municipal suffrage for women,
                                and should use their most strenuous efforts to get such a law enacted by their coming
                                Legislature. </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trust" TEIform="index"/>TRUST
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Whatever we may store up, we should learn this one lesson—that of
                                        trust. If we commit ourselves to the heavenly Father, and then follow His
                                        leading all through life, knowing that we are safe in the arms of the Lord so
                                        that we can bid good-by to every anxiety, then we shall find this old saying
                                        come true, "As thy days, so shall thy strength be." If you are in trouble,
                                        remember the day is over at sundown, and remember the promise, "As thy day is,
                                        so shall thy strength be.' God will not give you grace for to-morrow until it
                                        comes. He will take care of you today, and you will know the sweetness of that
                                        hymn by Cardinal Newman : "Lead kindly light, amid the encircling gloom, Lead
                                        thou me on; The night is dark, and I am far from home, Lead thou me on; Keep
                                        thou my feet, I do not ask to see The distant scene—one step enough for me. "1
                                        was not ever thus, nor prayed that thou Should'st lead me on; I loved to choose
                                        and see my path, but now Lead thou me on. I loved the garish day, and spite of
                                        fears, Pride ruled my will; remember not past years. "So long thy power hath
                                        blessed me—sure it still Will lead me on, O'er moor and fen, o'er crag and
                                        torrent, till The night is gone, And with the morn, those angel faces smile
                                        Which I have loved long since, and lost awhile." The Lord add His blessing to
                                        the preaching of His Word.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selccted</bibl></cit></p></div3><pb n="167" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Purest Blessing" TEIform="index"/> PUREST BLESSING</head><p TEIform="p">Canterbury, N. H. 1. Shun the thorn and grow the flower, Speak no sentiment unkind; 2.
                                Let thy deeds like sunlight falling Where the shadows often stray, 3. Best, amid the
                                pearls that glitter, In the victor's diadem, Let thy life like balmy showers, Give sweet
                                fragrance to the mind. And thy voice in loving accents Cheer the weary o'er life's way!
                                Is the one of purest water-----Love—the brilliant, sparkling gem! For with We are This
                                the days so swiftly passing, Friends may go and come no more; all so prone to error,
                                Gifts of love and gospel care halo of our Savior, This the glory of his strife, Let them
                                bear thy purest blessing,—Giving but refills thy store. Are the sweetest joys that
                                mingle With our battle and our prayer. Let us weave its radiant brightness In the fabric
                                of our life.</p></div3></div2><pb n="168" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Homiletic monthly" TEIform="index"/>The Homiletic Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Homiletic Monthly for June presents its readers with thirteen sermons and outlines
                                under the head of "Sermonic." The foreign preachers are Dr. K. F. A. Kahnis, of Leipzig
                                (translator from the German,) C»non Boyd Carpenter, and Mr. Spurgeou of London; the
                                American pulpit is well represented by Drs. Duryea, Cuyler, Howard, Talmage, and by
                                Revs. Mr. Beecher, Wm. V. Kelley, E. C. Ray, J. K. Folwell, and others. Among the fresh
                                things may be noticed the opinions of Drs. Talmage, H. S. Van Dyke and Chas. S. Robinson
                                on the Use of Manuscript in Preaching; some suggestions by Dr. Schafl" on the Homiletic
                                Value of the Revised Testament, and an article by Dr. D. II. Wheeler on the psychologic
                                explanation of "Faith Cures." The Commentary on James is continued by Dr. Ormiston, and
                                is a very thorough piece of work. The Editorial departments are full of suggestions and
                                helps for Preachers and other Bible Students.—$2.50 a year, 25 cents a single copy. Funk
                                &amp; Wagnalls, 10 and 12 Dey Street, New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ancient classics for English readers" TEIform="index"/>Ancient classics for English readers
                            </head><p TEIform="p">classics ton This is the title of a
                                unique and really delightful series of books, the first volume of which, "The
                                Commentaries of CsBsar," by Anthony Trollope, is just issued. The aim of the series is
                                to open to the unlearned English reader the beauties and treasures of classic lore, tell
                                who the writers were, gives some connected out.ine of the story they narrate, present
                                some of their most striking passages in choice English translation, and illustrate them
                                with the wealth of modern scholarship. There are 27 volumes in all, and heretofore they
                                have cost $1.00 each. They are publishing in The Elzevir Library, in really charming
                                style, at 15 cents each for binding, or 30 cents for cloth binding. "Herodotus," by
                                George C. Swayne; "Cicero," by W, L. Collins, and "Demosthenes," by W. J. Brodribb, arc
                                announced for immediate issue, and the other volumes are to follow, one or more each
                                week, until the series is complete. From even these marvelously low prices large
                                discounts are ottered to clubs and for prompt orders. John B. Alden, Publisher, 18 Vesey
                                St., New York </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Phrenological Journal and Science of Health, June; Contents ; Peter Cooper, with
                                portrait, Studies in Comparative Phrenology, Development of Musical Instruments,
                                Self-Esteem, James B. Eads, with portrait, Experiments in Psychology, Position in
                                Society, Political Economy, Causes of Malarial Diseases, Kitchen Leaflets, Notes in
                                Science, Editorial, Wisdom, Mirth, etc, etc. Fowler and Wells, 733 Broadway, N. Y.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Waste no vain words on the past..." TEIform="index"/>Waste no vain words on the past...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Waste no vain words on the past; spare them for the future. He is rich enough who has
                            wherewithal to be charitable.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Letters" TEIform="index"/> Kind Words for the Year 1883.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Shaker Manifesto for Jan has among its articles..." TEIform="index"/>
                                The Shaker Manifesto for Jan has among its articles...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> [From the Church Union.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Jan. 1883. The Shaker Manifesto for Jan has among its articles one containing
                                        "nine rules for right living," which should be framed and kept in plain sight.
                                        The little monthly should be a visitor in every home.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Church union" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Definition of Bible terms" TEIform="index"/> DEFINITION OF BIBLE TERMS</head><p TEIform="p"> A days journey was thirty-three and onefifth miles. A Sabbath day's journey was about an
                            English mile. Ezekiel's reed was eleven feet, nearly. A cubit is twenty-two inches, nearly.
                            A hand's breadth is equal to three and fiveeighth inches. A finger's breadth is equal to one
                            inch. A shekel of silver was about fifty cents. A shekel of gold was $8.09. A talent of
                            silver was $538.82. A talent of gold was $13,809. A piece of silver, or a penny, was
                            thirteen cents. A farthing was three cents. A gerah was one cent. A mite was one cent. An
                            epha, or bath, contains seven gallons and five pints. A hin was one gallon and two pints. A
                            firkin was seven pints. An omer was six pints. A cab was three pints. Household.
                            "Self-inspection is the only means to preserve us from self-conceit." Benjamin H. Shannon,
                            May 13, at Shakers, Ohio. Age 63 yrs. Omar Pease, May 16, at Enfield, Conn. Age 67 yrs. 7
                            mo. and 7 days. Sally Kelly, June 7, at Canterbury, N. H. Age 84 yrs. 8 mo. 27 days.</p></div2><!--
                        <pb id="p29"/>
<div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]<pb id="p30"/>
                            <pb id="p31"/>
                            <pb id="p32"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>