<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1107" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><date value="18810701" TEIform="date">July 1881</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">145- 168</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--                 <pb id="p1"/>
                                        <p>MANIFESTO. G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, N. Y. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT SHAKERS. N. Y. "And
                        they shall turn to you for a testimony: '* "Go preach the Kingdom of God!" ADDKESS ALL COMMUNICATIONS TO 'The Shaker
                        Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. . 1881. Vol. XI. No. 7. July, 1881. 60 Cents Per Annum. The Shaker</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="145" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Zodiacal constellations" TEIform="index"/>THE ZODIACAL CONSTELLATIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/>LUCY S. BOWERS</byline><p TEIform="p">The sun and the stars move on in their course, Nor fail the full race to pursue; And give
                            unto all of their undimming light, And beauty which ever seems new. With knowledge acute of
                            their mystical ways, The astronomer follows them still, As on through the depths of the
                            twilight they go, Their mission of years to fulfill. The ancients of yore on the Chaldean
                            plains, Watched nightly the stars in their train— As earth rolling over retreated from
                            light, While they glittered, again and again. Their clusterings appeared to their fancy or
                            mind, To measure the lapse of earth's time, And each constellation full well symbolized, The
                            season through which they might shine. Their harvest, their winter, and spring time were all
                            Made known by the signs in the sky ; Which rising aloft in the orient light, Would set when
                            their season passed by. * * * * The Sun enters Aris, the Ram of the sky, 'Mid frost, and mid
                            storms that are cold; But the Spring, Equinox in its vernal array, Is the glory it seeks to
                            unfold. Bright April approaching, with Taurus to reign, Replenished is earth at its dawn :
                            The steer, and the hind, and blossom appear, Held sacred in days that are gone. The world
                            turneth o'er, and the sunmoveth on, Until Gemini brilliantly shines; Then superabundantly
                            treasures are given, And rich are their varied designs. 'Neath Cancer we live, in delights
                            that will pass In beauties known only to June ; But the Crab moving back continues the
                            round, Though this solstice comes always too soon. Now thirsty and panting with fever an^
                            heat, The Lion, his jungles will leave; And forth to the banks ef the river doth go, Of
                            water so sweet to receive. 'Tis thus represented, July cometh on, When Leo is fair just
                            above ;— The day-breeze is sultry the dew scarcely falls, But his reign we admire and love.
                            The Waterman comes with his measure of tears, And long does he give of his store, But
                            Aquarius i.pw in the oxidant sky Reminds that his reigning is o'er. And slowly the streams
                            now give of their life* For Pisces is bright in its dawn ; <pb n="146" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> Rich gifts
                            for sustaining1 the hungry, who Would have famished e'er winter had gone. Thus the Sun goeth
                            on in his unceasing round, And fair is his star-lighted way, Whose time the sidereal letters
                            record, And betoken the dawn of each day. So the scenes of the Zodiac, one after one,
                            Successive in beauty appear ; The subjects of interest, study and praise, As they teach us
                            their lessons of cheer. O Queen of the harvest so wealthy and fair What gleams lit thy
                            journey along, Thy golden array is a burden of worth And the sound of the reaper thy song.
                            Thus Virgo — the Virgin—shines brightly aloft, And calm is her lingering night, When fading
                            away in the distance afar, We instead view the Balance of light. 'Tis.Libra the giver of
                            justice unfeigned, Though divider of sunshine and shade Which measured to earth all alike
                            may observe, Equilibrium perfectly made. October adorned with rich clusters of fruit, Is
                            more lavish than temperate or wise, And the Scorpion soon of his bounty bereft, Kecedes at
                            the loss of his prize. The leaf gently falls and November near by, The rabbit his home must
                            inlay, For the Archer abroad tells this secret to all, Sagittarius is after his prey. The
                            Goat which ascends the high mountainous rocks, Is the emblem of Winter so drear, But the sun
                            climbing up from his solstice of ice, Makes Capricorn brightly appear. Explanation: To the
                            Egyptians, the stars as clustered together represented different productions of nature in
                            those seasons over which they seemed to preside. Thus the Spring signs, Aris.Taurus, Gemini
                            were distinguished for the production of such animals, as were held in the highest esteem.
                            The third month being the most abundant, was represented by Gemini. When the sun enters the
                            fourth sign, it retrogrades or begins to move toward the south pole, which motion is
                            represented by Cancer, the Crab, which often runs backward. The heat, which follows in the
                            next month, is denoted by the Lion, which at this season impelled by thirst leaves the
                            desert and visits the banks of the Nile; August or harvest time is characterized by a
                            Virgin, or female reaper, bearing an ear of corn. When the sun enters Libra the days and
                            nights are equal all over the world, and seems to observe an equilibrium, like a balance.
                            Autumn, which produces fruits, brings with it a variety of diseases; and this season is
                            denoted by the venomous Scorpion, which is thought to wound with its sting as it receded.
                            The fall of the leaf was the season for hunting ; which is represented by a huntsman or
                            Archer. The Goat, which delights in clambering, is the emblem of the Winter solstice, when
                            the sun begins to ascend from the southern tropic. Aquarius is represented by the figure of
                            a man po uring out water from an urn,an emblem of the watery or uncomfortable season of
                            Winter. The Fish, the twelfth or last sign, denotes the fishing season; the severity of the
                            season being over, and the flocks not affording sustenance, the seas and rivers were then
                            opened and abounded with fish. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brooke-farm community" TEIform="index"/>BROOK-FARM COMMUNITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER</byline><p TEIform="p"> On the death of George Ripley, founder of the " Brook Farm Community," the London Standard
                            discourses thus: "To those whose memory extends back forty years the death of George Ripley
                            will recall the famous experiment with which his name will ever be connected. We refer to
                            the Brook Farm Community. It was a socialist attempt to make the world better." A commune,
                            that numbered among its members Emerson, Thoreau, Hawthorne and Margaret Fuller, could
                            scarcely fail to leave its mark. Of the cultivated men and women who took part in it, nearly
                            all are dead. George was the soul of the enterprise, into which he cast a fortune which
                            would have saved him from a life of toil its loss entailed. This commune was a gathering of
                            great- <pb n="147" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. 14? hearted Idealists, full of life and
                            enthusiasm. After studying a few notices of their life which the members have placed on
                            record, the reader is inclined to believe that the Brook farmers looked on the whole affair
                            as if a communal life was a prolonged picnic, with some philosophy to sublimate the
                            earthliness of plowing fields and milking cows. Brook Farm was an innocent community ; every
                            one did as seemed right in his or her eyes, yet the breath of scandal never touched George
                            Ripley's community. About the year 1840 was a time of peace, and there was a kind of ferment
                            heating up the Old world and the New. The Americans had got over their first bursts of
                            patriotic ardor, and were discovering that life ought not to be wholly spent in pursuit of
                            individual interests. With them socialistic experiments took root early and succeeded best.
                            But Idealists who expected to find in the model republic the best of all possible
                            governments were disappointed at rinding one not much better than that from which they had
                            fled. The reaction naturally landed them in researches after higher forms of social life.
                            The people were growing dissatisfied, and they began to dream dreams, and seek out seers ;
                            and for the time being, the thoughtful theorist was expatiating on the Essenes, and the
                            Therapeutic, the Shaking Quakers, Plato's Republic, and Moore's Utopia. Brook Farm was a
                            pleasant enough affair. The members chopped wood and talked of the infinite; peeled apples
                            and reconstructed the universe ; and as Hawthorne expressed, " felt they were leading a
                            righteous and Heaven-blessed way of life." Before breakfast he chopped hay for the cattle,
                            brought wood and replenished the fires, and then went down and ate a huge mound of buckwheat
                            cakes. After breakfast George Ripley, himself, and another member armed with four pronged
                            tools made a gallant attack on a heap of manure. The novelist jocularly intimates '' that
                            after this hard work and plain fare, that he felt the original Adam reviving within him." A
                            life of labor for the good of the community at first had its charms, but when the novelty
                            wore away, the socialistic enthusiasm also evaporated. Of course the " Brook Farm " failed,
                            its theory was excellent, too good for the nineteenth century. Its founders were noble men
                            and women, but they left out of account that important factor '' Human nature." They indeed
                            tried to live a better life, ahd to return to a simpler state of society, which they fondly
                            fancied to be that of the " natural man." But the melancholy truth is, " the natural man "
                            does not love his brother — he eats him. (Hence) George Ripley and his faithful followers
                            went forth into a stormy, jeering world, poor, sorrowful, but unconvinced. In the Brook Farm
                            Community we find two forces in operation — one that formed it, and another which destroyed
                            it. Do these opposite forces inhere in man ? If they do, then man can create communities,
                            and also destroy them, whenever he wills to do so. On looking into man, we find, that he in
                            common with all animals has an emotional life represented by the propensities. And that he
                            has also an emotional life represented by manifestations of justice, benevolence, mercy and
                            aspirations after, and a growth into these divine attributes. Of this dual emotional life,
                            the Apostle remarked : " I feel a law, a force in my members, warring against the law of my
                            mind, etc." All human manifestations refer themselves to these laws ; whether they create a
                            community having goods in common, or destroy such an order of things, whether they bring
                            forth peace on earth, or war with all its horrors. Man creates his own social conditions,
                            and is the subject of the inspirations he yields himself to obey. At present, the
                            preponderance of the animal in man renders the formation of communities having goods in
                            common all but impossible. Even those who yield themselves to obey the inspirations of the
                            higher law will from time to time — as Hawthorne did —" feel the old Adam reviving within
                            them." Therefore, those who will be the disciples of the Divine Teacher will have to do as
                            the '' Master " did and as Paul did — bear a daily cross, otherwise there can be no
                            releasement from the bondage of the propensities, and the social conditions incident
                            thereto. <pb n="148" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 148 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Man stands between the heavens and
                            the Hells If he wills to have the help of the former, he will have to be an earnest worker,
                            and work up hill all the time. The law of the life of the propensities is, " The love of
                            self at the expense of others." The law of the higher life, " is the love of others, at the
                            expense of self." The latter law, when in operation, creates communities having goods in
                            common; when they fail it is because the former law prevails. The mystery of living the
                            higher — the divine — life while on earth ishere unfolded: The higher law does not
                            manufacture communal life out of the earthly one, nor from its conditions; but creates all
                            things anew according to the law of the higher emotional life in man. Fulfilling that
                            remarkable prophecy—-Jer. 51, 21, etc.: '• That not a stone for a foundation nor for a
                            corner could be accepted from the lower life, in rearing the social structures appropriate
                            to the higher one." The correspondent of the Standard states: " Man does not love his
                            brother — he eats him." Is this not true politically ? And under the competitive system do
                            not men swallow one another up? Is not commercial cannibalism a leading force in all the
                            cities of Christendom ? The unrestrained action of the propensities from the eating of huge
                            mounds of buckwheat cakes to the criminal extravagances of Delmonico's, the absorbing
                            speculations of the merchant, and the exploits of the warrior, are at variance with the
                            beneficent procedure of communal life. A community, to be alive and growing, must be
                            beneficent. If it cares but for itself, it will die. There is nothing that arrests the
                            action of the higher life among men, and so destructive of personal and social progress as
                            is war. Under its power men become demoniacal machines — give themselves up body and soul
                            for destructive purposes. It seems that the morality of individuals and of nations was based
                            only on their ability to conquer, hold and monopolize land, and hence, to vitiate the
                            conditions of human equality — creating classes and castes among men. The writer lately had
                            a visit with one of the survivors of the Brook Farm Community. It was refreshing to hear the
                            testimony : " that George Ripley and his companions sought the elevation of the lowly, and
                            that social privileges and distinctions were alike open to all." All honor to the Brook Farm
                            Communists whether in the land of souls, or still in the body. They honored themselves,
                            Massachusetts and humanity. Happy day, when men and women will fulfill all righteousness,
                            while doing '' that which is right in their own eyes." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pride" TEIform="index"/>PRIDE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p"> There is much truth contained in the proverb that " pride goeth before destruction and a
                            haughty spirit before a fall;" and also that '' pride and anger were not made for man." The
                            question has been asked, and with much propriety: Why should mortal man be proud ? What does
                            he possess that he has not received from sources outside of and beyond himself? When we view
                            the helpless infant rocked in the cradle, or folded in its mother's arms, and see how it
                            requires assistance every hour, its very life depending upon aid thus rendered, we are
                            forced to acknowledge the indebtedness due to those who tenderly nurture and care for us
                            through all the infantile years. As time rolls on, physical strength increases, thoughts
                            mature and expand, and the care of parents and guardians grows less, until we conclude to
                            venture out upon the sea of life for ourselves, in a vessel of our own choosing — if
                            circumstances will permit —and sail upon smooth waters when we can, and toss upon the
                            rolling billows when we must, and breast the fierce winds and rude storms as best we may,
                            while steer ing for the port we have set out to gain. Whatever our aspirations may be, and
                            whichever way we bend our course, we are dependent upon the forces of nature or providence
                            to aid and direct, without which our own efforts would be ineffectual. Unaided human effort
                            cannot effect much, <pb n="149" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 149 but co-operative action
                            with seen and unseen forces, when in harmony with written and unwritten laws, are oftentimes
                            marvelous in results ; success or failure is largely due to relations thus sustained. If the
                            fullest success attend us in our life pursuits, still, of what shall we boast? Or why should
                            we be proud or lifted up ? We cannot say to this agency or that, I have no need of thee.
                            Philosophers, astronomers and geologists, together with wealth and pleasure-seekers, have
                            had pioneers who preceded them, and have their compeers at the present time. If modern
                            science, through various instrumentalities, has produced improved methods of attaining
                            desired results, in the study of the stellar regions or in the accumulation of knowledge and
                            wealth by analysis of minerals and soils, it, is the product of many minds, and of
                            persistent and persevering effort; but, if such attainments are applied to the earth life
                            only, they are of short du ration as far as individuals are concerned, for, as has been
                            truthfully said, " it is, seemingly, but a step from the cradle to the grave." If the desire
                            of the heart be unselfish, and the ruling purpose of our life work is directed to benefit
                            humanity and to leave the world wiser, richer and better for our sojourn in it, then our
                            existence in therudimental sphere will prove a blessing, and will call forth gratitude free
                            from self-exaltation. If such be our aim, we shall be apt to make a clean record during our
                            pilgrimage here, and to gain a clear title to an inheritance in the world of realities
                            beyond. As we are perfectly dependent when we first open our eyes upon material objects in
                            the mundane sphere, so are we also helpless and dependent when we pass out of it into other
                            states of existence, and, without doubt, myriads of souls who pass out of this world, and
                            are born into spirit life, are as helpless as is the infant when ushered into being here,
                            and as ignorant of the laws which govern that land, and of the dwellers there, and will
                            require as much attention at the hands of nurturing,guiding and disciplinary paternity there
                            as here before they become sufficiently developed to act, with discretion, for themselves.
                            Ah! how little we know of the vast future, of its boundless stores of knowledge and wealth,
                            now hidden from our view, to be revealed in the fullness of time. How vague are our thoughts
                            and incomplete our understanding concerning the designs of the Creator in regard to the
                            worlds of mind and mat" ter revolving in unmeasured space! The more we realize this truth
                            the more we shall feel our inability to act independently and the less disposed to glory in
                            our own attainments, whether of greater or less magnitude. Pride, fostered in the human
                            heart, has decoyed and deceived many. One of the inspired prophets of olden time said: "
                            Though thou exaltest thyself as the eagle, and though thou makest thy nest among the stars,
                            thence will I bring thee down, saith the Lord." Righteousness exalteth individuals and
                            nations. When we launch our vessels upon time's broad ocean, should we unfurl truth's
                            banner, bearing the inscription " Honesty and Justice," and firmly resolve never to sail
                            under another ensign, we would find in the end that we had secured a name and place, better
                            and more enduring than any potentate of earth could give or receive, or that wealth could
                            procure. We should be carried above personal self-seeking and renown, and our highest
                            aspiration would be to honor God and benefit humanity, by first purifying our own hearts.
                            Then we could be instrumental in uplifting others to better conditions, and thus form
                            credentials worthy to be presented to the high courts in the spirit world, and to be stored
                            among the archives there.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Circumcision and beards" TEIform="index"/>CIRCUMCISION AND BEARDS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p"> In the primitive church, certain men taught the brethren : " Except ye be circumcised, ye
                            cannot be saved." Acts 15. Paul and Barnabas controverted this position. The result was, a
                            delegation of the disputants went up to .Jerusalem — to the church — to argue the case.
                            Speeches were delivered pro and con. The Jerusalem church was composed of Jews, who had ever
                            been taught, from their youth up, that circumcision was a seal of salvation, making a <pb n="150" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 350 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. distinction — a line of demarcation —
                            between the people of God and the "world of ungodly Gentiles. Probably there never was an
                            external rite that had more internal virtues attached to it. In truth, the Jew conceived it
                            as a separating act from the heathen or Gentile. Was it any wonder that the Apostles should
                            require Gentile converts to be circumcised, on pain of eternal damnation ? They made a
                            strong case ; but there was a stronger than they — a stronger power than they possessed.
                            Peter had been disciplined unto this very work. " When Peter was come up to Jerusalem, they
                            of the circumcision — Apostles and brethren — contended with him, saying, Thou wentest into
                            men uncircumcised and didst eat with them." Acts 11. Peter rehearsed the whole matter of his
                            vision, coincident with the vision of Cornelius — how angels brought them, Jew and Gentile,
                            together, when the Holy Ghost fell on them, as on us at the beginning ;" from which he thus
                            concluded : " Forasmuch, then, as God gave them the same gift as He did unto us, who believe
                            on the Lord Jesus Christ, what was I that I could withstand God ?" The Apostles and brethren
                            concluded: "Then hath God also to the Gentiles granted repentance unto life." Thus the point
                            was settled that the gospel was as free to Gentiles as to Jews. Gentiles could be saved, but
                            on what conditions, was the question nest in order? The disciples, who had been Pharisees,
                            said, the Gentiles must first become Jews in order to become Christians — they must be
                            circumcised or they could not be saved. It was by facts, not words nor desires, that the
                            first point had been settled. The Gentiles, while in uncircumcised condition, were blessed
                            of God — received spiritual gifts, just as did those who had been circumcised— the Holy
                            Ghost making no distinction between them on that account. It decided that circumcision or
                            uncircumcision was nothing but a new life—change of character. How this decision came across
                            the life-long habits of thought of the Apostles and brethren — the church — we can easily
                            imagine, by what is transpiring in our own day, subject to our own observation. We have
                            Jerusalem churches in all our societies of Shakers, composed of apostles and brethren, who
                            have, like the Jerusalem church, borne the burden and heat of the day. They shaved while in
                            the world, before the gospel reached them, just as they used alcoholic drinks, ate pork,
                            smoked and chewed tobacco, and did many other things not now allowableThese habits became,
                            to them, sanctified, by being incorporated with true gospel faith and practice. At this
                            time, when persons ' are being called into the gospel who do not choose to shave — did not
                            shave while in the world, but who are good believers in all things else, the question comes
                            up, Can they be saved except they shave ? This is the question that conscientious novitiate
                            elders and brethren of the gathering families are sending up to the churches — the old
                            believers— to settle. As in the other case, in the primitive church, God has settled it
                            before and for them, the Holy Ghost having been just as free to give gifts to the unshaved
                            as to the shaved. In all things they have been, and are, approved by the powers of the world
                            to come. Will not the shaving believers call to mind the words of Peter : " What was I that
                            I should withstand God ?" In the most serious political situation of our country — the
                            choice of a chief magistrate — if the nation be saved from anarchy and confusion, resulting
                            from the strife of parties for the offices — pre-eminence — it will be by leading minds in
                            the losing party rising superior to party selfishness and private ambition, and uniting with
                            the winning party, upon statesman-like principles, to build up the government, as conserving
                            the good which has been gradually accumulating for generations past, through the labors and
                            sufferings of patriots, humanitarians and true reformers. Such men may be republicans or
                            democrats, but, above all, they are American citizens, seeking thewel fare of the human race
                            by working out a perfect civil government on this continent. How much union there is in this
                            object may be seen by comparing the platforms of principles and measures issued by
                            republicans and democrats before the election. They were well-nigh identical. It is doubtful
                            whether the sovereign people could tell, at the end of four years, which had been their
                            chief <pb n="151" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 151 magistrate, a republican or a
                            democrat, if the name could be concealed. It is a strife between tlie ins and outs, clean
                            cut "Let us have peace and a President!" is the people's cry, March 1st, "no new election,
                            no delay, no filibustering to gratify partisan feeling or personal jealousy and revenge, for
                            men who will thus act have no business in Washington as legislators." Judgment begins at the
                            house of God. If the people of God, unto whom Christ has appeared a second time, without
                            sin, unto salvation, cannot increase with the increase of God from faith to faith, through
                            the seven travels by which they, being Gentiles by descent, habit and thought, shall
                            progress up out of the labyrinth of error — the corruptions that are in the world through
                            the lusts of generation, of property and digestion — to the law that in itself, when
                            divested of traditions, comments and interpretations, is pure and holy, so much so that
                            heaven and earth would both pass away and be no more, as easy and as certain as the law upon
                            which they rest could pass away. The natural comes first. Unless we do right in food,
                            generation and property, there is no use multiplying wards about salvation in this world or
                            any other. The marriage of the lamb and bride means a union of the law and gospel — this,
                            and nothing else. Certainly it was not the marriage of Jesus and Ann, according to our first
                            childish thoughts, as first cycle theologians. The Gentiles, as such, have in them the seven
                            plagues, or forms of evil, that are to be revealed by light and removed by power in the
                            seven travels of the church — the seven cycles of John the Revelator. The Gentile
                            mother-church must be clothed in fine linen — in garments of needlework, in wrought gold —
                            great persistent labor and toil — in the physiological righteousness of Jewish saints. All
                            the conservatism of human nature, as exhibited in the ante-diluvians, in the Egyptians, in
                            stiff-necked, rebellious Israel, in the Jews who stoned the prophets and killed those whom
                            the Christ Spirit had sent unto them, who crucified Jesus before and after He left the body,
                            put to cruel deaths all the twelve Apostles, inaugurated a century of martyrdoms, followed
                            the two witnesses for twelve hundred and sixty years, until Ann Lee arose, a mother in
                            Israel, and a civil government was established that bound the dragon of church and State, by
                            separating civil and ecclesiastical governments — all that conservatism is in the present
                            people of God, the Shakers. They must be overcomers in all these respects, as none before
                            them have been — must be baptized into the spirit of truth as to rise above educational
                            prejudice and prepossessions, personal, petty jealousies and self-seeking gratifications of
                            the physical senses, or of the mind — must have God in all their thoughts until salvation be
                            their song and progressive redemption their life-long desire and effort, being circumcised
                            in heart and spirit, cut off from the earth, knowing no man nor woman after the flesh, all
                            things being created anew and all things of God. Would not such souls cease to mutilate
                            them, cease to shave, as the Jewish converts ceased to mutilate each other, by ceasing to
                            teach, preach or practice circumcision ? Is not the habit of shaving as truly a bodily
                            mutilation, as being made eunuchs of men ? And as an unphysiological, disease-producing
                            practice, is it not more dangerous, and far more revolting to the outward sight of normal
                            Jews, than was circumcision ? ADDENDA: First Pentecostal,Church. This church, being composed
                            of Jews, assumed that Gentiles had no part nor lot in the matter — could not become
                            Christians. After the Holy Spirit decided otherwise, and convinced, first, Peter, then the
                            whole Jerusalem church, that Gentiles could become good Christians, the same as Jews, the
                            second idea was, that Gentiles could not become Christians unless they were circumcised, the
                            Jewish converts not perceiving that circumcision was but an external rite, pointing toward a
                            life of Christian celibacy, and that when the substance had come the type was used up. The
                            Holy Spirit and church at Jerusalem decided that Gentiles need not be circumcised. Second
                            Pentecostal Chtikcii. This, being composed of Gentiles, who <pb n="152" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 152 THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. had been accustomed to shaving as the Jews had been accustomed to
                            circumcision, decided at first that Jewish converts must be shaved or they could not be
                            taken into union. Have not the Holy Spirit and this Gentile church as good a right to revoke
                            that decision as the Holy Spirit and Jerusalem church had to change from the first idea —
                            that Gentiles could not be saved at all — and the second idea — that, if saved, they must be
                            circumcised ?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Discipline" TEIform="index"/>DISCIPLINE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Covet thou the holy spirit of discipline ; that which controls the thoughts, directs the
                            motives, bridles the tongue, veils the eyes, sets a seal upon the lips, reins the emotions,
                            subdues the passions, guards the morals, c orrects the habits, governs the appetites, graces
                            the carriage, lightens the footsteps,re fines the manners, softens the language, chastens
                            the loves, quickens the Kpirit, expands the soul, moulds the intellect, and inspires to ever
                            increasing goodness. Thus shalt thou through the perfective grace of Wisdom, be transformed
                            from the animal and earthly into the divine likeness of thy heavenly Father and Mother. ML
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Flattery" TEIform="index"/>FLATTERY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p"> Beware of the flatterer's wiles! Many an innocent and confiding person has been drawn from
                            the path of rectitude and virtue by the bland smiles and words of seductive flattery. " How
                            handsome are your gaudy wings, how brilliant are your eyes," said the artful spider to the
                            foolish fly, he was trying to ensnare. In that little fable lies a good moral which all
                            young people would do well to heed. Flattery, like a cunning serpent, is as sure to sting as
                            charm, they who carry it on their lips, bear the invective in their hearts. The fawning
                            sycophant always proves the betrayer of confidence, love and trust, and should be shunned by
                            all who would sacredly guard their virtue and honor. Vain adulation stimulates vanity and
                            self-love. The person who is marked as the central attraction in society, and becomes the
                            main object of blandishment and praise, often proves a most disagreeable and unlovely member
                            of the household ; because human nature, nurtured in the unreal and superficial1, rises
                            above just and honest criticism of actual faults which exist in the character, despite
                            external charms ; and the reproof of genuine friendship is too often resented with contempt
                            and sullen anger. "Praised abroad and scolded at home," retorted an indolent beauty, whose
                            young life poured out on the stream of folly, lashion and dissipation, overleaped the curb
                            and restraint of parental reproof. But, are not parents often the most to blame? The child
                            is petted and pampered in self-will; pride and vanity is cultivated in the extreme gaiety of
                            attire. And surrounding friends, anxious to court favor, bestow undue praise on the young
                            aspirant, whose own precocious nature needs but a spark to fan the flame that shall consume
                            every particle of modesty and virtue, that might, under other circumstances, be unfolded in
                            real beauty and worth. " There is no faithfulness in him who useth the tongue of flattery."
                            The honest man and woman choose not vain words to vindicate their friendship. The "truth
                            revealed in their inward parts," comes forth in plainness of speech ; such stand upon the
                            solid ground of unimpeachable integrity. They do not always please, but ever prove the best
                            and truest friends in adversity, as well as prosperity The scriptures abound with moral
                            instruction concerning the evil effect of flattery,as well as the good effects of reproof,
                            when it is accepted in the right spirit. It would be well for the young to turn their active
                            minds and unfolding faculties in right channels of thought. To search out the words of
                            wisdom and truth, given for guidance and direction in paths of wisdom, peace and abiding
                            happiness, leaving forever all frivolous, foolish thoughts and imaginations of fleeting
                            evanescent life, for things real and substantial, and strive earnestly to culti-f <pb n="153" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 153 vate these principles that shall form a
                            character embodying truth, sincerity and uprightness of purpose and action.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Government" TEIform="index"/>GOVERNMENT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/>CATHARINE ALLEN</byline><p TEIform="p"> A central intelligence and governing force act upon every fibre of the universe, through
                            laws adapted to its varied departments. The lower strata of material existence are subject
                            to compulsive forces, which continually operate to bring forth order from chaos. Without
                            government there can be no organization ; this is demonstrated even in the insect creation,
                            of which the ant and bee are wonderful examples. As higher developments have appeared, and
                            intelligence has increased, instinct has given place to reason, compulsion to free agency.
                            As population has multiplied in different sections of country, and human beings have been
                            brought nearer together in social relations, the greater has been the necessity of
                            self-government, as well as for definite leadership and authority to prevent encroachments
                            upon the rights of others. This authority, whether administered in despotic, theocratic,
                            democratic or republican forms of government, has usually been a reflex of the theological
                            views entertained; for the theology of a people bears the most potent influence in shaping
                            the systems and customs of society. This has been especially the case in those countries
                            where the civil laws and those pertaining to every department of life have been included in
                            the sacred books; and where entire executive authority has been vested in the priesthood.
                            The justice of such governments has been particularly dependent upon the conceptions of
                            Deity then entertained; and the progress of nations thus confined has necessarily been much
                            slower than in those where the civil laws have been left free to adapt themselves to the
                            ever expanding needs of society. But however free the civil polity is from ecclesiastical
                            rule, it will ever be an index of the religious sentiments as well as of the social and
                            intellectual standing of the people. Therefore civil governments can only advance with the
                            growth of humanity toward the Great Soul of Justice and Love. All law is absolute, universal
                            and eternal. Any thing framed by the ingeuuity of man that cannot meet response from the
                            higher sentiments of his fellow man will sooner or later perish, for the "government must
                            rest upon the consent of the governed," no other basis can be enduring. History repeats
                            again and again the story of despotic reign, which, like a house divided against itself,
                            ends in anarchy and destruction; proving that the laws of justice are stronger than mighty
                            armies, and that the fires of immortal liberty will continue to burn deeper in the soil of
                            humanity, till, bursting in volcanic grandeur, the mountains of kingly rule and of all
                            usurped power shall be leveled, upfilling the valleys of oppression and suffering. A true
                            government will provide equally for all its subjects ; this can never be done until the land
                            is caused to become a birthright inheritance, as are the sunlight and air ; for " just in
                            proportion as land becomes property " the cry for bread will be heard from the oppressed.
                            Wealth and pauperism, class and caste. Continual strife between capital and labor,
                            ignorance, war and crime of every nature, are inevitable results of all systems of monopoly.
                            This is recognized by many ; but, where is the remedy ? Philanthropists, socialists and
                            statesmen of the highest intellectual genius, all fail to find it. But, let man look
                            downward through the kingdoms of nature, and learn that it is the dual forces, male and
                            female, which there preserve order and harmony. Let him look upward to the planetary
                            systems, and observe the same fact; thus through outward nature, and through his own
                            affections, learn that God, the great ruler and governor of all, is father and mother, Then
                            let him strive to imitate the pattern set in the heavens, in the framing of earthly
                            institutions, and he will find that the same parental government there applied will be
                            productive of harmony, peace and prosperity. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="154" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soul travel" TEIform="index"/>SOUL TRAVEL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, O." TEIform="persName"/>O. PRENTISS</byline><p TEIform="p"> Sublime ideas are wrapped up in tins adjective and noun. When soul takes its mortality along
                            it is rather a slow coach. Steamboats and railroads are decided improvements upon former
                            editions. Leaving mortality behind, we occasionally make soul excursions in worlds that will
                            shortly be ours. There we meet with friends, who are wholly liberated from mortality incum.
                            brance, and we actualize, for the time being, one of the items of the creed of our early
                            childhood, "The Communion of Saints." In mortality or out we are never alone. Congeniality's
                            unerring law draws kindred minds together, irrespective of mortality. Who would have good
                            society, let him and her be good. We are enshrined in mortality for educational purposes.
                            This is our seminary. If we graduate, it is well; if not, all is not lost. A penitentiary
                            awaits us, in the next world, where, like the Nazarene, we may " learn obedience by the
                            things we suffer." To attain sublimest elevations—-society of transparent seraphim and
                            cherubim —neither time nor opportunity may be lost. By indomitable self-control, native
                            innocence must be retained unmarred.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whenever you see a wrong deed and have the courage to say..." TEIform="index"/>Whenever you see a wrong deed and have the courage to say...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Farrar, Canon" TEIform="persName"/>Canon Farrar</byline><p TEIform="p">, in closing his sermon at St. Margaret's, Westminster, on a recent Sunday, said : " Whenever
                            you see a wrong deed and have the courage to say, ' It is wrong, and I, for one, will have
                            nothing to do with it;' whenever you come in contact with a low and unchristian standard, or
                            a bad, unworthy habit, and are man enough, first, to refuse to succumb to it, and then to do
                            your best to overthrow it, you are a prophet, and by acting thus you can help to improve the
                            moral judgment and raise the moral standard of the world. Your words and deeds will breathe
                            like fresh wind through the perfumed and polluted atmosphere of society. Be brave, be just,
                            be truthful and honest to the heart's core, and so serve your brother man, your Father God,
                            and your Saviour the Lord Christ. If the gospel be the example of Christ, this is the gospel
                            and nothing but the gospel."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Adamsville, May 28,1881" TEIform="index"/>Adamsville, May 28,1881</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Burrington, J. Warren" TEIform="persName"/>J. Warren Burrington</byline><p TEIform="p"> Adamsville, May 28,1881 Mr. F. W'Evans: Dear Sir:—Through the courtesy of Mr. Q. H.
                                Philips, I learn that your people have brought the culinary art — the selection of food
                                and preparation thereof--to a fine science. Being myself a sensitive,and having to adopt
                                rules different from the people around me in order to live at all (in the body), I would
                                like to get a little light on how your people prepare their food, and the kinds you use
                                in every-day life, for my own benefit and health. If not asking too much, would like to
                                have you write me whatever you feel disposed to concerning the matter. I eat no meats,
                                and find superfine flour injurious ; live principally on fruits and cereals ; find it
                                hard to get the whole grain and save the necessary chemicals — properties contained
                                therein. Now, if you will give me a little light on the choice of food and the
                                preparation for use, you will confer to me a great favor. Yours in spirit and in truth,
                                Adamsville, Franklin Co., Mass.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, June 5, 1881" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, June 5, 1881</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline><p TEIform="p"> Mt. Lebanon, June 5, 1881 J. Warren Burrington : Respected Friend:—Your letter of May 28
                                at hand. I am always pleased to meet people who have, at least, one idea of reform. In
                                the revelation of St. John, it is stated that the number of the beast was 666 — the
                                letters composing an evil to which humanity is subject. If there has to be that number
                                of reforms to redeem humanity, for each one we should be thankful. You have found a very
                                important reform. If true to it, it will lead you into all truth — all the re forms —
                                666. Moses taught physiology: " The Lord your God shall take all sickness away from the
                                midst of you." Jesus healed the sick, enjoining, "Go and sin no more." Ann Lee put the
                                axe to the root of disease,the king of evils ¦— prostitution of man's creative powers.
                                There is not among all the lusts of flesh and mind, one to be compared with the<pb n="155" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 155 sexual lust. Conquer that, and you need
                                not fear any of the crew of evils that curse the race. As cutting off a dog's head cures
                                him of sheep killing, so does the resurrection effected by the Christ Spirit cure
                                natural men and women of the lusts of body and mind. It kills them dead, and then raises
                                them up again. " I kill and I make alive —I wound and I heal." Except a man hate his own
                                (generative) life, he cannot have the life of Christ. This is Shakerism. It came first
                                to Gentiles, who previously had no reform in diet, generation, property or social
                                organization. The Jews possessed the most radical reform in all those departments: In
                                diet, manna/ in generation, sexual commerce once in three years to beget a child, then
                                three years before 'it was weaned, during which time entire abstinence was the rule; in
                                property, land, clothing,food,houses orients — in common. For forty years these
                                conditions existed among a million of people, more or less. The first step .the captive
                                Jews in Egypt took was to make unleavened bread — " Shem bread " — that would keep. It
                                was good wheat, mixed with water, baked so hard that they " break " it — hence "breaking
                                of bread." Can you break leavened bread composed of superfine vvheaten flour from the
                                Rochester Mills? No more than you could break paste. The teeth are not needed to eat
                                such bread. Dentists remove them as useless. Cows fed upon distilleryslops shed their
                                teeth as of no use in manufacturing milk from such materials. Soft food and ten minutes
                                to gulp it down makes modern Christians, who believe any thing the priest prepares, as
                                they eat what the cook concocts: A trinity, an atonement, resurrection of their physical
                                bodies, etc., etc.; that a king can do no wroug; that one man, like Joseph in Egypt, may
                                rightfully buy all the land of the nation ; that women are not citizens— have no rights
                                man is bound to respect — their mental and physical stomachs are like an India rubber
                                bag, or an omnibus, never full, and never digest what is put into it. The man who was
                                born all along shore and my instruction will be, to you, somewhat alike in definiteness
                                and concentration. At first, Wisdom leads her children by crooked ways and brings fear
                                and dread upon them, torments them with her discipline, and afflicts them with unwelcome
                                truths, until she has tried them by her laws and proved them by her injunctions and can
                                trust their souls; then she turns the straight way unto them, comforts them and shows
                                them her secrets. Seek first the kingdom of heaven, for which you have so long been
                                praying. It is somewhere upon the earth. When you find it seek its righteousness — not
                                any thing else — for the kingdom of heaven is as a net cast into the sea—good and bad
                                fish are in it — truth and error — right and wrong — chaff and wheat. Then shall they
                                return and discern between the precious and the vile—between him that serveth God and
                                him that serveth Him not. This will require thought, discrimination, understanding of
                                principles — Faith, Hope and Love. Respectfully,</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unchristian antagonisms" TEIform="index"/>UNCHRISTIAN ANTAGONISMS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We received, recently, a letter from a friend, from which we make the following extract:
                                "I subscribed for The Manifesto to learn of your principles. I have found much to
                                admire, and but little to object to. I, however, take strong objections to your doctrine
                                of Celibacy, as being at variance with nature, etc." Thus we have the repetition of the
                                same old, olden story. Preferences to remain on the lower, animal plane, are to be
                                regarded with a respect due their value. Desires and aspirations for a resurrection of
                                life, in this world, will at the same time be in order, and will command the respect of
                                those who plead against Celibacy as an unnatural observance — and a respect too, that
                                needs somewhat of repelling,<pb n="156" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 15G THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. else it
                                becomes adoration, for virgin Celibacy brings its own sufficient reward. Now we see
                                standing afar in the distance, not only individuals, but churches, who wish, that with
                                all the good and glory and worldly honor they have, that they might also have added-the
                                exceeding weight of glory of the "celibate for the kingdom of heaven's sake." It is
                                singular, yet easily apparent, that men and women single out this Christly practice to
                                abstain from it: They may abhor War, and love Peace; they may give abundantly to the
                                poor, even to stripping their own estates to a condition of pauperism for that purpose ;
                                they may shut themselves out from mingling with the busy, worldly, political world in
                                order the better to imitate the beautiful master and exampler, Christ; but they cannot
                                afford to forego the pleasures of the licenses of marriage, and all the indulgences
                                which the marital rite covers, antagonistic to genuine, radical Christianity. From our
                                friend's letter we quote further: " I find but very few churches or individuals who are
                                willing, and do take Jesus Christ as an example for their life in this world, believing
                                it to be inexpedient." Hence, the decline of Christianity in its pristine glory! Truly,
                                very few are willing, however "able," to submit to the eunuchizing process recommended
                                by the Christ for all " who are able." The sum is this: Those who arc able to follow
                                Christ, as Christ lived in Celibacy, and who do so willingly, will have the simple, but
                                rich rewards which such a life will bear, without Fail; and such rewards are envied by
                                the same unwilling, antagonistic enemies to the true Christ life. Now, the questions to
                                all desiring to bo genuine Christian communicants are, " Are you able to accept and live
                                Christ's lifer "Are you willing to do so? " Upon this ability or non-ability,
                                willingness or unwillingness depends immortal results. What though "but few " are found
                                who will live Christ! This is the worldly apology for living unchristly.—" I do not want
                                to appear odd in the world — not only that but I like the present effects of a worldly
                                life!" As before, the world is ready for a change from war to more peaceful relations;
                                ready for a more humanitarian, communistic relation among fellow men ; ready for less
                                worldliness in every other respect, barring the pleasures of the flesh. There are
                                springing up in New York city, and elsewhere, societies and secret organizations for the
                                expulsion from the wearing apparel, of the entire households of all gold, pearl, and
                                glittering ornaments. Pkidb gets a clubbing, and we hope, to its destruction, apparent
                                to those who will not to destroy it. Everywhere, among all Christians, so-called
                                denominations, are seen, and heard, and felt the benign influences of peace—in direct
                                opposition to the introduction of wae, by Constantine, as a proselyting method. Hope
                                wafts triumphantly in this. Intemperance— than which there can be no greater bane to
                                Christian influences—is receiving attention, although as yet undue attention, from its
                                special advocates. Just here let it be understood that In temperance can never be
                                suppressed; but it can be supplanted by the general <pb n="157" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. 157 principles of self-denial, which are largely covered by a Celibate life.
                                Whoever lives a celibate life, must, not simply will, be very temperate in eating,
                                drinking, and generally. We are aware that the churches commonly have introduced as
                                sacraments many elements antagonistic to the Christ life: Marriage is one; Private
                                property is two; Worldly pre-eminence is three; and from these three mentioned we have
                                the results of continual disturbances. We know, at present, but few are willing to stop
                                long enough to think; but we have tried to condense Christian requirements in so short a
                                space that " he who runs may read," and use sufficient selfdenial to withstand in a
                                measure the unnatural, unchristian influences prevailing. ¦</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Monopoly" TEIform="index"/>MONOPOLY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">EDITORIAL NOTES. Beware of those engaged in monopolizing the fruits of other's labors.
                                Beware of the Corruptionist ! There never was a time when so-called men were cheaper;
                                when Legislatures could be procured easier; when courts could be suborned with so little
                                money, and when so little indignation rested among the people! We hope, if there is a
                                God of nations, who has cognizance of the doings of the governments of this country and
                                the world, that there may be, if necessary, a revolutionary volcano that Will burst
                                asunder the moxopoly of our church, of other churches and of The States and 'General
                                Government, never more to be consolidated. Corruption walks upright, and among the
                                powerful; let the apparently powerless take on courage and feel strong in their position
                                of innocence. Corruption never did exist long without discovery, in high nor low
                            places.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Revision" TEIform="index"/>THE REVISION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We are glad our remarks in June No. concerning the revision of the New Testament are
                                having such a far and wide consideration. Our article upon that question — righteous
                                revising or otherwise— is having the desired effect. The general opinion is that the
                                revision will work detrimentally to the commonly paid, idolatry toward the Bible. That
                                detriment will work but very little permanent harm. It will hasten the day when men and
                                women will learn, that Testament or no Testament, the life of Christ, and THOSE WHO
                                FOLLOW IT CLOSELY*, ARE THE BEST TESTAMENT BEFORE THE WORLD.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="July no." TEIform="index"/>July No.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The Manifesto for July will commend itself. We must call special attention to the article
                                upon " Brook Farm," and "The Beard and Circumcision;" also to the beautiful music of our
                                respected Elder Augustus Blase, of Shakers, N. Y. We have some beautiful music in store
                                for our singers in future. We also ask attention for the articles we quote, as being
                                especially timely for consideration. To our advertising columns we scarcely need to call
                                particular attention. We advertise only what we know to be the best.</p></div3></div2><pb n="158" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>RELEASED FROM EARTH</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Palmer, Thomas" TEIform="index"/>Thomas Palmer</head><p TEIform="p">At Hancock, Mass., May 11, , aged 77 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Collins, Lucas" TEIform="index"/>Lucas Collins</head><p TEIform="p">Also: June 2, , aged 84 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wright, Franklin" TEIform="index"/>Franklin Wright</head><p TEIform="p">Also, June 14, aged 77 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fairbanks, Marilla" TEIform="index"/>Marilla Fairbanks</head><p TEIform="p">At Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., June 5th, the beautiful, to the last, , aged 75 years, long
                                    the able and accomplished eldress of the Second Family. Very few individuals have
                                    wrought more for the faith, however successfully, than has this mother in our Zion,
                                    and " her works will follow her."</p></div4></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notice" TEIform="index"/>Notice</head><p TEIform="p">We especially ask those who have not paid their dues for The Manifesto to be prompt in
                                their remittances, as we cannot meet our creditors unless they do so. We also beg from
                                those who are able and would aid us, any contribution in their power, toward the
                                sustenance of our paper. We work without pay.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Getting up a quarrel" TEIform="index"/>GETTING UP A QUARREL</head><p TEIform="p">In the depths of a forest lived two foxes who never had a cross word with each other. At
                                length one of them said to the other, " Let us quarrel.'' '' Very well," said the other,
                                " as you please, dear brother; but how shall we set about it?" " Oh," said the first, "
                                it cannot be difficult; two-legged people fall out, and why should not we ? " They tried
                                all sorts of ways, but could not succeed, because one would always give way to the
                                other. At last one of them brought two stones. " There," said he, " you must say they
                                are yours and I will say they are mine, and then we will quarrel and fight and scratch
                                each other. Now I will begin. Those stones are mine!" "Very well," said the other, " you
                                are welcome to them." " But we will never quarrel in this way," said the first; " don't
                                you know it takes two to make a quarrel ? " If all the boys and girls would do as the
                                foxes did, what peace, harmony and love would prevail. Children, if others want to
                                quarrel and fight let them do it all alone. If you never help them they will soon get
                                sick of the business.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Do thy little" TEIform="index"/>DO THY LITTLE</head><p TEIform="p">Do thy little — God has made Million leaves for forest shade — Smallest stars that glory
                                bring. God emyloyeth every thins:. Then the little thou hast done — Little battles thou
                                hast won ; Little masteries achieved. Little wants with care relieved, Little words in
                                love expressed, Little wrongs at once confessed, Little favors kindly done. Little toils
                                thou didst not shun, Little graces meekly worn, Little slights with patience borne —
                                Those shall crown thy pillowed head, Holy light upon thee shed. Those are treasures that
                                shall rise Far beyond the smiling skies.</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="And the boy was right" TEIform="index"/>And the Boy was Right</head><p TEIform="p">. — A bright little boy who had been engaged in combat with another boy. was reproved by
                                his aunt, who told him he ought always to wait until the other boy " pitched upon him."
                                " Well,"' exclaimed the little hero, " but if I wait for the other boy to begin I'm
                                afraid there won't be any fight."</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Venerable churchwarden carrying around the bag for collection..." TEIform="index"/>Venerable churchwarden carrying around the bag for collection...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Venerable churchwarden carrying around the bag for collection. Frantic scream of terror
                                from a small child who has a lively remembrance of the traitor apostle : "Oh, mamma,
                                mamma ! Here's Judas coming !"</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="PROMINENT Pennsylvania clergyman says " TEIform="index"/>PROMINENT Pennsylvania clergyman says...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A PROMINENT Pennsylvania clergyman says that if the ministers in that State should
                                plainly preach the doctrines of the Sermon on the Mount, they would find themselves
                                without congregations in less than six months. They must give to their discourses a tone
                                which will not offend the wealthy sinners who pay the greater portion of the pew
                            rent.</p></div3></div2><pb n="159" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Table</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North American Review" TEIform="index"/>North American Review
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Persian queen" TEIform="index"/>Persian queen
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Thwing, Edward P." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Salon of Madame Necker, vol. III" TEIform="index"/>Salon of Madame Necker, vol. III
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline">Translated from the French by <persName reg="Smith, Mary Stuart" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">The July number of the North American Review will contain an exhaustive article on Indian
                                affairs by Carl Sclmrz, and a very lively one on " The Power of Public Plunder " by
                                James Parton. Thr Persian Queen. By Rev. Edward P. Thwing. No. 63, Standard Series.
                                Octavo form. Price, 10 cents. New York : I. K. Funk &amp; Co., publishers. The Salon
                                of Mabamk Nectcer. Vol. III. Translated from the French by Mary Stuart Smith. No. 64,
                                Standard Series. Quarto form. Price, 15 cents. New York: I. K. Funk &amp; Co.,
                                publishers. Madame Necker, as is well known, was the mother of Madame de Stael In this
                                volume we have most interesting reminiscences of the early life of the daughter, and
                                much about the social life in France, which preceded the bloody reign of terror. It is
                                an exceedingly interesting book. I. K. Funk &amp; Co., 10 and 12 Dey street, New
                                York.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thorough study of the Bible" TEIform="index"/>THOROUGH STUDY OF THE BIBLE</head><p TEIform="p">In order to understand the Bible we will have to study it carefully. I was told in California
                            that the purest and best gold that they get they have to dig the deepest for ; and so in
                            studying the Bible, we must dig deep. And there are a great manj' Christians walking on
                            crutches in their Bible studying. They do not dare to examine for themselves. They go
                            wondering what others say, what Kd wards says, what the commentators say. Suppose you look
                            and see for yourselves. God has given you your own mind to use. If we will go to the Word of
                            God and be willing to be taught by the Holy Ghost, God will teach us, and will unfold His
                            blessed truth to us. There are three books that every Christian ought to have if he cannot
                            have but three. The first is a Bible — one with good plain print that you can easily read. I
                            am sick of these little fine type. It is a good thing to get a good-sized Bible, because you
                            will grow old by and by, and your sight may grow poor, and you won't want to give up the one
                            you have been used to reading in after it has come to seem like a sort of lifelong
                            companion. The next book to get is ''Cruden's Concordance." You cannot get on very well in
                            Bible study without that. There is another book printed in this country by the Tract Society
                            called the " Scriptural Text-Book." It was brought out first in London. These three books
                            will be a wonderful help to you in studying the Word of God. Another thing — do not read the
                            Word of God as I used to, just to ease your conscience. I had a rule to read two or three
                            chapters every day. If I had not done it through the day, I would read them just before I
                            went to bed, to ease my conscience. I did not remember it perhaps an hour, but I kept the
                            rule. You will never' get much out of it in that way. It is a good way to hunt for something
                            when you read it. Two words will give you the key to the whole Bible — Christ and Jesus. The
                            Christ of the Old Testament is the Jesus of the New, and the two Books explain each other.
                            Yon may search for these words in your study. Sometime ago I went through the building where
                            Prang's chromos are "produced in Boston. They were bringing out a chromo of a prominent
                            public man, and he showed me this picture in its different stages of progress. In the first
                            stone there was no trace of a man's face — only a little tinge of color that did not suggest
                            any shape. I saw the next stone, and still no face, and the third, and so on, and not until
                            the fourth or fifth stone was there any likeness of a face at all. After a little it began
                            to show, and yet not until I came to the 14th or 15th stone did it look at all like the man
                            himself; and not until the 26th stone did it look natural as life. That is the way it is
                            when we read the Scripture. We take it up and do not see any thing in it ; we read it again,
                            but see nothing; again, and again, and after you have read it 25 times you will see the man
                            Christ Jesus stamped on every page. The Old Testament was written only to teach us who
                            Christ was. Moses, the law, the prophets, they all testify to Christ. You take Christ out of
                            the Old Testament and it<pb n="160" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 160 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. is a sealed book to
                            you. It has been a great help to me in studying the Bible to study one book at a time.
                            Suppose you spend six months reading Genesis ; getting the key of that, you get the key to
                            the whole Bible. Death, resurrection, and the whole story are told in Genesis ; all in
                            types, to be sure, and shadows that are brought out further on. There are eight great
                            beginnings in Genesis — the beginning of creation, the beginning of marriage, the beginning
                            of sin and death, of sacrifices, of the covenant, of the nation, and the human race and the
                            Hebrew race. Take up these eight beginnings and see what they teach, and this key will
                            unlock to you the rest of the Bible. If you just take the Bible itself alone, without any
                            other book to help you to interpret it, one passage will explain another. Instead of running
                            after the interpretations of different men, let God interpret it to your soul. As Stephens
                            said: Do not study it in the blue light of Presbyterianism, or the red light of Methodism,
                            or the violet light of Episcopalianism, but study it in the light of Calvary. One man says,"
                            I am a Romanist, and it has got to teach what Romanism teaches ; another says, I am a
                            Protestant, and it has got to teach me what Protestantism teaches." Take it up independent
                            of these, and after you have dug its meaning out for yourself it will be so much sweeter to
                            you. Another way is to take it up topically. Suppose you spend three or four months reading
                            all you can find about love, after that you will be full of love. Then take the word grace,
                            and run through the Bible reading all there is about grace. After I had been studying grace
                            for two or three weeks, I got so full that one day I could not stay in my study any longer,
                            and went out on the street, and asked the first man I saw if he knew any thing about the
                            grace of God. I suppose he thought I was crazy, but I was so full I had to talk to somebody.
                            Then the subject of Heaven. Take up the Bible and let God speak to you about it. If you go
                            into court you will find that the lawyer just gets all the testimony he can on one point,
                            and he heaps it before the jury. If you want to convince men of any grand truth, just stick
                            to that one point. Take up the Word and get all the testimony yov can ; bring in Moses, and
                            David, and Joshua, and every apostle you can, and make them testify. If you read all the
                            Bible says of forgiveness, before you have studied it a week you will want to forgive every
                            one.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ancient Latin elegy" TEIform="index"/>ANCIENT LATIN ELEGY</head><p TEIform="p">[From Prudentius, a Latin Christian poet, born in Spain, A. D. 348. Bentley called him " the
                            Homer and Virgil of the Christians."] No more, no more in tears complain, Cease, mourners,
                            cease your sorrow vain ; Give these dear pledges to the earth ; This death is but a second
                            birth. What mean these sculptured marbles fair, O'er the cold clay reposing there ? Mute
                            tokens of the faith we keep, He is not dead, but lies asleep. What though upon this silent
                            brow No light of thought is beaming now ; It only rests a little hour, To waken with a
                            nobler power. Returns the day when his dear form Shall kindle with the life-blood warm, And
                            once again the glowing mind Visit the form it left behind. These senseless clods, so long
                            that lay To the devouring grave a prey, Upward on eager wing shall soar, Following the souls
                            they loved before. So from the dry seed blossoming, Joyous the blessed life shall spring;
                            And gazing from the turf below, Its own full ripened fruitage know. Receive, O Earth ! this
                            treasure blest, Hold it within thy loving breast; This dust of man, in death how fair, How
                            noble, yield not to thy care. This was the saintly soul's abode, Built by Thy breath,
                            eternal God ! And in this sacred dwelling place Christ sojourned once in truth and grace.
                            Then guard thou well this holy trust Till, mindful of his clear loved dust, The risen Lord
                            of life demands His own true image from thy hands. Onward the year of justice rolls, God's
                            fulness for all yearning souls, When this dear form, thy charge no more O open grave ! thou
                            shalt restore.</p></div2><pb n="161" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Realities of war" TEIform="index"/>THE REALITIES OF WAR.</head><p TEIform="p">[From Herald of Peace.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Can any one read the following and then say that war isnot cruel? What think you
                                    of Christians, who claim to be peace-makers, engaging in cruelties like this? A very
                                    popular writer thus describes a battle:—"We have been fighting at the edge of the
                                    woods. A moment ago the battery was a confused mob. We look again, and the six guns
                                    are in position, the detached horses hurrying away, the ammunition chests open, and
                                    along our line runs the command,' Give them one more volley, and fall back to
                                    support the guns.' We have scarcely obeyed when boom ! boom ! opens the battery, and
                                    jets of fire jump down and scorch the green trees under which we have fought and
                                    struggled. The shattered old brigade has a chance to breathe,for the first time in
                                    three hours, as we form a line and lie down. What grim, cool fellows those
                                    cannoneers are ? Every man is a perfect machine. Bullets splash dust into their
                                    faces, but they do not wince. Bullets sing over and around, they do not dodge. There
                                    goes one to the earth, shot through the head as he sponged his gun. That machinery
                                    loses just one beat, misses just one cog in the wheel, and then works away again as
                                    before. Every gun is using a short fuse shell. The ground shakes and trembles, the
                                    roar shuts out all sound from a battle-line three miles long, and the shells go
                                    shrieking into the swamp to cut trees short off, to mow great gaps in the bushes, to
                                    hunt out and shatter, and mangle men until their corpses cannot be recognized as
                                    human. You would think a tornado was howling through the forest, followed by billows
                                    of fire, and yet men live through it — aye, press forward to capture the battery. We
                                    can hear their shouts as they form for the rush. Now the shells are changed for
                                    grape and canister, and the guns are fired so fast that all reports blend into one
                                    mighty roar. The shriek of a shell is the wickedest sound in war, but nothing makes
                                    the flesh crawl like the demoniac singing, purring, whistling grapeshot, and the
                                    serpent-like hiss of canister. Men's legs and heads are torn from bodies, and bodies
                                    cut in two. A round shot or shell takes two men out of the rank as it crashes
                                    through. Grape and canister mow a swath and pile the dead on top of each other.
                                    Through the smoke we see a swarm of men. It is not a battle line, but a mob of men
                                    desperate enough to bathe their bayonets in the name of the guns. The guns leap from
                                    the ground, almost, as they are depressed on the foe.and shrieks and screams and
                                    shouts blend into one awful and steady cry. Twenty men out on the battery are down,
                                    and the firing is interrupted. The foes accept it as a sign of wavering and come
                                    rushing on. They are not ten feet away when the guns give them a last shot. That
                                    discharge picks living men off their feet and throws them into the swamp, a
                                    blackened, bloody mass. Up now, as the enemy are among the guns. There is a silence
                                    of ten seconds, and then the flash and roar of more than '8,000 muskets and a rush
                                    forward with bayonets. For what! Neither on the right nor left, nor in front of us
                                    is a living foe! There are corpses around us which have been struck by three, four,
                                    and even six bullets, and nowhere on this acre of ground is a wounded man ! The
                                    wheels of the gun cannot move until the blockade of death is removed. Men cannot
                                    pass from caisson to gun without climbing over rows of dead. Every gun and wheel is
                                    smeared with blood; every foot of grass has its horrible stain. Historians write of
                                    the glory of war. Burial parties saw murder, where historians saw glory."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Herald of peace" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Imperfect religion" TEIform="index"/>IMPERFECT RELIGION</head><p TEIform="p">Very much of the religion of the day is an easy-minded religion, without conflict and
                            wrestling with self-denial and sacrifice — a religion which knows nothing of the pangs of
                            the new birth at its commencement, and nothing of the desperate struggle with the flesh and
                            with the devil, day by day, making us long for resurrection, deliverance, for the Lord's
                            return. It is a second-rate religion — a religion in which there is no largeness, no
                            grandeur, no potency, no noble-mindedness, no all-constrain <pb n="162" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 162 THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. ing love. It is a hollow religion, with a fair exterior, but with an
                            aching heart—a heart unsatisfied, a soul not at rest, a conscience not at peace with God ; a
                            religion marked, it may be, by activity and excitement, but betraying all the while the
                            consciousness of a wound hidden and unhealed within, and hence unable to animate to lofty
                            doings, or supply the strength needed for such doing. It is a feeble religion, lacking the
                            sinews and bones of harder times, very different from the indomitable,
                            much-enduring,stormbraving religion, not merely of apostolic days, but even of the
                            Reformation. It is an uncertain religion ; that is to say, it is not rooted on certainty ;
                            it is not the outflowing of a soul assured of pardon, and rejoicing in the filial
                            relationship between itself and God. Hence, there is no liberty of service, for the question
                            of personal acceptance is still an unsettled thing ; there is a working for pardon. All is
                            thus bondage, heaviness, irksomeness ; there is a speaking for God, but it is with a
                            faltering tongue ; there is a laboring for God, but it is with fettered hands ; there is a
                            movement in the way of His command, but it is with a heavy drag upon oar limbs. Hence, the
                            inefficient uniniiuential character of our religion. It does not tell on others, for it has
                            not fully told upon ourselves. It falls short of its mark, for the arm that drew the bow is
                            paralyzed. —Rev. Horatius Bonar, D. D,</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Clean money" TEIform="index"/>CLEAN MONEY</head><p TEIform="p">As a godly merchant lay upon his dying bed, he spoke to his children of the little property
                            which he had acquired and was leaving behind him. " It is not much, but theie is not a dirty
                            shilling in it." There is such a thing as clean money. It may be earned by diligence in
                            business, by honest labor of hand or mind, or by the severest occupations which are not
                            esteemed as either easy or genteel; but there is money, even in the purses and coffers of
                            many who profess to be followers of Christ, which all the waters of Jordan could not make
                            clean. There are the wages of unrighteousness, the gains of ungodliness, the hoarded spoils
                            wrung from thin hands of the poor and the needy; there are revenues from the traffic in
                            strong drink ; there are rents paid to church members for places that are used as traps and
                            pitfalls to ensnare unwary men ; there are gains acquired in a thousand ways that are
                            blackened with the stain of sin and with the curse of God. Thousands on thousands have thus
                            laid up wealth which shall ensnare their children and beguile them to their ruin! and which
                            shall finally eat their flesh as it were fire, when the Judge who standeth before the door
                            shall come to make inquisition for blood, and to punish the ungodly in the last great day. O
                            man of earth, as you look upon your gains and treasures, as you count your hoards and
                            estimate your possessions, ask yourself the question, IxtMs clean money? and decide that as
                            God shall give you grace and help, nothing which you possess shall deserve the curse that
                            follows the wages of unrighteousness, the gains of those who know not and fear not God.— The
                            Armory.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Never too late to learn" TEIform="index"/>NEVER TOO LATE TO LEARN</head><p TEIform="p">Socrates, at an extreme old age, learned to play on musical instruments. Cato, at eighty
                            years of age, learned the Greek language. Plutarch, when between seventy and eighty, began
                            the study of Latin. Boccacio was thirty-five years of age when he commenced his studies in
                            light literature ; yet he became one of the great masters of the Tuscan dialect. Sir Henry
                            Spellman neglected the sciences in his youth, but commenced the study of them when he was
                            between fifty and sixty years of age. After this time he became a most learned antiquarian
                            and lawyer. Dr. Johnson applied himself to the Dutch language but a few years before his
                            death. Ludovico Monaldesco, at the great age of one hundred and fifteen, wrote the memoirs
                            of his own times. Ogilby, the translator of Homer and Virgil, was unacquainted with the
                            Latin and Greek till he was past fifty. Franklin did not fully commence his philosophical
                            pursuits till he had reached his fiftieth year. <pb n="163" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO.
                            163 Dryden, in his sixty-eighth year, commenced the translation of the Iliad, that most
                            pleasing production. We could go on and cite thousands of examples of men who commenced a
                            new study, either for a livelihood or amusement, at an advanced age. But every one familiar
                            with the biography of distinguished men will recollect individual cases enough to convince
                            him that none but the sick and indolent will ever say : " I am too old to learn."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love constitutes my crime" TEIform="index"/>LOVE CONSTITUTES MY CRIME</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Guyon" TEIform="persName"/>Madame Guyon</byline><p TEIform="p">IN PRISON. Love constitutes my crime ; For this they keep me here, Imprisoned thus so long a
                            time For Him I hold so dear. And yet I am, as when I came, The subject of this holy flame.
                            How can I better grow! How from my own heart fly! Those who imprison me should know True
                            love can never die. 5Tea, tread and crush it with disdain, And it will live and burn again.
                            And am I then to blame? He's always in my sight; And having once inspired the flame, He
                            always keeps it bright. For this they smite me and reprove, Because 1 cannor, cease to love.
                            What power shall dim its ray, Dropped burning from above! Eternal life shall ne'er decay,
                            God is the life of love. And when its source of life is o'er, And only then, 'twill shine no
                            more. 1648-1717—</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Indebtedness" TEIform="index"/>INDEBTEDNESS</head><p TEIform="p">The trouble is, people do not live within their means. One individual thus soon becomes under
                            obligation to another, and is speedily made a bond-slave of the varying fortunes of one
                            whose business is very differ ent from and is not directed by his own volition, but by the
                            will, wishes, and caprice of those who rule over him. Besides he not only involves himself,
                            but he entails his misfortunes, like a cancerous scrofula, upon his innocent family, and
                            many are made to suffer the penalty of the sins of one. He is afflcted more deeply as the
                            years go by, and his circumstances change. His needs change, his calculations change, the
                            facts of life change, and if he had the act to do again he would feel himself a criminal to
                            allow such a thing. But he has already made the obligation, and he must now stand to it,
                            even though he suffer severely, and his posterity after him. The penalty of the criminal
                            must be suffered, though the enormity of the crime be largely mitigated by the ignorance or
                            heedlessness of the act long before performed. Peter the First, king of Portugal, to
                            restrain undue luxury, and prevent the ruin of families, is said to have absolutely
                            forbidden his subjects from buying or selling without immediate payment, and for the second
                            offense made the punishment death. —American Wesleyan.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hermit's prayer" TEIform="index"/>THE HERMIT'S PRAYER</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A young man who had great cause of complaint against another told an old hermit
                                    that he was resolved to be revenged. The good old man did all he could to dissuade
                                    him, but in vain. The young man persisted in seeking vengeance ; and then the old
                                    hermit said to him, " At least, my young friend, let us pray together before you
                                    execute your design." The young man assented, and the hermit began to pray in this
                                    way : '' It is no longer necessary, O Heavenly Father, that thou shouldst defend
                                    this young man, and declare thyself his protector, since he has taken upon himself
                                    the right of seeking his own revenge." The young man fell on his knees before the
                                    old hermit and prayed for pardon for his thought, and declared he would no longer
                                    seek revenge of those who had injured him.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The quaint old emblem writer, Querles, says..." TEIform="index"/>The quaint old emblem writer, Querles, says...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The quaint old emblem writer, Queries, says : " Has any wronged thee ? be bravely revenged.
                            Slight it and the work is begun ; forgive it and it is finished. He is below himself that is
                            not above an injury."</p></div2><pb n="164" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Clergyman's call" TEIform="index"/>A CLERGYMAN'S CALL</head><p TEIform="p">A good story is told of Dean Stanley who traveled extensively through the United States a
                            year and a half ago. He was spending the night with some New England friends and desired to
                            be called at an early hour in order to proceed on his journey. The task was assigned to a
                            boy employed in the house, who was instructed especially, that after rapping at the dean's
                            door and hearing the question, " Who is there ? " he should reply, " The boy, my lord," and
                            then discharge his errand. The boy was at the dean's room at the exact moment, and rapped
                            softly at the door. Upon hearing the question, " Who is there ?" he answered, " The Lord, my
                            boy ; " the transposition of words occasioned a peal of laughter from the distinguished
                            visitor. The dean considered the incident a capital one, and told it with a great deal of
                            amusement.</p></div2><div2 type="story" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Something inside a pig" TEIform="index"/>SOMETHING INSIDE A PIG</head><p TEIform="p">Said Edward Everett once, " The common people will always understand a speaker who
                            understands himself and uses simple language." But some speakers seem to possess the
                            incurable faculty of always shooting over the common people's heads. The story is told of aj
                            city minister who, after preaching for a friend in the country, was told by the latter: '•
                            You have given us a very good sermon, with one exception, and that is, you used some word
                            our people don't understand." The former thought the latter was certainly mistaken, and
                            asked what single word he had vised that all could not understand. " Why," replied the
                            other,'' you said ' felicity ' instead of ' happiness.' Now, all our people know what'
                            happiness' is, but a great many of them, I am sure, do not know the meaning of ' felicity.'"
                            As the preacher doubted this, the country minister said: "There comes one of our plain,
                            simple farmers ; we will ask him." And as the farmer came up he said: " We were just
                            speaking about a word — the word ' felicity;' can you tell us what is its meaning !" "Why,
                            yes," said the farmer; "certainly I know what 'felicity' is; it is somethinginside a pig,
                            though 1 don't know exactly what !"</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Parable on tobacco" TEIform="index"/>A PARABLE ON TOBACCO</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Slenker, Elmina D." TEIform="persName"/>Elmina D. Slenker</byline><p TEIform="p">Then shall the kingdom of Satan be likened to a grain of tobacco-seed, which, though
                            exceedingly small, being cast into the ground, grew and became a great plant, and spread its
                            leaves rank and broad, so that huge and vile worms found a habitation thereon. And it came
                            to pass, in the course of time, that the sons of men looked upon it, and thought it
                            beautiful to look upon, and much to be desired to make lads look big and manly. So they put
                            forth their hands, and did chew thereof. And some it made sick, and others to vomit most
                            filthily. And it further came to pass, that those who chewed it became weak and unmanly, and
                            said, We are enslaved, and cannot cease from chewing it. And the mouths of all that were
                            enslaved became foul, and they were seized with a violent spitting ; and they did spit even
                            in ladies' parlors, and in the house of the Lord of hosts. And the saints of the Most High
                            were greatly plagued thereby. And in the course of time it came also to pass that others
                            snuffed it ; and they were taken suddenly with fits, and they did sneeze with a great and
                            mighty sneeze, insomuch that their eyes were rilled with tears, and they did look
                            exceedingly silly. And yet others cunningly wrought the leaves thereof into rolls, and did
                            set tire to one end thereof, and did look very grave and calflike ; and the smoke of their
                            torment ascendeth up forever and ever. And the cultivation thereof became a great and mighty
                            business in the earth ; and the merchantmen waxed rich by the commerce thereof. And it came
                            to pass, that the saints of the Most High defiled themselve therewith, and said. Wherefore
                            this waste ? and why do these little ones lack bread and shoes and books ? Turn now your
                            fields into corn and wheat, and put this evil thing fur from you, and be separate, and
                            defile not yourselves any more.; and I will bless you, and cause my face to shine upon you.
                            But <pb n="165" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. 165 with, one accord they all exclaimed, We
                            cannot cease from chewing, snuffing, and puffing ; we are slaves. — </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gems of thought" TEIform="index"/>GEMS OF THOUGHT</head><p TEIform="p">Do not, as you hope for success, spend your time in idleness. Flattery is a false coin which
                            has circulation only through our vanity. Conscience is the voice of the soul; the passions
                            are the voice of the body. Men seldom improve when they have no other models than themselves
                            to copy. You cannot dream yourself into a character ; you must hammer and forge yourself
                            one. To be comfortable and contented, spend less than you can earn, an art which few have
                            learned. The first time a man deceives you, the fault is his ; if he deceives you the second
                            time, the fault is your own. We appreciate no pleasures unless we are occasionally deprived
                            of them. Eestraint is the golden rule of enjoyment. Civility is in itself a fortune, for a
                            courteous man always succeeds in life, even when persons of greater ability sometimes fail.
                            Good temper is like a sunny day ; it sheds a brightness over every thing ; it is the
                            sweetener of toil and the soother of disquietude. There is a pleasure in contemplating good;
                            there is a greater pleasure in receiving good ; but the greatest pleasure is doing good,
                            which comprehends the rest. Every man carries about with him a touchstone, if he will make
                            use of it, to distinguish substantial gold from superficial glittering, truth from
                            appearance. Give us sincere friends, or none. This hollow glitter of smiles and words —
                            compliments that mean nothing — protestations of affection as solid as the froth from
                            champagne — invitations that are but pretty sentences, uttered because .such things are all
                            worthless. There are treasures laid up in the heart — treasures of charity, piety,
                            temperance and soberness. These treasures a man takes with him beyond death, when he leaves
                            this world. Were we to take as much pains to be what we ought to be as we do to disguise
                            what we really are, we might appear like ourselves, without being at the trouble of any
                            disguise at all. There is no fortune so good but that it may be reversed, and none so bad
                            but it may be bettered. The sun that rises in clouds may set in splendor, and that which
                            rises in pleasure may set in gloom. It should be pointed out with continual earnestness that
                            the essence of lying is in deception, not in words ; a.lie may be told by silence, by
                            equivocation, by the accent on a syllable, by a glance of the eye attaching a peculiar
                            significance to a sentence. Be true to yourself, and enemies cannot harm you. They cannot,
                            by all their efforts, take away your knowledge of yourself, the purity of your motives, the
                            integrity of your character, and the generosity of your nature I would not give much for
                            your religion unless it can be seen. Lamps do not talk, but they do shine. A light house
                            sounds no drum, it beats no gong, and yet far over the waters its friendly spark is seen by
                            the mariner. So let your action shine out your religion. Let the main sermon of your life be
                            illustrated by your conduct, and it shall not fail to be illustrious. Closely related to the
                            matter of morals is that of manners; indeed, a man's moral character influences largely his
                            manner toward others, and if we possess the self-respect that comes from our following our
                            convictions of right, we shall naturally become pleasant and thoughtful in our relations
                            with those about us. Still we are liable to be careless even when our intentions are the
                            best. Politeness costs nothing. It is a small thing to be kind and obliging but these little
                            things will make many friends in early life, and the habit of politeness, when once well
                            formed, will be of great advantage to us in after years.</p></div2><pb n="166" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bolting his food" TEIform="index"/>BOLTING HIS FOOD</head><p TEIform="p">Sam Slick tells us the story of the Honorable Alden Gobfoie, secretary of legation in
                            England, who was dyspeptic, so he goes to Abernethy, the great English physician, for
                            advice. " What's the matter with you V says the doctor. "Why," says Alden, "I presume I have
                            the dyspepsy." "Ah," says he, "I see — a Yankee, swallowed more dollars than you can
                            digest." "lam no American citizen," says Alden with great dignity ; I am secretary to our
                            legation at the court of St. James." " The dickens you are ! " says Abernethy ; " Then
                            you'll soon get rid of your dyspepsy." " I don't see that inference," said Alden. " But I
                            tell you it does follow," said the doctor, "for in the company you'll have to keep you'll
                            have to eat like a Christian." It was an everlasting pity Alden contradicted him, for he
                            broke out like one distracted mad: " I'll be hanged," said he, "if ever I saw a Yankee that
                            didn't bolt his food whole like a boa-constrictor. How can you expect to digest food that
                            you neither take trouble to dissect or time to masticate ? It's no won der you lose your
                            teeth, for you never use them ; nor your digestion for you overload it; nor your saliva, for
                            you expend it on the carpets. You Yankees load your stomachs as a Devonshire man does his
                            cart, as full as it can hold and as fast as he can pitch it in with a fork, and drive off.
                            And then you complain that such a load is too heavy for you."</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Diptheria" TEIform="index"/>DIPHTHERIA</head><p TEIform="p">The Scientific American says .- " As every physician knows, it is no uncommon thing for
                            adults to have diphtheria so mildly that it is mistaken for an ordinary sore throat
                            resulting from cold ; yet such a person can easily infect a child, and the child become a
                            center of malignant infection. In view of the fatal prevalence of diphtheria, therefore, the
                            kissing of a child upon the mouth by a person with a sore throat is hazardous, if not
                            criminal ; and scarcely less so is the practice of allowing children to kiss their ailing
                            playmates. It would be wise to exercise great caution in this matter, if not to discontinue
                            the practice of kissing upon the mouth altogether." Mr. John S.i Wiles, a surgeon of
                            Thorncombe, Dorset, writes to the London Times that after two cases of malignant diphtheria
                            out of some nine or ten he had been called to attend had proved fatal, the mother of a sick
                            child showed him an extract from an American newspaper concerning a practitioner who used
                            sulphur to cure the disease. Accordingly he used milk of sulphur for infants and flowers of
                            sulphur for older children and adults, brought to a creamy consistence with glycerine ;
                            dose, a teaspoonful or more, according to age, three or four times a day, swallowed slowly,
                            and the application of the same to the nostrils with a sponge. Result : he did not lose a
                            case there or elsewhere, and he succeeded in saving life when the affection had almost
                            blocked the throat. A correspondent to the New York Tribune writes: "I keep a glass can of
                            sulphur water, made by shaking a table-spoonful of sulphur with a pint of water till the
                            sulphur settles to the bottom, constantly on hand, and at the first complaint on the part of
                            any member of the family of sore throat I wrap the throat with flannel, and give a
                            teaspoonful of the sulphur-water several times a day. I have used this remedy for more than
                            a year with success, and have had no,«evere cases of sore throat in my family since I began
                            its use, though previous to that time they were of frequent occurrence in cold and damp
                            weather. The diet should be simple and nutritious—milk, eggs, beef, chicken, broth and the
                            like."</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A stronger temperance sermon will never be told than..." TEIform="index"/>A stronger temperance sermon will never be told than...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A stronger temperance sermon will never be told than the old one which an unfortunate woman
                            of Cape Girardeau, Mo., delivered before her husband in a bar-room. Setting a covered dish,
                            which she had brought with her, upon the table, she said : " Presuming, husband, that you
                            are too busy to come home to dinner, I have brought you yours," and disappeared. With a
                            forced laugh he invited his friend to dine with him, but on removing the cover from the
                            dish, found only a slip of paper, on which was written : " I hope you will enjoy your meal;
                            it is the same your family have at home."</p></div2><pb n="167" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Agricultural</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hornless cattle" TEIform="index"/>HORNLESS CATTLE</head><p TEIform="p">A farmer who owns forty-seven head of hornless cattle gives in the Western Rural his
                                reasons for preferring them. He says: " First they are about as harmless as a flock of
                                sheep ; second, sheep, colts and horses can run in the same pasture or yard, and drink
                                out of the same tank, with perfect safety; third, it is sometimes necessary to milk in a
                                storm, and I have only to open the cow-stable door and twelve cows will not take more
                                room than three pairs of horns ; fourth, a straw rick two rods long and twenty feet wide
                                will make a first-rate shelter for thirty head of young mulley stock; for they will soon
                                have the rick shelved all around, lie down like so many hogs, and be comfortable under
                                the edges of the stack, while six pairs of horns could hardly be accommodated on the
                                same territory. I never have had my horses wounded, or colts, sheep, calves, children,
                                women, or men tossed upon mulley-bull's horns. My stock are descendants of the old
                                English red mulley breed."</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watering horses" TEIform="index"/>WATERING HORSES</head><p TEIform="p">If after feeding hay and then oats we allow a horse to take a large drink of water, a
                                considerable part of the oats will be carried by the water into the intestines, and he
                                get little of the advantage of feeding the oats after the hay. If such a drink is taken
                                soon after eating hay alone, the effect will not be so injurious, because hay does not
                                need so long a time for digestion as grain. If only one or two quarts of water are
                                allowed, it will pass the food in the stomach without changing its position to any great
                                extent. When the stomach has got rid of a considerable portion of its contents, it seems
                                a difficult matter for it to force out the remainder, and fermentation and colic
                                sometimes result. A drink of water at such a time, by carrying on the substance which
                                has remained long enough, relieves the condition. This probably explains why some
                                horse-car companies have found it advisable to have their horses watered at midnight.—
                                Rail's Journal of Health</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A farmer at Tremont, near New York city, offers this as a sure cure for potato bugs..." TEIform="index"/>A farmer at Tremont, near New York city, offers this as a sure cure for potato bugs...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A farmer at Tremont, near New York city, offers this as a sure cure for potato bugs :
                                Dissolve one ounce of saltpetre, two ounces of alum and half a pound of the commonest
                                brown soap in three gallons of water, and sprinkle with a watering pot over the growing
                                plants.</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nebraska custom that should be adopted in every state and territory" TEIform="index"/>A
                                Nebraska Custom that Should be Adopted in Every State and Territory</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">One of the most poetical, as well as practical, official papers of the
                                        succession of messages and manifestoes that the year has brought forth, is the
                                        proclamation of the Governor of Nebraska, wherein he appoints the second
                                        Wednesday of April as Arbor Day. Governor Nance sees the beautiful as well as
                                        the useful side of this custom, and almost forgets the precise diction of
                                        official documents and falls into more elegant phraseology. The people are
                                        enjoined to leave their business, to forsake the shop, the plow, the mill, to
                                        forget trade and agriculture, for one day, and to plant trees. " Let it be
                                        remembered," the proclamation concludes, "that those who plant trees build
                                        living monuments to their own industry, and are benefactors of mankind, while
                                        benefiting themselves." </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Helena herald" TEIform="index"/>Helena Herald</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A piece of charcoal put in the water in which codfish or cabbage is boiling will..." TEIform="index"/>A piece of charcoal put in the water in which codfish or cabbage is boiling will...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A piece of charcoal put in the water in which codfish or cabbage is boiling will destroy
                                all disagreeable smell. If you have a piece of tough meat to cook, rub it over with
                                carbonate of soda or vinegar before cooking, wipe it off and your meat will cook tender
                                instead of tough.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cement for leather" TEIform="index"/>Cement FOR Leather</head><p TEIform="p">One who has tried every thing says that after an experience of fifteen years he has found
                                nothing to equal the following as a cement for leather belting: Common glue and
                                isinglass, equal parts, soaked for ten hours in just enough water to cover them. Bring
                                gradually to a boiling heat, and add pure tannin until the whole becomes ropy or appears
                                like the white of eggs- Buff off the surfaces to be joined, apply this cement, and clamp
                                firmly.</p></div3></div2><pb n="168" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Happy clime journey" TEIform="index"/>THE HAPPY CLIME JOURNEY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blase, Augustus" TEIform="persName"/>Augustus Blase</byline><p TEIform="p"> Shakers, N. Y. 1 I'm now on my journey to that happy clime, Where grief and sorrow are no
                            more, 2. With courage and zeal I will hasten away , From all that is a hind'rance to me,
                            Where love and sweet union the faithful entwine, O how I long for that beautiful shore To
                            dwell with the saints in a bright, endless day, Completely redeemed, yea happy and (free.
                            That beautiful shore, that beautiful shore, Where joy and So happy and free, so happy and
                            free, The followers of rejoicing will be ever more, I long to be there, a true Jesus for
                            ever will be, That I will be one, all evil rightful heir, Of heaven's rich blessings and
                            glories to share, I'll shun, And onward I'll move'till the victory is won.</p></div2><pb id="p29" TEIform="pb"/><!--                     <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>