<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2904" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">29</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><date value="18990401" TEIform="date">April 1899</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">49-64</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="29" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
 1899.
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
with large type and on excellent paper.
It contains  130 pages and has
ILLUSTRATIONS
of the Shakers and their
A SUMMAEY VIEW
OF  THE
MILLENNIAL church,
OK
"United   Society   of  Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price, 50 cts.
The  work gives  quite an extended account of the Several SOCIETIES, their
organization and general management.
Price, 50 cts.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF  TEE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cU.
THE ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all their
property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. It now has 5,000
acres of land in Southeast Missouri on
which it offers a home and employment
for life to all acceptable persons who may
wish to join it.            50  cents a year;
specimen copy free.    Address A. Longuy, 2819 Olive St. St. Louis, Mo.
AND
SHAKERISM.
By Giles B. Avert.
Price,  15cts.
APRIL,
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
TEE   MANIFESTO.
The Journal of Hygeio-Thekapt for February, 1899, continues the interesting serial
"The Science of Life," by Dr. T. V. Gifford.
Among the many "Gems of Thought" presented, is this truism; "Song is an absolute necessity of life.    We can never be in this life nor
in the life to come, all that we ought to be if
we fail to exercise in some way the power of
song."   Dr. T. V. Gifford & Co., Kokonio, Ind.
(75 cts. a year.)
Major-General Wesley Merritt, U. S. A., will
continue the leading article to the April number of Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly,
published March 20th.    "The Philippine Campaign" is the subject of General Merritt's paperthe foremost topic of the hour, treated in
masterly fashion by the commander of the
United States Military forces which, in conjunction with the navy under Admiral Dewey
stormed and took the city of Manila, August
13,1898.    This article, like all others in Frank
Leslie's Popular Monthly, is^richly illustrated, constituting one of the most notable
contributions to magazine literature.
Ian Maclaren, who is now on a lecturing
tour in this country, begins in an early issue
of The Ladies' Home Journal his latest piece of
literary work.   It is a series of popular articles in which he defines the relation that a
minister holds to his congregation; how a
preacher is helped.by his people; how a con.
gregation can make the most of a minister,
and other phases of the most satisfactory attitude of a congregation to a   pastor.
Address H. L. Hastings, 47 Cornhill, Boston,
Mass., for a copy of "Israel's" Messiah" or
"Why the Jews reject Christ," if you have not
already read it.   Jew and Gentile will be interested in its perusal.   The gospel has a noble defender in the author and his pen keeps
the truths of Christianity in perpetual circulation.
We have Just received from "The Missionary
Herald," a neat pamphlet entitled "Ceylon, A
Key to India" by Mary and Margaret W.
Leitch.   It is beautifully illustrated and its
graphic personal experiences can not fail to
attract attention from the reading public.
To the thoughtful, mission loving mind it
strikes a dual chord of victory and warning,
the former recognizing the noble accomplishments of the present and past, the latter ques.
tioning, What of the future?   The educational
and medical features of the work particularly
reflect credit on the consecrated womanhood
that has entered the field.   The gifted authors
of the book have our thanks and earnest
prayers.   May God prosper our home and
foreign missions!   Missionary HeraldExtra
Single copies, postpaid, 10 cts.   Address Chas.
E. Swett, No. 14 Beacon St., Boston, Mass.
The event of the literary year will be, undoubtedly, the great novel upon which Count
Tolstoy has been laboring in order that he
may devote the proceeds to the transportation to Canada of three thousand Russian
Quakers.   It is generally believed by his
friends that this work will probably mark the
conclusion of Count Tolstoy's literary career.
Not merely on this account, but because of
the subject treated, it will attract the widest
attention the world over.   It is a profound
study of the life of man and woman and treats
of the three phases of lovethat of the youth
that of the young man, that of the man in mature age.   The Cosmopolitan Magazine announces that it has secured the sole right of
publication.
An original article by Washington Irving is
an unusual event in magazine literature.   The
Outlook has been fortunate enough to obtain
through representatives of the Irving family,
a heretofore unpublisht article by Washington Irving, called "A Festal Day in Rome."
It has intrinsic interest, which is increat>t by
an introductory sketch showing how Irving's
literary ambition came into being and by a
line portrait.   ($3 a year.   The Outlook Company, New York.)
The night salutation, besides "God give you
good-night," is "Sleep safely to-night" and
"God bring you safe from the death-sleep of
night!"   I have heard both these frequently
inJthe_,Western islands, and they are also
used in the outer Hebrides.   The last one
shows the Catholic desire to die after due
preparation.'not to be taken unawares;
"Bas Criostaidhe, ola's aithrighe
Go bhfaghaidh ar n.anam bocht!
A Christian death, with unction and pennance,
May our poor souls receive!"
is a frequent prayer.   Then there are many
beautiful Gaelic hymns to be recited when
"raking the fire," and on other occasions.
Some of these collected by Dr. Hyde, myself
and others, will appear in Dr. Hyde's "Religious Songs of Connacht."   When the last candle is put out at night the prayer is "God be
good to the souls of the faithful."   The dead
are always remembered in Ireland; no one
would dream of passing by the roadside
without a short prayer for those who rest
there, who in Gaelic phrase are "on the path
to truth" and are numbered with "the host of
the dead."   In the Highlands they say of a
dead friend, "Rest and ease to him who lives
not;" in Ireland, when speaking English,
"God be good to him!" or "God be with him!"
in Gaelic "The blessing of God with his soul!"
and "The light of Heaven to him!"Donahoe's.
Sketches of Shakers and Shakerism. A synopsis of the United Society of Believers in Christ's Second
Appearing. Illustrated. By Giles
B. Avery.    Price 15 cts.--><pb n="49" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hidden manna" TEIform="index"/>THE MIDDEN MANNA.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, Jessie" TEIform="persName"/>By Jessie Evans.</byline><p TEIform="p">AMONG the breathings of God given for the courage and heavenward perseverance of souls,
                            perhaps none is more precious than the sublime promise : "He that hath an ear, let him hear
                            what the Spirit saith unto the churches ; To him that overcometh will I give to eat of the
                            hidden manna." It seems to add a sequel to the Savior's words : "Blessed are they which do
                            hunger and thirst after righteousness ; for they shall be filled." Much has been experienced
                            and written of the conflict through which the soul must pass in order to merge the selfish
                            will into the divine will, sacred writ is flooded with light to lead the soul to an
                            attainment of this all-important result, yet the desirable blessing remains to many still
                            afar off. The world is full of wranglings and unrest, and the sea of human life is crested
                            with many billows. Creeds are dissected and discarded, the church vainly seeks a remedy for
                            its scant assemblies, the pulpit is derided for proclaiming too much or too little truth, or
                            rather because it does not present that type of truth (?) which is elastic enough to
                            circumvest personal pride and still ease the pangs of a sleepless conscience. But a
                            revelation of this nature has not yet come from God, and those who defer the vital decisions
                            of salvation untiL a day of legal compromise will wait in vain. The voice "crying in the
                            wilderness" awakened some who had "ears to hear" and the "Lamb of God" followed to find a
                            few souls waiting for his immortal doctrine. Will this doctrine ever please the public ear?
                            The text seems to point to the negative view. <pb n="50" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 50 THE MANIFESTO. The
                            overcomer referred to is not a passive character who has acquired a title without toil; he
                            is in every sense of the word a reformer, a transformer. Into his life has been received,
                            willingly or not, a powerful, pungent testimony, which, received from the lips and life of
                            the uncompromising Savior, and sealed by the Fatherhood which authorized the Christhood,
                            puts to the sword all the enemies that refuse to surrender. Narrow, selfish affections
                            dissolve in the broad universal love which the new commandment signalizes. Personal
                            preferences are gradually, often painfully, merged into the all-absorbing yearning to follow
                            the divine appointments. This is not the work of a moment, nor the bauble of a child. The
                            sinews of his manhood are daily tested by a law before which human strength is weakness, in
                            whose even balance the least shall be the greatest, "a little one shall become a thousand
                            and a small one a strong nation." The fibres of his self-will vibrate with many a thrill of
                            suffering unechoed by the world, the tears of his soul he conceals behind a placid
                            countenance lest men should gain his spirit's secret and cloud the horizon of his pure
                            sacrifice with their weak human sympathy. But the struggle escapes not the slumberless One,
                            God is ever cognizant, and his perfect law provides for the safety of his wrestling children
                            lest at any time they dash the foot against a stone, human or otherwise. Though of the
                            earth, earthy, they have established in their hearts a new kingdom where an enlightened
                            conscience is enthroned, to whom every faculty of body and mind gives honor in willing
                            subservience. While resident on the earth, they are not "of the world," their minds have
                            risen "above the blue" into the hidden pastures by a path that "no fowl knoweth, and which
                            the vulture's eye hath not seen ;" and a " highway shall be there, and a way, and it shall
                            be called The way of holiness; the unclean shall not pass over it," not because the redeemed
                            guard the holy spot from intruders but because the force of God's law is inexorable. The
                            overcomer enters into a wonderful inheritance. He finds himself, by divine promise, an "heir
                            of God" and a "joint heir with Christ." The fruitfulness of the earth insures the
                            maintenance of the natural man, that which conduces to the health of the body springs up on
                            every hand." But the Lord is mindful of his own, he remembers his children," and his grace
                            is richly provident of the good things invisible that sustain and build up the soul. Famine
                            comes only to the prodigal, husks are eaten in the "far-off" countries, "bread enough and to
                            spare" is in the Father's realm. They who meet the discipline of sorrow and realize the
                            blessedness of the ^refining processes outlined by the law of eternal right, enter into a
                            community of soul, whose open doors "no man can shut." Kindred souls find each other sooner
                            or later, a common bond attracts them, a freemasonry of spirit exists among them, and the
                            signs and counter-signs invite a confidence never misplaced. To such, who are strangely
                            always in the minority, if God's side can ever <pb n="51" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 51 be a
                            minority, the prophets speak in comforting tones. The richest promises of God rise from the
                            pages of sacred history for their consolation. The strife between practice and principle
                            having ceased, the Christian feels the power of peace resulting from the relinquishment of
                            his life forces to divine law. Surrounding influences exert a great power as he awakens to
                            the responsibility of adapting his little life to the larger life around him that God's
                            glory may he the issue of every hour. Godly lives corroborate his experience, holy counsel
                            confirms his faith, thoughtful prayers strengthen his courage, and a brother's hand of
                            fellowship communicates a vigor that gives a firmer ring to his voice, leaves a deeper
                            furrow behind his plough of daily service, and imparts a richer hue to his consecration.
                            Contrary influences, on the other hand, try and rivet his faith, they test the resisting
                            capacity of his steadfastness, under the strong wind of adversity like a sound tree he
                            strikes his roots deep and wide to withstand the force, and in the storm he best learns the
                            use of his anchor, compass and sounding-line. So the Christian loves his friend and his
                            enemy. Both foster his spiritual growth, both fulfill a wise design in the divine planning.
                            One strengthens his virtues, the other exposes his weaknesses. Neither must be evaded if the
                            growth be symmetrical. Truly, God's wisdom has provided good friends for the Christian. But
                            all this points outward. Away from the strength that circumstances and associations bring to
                            him, there is in the heart of the overcomer an abiding substance, a living presence, a
                            divine entity, which proves true, at every mile-stone of his ennobling journey, the sacred
                            promise quoted by the Revelator. His spiritual seuses recognize this invisible reality, this
                            necessity. His soul accepts with avidity the blessed food, that tones up its tissues and
                            empowers it for renewed activity, and looks never in vain for its constant bestowal. Every
                            day the manna drops from heaven into the inner wilderness and his soul freely gathers it in
                            according to its need. Once this precious manna puts vitality into a man's inmost being and
                            the hunger is gone forever, for the supply never fails. He who feeds his soul energies upon
                            this food shall live forever, for as the natural manna repaired the waste of the physical
                            man, so this "hidden manna," bestowed by an all-wise Providence, contains all the elements
                            for the upbuilding of the spiritual man. As he prays "Give us this day our daily bread" and
                            his hands earnestly labor for the "meat which perisheth," his soul reaches upward into the
                            goodness of God's promise to secure its daily supply of that "meat which endureth unto
                            everlasting life." If he gather much in his mental voracity he has "nothing over," and if in
                            humble sorrow he gathers little he knows "no lacks," for He who sends the precious food
                            supplies just what is needed, and the soul is permitted to appropriate only what is for its
                            nutrition. Our Savior said, "If any man eat of this bread he shall live forever." But
                            reception only is not sufficient. This must be followed by the slower, more permanent
                            processes of absorption and assimilation, and where the "stature <pb n="52" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 52 THE
                            MANIFESTO. of the fulness of Christ" is maintained, the hygiene of the soul imposes fasting
                            as well as feasting days. Spiritual law is wonderfully adapted to the health of souls, all
                            so similar in need yet so strangely different in structure. "One man's meat is another man's
                            poison" as really in the spiritual as in the physical economy ; and the relish of the soul
                            is directed intuitively toward that which is for its best good. Hence we can not follow with
                            impunity the regimen of others. Were we dependent upon others' givings for our soul
                            supplies, the problem of capital and labor might intrude itself upon the religious as upon
                            the material world, but monopoly ceases when we enter the new birth. Here it is man for man.
                            "Whatsoever a man soweth, that shall he also reap." We may do good for and to each other,
                            and the world cries out daily for more of this philanthropic spirit, but the law of eternal
                            equity metes out to the giver the measure of his giving and to the receiver the measure of
                            his receiving, "God is not mocked." Influence does much to fashion individual character, but
                            when in the history of souls judgment is laid to the line and "righteousness to the
                            plummet," the spiritual stature of manwill it not be determined by the ' 'measuring rod" of
                            personal power, aspiration and attainment ? "I have meat to eat that ye know not of," the
                            Savior said, and to the solitude of the mountain he repaired for his soul feast. As did he,
                            so should his disciples do. Christian silence marks the hour of truest worship, for then the
                            soul is eloquent, and in holy communion it feasts on the bread broken and blessed by its
                            "Author and Bishop." All the real things of God are invisible to the natural eye, and
                            unspeakable in human syllables. We may speak of them, but we can never describe them. So the
                            heavenly manna is known only to "him that receiveth it," but the life which it supports, the
                            eternal energy which it establishes is destined to people the Christian world with manhood
                            and womanhood, citizens worthy the name and nerved to meet the crises of the times without
                            blenching. Are you still hungering in spirit? Christ says to you, "I am the bread of life ;
                            he that cometh to me shall never hunger; and he that believeth on me shall never thirst."
                            East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thoughts penned by an invalid" TEIform="index"/>
                            THOUGHTS PENNED BY AN INVALID.</head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by Elder John Whiteley.]
                            iLGive us this day our daily bread." WE are too apt to dwell on the future rather than in the
                            present moment ! How frequently we hear people say, "I will do such a thing to-morrow" or
                            next spring or fall or the coming year. I heard some one say a few days since, "We are
                            talking over our plans for next summer" and the <pb n="53" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTOi 53
                            thought came to me "Ye know not what a day may bring forth for in such an hour as ye think
                            not the Son of Man cometh." Man goes forth in the morning full of strength and hope, and
                            before the evening comes, he is cut down and the place that knew him knows him no more ! How
                            important then it is for us, my gospel friends, that we should guard and improve the
                            present, for upon this day and moment the future must rest, for the noiv will soon become
                            the past, beyond recalland as we reflect upon it we should ask ourselves "if we have quit
                            ourselves like men." In order then to obtain a proper spiritual frame, our souls must be fed
                            with that bread of life which cometh down from Heaven, seeking only for that which is
                            highest, purest and best. Too many persons are apt to think that when we ask for our daily
                            bread, it means simply, that which supplies our physical wants ! But it means more, for
                            while we should see to it with scrupulous care that nothing enters into the "temple of the
                            living God" that would debase or weaken it, we should be all the more impressed with the
                            great importance of having our spiritual natures furnished with proper food and nourishment,
                            and that regularly and constantly. How often are we inclined to neglect to furnish by prayer
                            and faith, the nourishment needed to fill our soul's requirements. We say we will wait for
                            "some more convenient season" which in many cases results in nothing being done. As the body
                            becomes weakened and unfitted to do its proper work if it receives not proper nourishment,
                            so must the soul that is neglected become dwarfed and enfeebled. We then can not too
                            urgently or frequently ask the good Father and Mother to send love into our hearts, for if
                            we are filled with that, we have indeed the bread of life which will enable us not only to
                            enter into the joys of this life, but will help us to journey on cheerfully toward the joys
                            that belong to the home above, the delight of which we can but faintly imagine. For there
                            will be no tears, no separations, but love divine abides. May the daily bread of love,
                            peace, faith and joy ever be found on our life's table, and the loving Father and Mother its
                            constant guests.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Autobiography of sister Mary Hazard" TEIform="index"/>AUTOBIOGRAPHY OF SISTER MARY HAZARD.</head><p TEIform="p">I was born November 11, 1811, in Hancock, Berkshire Co., Mass. My first known ancestor,
                            Robert Hazard, came from Wales, in 1640 and settled in Rhode Island. Some time in 1700,
                            Jonathan Hazard, his grandson, and my great-grandfather with his family moved to Hancock,
                            Mass., then a new country, where my father was born in 1775. My mother, Lucy Vaughn, was
                            also born in 1775, and they were married in 1796. I was the youngest of eight children. My
                            father, a Justice of the Peace, was called Squire Hazard. He represented the town and state
                            and was for a time Senator of the state. During his term in office there was great
                            excitement about war, and all must enlist as soldiers or pay a heavy fine; and it was
                            through my father's influence that the <pb n="54" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 54 THE MANIFESTO. Shakers in
                            Massachusetts were exempt, on account of religious principles, from learning war or paying
                            the fine. The Brethren from the Shaker settlement frequently called to see him on business,
                            and altho a child, I saw something in these Brethren which seemed so good and pure that I
                            was very much attracted to them. About this time I became acquainted with Mary Fairbanks, a
                            distant relative, who had children among the Shakers. She told me much about her youngest
                            daughter Olive, how happy she was, and once when returning from a visit to the Shakers,
                            brought me a letter from Olive in which she invited me to visit her at New Lebanon. This
                            invitation pleased me, and I wanted very much to go there and attend school. I askt my
                            parents but my mother opposed the plan. My father being better acquainted with the Shakers,
                            made no objection but insisted if I went that I should return when the school term closed.
                            Shortly after this two Brethren called on my father and he mentioned to them my desire to go
                            to the Shaker school. They replied that he had done so much for the Shakers they would be
                            pleased to have me come. "But," said they, "what if she wishes to stay?" He said he would
                            willingly consent, but my mother was opposed to my going even for a short time. Nevertheless
                            I continued my pleadings until mother consented. In June 1824 two Brethren came again to
                            consult with my father, and invited my parents to attend the dedication of their new
                            Meetinghouse on the Sabbath, July, 4. They accepted the invitation and decided to grant my
                            long cherished desire, to go with them and remain for the school term; and when I went to
                            get my books I bade a silent farewell to my former school, feeling I should never return to
                            it; which proved to be true. As soon as I arrived at the village I felt perfectly at home.
                            The next day being the Sabbath we attended the dedication of the Church. Afterward, my
                            parents visited with the Brethren and Sisters, and my mother's opposition changed into love
                            for the people, and she readily gave her consent for me to remain if I chose to do so and my
                            parents both promist never to take me away and their word was as good as law. Living so near
                            my parents, at their request I often visited them, and sometimes my young companions, just
                            entering into society, would plead with me to remain with them and held out many temptations
                            of the worldly life; but my love for and interest in my Shaker home was stronger than all
                            their enticements and they past me by as the idle wind. My parents always gave me good
                            counsel and taught me to be industrious and prudent; be kind, and if it was my choice to
                            remain with the Shakers, to live according to my profession. My father would say: "Mary, if
                            you want to be a Shaker be what you profess, and don't be a hypocrite. Be careful of the
                            company you keep for there is danger everywhere of young people gathering to those of weak
                            moral character instead of the strong." My mother always said she took more comfort visiting
                            me than any of her children, altho they were all well married and comfortably settled in
                            life. I have always had a double love and honor for my parents that they were willing to
                            give me up to follow my own religious inclinations, and to strengthen me in my belief and
                            altho I had everything in my father's house that I could desire, it was not to be compared
                            to the happiness I enjoyed in my Shaker home with so many like myself, who had sacrificed
                            the world for the pure spiritual life. During the thirteen years I lived at the North
                            family, my parents provided all my clothing or gave me the money to use as I needed. In
                            1837, there being several deaths in the Church family, I was askt by the Elders if I was
                            ready for a fuller consecration, to leave my home at the North family <pb n="55" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE MANIFESTO. 55 and become a "Church member" which in those dajs meant more of a
                            separation from my natural kindred. I replied that I would go. I then went with some of my
                            Shaker friends to acquaint my parents with my proposed change, telling them I should not see
                            them as frequently as I had done, all of which seemed right to them and when on the 7th of
                            June I ascended the steps to my new home at the Church family, I felt like a virgin about to
                            consecrate her life in the Temple of Holiness. In the year 1846 I was askt to assist in the
                            Office and in 1851 was appointed one of the deaconesses, where I remained until December
                            1896. In all my years of service I have aimed to be just in all my dealings and true to the
                            Community whose interest I was privileged to guard. Having signed the Church Covenant soon
                            after my admittance into the Church, in all the years I have occupied as financial assistant
                            I have never spent the value of a dollar for myself only as I shared with my Sisters. In my
                            father's will which he often showed to me, there was much bequeathed me, but just previous
                            to his death some who married into the family altered the will, in a way that I could ha\ e
                            but a small portion unless I left the Shakers, and knowing I would not do that, they felt
                            sure of being the gainers. By some unknown or unfair means they gained my father's signature
                            to it. But the $1000 I did receive in money, according to the Covenant I had signed I freely
                            devoted to the interests of Community, and felt happy in giving my little to the home I
                            loved, while I pitied those whose conscience must be troubled with what they had gained by
                            fraud. Now in my declining years I have a conscience void of offence before God and man. I
                            have naught but love and blessing for those who bear the heavy burdens of Community in this
                            day, and I pray that they may be blest with wisdom in all their duties. I love and bless all
                            my faithful Brethren and Sisters, praying that my advanced age may never find me a burden
                            where I have always determined to be a blessing. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Order of mediation, no. 3" TEIform="index"/>THE ORDER OF MEDIATION. NO. 3.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lyon, John" TEIform="persName"/>By Elder John Lyon.</byline><p TEIform="p">iHHE new creation is clearly typified by this dispensation, not only in the _L laying of its
                            foundation in a mediatorial order but in its being sustained1' as God's mediatorial order,
                            both with those who lived in obedience, and with those who lived in disobedience. God always
                            so adapted the means to the end that when He laid His plans, it was from an immutable
                            source, unalterable, leaving no alternative for man. He must comply with it or suffer the
                            penalty. Man was created an earthly being, and was endowed with all the animal propensities
                            like the rest of the animal creation. He was also endowed with a rational soul, capable of
                            spiritual existence, and God evidently intended that when he had faithfully fulfilled his
                            earthly duty he should rise to a spiritual order. The law given to Adam was to govern the
                            earth, and by ruling his own nature, he ruled the earth. Had Adam kept the law and remained
                            in sub- <pb n="56" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 56 THE MANIFESTO mission to God, there could have been no
                            possibility of the powers of evil leading him away from God. As man did not keep his
                            rectitude it was necessary that a way should be provided to effect a resurrection. In the
                            fullness of time, God introduced the creation of the new heavens and earth, by creating a
                            new man, with all the animal propensities like Adam. God gave to him power to rule his own
                            life, and left him to his own free choice, either to obey the will and command of his
                            Creator, or rebel, and be subject to his animal inclinations. In the resurrection state he
                            was called the second Adam, and became the resurrection to whom all souls must come, and was
                            called Jesus (Savior) because he should save his people from their sins. Jesus said, "I am
                            the resurrection and the life."John, xi., 25. When Jesus was about thirty years of age, God
                            anointed him with wisdom and power, and gave unto him the elements of eternal life. "Thou
                            art my beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased." It was at this period of his life that he
                            began the work of regeneration, and for the space of three years he "trod the wine-press
                            alone." God appointed Jesus as a mediator between himself and man. To qualify him for this
                            office God put all things into his hands relative to the order of the New Creation. As Jesus
                            said unto Thomas, "I am the way, the truth and the life; no man cometh to the Father but by
                            me."John, xiv., 6. Jesus did not come in his own name, but God, his Father, sent him with
                            the proclamation to the world, "No man cometh to the Father but by me." To show that the
                            mediatorial agency was given to man, Jesus called himself the Son of man. Scripture, at
                            length, might be quoted to show with what power God anointed him. Jesus declared that he had
                            power to forgive sin. He is Lord of the Sabbath and of all things in relation to the New
                            Creation. He declared to his followers that he who sowed the good seed was the Son of man,
                            and that the harvest was the end of the world. When he should come, he would sit on the
                            throne of his glory, and that all nations should be gathered before him, and that he would
                            separate them, as the shepherd the sheep from the goats. THE FOUNDATION WORK. We will now
                            take a view of the principles by which Jesus laid the foundation of his work. His kingdom
                            was submission to that power by which he was appointed,"I came down from heaven, not to do
                            mine own will, but the will of Him that sent me."John, vi., 38. I can of myself do nothing,
                            as I hear I judge and my judgment is just, because I seek not mine own will but the will of
                            the Father who sent me. Jesus taught his followers the impossibility of entering this
                            kingdom without submission to God and as God has appointed a mediator, how is it possible
                            for anyone to be in submission to God unless he is in submission to the mediator? Whoever
                            sets at naught those appointed in the mediatorial order of God, have no God. <pb n="57" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 57 Jesus said, "Verily I say unto you, except ye be converted
                            and become as little children ye shall not enter the kingdom of heaven."Matt, xviii., 3. He
                            taught them the importance of humility on entering the work of regeneration. "If any man
                            will come after me, let him deny himself and take up his cross and follow me." It is true
                            that Jesus taught many moral precepts in order to prepare the people to enter the work of
                            regeneration. "Verily, verily I say unto you, he that receiveth whomsoever I send, receiveth
                            me, and he that receiveth me, receiveth him that sent me." After Jesus had established this
                            foundation, no one who belonged to the order of regeneration, ever found access to Jesus or
                            to God through him unless they found him in an earthen vessel. Perhaps some will, say that
                            Saul found him on his way to Damascus when he saw a bright light and was struck to the
                            earth. This agent was to put Saul in a situation to find the Mediator. {To be
                        continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keeping busy" TEIform="index"/>KEEPING BUSY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilson, Joseph A." TEIform="persName"/>By Joseph A. Wilson.</byline><p TEIform="p">IT is a peculiar part of human nature for the mind to be continually active. No matter how
                            indolent, improvident or careless an individual may be, if he or she be possessed of a
                            healthy brain,his or her mind is continually employed, either for good or evil. The mind is
                            never dormant, like time, it keeps moving on, and unless properly busied, it will find its
                            way into mischief. A very prominent gentleman once said, on being asked how he managed to be
                            successful and happy, that he always managed to keep just a little more work ahead of him
                            than he could comfortably do during any given time. He kept employed. The moment one becomes
                            idle the brain still works on, and, unless better employed, will find its way into
                            difficulties. Under such circumstances, and at such times, one dreams over real or fancied
                            troubles,broods over the dead past, or sees and points out the faults of others. By keeping
                            busy one must not necessarily be employed at some manual labor. Not at all. A good book or
                            some errand of mercy will do as well. But anything that enables one to rise above the petty
                            jealousies, and refrain from the annoying gossiping that often mars life, and ruins its
                            sweetest charm, is good. A closer communion with the Holy Writ, and keeping well employed
                            are commendable. White Water, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oh what is worth our thoughts..." TEIform="index"/>Oh what is worth our thoughts...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Oh what is worth our thoughts, our labor, our affections while here, but that which will tell
                            for eternity.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. P.</byline></div2><pb n="58" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. APRIL, 1899. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is publisht by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all communications
                            to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. TERMS. One copy one year, postage paid.
                            A cross in the margin will show that your subscription has closed. .50 subscription by Money
                            Order should be on the Post Office at Concord, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">February. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Rain. Snow. 1898. 29.5 }4 in.
                                23 in. 1899. 24.43 % " 37 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 50 above 0. Lowest " " " " 10
                                below" Number of rainy days " " 1 " " snowy " " " 7 " " clear " " " 6 " " cloudy" " " 14
                                March, 1899. Lo! The winter is past with its cold chilling blast, but its direful
                                effects still rest upon us, enfeebling many, among the group is numbered Eldress Dorothy
                                Wright. Her first ailment was a sprained ankle. Her second is pleurisy. Hope this will
                                be the last. 1899 thus far has been a season of affliction and sickness. Very few, if
                                any, but what have had a draught of the bitter in some form. We are engaged at present
                                in putting a new boiler in our Extract Laboratory and repairing the building otherwise.
                                As Brother Alonzo G. Hollister will soon be in your midst, he can give you all the
                                particulars. Snow, ice, rain and slush form our variegated highways, which make
                                traveling very unpleasant. A few hands are working on the State Road, but the work moves
                                at snail pace. I am putting the bit and martingale on my pen lest it writes more than
                                300 words and thus break the kind Editor's law. "O, deem it not an idle thing A pleasant
                                word to speak; The face you wear, the tho'ts you bring, A heart may heal or break."
                                "I'lant blessing, and blessing will bloom; Plant hate, and hate will grow; You may sow
                                to-day, to-morrow will bring The blossom that proves what sort of thing Is the seed,the
                                seed you sow." Calvin G. Reed. South Family. March, 1899. Time's on the march, the quick
                                march too And April, May, the same thing do; To the march of time there is no end
                                Eternity with time must blend. Our ice has proved a clear success, 'Twas clear as
                                crystal, and the best; From twelve to thirteen inches thickT Gathered thoroughly and
                                quick. When come the days of hot July, The healthful ice we'll not pass by, 'Twill have
                                a place in drink and food, And all will then pronounce it good. Our fire wood is well
                                secured For one more yearwe're well assured. Our blessings all, we can not count, To
                                legions many they amount. Sometime we'll have a new "high way," 'Twill be cast up some
                                future day, For builders work upon the road, While up and down men draw their loads. <pb n="59" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 59 And some will sing and some will swear The old
                                road's steepthey just declare. Some to their horses they are kind While others, they are
                                not, we find. But oh! we wish that they could see How wicked it is not to be. Of Eldress
                                Annie we can say She is improving, day by day. La Grippe has lost its grip, at last, And
                                gone with winter that is past. We hope our friends both far and near Have lost their
                                "grip" and found good cheer. We hope good health again may reign From Florida to breezy
                                Maine. And to our Editor we send Our best of wishes without end. Genevieve DeGraw. North
                                Family. March, 1899. Winter is usually considered a dull time, but this year, the latter
                                end of it has been made almost too interesting for us by a visit from the grippe.
                                Happily, he is now departing with the departing season, and tho he has done us little
                                serious harm, we hope he will mislay our address, or do something or other that will
                                prevent his ever returning. Out of doors snow has lately been very much in evidence, and
                                so, little has been done that required open air labor. We have had some eighty tons of
                                hay baled, as that seemed to be necessary in order to make room for next summer's crop:
                                and soon we hope to begin sawing up our next winter's supply of wood, which up till now
                                we have been hindered from doing, one thing and another coming in the way. Of spring's
                                close presence we find ample proof in the arrival of plentiful lambs, white-faced some,
                                and some black-faced, but all of them, chock-full of fun. Calves too are many just now.
                                Our brother Floyd has some eighteen of them under his care at present, and is doing very
                                well with them, and they are such clever calves too! On Christmas day, he informed us
                                that they could eat hay when they were a week old, and added, that was more than we
                                could do at that age; and we had perforce to admit such was the sorrowful case. Under
                                Brother George's excellent care, our poultry continue to give a very abundant supply of
                                eggs; considering the season of the year : and in such wise go our temporal activities.
                                We try to find in them avenues or windows through which to look out into the eternal,
                                for it is only half using this beautiful world we live in, to let our sight be stopped
                                by the object that it meets, and make no attempt to see further. Frederic McKechme.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">March, 1899. Evidences are rapidly accumulating as proof of the fact that the gift, or if
                                we may use a more modern phrase the science of spiritual healing has not become a thing
                                of the past, unable to manifest its power as a beneficent factor in the regeneration and
                                resurrection of life in both the physical and spiritual domain. The increasing number of
                                magazines, weekly and monthly, which are advocates of the truth of the doctrine of
                                spiritual healing and advocate'its application both for relief and cure of the many ills
                                of life is proving the truth of the scriptural statement that "man can not live by bread
                                alone;" it being interpreted from the knowledge that the externalities of life's
                                manifestation cannot satisfy the immortal spirit, neither are they capable of
                                ministering the true resurrection to the physical, or can they place human life above
                                the influence of drug medication whose advocates are at present seeking through
                                legislative enactments to suppress the beneficent efforts of those who through the gift
                                of healing are seeking to alleviate human suffering. From all points of the compass;
                                from Maine to Oregon, California, Texas, Florida and many other sections of the country
                                we have received literature advocating" the use of that beneficent gift and we can <pb n="60" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. with joy exclaim, Lord our eyes are beginning to
                                see the glory of thy salvation. May our days be long that we may witness the blessed
                                fulfillment of thy promise, the healing of the nations. The editorial in March number on
                                "The food we eat," can be given no higher praise from our feeble pen than that it has
                                spoken the truth on that important subject. How few there are that are blest with a
                                healthy digestive organization capable of assimilating the food needed to build up a
                                healthy body? and how few there are that give that important subject the consideration
                                that it deserves. Let the good work go on; we will cast our mite into the mighty caldron
                                of constructive thought that it may help forward the good time coming when human life
                                will stand upright in its physical and spiritual aspects, the highest embodiment of the
                                creative presence. Hamilton DeOraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">March, 1899. Makch came in like a lamb, but no doubt we shall hear the lion's roar before
                                he goes out. Thus far some of the days have been very fine. We have commenced our spring
                                work in the greenhouse; seedsowing, etc. The Brethren have lately put a No. 2. Baby
                                Separator into our cow-barn and this will lessen the dairy work to some extent. They are
                                getting over 32 gallons of milk per day. The Separator cream tested 32 per cent butter
                                fat, while the old creamery cream tested 22 per cent. General Eepairs is stopping with
                                us. I notice the window blinds, of one house and then another, missing and find on
                                inquiry they are undergoing a reformation of a new coat. So are many of the rooms in the
                                brick dwelling, also sleighs, wagons, etc., which have been in with the Oeneral and come
                                out looking quite new. Our deserted Village, the Poland Hill Farm, has at last been sold
                                to the Kicker Brothers, who will soon turn it into a very beautiful place which their
                                guests will enjoy visiting. The family have been afflicted with much sickness the past
                                month, which was a great hinderance to our fancy basketwork. Nearly all have had La
                                Grippe in one form or another, but at last all are safe and that is much to be thankful
                                for. Ada S. CumniinffS.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">March, 1899. We realize as the lengthening days pass that "winter's reign is nearly
                                over," and that soon spring, the loved harbinger of birds and flowers will be with us,
                                and with gentle smile and touch awaken nature's sleeping children to renewed life. We
                                are willing to bid adieu to poor, overworkt winter. Surely his part has been performed
                                faithfully and he should be awarded due praise. The snow has fallen thick and fast, the
                                wind catching it has piled it in huge drifts here and there, the thermometer has reacht
                                a lower point than for many years, and a genuine blizzard has been introduced to
                                complete the record. But intersperst with this have been bright, sunshiny days when
                                jingling sleigh-bells chimed merry times as the sleighs past over the smooth snow. The
                                ice, of fine quality, and plenteous in supply, was promptly gathered, for we find in
                                spite of our dislike for winter we enjoy a little of its preserved essence during the
                                warm summer months. La Grippe laid seige to our home in February, and for a few weeks
                                held us unwilling captives. Still we did not despair but rallying our weakening forces
                                struck a final blow for liberty and rose to conquer. Day and night we waged warfare
                                until the enemy beat a retreat, not being able to cope with our armed forces, who fought
                                with pellets and plasters so skillfully. At present the wounded are nearly recovered and
                                peace once more reigns. The busy mill at the foot of the hill, and the buzzing saw in
                                the valley, are at work all day converting once stately trees <pb n="61" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                MANIFESTO. 61 into boards and cords of wood for extensive uses. And so with its lights
                                and shades time passes onward. Already nearly a quarter of the new year has become a
                                part of the past. May the days yet awaiting be filled with blessing for our brothers and
                                sisters in other homes, while unitedly we endeavor to raise aloft our banner whose motto
                                is "Purity and Truth." Fidelia Estabrook.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">March, 1899. "Nature is blazing with the light of thought And mind effulgent with
                                divinity; For God alike through mind and matter wills, Works, ultimates himself
                                forevermore." Who, understanding the growth of nature and the laws of progressive
                                intelligences, can doubt that "God alike through mind and matter ultimates himself." Do
                                not the achievements in every moral, educational and scientific department of life, as
                                well as the more universal spirit of national and international union existing, all bear
                                impressions of "mind effulgent with divinity" that evolves the crude into better; the
                                triumph of right over wrong; of truth over error? In our national arena of life,
                                President McKinley and Gov. Roosevelt stand as men of high prestige, character and
                                Americanism, whose aim for political incorruption, bears one phase of "mind effulgent
                                with divinity." They are worthy recipients of a nation's homage, yet there are thousands
                                who, though not named on the nation's register of illustrious countrymen, are as worthy
                                of the epistles of commendation for well-doing, pledged to bear the Christian cross of
                                self-denial and to extend the staff of life to the needy and teach them the way of
                                victory over sin and self. Over a century ago, our Church was founded by like Christly,
                                stalwart souls, and to-day their noble successors fail not in receiving the coin of soul
                                appreciation for merited work. Since last "note" we welcomed our revered Ministry from
                                Mt. Lebanon. They were accompanied by our valued Eldress Emeline Hart, lately appointed
                                to the place made vacant by the ascension of Eldress Joanna Kaime, and Eldress Harriet
                                Johns, appointed as associate with Eldress Emeline. A unanimous greeting was accorded
                                Eldress Harriet. If we all blend with the eternal integrity and willforce of the Christ
                                spirit as we feel its forces from within and from each other, we will know that "God
                                ultimates himself in our lives and to the work of blessing others." Winter is preparing
                                his dirge of decadence, at which we grieve not, as we all long to hear the new song of
                                balmy spring. Snow enough to make sledding easy enough to draw from the hills 100,000
                                ft. of logs, 200 cords of fire wood, and 17 cords ^of ice from Mascoma Lake. George H.
                                Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoossee, Florida" TEIform="index"/> Narcoossee, Fla.</head><p TEIform="p">March, 1899. The lessons that the Florida farmers and gardeners are learning are both
                                pertinent and timely. And every one who feels to come to Florida for a home and live by
                                agriculture should read the last five year's experience of the state. It has taught
                                those who are now living here that the greater portion of the state is unsafe for the
                                culture of tropical fruits and winter vegetables with more chances against them than in
                                favor of profitable returns, excepting in the sections below the twenty-sixth parallel
                                or region not materially damaged by any cold up to date. There the orange, the lemon,
                                the pine-apple, and guavas, with other tropical fruits, have never been seriously
                                damaged by frosts. This is a small country compared to the area of the state and will
                                always be until some of the great and noble minds who have the wealth feel enough for
                                the good of humanity to open their purses as well as their hearts and spend a few
                                thousand dollars in draining the Everglades. <pb n="62" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 62 THE MANIFESTO. We
                                have suffered little compared with many of our friends north of us. As our greatest aim
                                has been in cultivating the pine-apple, our greatest efforts were turned in time of the
                                freeze for the salvation of that crop, and at this date we have the consolation of
                                seeing our efforts rewarded by about seven-eighths of the crop. It is safe to say there
                                is but little damage done to our cane field, excepting a small percentage of the stubble
                                cane from which we made our last year's crop of syrup. It is generally expected that a
                                reasonable crop will result from it the second year, but the crop we are depending upon
                                was all planted before the freeze and received no hurt. We also have a large piece of
                                cassava which was planted at the same time that is in good condition. These are our
                                three staple crops and should we succeed in saving these we shall feel that we have come
                                out of the blizzard with but little damage. True, our winter vegetables, with the
                                exception of cabbage, onions and turnips were all cut down and we have had but very few,
                                but we are thankful for what we have had. Andrew Barrett.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Food we eat, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>THE FOOD WE EAT. NO. 2.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder H. C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">FitoM a very early date the growing, moral state of mankind has revolted against this
                            vulture-like system of eating, and Abraham has the honor of being the first reformer in
                            dietetics. Following him on this same line was that wonderful plan of reformation under the
                            Mosaic Law, and its faithful continuance bytthe Jewish nation. Through the influence of that
                            law many of the most objectionable animals as well as birds and fishes were prohibited as
                            food. And yet this moral discipline had no influence on the surrounding nations, as they
                            continued the practice of an omnivorous diet, and we as children of those parents have
                            largely inherited their tastes and appetites so that those who now profess to lead a
                            Christian life, and those who make no profession are equally ready to justify the course
                            that is taken in eating both fat and blood and also the flesh of all the clean and unclean
                            Biblical animals. Certainly, it can do no harm to give this subject a passing thought as
                            there is not much danger that one or two degrees more of moral elevation will do us any
                            special injury. The New Testament has but little to say on the subject of food, for the
                            simple reason that Jesus and his disciples were all educated under the Jewish Law and were
                            thoroughly disciplined in regard to the food they should eat. At a later date a disturbance
                            arose among the Gentile Christians that gave the apostle Paul some little trouble before he
                            could restore peace to the church. When Peter fell into a trance and saw a sheet let down
                            from heaven on which were all manner of fourfooted beasts, and creeping things and fowls of
                            the air, and he was told to kill and eat he was evidently astonisht. He had up to this date
                            received his inspiration from Moses and the prophets. We are not surprised that Peter was
                            frightened at such an exhibition, as it would have frightened any Jewish Christian. It was
                            enough for him to know the Law had forbidden the eating of unclean animals, but when he
                            learned that it was intended only for a lesson to make him more charitable to the Gentile
                            nation, he accepted the vision with good grace. A thoughtful writer H. A. Bradbury, in the
                            "World's Advance Thought" of Feb. 1895 writes as follows;"A reform is needed that has a
                            regenerative force to raise the being to a higher key of desire, for man's desires are
                            sensual, his appetites are depraved and he contracts unheard-of diseases; of passions and of
                            worldly lust he is full. Animal flesh food stimulates the propensities from whose unbridled
                            activity all the evil of the world results. If the thoughts are to be pure the environment
                            must be pure. It will not do to mix dead flesh with live <pb n="63" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 63 fruit nor make the stomach a disinfectant to digesting animal bodies." A
                            writer of this reformed order is establishing himself as one of the saviors of the race, and
                            his influence for good is of great value. The Apostle in his love for man writes;"To be
                            spiritually minded is life and peace," and the Christian should study what may help him to
                            become spiritually minded. With the above illustrations we may compare that of the
                            Hottentots of whom the African traveler, Barrow, writes;"Ten of our Hottentots ate a
                            middling sized ox all but his hind legs in three days." The same authority says; "Three
                            Bosjesmans had a sheep given to them at five p. m. which was entirely consumed before noon
                            the next day. These people are equally filthy and gluttonous with the voracious vultures and
                            are extremely sensual." After such a picture of the human family we can very readily turn
                            again to a class that stands on a higher elevation. Dr. L. Grossman writes in the Journal of
                            Hygeio-Therapy, of Dec. 1894, as follows; "We observe that civilized man lives on fruit only
                            in exceptional cases; in the main, however, he lives on a mixed diet, consisting of meat and
                            plant foods." "In the long run this must prove injurious and the ever increasing disease and
                            degeneration of our age, although in part due to other perverse conditions of life, teach
                            with appalling obviousness that a mixed diet can not be the one ordained by nature to man."
                            "Nearly all slaughtered animals are diseased, for fattening is based upon the principle of
                            the symptoms of disease." Man is learning that with an immortal soul he needs a more
                            disciplinary care for his life than do the beasts that perish. Head what was written by Dr.
                            L. M. Holbrook in the December Conservator:"Is animal food necessary to health and the
                            highest development of man? We do know that a very considerable portion of the race live
                            without animal food, and even in those races of which a majority consume it, there are many
                            individuals who do not seem to suffer very much, but rather gain by its non use." "We know
                            that disease (dyspepsia) is most prevalent where most meat is eaten. The moral sense of the
                            masses will never develop to that high degree of which it is capable so long as the
                            slaughter of animals is considered necessary to supply our daily food." After pursuing this
                            interesting subject so far and obtaining so much that is valuable from these thoughtful
                            minds, we accept this proverbial conclusion "Man is what he eats." This is also the opinion
                            of W. H. Galvani who wrote an interesting article on this subject in the R. P. J. of Feb.
                            1895. "The animals that subsist upon other animals are savage, spasmodic and lack
                            persistency of effort, while on the other hand the animals that subsist on such food only as
                            is obtained from the vegetable kingdom are comparatively mild, endure continuous labor and
                            possess persistency of effort. The craving for animal food is due to the presence in its
                            composition of certain extractives, which are the source of its being of a stimulating
                            character. Stimulating foods demand of the system stimulating drinks, and so develop a taste
                            for liquors." (To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible Class" TEIform="index"/>From the Bible Class.</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="'Martha, Martha, thou art careful..." TEIform="index"/>Martha, Martha, thou art careful...</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hathaway, Rebecca A." TEIform="persName"/>By Rebecca A. Hathaway.</byline><p TEIform="p">"Martha, Martha, thou art
                                careful and troubled about many things: But one thing is needful: smdMary hath chosen
                                that good part."Luke, x., 41, 42.
                                The above mentioned words were spoken by Jesus at one time when in the home of Martha and
                                Mary. Martha, who we perceive was earnestly engaged with household duties, was troubled
                                because her sister was sitting at the feet of Jesus, listening to the wise and beautiful
                                words which fell from his lips. We may trust that she was enabled to help some other
                                soul, from receiving this added blessing of strength. <pb n="64" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 64 THE
                                MANIFESTO. "But one thing is needful,"Martha was undoubtedly giving all her time and
                                strength to the providing of perishable things, perhaps knowing no higher need, nor
                                realizing the importance of the message being spoken by Jesus; Mary appeared negligent
                                in duty, hence Martha's appeal to Jesus;"Bid her therefore that she help me." Here was
                                Jesus' opportunity to impress a lesson of the immortality of his teachings. "Martha thou
                                art troubled about many things; but one thing is needful; and Mary hath chosen that good
                                part." Had he not previously taught, "Take no thought what ye shall eat, or what ye
                                shall drink, or wherewithal ye shall be clothed?"Take no anxious thought, let your first
                                and greatest concern be to "seek first the kingdom of God, and his righteousness, and
                                all things needful shall be added." We do not for one moment imagine that Jesus meant
                                the needful things of life would be added to the indolent and selfish ; but the Kingdom
                                of Heaven sought first, is a safe guide leading and guiding us in the daily walks of
                                life to follow where the Christ can bless, speak as the Christ would speak, and thus so
                                beautifully combine service with worship, as to render the whole life praise unto God.
                                Later in the second manifestation of the Christ spirit we have the guide, "Hands to
                                work" and "heart to God." The first condition, "Hands at work," may only signify toiling
                                for an earthly subsistence; "heart to God," added as a guide to the hands enables us to
                                fulfill by word and work the Savior's prayer, "Thy kingdom come, thy will be done in
                                earth as it is in heaven." East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be careful to leave your sons..." TEIform="index"/>Be careful to leave your sons...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Be careful to leave your sons well instructed, rather than rich; for the hopes of the
                            instructed are better than the wealth of the ignorant.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A weak mind is like a microscope..." TEIform="index"/>A weak mind is like a microscope...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A weak mind is like a microscope, which magnifies trifling things, but can not receive great
                            ones.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Best you can" TEIform="index"/>THE BEST YOU CAN.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">What use to frown when things go wrong? A frown won't set them right, Be brave of
                                    heart, and sing a song, To make the burden light! That this is true I quite believe;
                                    He is the wisest man Who sings when care and trouble come, And does the best he can.
                                    The man who broods o'er trouble finds His burdens heavier grow, As he climbs up the
                                    hill of life; The wise man does not so. He gathers flowers beside the way; He says
                                    to fellow-men "Let's make the most of pleasant things, Anddo the best we can." In
                                    thinking of another's need We oft forget our own; So let vis think of others more
                                    Not of ourselves alone. Keep up a brave and cheerful heart, 'Tis aye the wisest
                                    plan, To sing when care and trouble come, Anddo the best we can. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Standard" TEIform="index"/>.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="James Russell Lowell said..." TEIform="index"/>James Russell Lowell said...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">James Russell, Lowell said, "War," (generally) "is murder" and Gen. Sherman said, "War is
                            hell."</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Baltimore judge has decided..." TEIform="index"/>A Baltimore judge has decided...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Baltimore judge has decided that faith-cure doctors are not entitled to compensation.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dr. Brown says, 'Keep your feet warm..." TEIform="index"/>Dr. Brown says, 'Keep your feet warm...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Dr. Brown says, "Keep your feet warm, your head cool and throw medicine to the dogs."</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The influence of salt..." TEIform="index"/>The influence of salt...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> The influence of salt in any and all animal organisms is always destructive.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gifford, T. V." TEIform="persName"/>Dr. T. V. Gifford.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Copley, Elizabeth, Sr." TEIform="index"/>Elizabeth Copley, Sr.
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Elizabeth Copley, Sr., at Enfield, Conn. February 3, 1899. Age 82 years, 11 mo. and 7
                                days. She came across the Atlantic Ocean on account of her faith. She was true to it to
                                the end, in every sense of the word. S. E. C.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
POPULAR SCIENCE
Nature, Invention,
MruiPArchseology, Electricityliril TH
HLHuChemistry, Mineralogy,IILflL I II
Health, Hygien, Mdicme.
Pormerly Boston Journal of Ohemistry
ENLARGED and IMPROVED.
This popular monthly contains a large number of Short, Easy, Practical, Interesting and
Popular, Scientific articles, that can be Appreciated and Enjoyed by any intelligent reader,
even though he knew little or nothing of Science. It is intended to interest those who think
Profusely illustrated and Free
from Technicalities
Entirely Different from and much superior to
other papers with a similar name.
Monthly,  $1.60 per year.    Newsdealers,   15  cts.
Largest Circulation of any
Scientific Paper.
LILLAED & CO.,
108 Pulton St., New York.
  Mention this paper for a sample copy
HUMAN NATURE
is an illustrated Monthly, now only 50 cts.
per    year,    devoted   to   PHKENOLOGrY.
PHYSIOGNOMY,  HEALTH,   MEDIOAL
& SOCIAL EEPOEM.
Would you like a copy?
Send 5 cts. for Sample to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Francisco, Cal.
WONDERFUL strange REVELATION!,
DANIEL'S & STJOHN'S
PROPHECIES.
48 page pamphlet.    Price 10 cts.
13 for $1.00.
Address,   H. B. Beak, Pbeston, Ohio.
WITHOUT   DOUBT
THE BEST FAMILY PAPER PUBLISHED
IS   THE
NEW   YORK   WEEEY   WITNESS.
16 Pages.   Only   $1 a year.
Has a very wide scope, comprising as it
does the following departments:
Editorials,
Spirit of the Press,
Scientific and Instructive,
The Odd and Uncommon,
Our Country's Hope,
Foreign News,
A Talk With the Doctor,
Around the Hearth,
Little IVIen and Women,
Weekly Articles y Georg-e R. Scott
Talmag-e's Mention,
Money and Business,
World-Wide Field,
Our Family Story,
Farui and Garden,
Market Reports,
SABBATH READING.
16 Pages.   Only 50 cents a Year.
An Inter-denominational Weekly Paper.
Sabbath Heading is solely religious.
No news; no politics. A grand paper
for the truth-seeker.    It contains:
Editorial.
Christian Endeavor Topic,
Epwortta Iieag-ue Topic,
Sablmth-School Lntnon,
Choice Poetry,
Crood Stories,
Reports o Missions,
Mothers* Sabbath Afternoon
With the Children,
And a mss of matter carefully seleoted.
Send for free sample copies of Witness
and Sabbath Reading. And send for
free sample pages of our Bagster's Bible.
Address
JOHN DOUGALL& CO., 150 Nassau Street, New York.
EXPLAINING
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
ROYAL
Baking
Powder
Absolutely Pure
Makes the food more delicious and wholesome
____________________ROYAL BAKING POWDER CO., NEW YORK.
SHAKER HAMAMELIS
(WITCHHAZEL,)
A. remedy for Cuts, Burns, Scalds,
Headache, Sore Throat and all
cases of external inflammation
Taken internally for Bowel
Complaint, Bleeding of the
Lungs or Bowels, and for
all aches and pains.
For use externally, bathe the parts and
lay on a cloth wet with the Extract,    Internally, take one half teaspoonful three
times a day.    Use hot or cold.
Ask your druggist for it or send your
order to Akthub Bkuce.
East Canterbury, N. H.
50   YEARS'
EXPERIENCE
Trade Marks
Designs
Copyrights &c.
HOW TO MAKE MONEY!
If you are out of employment and want
a position paying you from $50 to $100
monthly clear above expenses by working
regularly, or, if you want to increase your
present income from $200 to $500 yearly,
by working at odd times write the GLOBE
CO. 723 Chestnut St. Phila., Pa. stating
age, whether married or single, last or
present employment, and you can learn
how to make more money easier and
faster than you ever made before in your
life.
HAVE YOU ''COMMON SENSE?"
If not, send at once for a free copy of this
liberal-minded advocate of advanced
thought, which brings health and
success.    Address
"Common Sense," M. O. 55 State St.
Chicago, 111.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain our opinion free whether an
invention is probably patentable. Communications strictly confidential. Handbook on Patents
sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice, without charge, in the
Scientific American.
A handsomely illustrated weekly. Largest circulation of any scientific journal. Terms, $3 a
year; four months, $1.  Sold by all newsdealers.
MUNN & Co.361Broadway New York
Branch Office. 625 F St., Washington, D. C.
AUTHORISED   RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY.
The religious basis of the Order must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>