<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1212" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><date value="18821201" TEIform="date">December 1882</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">265-288</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                        <pb id="p1"/>
                        <p> VOL. XII. DECEMBER. NO. 12. SHAKER MANIFESTO Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT
                        SHAKERS, N. Y. "Blessed are those that hear the word of God and keep it." SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H.
                        1882.</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p> [Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
--><pb n="265" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><!--
                    <div2 type="none">
                        <p> CONTENTS. . . ;¦ Page. Page. Reasons why Shakkr Societies cannot be Biblical Teachings, 274 MADE BODIES
                            CORPORATE, 265 A Day with the Shakers, ; ' 275 Be Ye Perfect, - . - 266 Spiritualism, 277 Judge Not, 266
                            Temperature of Bedrooms, - 277 What 1 Want, 267 To a Brother in Bonds, 277 Benjamin Whitcheb, . -267 Notes, 278
                            True Happiness, 269 Schools at Hancock, Mass. 280 At Last, - 271 Correspondence, 280 Character, 271 Life in the
                            Woods, No. 2, - , 281 Paul or Christ - 272 Deaths, 283 Responsibility, 272 Juvenile, 283 The Words we Speak, -
                            273 Books and Papers, 285 Self Examination, - - 273 Household, 286 A Prayer, - 214 Music,—Watching and Waiting,
                            2S8 Yol. XII. DECEMBER, 1882. No. XII. </p>
                    </div2>
                        --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reasons why Shaker's societies cannot be made bodies corporate" TEIform="index"/> REASONS WHY
                            SHAKER'S SOCIETIES CANNOT BE MADE BODIES CORPORATE.</head><p TEIform="p"> 1st. Trustees of corporate bodies inu.«t be elected by vote, by the members of the
                            corporation ; this is not in accordance with the genius of our institution. 2nd. Their term
                            of office is limited by law ; this would conflict with our interests sometimes, possibly.
                            3rd. Their powers and duties must be denned by law. Ours is most properly prescribed by our
                            Covenantal Constitution. 4th. The legal restrictions confine the authority of the Trustees
                            to the character of the political institutions of our country ; these are not compatible
                            with the genius of our institutions. Second. Morally and Religiously considered. 1st. The
                            real and personal estate is not a joint tenancy, nor a tenancy in common,. ^ but J a
                            consecrated whole! Therefore, it iw not consistent with the genius of the institution to be
                            organized or recognized as a body politic, nor a hody corporate. But it is a Body
                            Reli'jiovH, and very great care is requisite not to confound this characteristic feature! of
                            our institution with those of a body Corporate, or Politic. We cannot receive the forms or
                            principles of our institution from civil and political governments, and can have,
                            governmentally, and organically, no connection with them further than to obey their laws,
                            and enjoy the common protection, and endure the common obligations they extend to all as far
                            as our religious faith will permit. 2nd. Shakers ask governmental protection in the
                            arrangement of a perpetuity and entailment of real and personal estate to the Shaker
                            Covenantal Consecration and Institution, on the ground that the whole estate is a
                            consecrated possession, sacred alone to religious and charitable purposes, judged of by the
                            religious constitution of Christianity as <pb n="266" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 266 SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            understood by the true followers of Christ. 3rd. The Shaker's Society, as such, can never
                            connect itself with the world ; from this it must ever retain isolation. 4th. The Shakers do
                            not, and cannot hold property as a Community estate, whether real or personal. The property
                            'held in trust by them is all consecrated to God, and religious and charitable purposes. All
                            the Community can claim is the usufruct; and the Trustees hold this only in a legal sense
                            and in a capacity solely as Trustees, or God's agents, to manage it for religious and
                            charitable purposes, the usufruct of which, only belongs to the society of consecrators ;
                            and, the Trustees in common with their Brethren and Sisters of the Covenantal organization,
                            can only claim a share in the usufruct. 5th. It is, in all cases, very important that the
                            Trustees, when appointed to the office, should be covenant members of a full consecration.
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be ye perfect" TEIform="index"/> BE YE PERFECT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ervin, Anna" TEIform="persName"/> ANNA ERVIN.</byline><p TEIform="p"> There is nothing so much effects the minds of people generally, as to see religion embodied,
                            and acted out by those who profess to be the people of God. The gospel then presents itself
                            to their consciences in a living shape, and carries with it an influence that is
                            irresistible. "Be ye therefore perfect as your Father in heaven is perfect," is one of the
                            commands. And are there not elements in our natures out of which human perfectability may be
                            formed? And although we are conscious of being very distant from that perfection, does it
                            follow that this condition is unattainable ? Even though a life time may intervene, if we
                            comprehend that by discipline and culture, by the Spirit of God, by the teaching and example
                            of the Master, it is attainable, then we have all needed encouragement for effort. God is
                            infinite fullness, and will he not inspire the soul with hope in the certainty of
                            attainment? All we do is developed from the mind. Is it not then of vital importance that we
                            allow nothing to gain the slightest hold of the mind which we would shrink from seeing
                            carried out in the actual conduct of life ? Actions are the unerring tests of the tone and
                            quality of the mind. Hence only such mental or spiritual states should be festered as will
                            yield the fair fruits of noble human lives. Enfield, Conn. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Judge not" TEIform="index"/>JUDGE NOT</head><p TEIform="p"> WRITTEN FOR THE MANIFESTO. Judge not,— lest by wrongful judging Thou betrayest doubt of
                            heart, And a vain distrust, which sadly Drifts the soul from Hope apart. And maketh
                            selfishness intense, In hearts which feel no confidence. Judge not,—lest by sinful judging,
                            Thou dost cast the fatal stone, Sending pain into some sad life, Making misery for thine
                            own; And driving out its love and trust, Make some heart feel thy law unjust. Judge
                            not,—lest by scornful judging, Dost let fall,—beneath the stars,— And cross a brother's
                            pathway,— Treachery's impeding bars; Compelling thus his feet to stray, In blinding doubt,
                            from God away. <pb n="267" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 267 Oh hast thou a heart so hardened,
                            That it cannot even melt At the touch of Love's warm fingers ? Tell me,—hast thou never felt
                            An inward joy thrill into life At sight of Peace o'ercoming Strife? If not,—then thy soul is
                            selfish,— Trusting neither friend nor foe ; Cold, unloving, narrow-bounded ;— God forbid
                            that this be so, And may His charity be strown Across thy path-way, now o'ergrown. Oh ! it
                            is thy humble duty, God to serve,—while He shall rule; While He sitteth on the high throne,
                            Kneel thou, low, upon the stool; And learn thy brother's woes to feel, For judgment is not
                            thine to deal. Judge not, then, but Oh, be noble ! And another's fault forgive ; Pluck the
                            cruel thorn of sorrow From the heart,—and stoop to give A kiss to little child at play,— A
                            drink to pilgrim on his way.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What I want" TEIform="index"/> WHAT I WANT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY.</byline><p TEIform="p">I want a kind and tender heart. For other's woes to feel, A soul secure from fortune's dart
                            And bosom arm'd with steel To bear divine chastisement's rod And, mingling in my plan,
                            Submission to the will of God, With charity to man. I want a keen observing eye, An ever
                            list'ning ear, The truth, through all disguise to spy. And wisdom's voice to hear, A tongue
                            to speak, at virtue's meed, In heaven's sublimest strain And lips the cause of man to plead,
                            And never plead in vain My last great want, absorbing all, Is, when beneath the sod. And
                            summon'd by my final call, The mercy of my God ! Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Benjamin Whitcher" TEIform="index"/> BENJAMIN WHITCHER,</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY C. BLINN.</byline><p TEIform="p"> (Continued from last number.) Benjamin Whitcher still farther remarks, "From the autumn of
                            1782 I became personally acquainted wit', the leading characters of the Shaker Society at
                            Watervliet. N. Y. I also visited them at Ashfield and at Shirley, always spending several
                            days with them and attending all their religious meetings." "Having known Mother Ann Lee,'
                            Elder William Lee, Elder James Whittaker and others so familiarly, makes me able to bear
                            witness of their piety and morality, as well as of tho purity of their doctrines. They were
                            meek and humble, kind and benevolent, just and upright in all their deportment. "They were
                            industrious and prudent in all temporal concerns, and wisely temperate in all things. I saw
                            nothing, at any time, but wrhat an enlightened conscience could approve/' Although they were
                            greatiy persecuted for their testimony, and suffered severe personal abuse, yet they reviled
                            not, nor did they seek the least revenge. They were often filled witli godly sorrow, and
                            poured forth their prayers and tears to God, for the protection and salvation of souls. In
                            this, their hearts were often filled with joy and thanksgiving to God for the merciful
                            displays of his power and goodness. They were zealous, powerful and joyful in the worship of
                            God. They were very kind and charitable to the poor and needy, of all classes, and always
                            taught this to their followers as a necessary and abiding principle of righteousness. They
                            could with the greatest propriety, say to their people, "Be ye <pb n="268" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 268
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. followers of us, even as we follow Christ." After accepting the testimony
                            of renewed light, and learning from Mother Ann and the Elders, the benefits of a spirit of
                            universal interest for all, he from tills time forward, opened his house to all who accepted
                            the same form of faith, till he numbered, in his family, not less than forty three persons.
                            All sat at one common table, and were engaged in the business of the place, either in the
                            house or on the farm. For several years the Believers held their public meetings every
                            alternate sabbath at the house of Benjamin Whitcher, and. on the occasions ol the visits of
                            the Ministers from New Lebanon, meetings were held every day, both morning and evening
                            during their sojourn, which was usually eight or ten days. Those who had embraced the faith
                            often collected in large numbers on Saturdays, and generally remained till Monday ; and at
                            the time of the protracted meetings would remain during the whole week. At these times the
                            multitude were entertained with refreshments and lodgings with the greatest care and
                            liberality. For ten years Benjamin and Mary Whitcher continued as the faithful servants of
                            the Lord in providing for others, as well as and often better than for themselves. At times
                            they were reduced to a scanty supply of food, but never suffered from actual wart. John
                            Whitcher, in his history of the Church, writes, that, "Notwithstanding this great burden in
                            my father's house, I never heard one word of complaint. When we consider that our temporal
                            support depended almost wholly upon the cultivation of an exceedingly hard and stony soil,
                            the statement seems scarcely creditable ; yet these free-will offerings were, we think,
                            attended with a special blessing of divine Providence." For the better accommodation of
                            others, Benjamin would often subject himself to a privation by taking his lodging upon the
                            floor. So generous and pleasant was the spirit of this home, that many sought a residence in
                            the family for no other consideration than to enjoy a mutual privilege with the brethren and
                            sisters. Sometimes this would be done not only at the expense of all worldly honor and
                            friendship, but often upon the forfeiting of a valuable legacy. The principles of a joint
                            interest, however, were not fully taught till the gathering of the Society in 1792. At this
                            date, Benjamin Whitcher was one of the first who came forward and consecrated to the Lord
                            his estate of 100 acres of good land, valued at that time at $2,150,00 with all his other
                            property, for the benefit of the new formed society . When the church family was organized,
                            he continued as heretofore, to aid, instruct and look after the affairs of the family,
                            especially in regard to the spiritual instruction, and particularly during the absence of
                            Elder Job Bishop. On the first of January 1794, it was thought necessary to establish an
                            order &gt;f Elders in the family, and Benjamin Whitcher was appointed to the place of an
                            Elder Brother. His companions in the order were William Lougee, Mary Hatch and Molly Drake.
                            For twelve years he faithfully bore the burdens that devolve upon the order, and commanded
                            during the whole of this time, the love and respect of the brethren and sisters. <pb n="269" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 269 He was a man of deep sympathy, of a forgiving spirit and
                            of a very liberal and generous disposition. He consecrated eyery ability for the prosperity
                            of the gospel cause and fora permanent growth in righteousness. Although his duties for the
                            most part continued within the boundaries of the Community, yet the records inform us that
                            he visited the Societies of Harvard, Shirley and Enfield, N. H. He had been for a long
                            series of years one of the active, able bodied men, whose will and muscular fibre was good
                            for any emergency, yet as he advanced in years a general dropsy became his affliction, which
                            terminated his life on the 28th, of October, 1827, at the age of 77 yrs. 7 months and 20
                            days. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True Happiness" TEIform="index"/>TRUE HAPPINESS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eades, Hervey L." TEIform="persName"/>HERVEY L. EADES.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Before people will forsake the world and come to Christ, they^ will have to feel a strong
                            assurance that by so doing they will be rendered more happy here and hereafter. Happiness is
                            of three kinds, viz : celestial or spiritual; intellectual ; and sensual or animal ; and the
                            latter is unworthy the name, yet the multitude seek it and are thereby ruined. "He only can
                            be esteemed really happy who enjoys peace of mind in the favor of God ;" and this can only
                            be attained through Jesus Christ, by obeying His teaching, and walking as He walked. The
                            second is attainable by the good and the bad, according to their capacity and application.
                            The third is enjoyed by animals, and by animal, sensual man. "Every gratification," says Dr.
                            Beattie, "of which human nature is capable, may be comprehended under the one or the other
                            of these three classes, viz. ; "The pleasures of the outward sense, the pleasures of
                            imagination and intellect, and the pleasures that result from the right exercise of our
                            moral powers. The delights that arise from the latter source, and from the approbation of
                            conscience, are, of all gratification, the most dignified. The more a man attaches himself
                            to them the more respectable he becomes ; and it is not possible for him to carry such
                            attachment to excess. With disgust or with pain, they are never attended. "To virtue,
                            therefore, which is the right exercise of our moral powers, the character of chief good does
                            belong, which will appear still more evident, when we consider that the hope of future
                            felicity is the, chief consolation of the present life, and that the virtuous alone can
                            reasonably entertain that hope. As on the other hand, vice, in the most prosperous
                            condition, is subject to the pangs of a guilty conscience and to the dreadful anticipation
                            of future punishment, which are sufficient to destroy all earthly happiness." This
                            corroborates what I have said, and, coming, as it does, from one of your own number and
                            class, can be the more readily and easily received ; but I shall endeavor to make it still
                            more evident. I love to collate, compare and draw evidence for truth from any quarter. "The
                            prudent man forseeth the evil and hideth himself, but the simple go on and are punished."
                            Every reflecting mind will admit that the combination of the spiritual and intellectual
                            forms the only happiness worthy the name, which I call true happiness. This being in the
                            possession of <pb n="270" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 270 SHAKER MANIFESTO. any soul, he may be said to have
                            obtained "the pearl of great price." But none ever reached this goal till Jesus Christ came,
                            and, by the sacrifice and crucifixion of all sensual and merely animal appetites, obtained
                            and then declared the truth to the world ; "This is the way, walk ye in it." Since then,
                            philosophers and pious men, on the natural plane of life, could only approximate the truth,
                            we should learn of those, if such can be found, "who have purified their souls in obeying
                            the truth through the spirit,'"(I Pet. i. 22.) by obedience to Him who first found the whole
                            truth and brought "life and immortality to light."' For, "if any of you err from the truth,
                            and any one convert him —he who converteth the sinner from the error of his way shall save a
                            soul from death." James, v. 20. Then, iu accordance with the testimony and life of the
                            Savior, I affirm this great truth, which was hidden from the world till Christ, viz. ; that
                            all the miseries that are in the world, and afflict the human family, or ever will afflict
                            them, are, and will be the consequence of the indulgence of the lower passional nature of
                            man. On the other hand, all true happiness that was ever gained by any soul, was the
                            consequence of self-abnegation, that is the denial of the selfish, sensual, and lower
                            propensities; that is to Say, in brief, self-denial bringeth happiness,— self-indiiigeisee
                            bringeth misery. None can gainsay this truth. It comes to the home experience of every man.
                            Take any twenty four hours of your life, and before God and your conscience compare notes,
                            and see if I am not sustained in this declaration. Then write it in your minute books and in
                            your albums, and above all, write it in your hearts; and if you practice it in your daily
                            conduct through life, "your soul shall be saved from death." All men—great and good men—
                            anterior and subsequent to the advent of Christ, who are living on the Adamic or natural
                            plane, have believed, and still believe, that a moderate indulgence of the selfish and
                            sensual appetites was compatible with the celestial or higher Christ life, and the best of
                            them think some such gratification cannot be avoided. Hear Plato ; "The nature of mankind is
                            greatly degenerated and depraved. All manner of disorders infest human nature, and men,
                            being impotent, are torn in pieces by their lusts' as by so many wild horses." So it was;
                            man was impotent. Until Christ, there was J none to set the example or lead the way ; but He
                            comes with a light eclipsing all former lights ; with this great truth inscribed on His
                            unfurled banner, floating before the eyes of .the world. Selfindulgence bringeth misery ;
                            self-denial bringeth happiness. He does not admit of even a moderate indulgence of the
                            selfish and sensual, but gives His whole soul and body to God, and then says to the world,
                            "Follow me." Christ does not admit impotence in his true followers, and Paul says he "can do
                            all things (necessary to salvation) through Christ strengthening him." And how does Christ
                            strengthen His followers? He strengthens them by His teaching, but more by His example.
                            Although Locke admits the impotency of man, he tells us some good things. "If any extreme
                            disturbance (as sometimes it happens) possesses the whole mind—as when the pain of the rack,
                            love, <pb n="271" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 271 anger, or any other violent passion
                            running away with us, allows us not the liberty of thought—God, who knows our frailty,
                            pities our weakness, and requires of us no more than we are able to do, and will judge us as
                            a kind and merciful father. "But the forbearance of a too hasty compliance with our desires,
                            the moderation and restraint of our passions, so that our* understanding may be free to
                            examine, and reason, unbiased, gives its judgment, being that whereon a right direction of
                            our conduct to true happiness depends—it is in this we should employ our chief care and
                            endeavors. In this we should take pains to suit the relish of our minds to the true,
                            intrinsic good or ill that is in things. How much this is in every one's power by making
                            resolutions to himself, such as he may keep, is easy for every one to try. Nor let any one
                            say he cannot govern his passions ; nor hinder them from breaking out and carrying him into
                            action ; for what he can do before a prince or a great man he can do alone, or in the
                            presence of God, if he will." This is certainly commendable advice and sound reasoning, but
                            I am of the opinion that none will be able to fully keep themselves without the facilities
                            afforded in God's Zion, or the order He has established on earth for the protection and
                            redemption of man. (To BE CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="At last" TEIform="index"/> AT LAST.</head><p TEIform="p"> When on my day of life the night is falling, And, in the winds from unsunned spaces blown, I
                            hear far voices out of darkness calling My feet to paths unknown. Thou who hast made my home
                            of life so pleasant, Leave not its tenant when its walls decay; 0 Love divine, O Helper,
                            ever present, Be thou my strength and stay! Be near me when all else is from me drifting:
                            Earth, sky, home's pictures, days of shade and shine, And kindly faces to my own uplifting
                            The love which answers mine. 1 have but thee, 0 Father ! Let thy Spirit Be with me then to
                            comfort and uphold; No gate of pearl, no branch of palm I merit Nor street of shining gold ;
                            Suffice it if—my good and ill unreckoned, And both forgiven through Thy abounding grace— I
                            find myself by hands familiar beckoned Unto my fitting place : Some humble door among Thy
                            many mansions, Some sheltering shade where sin and striving cease, And flows forever through
                            heaven's green expansions Thy river of Thy peace. There, from the music round about me
                            stealing, I fain would learn the new and holy song, And find, at last, beneath Thy trees of
                            healing, The life for which I long.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whittier, John Greenleaf" TEIform="persName"/>John Greenleaf Whittier.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Character" TEIform="index"/> CHARACTER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/> JAMES S. PRESCOTT.</byline><p TEIform="p"> God is no respecter of persons, but of character, and this character is one who does the
                            will of God, as it is made known to him, or her, and was exem-r plified in the life of
                            Christ, both in his first and second Appearing, and is attainable by all who will live his
                            life and follow his example. It is a lovely character. Let all who name his name strive to
                            attain it, press into it. <pb n="272" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 272 SHAKER MANIFESTO. This character has no
                            creed except what is contained in the four Evangelists, Matthew, Mark, Luke and John, and in
                            this there is no authority for marrying in the church of Christ, but it is strictly a virgin
                            character, and has reference to those who are living a life of virgin purity. North Union,
                            Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Paul or Christ" TEIform="index"/>PAUL OR CHRIST
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barr, Lillie E." TEIform="persName"/>LILLIE E. BARR
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"I suffer not that any woman teach, Or bear the
                                    message of the Lord's good will. Let her keep silence ; she hath no call to preach
                                    'Tis hers to learn and modestly sit still." Thus the Apostle ; Yet the risen Lord,
                                    Waiting beside the newly-broken tomb For messenger to send with his first word Unto
                                    the church within that upper room, Chose but a woman with a loving heart. (Oh! fair
                                    her feet with these glad tidings "I am arisen, and I now depart [shod :) And go unto
                                    our Father and our God." Did Christ make some mistake, the first by her The truth
                                    and light of llesurrection shone? He Mary chose to be his messenger. Would Paul have
                                    sent St. Peter or St. John? </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Independent" TEIform="index"/>The Independent.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Responsibility" TEIform="index"/> RESPONSIBILITY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Annie" TEIform="persName"/> ANNIE STEPHENS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> There is a moral responsibility resting on each individual to yield obedience to the light
                            of truth that shines in the soul, clearly revealing to the understanding the path of duty
                            and right. It requires a great deal of courage to walk therein ; to do violence to our own
                            self-will, to put away the weaknesses of perverted nature, and conquer the many adversaries
                            of our soul's good. Though the effort and struggle are great, yet the recompense is equal.
                            The consciousness of victories achieved over evil, the glory of living above the sensual,
                            and rising in the pure spiritual realm of ever blessed realities, where angelic motives
                            inspire to noble and unselfish deeds ; truly brings fullness of peace, and a joy, that the
                            votaries of worldly pleasure know not of. How many heroic souls, have sacrificed their
                            physical lives, for the promulgation of great and true principles. How many have sacrificed
                            the preferments of this world, to spread some glorious truth, that God had revealed for the
                            uplifting of humanity. Many have fallen as martyrs in the cause of right, and though they
                            have suffered unto death by the hands of cruel designers, they were as firm in their faith
                            as the rock of Gribralter, knowing that the truth, "though crushed to earth will rise again"
                            triumphant and glorious. Though there are but few who tread the ascending and rugged paths
                            of duty with unfaltering trust; who listen to the Divine Voice within which ever calls to
                            come up higher ; still the number is increasing, the hearts of humanity are being uplifted
                            to a higher ideal of life ; and to a consciousness, of their responsibilities as immortal
                            beings. Who can deny the fact that the soul lives after its divestment of mortality, and
                            will continue to live through the countless ages of eternity. The grand possibilities of the
                            human soul lie before us, a life of endless unfoldment Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The beer garden that has been opened on the Mount of Olives is..." TEIform="index"/>
                            The beer garden that has been opened on the Mount of Olives is...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The beer garden that has been opened on the Mount of Olives is well patronized by
                        tourists.</p></div2><pb n="273" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Words we speak" TEIform="index"/> THE WORDS WE SPEAK.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">THE WORDS WE SPEAK. Our words are imperishable. Like winded messengers, they go
                                    forth, but never to be recalled—never to die. They have a mighty power for good or
                                    evil through all time ; and before the spirit of God they will be swift witnesses
                                    for or against us. The words we speak have a mighty power; and there are words
                                    angels might covet to utter. There are words of comfort to the afflicted. There are
                                    sad hearts that need comfort everywhere, and there are words of blame and cold
                                    indifference, or feigned sympathy, that fall like lead upon the stricken spirit; and
                                    there are blessed heart-words of cheer, which bear up the soul and enable it to look
                                    out from the dark night of its troubles, and discern the silver lining of the gloomy
                                    cloud. There are words of counsel to the young, to the tempted, the erring. Speak
                                    them earnestly, affectionately, and though the waves of circumstance may soon waft
                                    them away from your observation, yet sueli is God's husbandry, that if uttered in
                                    faith and with prayer, He will take care that on an earthly or heavenly shore the
                                    reaper shall rejoice that he was a sower. There are kind words; how little they
                                    cost, how priceless they are ! Harsh words beget harshness; and fretful words, like
                                    a certain little insect, sting us into a feverish impatience. But who can resist the
                                    charm of kind, loving words? The heart expands beneath them as to the sunshine, and
                                    they make us happjer and better. Then there are cheerful words, and why should we
                                    dole them out with such miserly care? They ought to form the atmosphere of our
                                    homes, and to be habitual in all our social intercourse. We have so many weaknesses,
                                    so many crosses, so much that is down-hill in life, that the habit of thinking and
                                    speaking cheerfully is invaluable. But there are other words against which we should
                                    pray, "Set a watch, 0 Lord, before my mouth : keep the door of my lips." There are
                                    words of falsehood and deceit. They lurk in our expressions of civility, our
                                    professions of friendship, our transactions of business. How early do children,
                                    even, begin to weave a web of deceit, and how carefully should those who train them
                                    watch against this sin, and, by example and precept, teach them always and
                                    everywhere to speak the truth. There are slanderous words—how mischievous they are !
                                    There are the words of the tale-bearers, that breed suspicions and jealousies in
                                    neighborhoods, and between families. There are envious words and flattering words,
                                    and faltering, which are no better. Then there is the long list of idle words, or
                                    by-words, as they are called. But there is another class of words to which we would
                                    gladly refer—they are the words of eternal life. Cornelius sent for Peter that he
                                    might speak words to him. What blessed words those were ! Will they not be
                                    remembered with joy by both speaker and hearer throughout all eternity? As we pass
                                    along through the world, God will often let us speak a word for Him; and if we seek
                                    His aid, He will make it a word of power and comfort, a word in season, to him that
                                    is weary.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self examination" TEIform="index"/> SELF EXAMINATION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/> MARTHA J. ANDERSON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> What is my aim in Life f Physical perfection, mental growth and spiritual unfoldment; these
                            iorming the only rational basis for a harmonious and happy existence. Selfdenial the corner
                            stone of the structure. What my purpose ? Well directed efforts for the accomplishment of
                            the greatest amount of good that lies within the scope of the combined faculties with which
                            I am blessed. Activity, industry, earnestness, and perseverance prerequisite for the work.
                            What my aspiration? An unwavering belief in i;.'.mortality, turns my face heavenward,
                            infills my mind with noble and divine thoughts, lifting my heart from the material and
                            sensuous, into the glorious realm of spiritual realities. Through aspiration inspiration,
                            through inspiration revelation. What my high resolve? That the innate, insatiate longing for
                            knowledge, manifested in mental grasping, eagerness to see, hear <pb n="274" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 274
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. and learn, shall be turned in the highest channel of acquisition and
                            experience ; that virtue and truth may govern and direct the intellectual, as well as the
                            spiritual faculties. "O my soul devour wisdom and swallow down understanding." Mt. Lebanon,
                            N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/> A PRAYER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lewis, Polly C." TEIform="persName"/> POLLY C. LEWIS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> O Heavenly Father, listen to my humble prayer,— Grant me thy kind protection, love and
                            tender care; I'm hungry, I am thirsty, give me food to eat, And waters ot thy life,
                            refreshing, pure and sweet. Henceforth, I will devote my strength, my all to Thee, My time
                            and talents, great or small as they may be I'm Thine, I'm Thine and all for Thee I will
                            forsake,— The yoke and cross of Christ, I will most freely take. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Biblical teaching" TEIform="index"/> BIBLICAL TEACHING.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Briggs, M. Ella" TEIform="persName"/>M. ELLA BRIGGS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> [Written for, and read before, the Bible Class.] "Lay not up. for yourselves treasures upon
                            earth, where moth and rust doth corrupt, and where thieves break through and steal." Matt.
                            vi. 19. To whom was Jesus speaking while giving this counsel, so fraught with wisdom. Even
                            at the present date it would seem very applicable, when worldly wealth becomes the great
                            absorbing theme. It could not have been exclusively to the few who were fishing for their
                            daily sustenance, those unto whom he had previously said, "Follow me and I will make you
                            fishers of men." It was, no doubt, spoken to the multitude, as the chapter is but a
                            continuation of his sermon on the mount. In addressing a multitude, one may have a very
                            diversified audience, and on this account we may suppose that he was speaking to persons of
                            every class. He would have them beware of acquisitiveness and to use the things of this
                            world as gifts from the Heavenly Father. This might have seemed almost superfluous to the
                            poor,—those who by incessant toil and hardships were obliged to earn their daily bread, but
                            to the selfish, rich man there is an ever present danger, of ease, and self-pleasure and
                            these especially must have been included in the admonition. To us, however, is fulfilled
                            this promise, "And every one that hath forsaken houses, or brethren, or sisters, or father,
                            or mother, or wife or children or lands, for my name's sake, shall receive an hundred fold,
                            and shall inherit eternal life." Matt. xix. 29. This enjoins upon us a greater
                            responsibility, while having reference to individual property, which the natural heart
                            broods over with a watchful eye. AVe should have a care and solicitude for the entire
                            heritage of God, faithful in the things of this life, that we may justly inherit Life
                            Eternal. "It is easier for a camel to go through the eye of a needle, than for a rich man to
                            enter into the Kingdom of God." Some who have gathered to themselves an abundance of wealth,
                            think we should not be censured for improving to the best advantage the faculties given by
                            the Author of every good gift. If strictly honest, an example worthy of the gods,—they
                            should realize a blessing, in this use of the talents given, to the honor and glory of God,
                            forever. However, riches have ever been cumbersome and a source of much discomfort. Even
                            Solomon after enjoying all that this earth could afford, exclaimed,—-"Vanity of vanities,
                            all is vanity." "But lay up for yourselves treasures in heaven, where moth and rust cannot
                            corrupt, and where thieves do not break through and steal." What are these imperishable
                            treasures, which abide even in eternity? We can take nothing of a material character to that
                            heavenly abode. What then may we be gathered unto? Every sacrifice made for the well being
                            of another, every kind word, or act will prove a shining thread, woven into the garment that
                            shall enrobe the spirit form. When a small child, I often heard that our Mother Hannah
                            Goodrich said, "Every pin saved is helping to make a star in your crown." If each Christian
                            virtue could be encouraged as the above, it might be to us of immortal wealth. These, then
                            are the treas- <pb n="275" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 275 ures to be sought after with all
                            diligence We have an evidence that there is a realm of peace beyond this sphere of action,
                            however rough may be the path. It is a land of realities, where each one shall receive a
                            reward as their works shall merit. "Where moth and rust cannot corrupt, and where thieves do
                            not break through and steal." Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="ashaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Day with the Shakers" TEIform="index"/> A DAY WITH THE SHAKERS.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A DAY WITH THE SHAKERS. The Enfield Ct. Shakers own 3000 acres of land in one
                                    body, besides outlying parcels. This land is divided among three ' families,"
                                    altogether numbering about 125 persons. The three farms are kept in beautiful
                                    condition. Industry and tidyness seem to be included in the watchwords of these
                                    peculiar but shrewd, thrifty, hospitable people. We found Elder Robert Aikin of the
                                    south family at work in the onion bed, and are indebted to him and all whom we met
                                    for kind and accommodating attentions. "Are you much bothered with the onion maggot,
                                    elder?" we inquired, among other questions. "Nay, not since I put coal ashes on the
                                    beds. They have troubled us for years previously, and my way has always been to go
                                    over the beds daily and pull out every onion plant that showed signs of being maggot
                                    eaten. In this way we got the pest cleared out pretty well each season. But this
                                    year I put on coal ashes and it has either killed the maggots or else they haven't
                                    come very plenty. I find that coal ashes seem to improve our currants and
                                    raspberries, too." "I see you have a big field of buckwheat over there." "Yea, there
                                    is 17 acres of it. It's very good, too, although only a little Bradley's phosphate
                                    was put on it. We sell a good deal of buckwheat for seed for $ 1 a bushel, and
                                    dispose of it in other ways. We use the straw for bedding and for mulching. Look at
                                    these currants. You see we mulched them heavily with buckwheat straw so that the
                                    weeds have been choked out, the ground has been kept moist and the fruit clean."
                                    "Those are pretty good sweet potatoes, ain't they, elder?" "Yea, those from the
                                    plants of our own raising are the best. The greatest difficulty we find is in
                                    keeping the potatoes through winter to have them to start plants from in spring. We
                                    pack them in dry sand or fine straw chaff and keep in a cool cellar. We start the
                                    plants in a hot bed. Plants from a distance don't do so well as home growth." One
                                    thing that struck us as a good idea was the Shaker method of harvesting hay. They
                                    get it in, in the afternoon, but don't unload it till the next morning. They have
                                    plenty of wagons and an abundance of floor space and shed room in which to house the
                                    loaded hay over night. By this means they can harvest a big lot of hay with
                                    comparative ease, and can pitch it off in the cool of the morning. But the average
                                    farmer can't afford the necessary "plant" for this convenient method of
                                    hay-harvesting,We were a good deal interested also in a "New Departure" corn
                                    cultivator, much used at the West, but just introduced here. Instead of going
                                    between the rows, this cultivator straddles'em as it were, one side of the machine
                                    going on one side the row of corn and the opposite part on the other side of the
                                    row. It is drawn by two horses, who walk between the rows. By cultivating with it
                                    both ways the ground is stirred and pulverized in a remarkably thorough manner, and
                                    little if any hand-hoeing is required. The axle of the cultivator (it runs on two
                                    light iron wheels) is of this form, _Q, so that the corn can attain a considerable
                                    height before the axle will brake it. "Yea, there is nothing that injures hay so
                                    much as to let dock weed get into it," said the good elder, as we walked through the
                                    mowings. "Last spring we spent a good many dollars in having the weed pulled out,
                                    and consider it a good investment. We don't mean to have the weeds get into our
                                    fields very thickly, but if they do get into the grass we mow it early before they
                                    go to seed. If we don't the seed gets into the manure and is spread all over the
                                    farm." This is true as gospel every time. And it is much easier to mow the weedy
                                    fields early before the weeds have seeded, than to attempt to exterminate the pest
                                    by manuring or cultivation. Daisy, thistle and sorrel especially need to be cut
                                    early for this reason. <pb n="276" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 276 SHAKER MANIFESTO. Mr. Richard Van
                                    Deusen is one of the most experienced fruit growers in Connecticut, His peach
                                    orchard of 850 trees is one of the best in New England. The trees are all uniform in
                                    shape and thrifty beyond all precedent. The trunks branch at about two feet above
                                    the ground; the body of the tree is about as broad as it is high, so that when
                                    loaded with peaches they can be almost wholly picked by a man standing on the
                                    ground. Hardly a tree is missing in the whole orchard, and so healthy and
                                    symmetrical are the tree* that it is worth going a long distance to tee them. The
                                    orchard is on a slight hill, the soil being of a red sand nature. The borers and the
                                    "yellows" have no foot-hold here, for Mr. Van Deusen has, after much experimenting,
                                    found what several years' use seems to prove to be a- permanent remedy for these
                                    very destructive pests. It is a wash which he puts on the trees in June, from the
                                    roots up to about a foot above ground. "Now, sir, what is that wash composed of?" we
                                    inquired. •'Oh, that is my secret. I sell the receipt for $2, but if I should tell
                                    you, you would print it in the paper and that would put an end to my .selling the
                                    receipt," and the good brother smiled shrewdly and good-naturi dly. The peach
                                    orchard is kept plowed and free from weeds, a fine tooth harrow being run through it
                                    occasionally to keep out the weeds. An additional orchard of 400 peach trees was set
                                    out this spring. The crop this year is an utter failure, the early frosts of last
                                    year having totally killed the buds. Brother Richard believes in intensified
                                    agriculture. If he doesn't net 8100 an acre he thinks it doesn't pay. This year
                                    among his other crops are five acres of turnip seed (just harvested,) five acres of
                                    onion seed and five acres of cucumber seed. "If Mr. Bradley could only be here to
                                    see those cucumbers 1" he exclaimed as we walked by the field. "On this side we
                                    applied a little Bradley's phosphate in the hill, on that side bone and ashes; just
                                    see the difference.'" It certainly was very marked, where the phosphate was used
                                    being nearly twice as large and of a darker green color than where the ashes and
                                    bone were applied. Brother Richard's farming operations on 24 acres yielded over
                                    $5000 last year at an expense of less than $1200. "That's what brings in the
                                    money,"' said he, pointing to the large field of onion seed. "Last year from two
                                    acres of onion seed I got $2200." There is in New England a great deal of light,
                                    plain land, as well as comparatively inaccessible hillsides, that is not worth
                                    cultivating and yet should not be allowed to remain idle. Elder Omar Pease of the
                                    north family of Shakers has appreciated the truth of this statement for years. He
                                    has carried out this doctrine, too, and of his 1500 acres 200 are now in young,
                                    thrifty white pine, all sowed by his own hand. He has tried every way of planting—by
                                    plowing and harrowing in, harrowing in on the sod, etc. After years of experience he
                                    finds, however, that merely sowing the seed on the turf is the best way. It will
                                    invariably get a good start and do well when thus planted, rib matter how hard the
                                    soil. Eight to ten quarts of seed per acre are sown. One lot of sandy plain land
                                    sowed in 1869 now has a dense growth 12 to 1G feet high. The seed does best when
                                    sowed in the early spring. "How do you obtain the seed?" "Ah, that was what it took
                                    me a long time to find out. And it took some years for me to learn what I have told
                                    you' about seeding with pine. Now about getting the seed. You know the pine see'l is
                                    borne in cones. Well, along in September the squirrels gnaw off these cones and they
                                    fall to the ground to make the winter store of food for the squirrels. In a good
                                    fruiting year the cones will be found under the pines very thick. We go into the
                                    woods with a cart and pick them up, gelting a load in half a day with good luck. The
                                    cones are spread out to dry on the floor of a shed or spare attic. We leave them
                                    there ti.l some time in winter, and then when .there's not much to do we rake or
                                    fork them over an 1 the seeds rattle out very easily. Then we rake off the cones and
                                    sweep up the seeds and put them in bags for future use. The pine seems to fruit well
                                    only once in three years. Some trees will seed well during years that other trees
                                    will not. This ought to be a good bearing year with our trees, but I'm afraid it
                                    won't be. The early frost last fall seems to have affected them."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Farm and home" TEIform="index"/>Farm and Home.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="277" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritualism" TEIform="index"/> SPIRITUALISM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescot, James S." TEIform="persName"/> JAMES S. PRESCOT. </byline><p TEIform="p">In writing on this subject I would like to say affew words, before I begin, and these few
                            words are found in the May No. of the Manifesto, page 110, under the heading NOTES. I
                            indorse the last eeven lines because they are the "multum in pawn" of tl±e tiuth of God. I
                            wish to bear witness to the truth. wherever found, "on heathen or on Christian ground." True
                            spiritualism is of God, and cannot be over-thrown, and even the Bible itself was founded on
                            ancient spiritualism, and was a fair sample and a faint reflection of the work of that
                            day—the good and the bad, the true and the false, all mixed together; and he who indorses
                            the plenary inspiration of the Bible, indorses ancient spiritual' ism. North Union,
                        Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Temperature of bedrooms" TEIform="index"/> THE TEMPERATURE OF BEDROOMS.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">THE TEMPERATURE OF BEDROOMS. One evil accruing from the cold sleeping room is the
                                    excuse it ofFers for imperfect ventilation, says a medical authority. It is so
                                    dreadfully cold at best, that'if the doors or windows are thrown open'even for a few
                                    moments through the day, one feels morally certain he will freeze to death at night,
                                    and hence the bedroom is left closed day after day, with no chance for the inside
                                    air to escape or the outside air to get in, save such as the small cracks between
                                    sashes and about windows afford. And what kind of air do we breathe in consequence?
                                    Air so impure and vitiated that the only wonder is that i does not kill on the spot,
                                    instead of deferring this result to some distant but no less certain day. The seeds
                                    of disease are sown in lie system, to grow and produce their fruitage by and by.
                                    Another disadvantage of the cold sleeping room is the necessity it engenders for a
                                    great amount of cover—an array of quilts and blankets that weigh upon one like lead,
                                    but fail to keep out the cold. Such a weight of bed clothes is both wearying and
                                    weakening, particularly to the young and frail. You wake in the morning feeling as
                                    if you had changed places with Atlas, and had been holding up the world on your
                                    shoulders through the night. All this may be avoided by having sleeping rooms so
                                    arranged that a little fire can be built in them at need. This does not mean that it
                                    is necessary to keep a fire all day or every day. But whenever the weather is damp
                                    or intensely cold a fire should be made and allowed to burn briskly for at least two
                                    or three hours before bedtime, to dry out the air and dry and warm the bed, after
                                    which it may be allowed to go out, though, if very cold, it is better to replenish
                                    with fuel, close the dampers and leave to emit a slow heat through the night. By
                                    doing this, and lowering one of the windows an inch at the top, you can be
                                    comfortable and have fresh air at the same time ; when, if other bodily conditions
                                    are favorable, you will sleep the sleep of the just and awake in the morning, not
                                    tired and frozen and out of sorts, but rested, happy and refreshed. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brother in bonds" TEIform="index"/> TO A BROTHER IN BONDS.</head><p TEIform="p"> Though cloudy now the atmosphere, And chill and frost may yet invade, A sea of glass with
                            fire appear, And drifts of toil through which to wade; The sun is still behind the cloud,
                            Whose rays will brighten, warm, dissolve, When Spring shall come to rend the shroud, And
                            beauties fresh and new evolve.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., M. E." TEIform="persName"/> M. E. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Part of the religion of the Hindoos..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Part of the religion of the Hindoos...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Part of the religion of the Hindoos is to be kind to animals. They carry this
                                    into such practical operation that they erect hospitals for sick and homeless
                                    brutes. At Bombay there is a hospital of this kind covering several acres. Part of
                                    it is open to the heavens, while the rest is occupied with low, stone buildings and
                                    she^s. The pious Hindoos believe that all life is sacred and that its preservation
                                    is in some degree an atonement for -d.i committed and many an evil conscience is
                                    purged by sending some unhappy beast to the hospital. Much of the food consumed by
                                    the sick animals is contributed in the way of sacrifices and thank offerings. Even
                                    lice and fleas find refuge in a room set apart for their accommodation, devout
                                    pilgrims and hired oeggars supplying their necessities.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="278" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Manifesto December 1882" TEIform="index"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO 1882.</head><p TEIform="p"> Office of Publication, The "Shaker Manifesto" is published at Shaker Village, Mer. Co., N.
                            H. All busi ness matters connected with the financial department of the paper will be
                            directed to the Publisher of Manifesto, Shaker Village, N. H. All other communications may
                            be addressed, Editor of Manifesto, Shaker Village, N. H. One Copy per. year, Postage paid,
                            .60 six months, .35 Enclose a two cent stamp for a specimen copy. To avoid mistakes, those
                            who send money, should write the name of their Post Office, County and State. TO One inch,
                            one insertion " " three " " " six " " " twelve " " column ----- ---- $ 1.00 each .75 " .65 "
                            .50 ----- 6.00 Larger spaces, rates in same proportion.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellenous" TEIform="index"/> NOTES</head><p TEIform="p">He went about doing good. Exactly. Just the work in which we should be engaged. The circuit
                            may be large or small; the number before whom we publish our mission, may be few or many,
                            but the same demand for the same continuous works of brotherly interest for poor humanity
                            has not essentially lessened. </p><p TEIform="p"> There are wounds to heal and tears to brush away, and at this moment we are anxiously
                            waiting for the good Samaritan to pass along. </p><p TEIform="p"> To throw out a stone when a piece of bread has been solicited would, by most persons be
                            considered as rather severe, or to place before the hungry a poisonous snake, when He had
                            asked for a fish. </p><p TEIform="p"> As cold and mean as this act may seem, the lesson was no doubt a powerful illustration of
                            character and very characteristic of those pharisaical Jews, and it does not require a very
                            close observer to see that the same quality of mind has been handed down through the many
                            generations and throws itself upon the society of today. </p><p TEIform="p"> There are some conditions which we "are bound to respect" if we are to become the children
                            of God, and one phase among the essentials is to be "peace makers." </p><p TEIform="p"> Religious creeds and dogmas are at a dscount. Faith and hope may have been seals of
                            genuineness and of safety at a former age, but the religion of Christ is to make a man,
                            "first pure, then peaceable and easily to be entreated," and this religion will never
                            commend itself very much to others till the nominal Christian learns first to "govern his
                            tongue" and then to purify his own heart. This must ever be found as far more effectual, in
                            the conversion of souls, than to work hard and selfishly to govrn others. </p><p TEIform="p"> The simplicity of the gospel lessons should not be over looked. "The good man, out of the
                            treasure of the heart, oringeth forth good things." "Speak gently 'tis a little thing,
                            Dropped in the heart's deep well; The good, the joy which it may bring, Eternity will tell."
                            A religious body of people by the name of "Overcomers" have arisen in <pb n="279" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/>
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. 279 Chicago. They consider that every act should be introduced by prayer.
                            They carry the bible with them, into their daily occupation and spend much of their tim,e in
                            prayer. We shall hope for the prosperity of this new class of religionists, that they may be
                            honorably entitled to the very significant name which they have chosen. </p><p TEIform="p"> There has been some little trouble in the public schools of Andover, Vt.. over biblical
                            recitations. A boy lef the school, by advice of his father, but without permission from the
                            teacher, during the reading of the bible. The case is before the County Court. These petty
                            quarrels over the reading of the bible, seem much like the duel fought by the two Knights,
                            after their dispute about the color of the shield. They neglected to examine both sides till
                            after the quarrel had ended. </p><p TEIform="p"> A. MERRY CHEISTMASI Before the close of the present month we shall enjoj one of those
                            especial days, that the thousands of little folks, and may be^no less in number of persons
                            of mature years, will hail with delight. Every reader of the Manifesto, very naturally, will
                            claim the right to make it all that its title designates, A Merry Christmas ! The wish
                            should pass from house to house and from village to village filled with an expression of
                            that love and Christian care which so rully abounded in the lite of the Lord Jesus. The
                            religious service, the dining hall, and the domestic duties of the d ,y should embody the
                            spirit of the festival, and awaken a cheerfulness in the mind, which shall impart new life
                            and be the means of making our lives better and happier than ever before. It is singular,
                            indeed, that a day so rigidly observed by a few Christian sects, should in process of time
                            have become so universally accepted as a day of good wishes, and happy remembrances. Even
                            our puritan fathers forbade the observance of the day, calling it a Roman Catholic feast, or
                            an observance of the Mass for Christ. As the date of the birth of Jesus has never been
                            ascertained, the consideration which we give to Christmas, must necessarily be a matter of
                            church pleasure, rather than as a fact. The Romish church in the sixth century "transferred
                            the celebration of the nativity of Christ to the twenty fifth of December for the purpose of
                            drawing away the Christian people from all participation in the heathen festivals, and of
                            gradually drawing the pagans themselves from their heathen customs to the Christian
                            celebration." </p><p TEIform="p"> Paterson, N. J. Editor of Manifesto :—We send thee two dolfars. Thou wilt send out that in
                            Manifestos when you like. We also send one dollar for our next year's subscription. H.
                            Arnot. We think we are able, fully, to appreciate the kindness of the above gift, and trust
                            that our dear friend will feel more than repaid, as he bears in mind the good word that is
                            sent from house to house. "He that giveth to the poor, lendeth to the Lord," retains all the
                            vitality in which the promise was given. Objects so worthy bear their own reward. <pb n="280" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 280 SHAKER MANIFESTO. </p><p TEIform="p"> Hancock, Mass. The school in District N.o. 7, known as the Shaker school, deserves an
                            honorable mention. It is a striking illustration of what has been so often said of home
                            influence among the pupils in our public schools. After three visits during the summer
                            session taught by Martha Johnson we feel justified in saying that better order is sustained
                            there than in any other school in town. We notice:! particularly the position of the pupils
                            while reading or reciting, no uneasy changing or lounging too frequently seen in school but
                            an erect, graceful attitude accompanied by a clear distinct articulation. It would be
                            gratifying if more of the politeness noticeable here could be developed in other schools in
                            town. We shall not soon forget the pleasant "Thank you" from classes to whom we had given a
                            little help by some suggestion or explanation. The recitations were prompt and correct, the
                            reading far above the average among pupils of their age. The school room a pattern of
                            neatness and comfort in itself, will seat twenty, and here as in everything is shown the
                            interest the patrons take in education. There is an ample supply of books, maps and whatever
                            is needed to assist both teacher and pupil and make the school pleasant and attractive. We
                            noticed a musical instrument and asked the teacher if she taught singing. She directly pi
                            oduced books, selected a piece and requested one of the girls to play, which she did quietly
                            and without any of the silly protestations usually made by the young lady of the present
                            time, while as in the other exercises every one cheerfully bore her part with. credit to
                            herself and pleasure to the listeners. The teacher, teaches not for a mere pecuniary
                            consideration, but works faithfully and conscientiously for the good of those entrusted to
                            her care. The Shakers have learned to some purpose that, "¦Whatever is worth doing, is worth
                            doing well." Susan M. AVliite. Chairman School Committee.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Sisters, Marcia and Mary;—I have been mentally..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Sisters, Marcia and Mary;—I have been mentally...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Canterbury,  October 5, 1882" TEIform="index"/> Canterbury, N. H. Oct. 5,
                                1882.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Sisters, Marcia and Mary;—I have been mentally saying to you this rare Oct. morn.
                                Please look out of your cottage window occasionally in a South' Easterly direction so
                                that you may get a glimpse of the scene which environs we apple-gatherers to-day, one
                                which I fain would transfer to canvass to ornament the walls of your cosy home were I
                                able to do so. "But," you reply "We cannot see so far away." Well then I will try to
                                give you a rough sketch of tlie picture in words for you really deserve to realize all
                                beautiful things. Behold us then upon a sunny slope beneath the beautiful pending
                                branches of the "Shropshire Vine" busily gathering the fruit and yet at intervals
                                pausing to take in the surroundings. The blue sky for instance, seen through the
                                openings of the spreading branches, the sun glinting between their myriad leaves, and
                                again throwing its broad beams over boundary and space just as it did centuries ago :
                                The pure breezes coming from far off sources of cleanliness like winged messengers,
                                seemingly to bear tidings of future peace : while sprinkled round our feet lies the
                                ruddy, ripe abundant fruit so abundant, hit aft&gt;. r a protracted drowth, we can
                                but realize the presence of that universal principle of benevolence which characterizes
                                all of God's work and to which neither of you are strangers in detail. <pb n="281" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 281 Methinks I catch your reply, "A beautiful picture
                                truly ; but sister this is only earthly beauty, which will fade before your sight as the
                                stars softly melt in the morning's clear light," In a few, brief days the cold realities
                                of ice and snow will check the free current of nature's vital tide. Very true, sister M.
                                but after all, it is not the mere scene itself that so enraptures, it is the thought of
                                that Divine Intelligence which seems to pervade, infill and surround the whole visible
                                landscape. May we not term it a heaven upon earth? One degree of heaven you say, if the
                                heart of the admirer is at peace with conscience and therefore in sympathy with all that
                                is noble good and true. Thank you,—This reply reminds me of a thought which recurred to
                                me in church last Sabbath on hearing the subject of happiness treated by different
                                speakers. Since you were not present think I will give you the item.. One of our young
                                sisters testified strongly of the joy which she experienced from day to day in trying to
                                live agreeably to the dictates of a faith which had rendered hw so happy. She said, I
                                wish that other young companions not of our persuasion could share iu my happiness.— A
                                neighbor and friend present, who with others had been invited to speak, responded kindly
                                to the invitation;—saying, that with reference to the wish expressed for others to share
                                in our happiness, he presumed that all present were happy. He had no reason to doubt but
                                that all were trying to do their best and consequently are as happy in their own good
                                homes and happy fire sides as they wished to be. On listening to this last remark, I
                                thought bow aptly one of Ruskin's aphorisms on drawing would fit into the first
                                speaker's reply were this an appropriate season for discussing the question. "Every
                                light is a shade compared to higher ghts, till you come to the sun ; and every shade is
                                a light compared to deeper shades till you come to night." Using this comparison I
                                mentally said, then will this not apply to those various mental states which we call
                                happiness? Happiness to a certain degree is realized by all conditions animal, human and
                                divine. The animal world is generally happyf when well fed, regardless of associations.
                                A good bone, and a caress from the master, renders Ivdo 1 appy. Plenty of toys with
                                space for noise, enough to eat drink and wear usually happifies the child. The mere
                                worldling enjoys his wealth in various forms and is happiest when Fame speaks loudest of
                                his ability 1o amass it. The thrifty farmer also is proverbially happy especially if he
                                realizes what the poet says of him.— "A happy man is Farmer John, O, a rich and. happy
                                man is he ! He sees the pea% and pumpkins growing The corn in tassel, the buckwheat
                                blowing And fruit on vine and tree."— and ttiough convinced of all this, yet,
                                metliought,—Every degree of happiness which begins and ends with terrestrial life is but
                                a shade in comparison with that higher, more substantial happiness which I know that you
                                and many others enjoy, who by a practical Christian experience have followed the Savior,
                                not "afar off." Dear sisters and mothers, please accept this tribute with the love of
                                our little party now busy in the orchard. Affectionately thine,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stickney, A. C." TEIform="persName"/>A. C. Stickney. </byline></div3></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life in the woods, No. 2" TEIform="index"/> LIFE IN THE WOODS, NO. 2.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sproat, Granville T." TEIform="persName"/>GRANVILLE T. SPROAT.</byline><p TEIform="p">[Being a narrative of events that occured during a sojourn of twelve years among the Indians
                            of the North-West.] But, to return to our journey. When we reached the Indian camp, I threw
                            up my wigwam in the enclosure, and Ma-gwah-gah-bo also constructed his own, not; many feet
                            distant. I then went out to visit the Indians, leaving him sitting in my wigwa.m. When I
                            returr ed, he, had retired'to his own, and, J. noticed that a bottle of antimonial wine,
                            among my medicines, had been disturbed. I looked, and found that out of a quart, nearly a
                            pint was missing. I thought, "Has the old n: an been drinking my antimonial wine— thinking
                            it to be fire-broth? (whiskey.). If so, I shall hear from him before morning; therefore I
                            will be quiet and wait." About midnight, his old wife came running into my <pb n="282" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 282 SHAKER MANIFESTO. wigwam. She was in a great fluster : "Oh, do go and see
                            Ma-gwah-gah-bo !" "Why, what is the matter?" "Oh, he is so sick! He has done nothing but
                            vomit, all day and all night." I arose and went into his wigwam. There he lay—stretched on
                            the ground, with hardly strength left to move a limb. "Ah-koo-zitnah?" ("Sick? hey?") "Yes,
                            very sick" "What is the matter?" I shall never forget his look of drollery, as he said, "You
                            know as well as I do? Is this the way the fire-broth does, when the Pale Faces drink it?
                            make them so sick?" -"Yes, just so sick—sometimes." Well, if this is the way the firebroth
                            does, I will never drink any more firebroth as long as I live." And he kept his word. I
                            never knew of his drinking liquor after this—always remembering the antimonial wine—the
                            fire-broth. While stopping at this time in camp, I saw, for the first time, an Indian
                            punished for murder. He had killed his wife; or had so misused her that she died in
                            consequence. On her grave, after her burial, I saw him sitting; his face painted black, and
                            his whole appearance exhibiting the most extreme dejection. I said to Ma-gwah-gah-bo, "Why
                            does he sit there in that guise, and with that look of despair" He replied, "He has killed
                            his wife; he knows what the end will be." He then told me that the Indians punish murder by
                            taking all the hunting and fishing implements from the murderer, shutting him out from their
                            wigwams, and thus condemning him to death by starvation. If he goes to ask for food, and it
                            is given him, poison is given with it, by the command of the chief. If he attempts to flee
                            to another tribe, the question is asked, "What does this murderer here?"—since nothing but
                            murder, they know, would induce him to leave his own tribe for another; and he is condemned
                            to suffer the same fate from which he vainly tried to escape. If he builds for himself a
                            lodge in the wilderness, he is pursued, and poison is secretly administered in his drink, or
                            food. 'Tis a doom from which there is no escaping. Go where he will, the avenger of blood is
                            at his heels. He another Cain—branded with his mark upon him—a "fugitive and a vagabond in
                            the earth." I tremble to think of such a doom—so miserably lingering and hopeless! A few
                            evenings after witnessing the burial scene, as I sat in my wigwam, the murderer entered. He
                            looked pale and haggard, and seated himself on the ground, near the door. Neither of us
                            spoke. At last he asked the question, "Has the pale face got meat in his kettle?"—Now, the
                            Indian has, hanging in his wigwam, what he calls the "stranger's kettle," in which he puts
                            meat for the stranger. It hangs within his wigwam just before the door, that the stranger
                            may have free access to it. Beneath it lies the "stranger's mat," and there is no wigwam
                            without the stranger's mat and kettle. I replied, "Yes, there is meat in the kettle." He
                            said, "May I speak a word? Has the pale face put poison into his kettle?" "No," I replied,
                            "I never put poison into my kettle." "Then, I will eat," he said, and got up, helped himself
                            to the meat, and sat down. After a few moment's silence he arose to go, and said, "If I
                            should come again tomorrow, would there still be meat in the stranger's kettle?" I replied,
                            "If you should come again tomorrow, there is the kettle—help yourself. But if you should
                            come to my wigwam every day, and ask me for meat, and I should give it you, would not the
                            chief order poison to be put into my kettle too? Should we not both of us die;" He replied,
                            "The pale face speaks the truth. I shall not come any more. And he did not come any more.
                            After three days, as I was goirg through the camp, I heard the sound of distress coming from
                            one of the wigwams. I looked in. There he lay, prostrate on the ground, writhing in agony. I
                            asked the woman standing out side of the wigwam, "Who gave him the poison?" "I gave it to
                            him," she replied. "The chief ordered it. He came to my wigwam, and asked me for food. I put
                            poison into it. He knew there was poison in it. He wanted to die. I did not stop to witness
                            his agony. I came right away." The Indians believed that, after death, the soul goes on a
                            three day's journey over a vast prairie. This prairie is barren and desolate, and shrouded
                            in darkness, without sun, moon, or stars, and with only the feeble 13gM <pb n="283" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 283 of the fire left burning for them, over their graves, to guide the
                            traveler on his journey. Fie often missed the way, for the path was narrow, and side paths
                            were leading from it, which, if taken, would become more and more obscure, and lead the
                            traveler out on to a trackless waste. Wandering spirits, (Teefo',)would often meet him, and
                            whisper in his ear, shrieking, and gibbering, in the dreadful darkness. If he had been a
                            murderer, his feet trod on serpents, (Key-e-bcck,) that stung him, and wild beast, (
                            Raw-sham-gance,) the wild cat, the panther, and the bear, would tear his flesh. But if he
                            had been a good Indian, true and faithful to his tribe, had sat by the council fires of the
                            chiefs, and spoken words of wisdom to the young men, then he easily regained his path, and
                            pursued his way directly to the mystic spirit river that separated the prairie from the Land
                            of Souls. There he could look over, and see beautiful lodges, and encampments, on the other
                            side, and friends coming out to meet him, down by the river shore. He crossed the river in
                            safety, on a pole that lay floating on the water, over which none could pass in safety. (To
                            BE CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Society Record DEATHS</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Easterbrooks, Susan Ann" TEIform="index"/> Susan Ann Easterbrooks</head><p TEIform="p">, at White Water, Ohio, Oct. 14. Age, 6Q yrs. 10 mo. and 6 days. A faithful and valued
                                soul who spent her whole life in faithful gospel duty.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bear, H. B." TEIform="persName"/> H. B. Bear.</byline></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rankin, Solomon" TEIform="index"/> Solomon Rankin</head><p TEIform="p">, at South Union, Ky. Nov. 3. Age, 85 yrs. and 5 mo</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fuller, Deborah" TEIform="index"/> Deborah Fuller</head><p TEIform="p">, at New Gloucester, Me. Nov. 5. Age, 79 yrs. and 6 mo. She was one of the most beloved
                                sisters and firm pillars in that community. Remarkable for her talents, her virtue and
                                purity of life, she was at a very early age called to responsible places of care and
                                trust which she always filled with grace and honor, and for many years was one of the
                                leading Eldresses presiding over the two communities in Maine. She had resided some
                                seventy-two years in the community and her presence and sweet influence will be sadly
                                missed by her people to whom she was attaclied by the most endearing ties of Christian
                                love.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sawyer, Otis" TEIform="persName"/> Elder Otis Sawyer.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>Juvenile</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mystery of the seed" TEIform="index"/> THE MYSTERY OP THE SEED.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Larcom, Lucy" TEIform="persName"/>Lucy Larcom.</byline><p TEIform="p">Children dear, can you read The mystery of the seed— . The little seed that will not
                                remain In earth, but rises in fruit and grain? A mystery, passing strange Is the seed,
                                in its wonderous change; Forest and flower in its husk concealed, And golden wealth of
                                harvest-field. Ever around, and above Works the invisible love, It lies in the heaven
                                and under the land, In blossom and sheaf and reaper's hand. Sower, you surely know That
                                the harvest never will grow Except for the angel's snow and rain Who water and ripen the
                                springing grain! Awake for us, heart and eye, Are watchers beyond the sky; There are
                                unseen reapers in every band Who lend their strength to the weary hand. When the
                                wonderful light breaks through From above, on the work we do We can see how near our
                                helpers are Who carry the sickle and wear the star. Sower, you surely know That good
                                seed never will grow Except for the angel of joy and pain, Who scatter the sunshine and
                                pour the rain.' Child, with the sower sing! Love is in every thing! The secret is deeper
                                than we can read— But we gather the grain if we sow the seed.— Lucy Larcom in St.
                                Nicholas.</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="This is not the cold I had last winter, said a little fellow of five years..." TEIform="index"/>
                                This is not the cold I had last winter, said a little fellow of five years...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">This is not the cold I had last winter, said a little fellow of five years, that was a
                                big one that made me stay in bed.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>E.</byline></div3><pb n="284" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind Driver" TEIform="index"/> THE KIND DRIVER.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">THE KIND DRIVER. A lady sitting at a window with some friends, saw a wagon
                                        and a pair of horses cuming down the road, driven by a stout boy. "Here comes a
                                        kind driver," she said "I've noticed the way he treats his horses, and their
                                        obedience and attachment. Wait until he gets near, and I'll speak to him.' So
                                        when the boy came opposite to the house, the lady called out, "Good morning,
                                        Benjamin. Won't you show my friends what a bright pair of horses you have? Make
                                        them shake hands." The driver called, "Whoa!" to the horses, and as soon as they
                                        had stopped, he said, speaking to one of them," Tom, shake hands !'' when
                                        instantly the horse lifted his foot in a pleased, gentle way, and gave it into
                                        the boy's hand, who, after shaking it and letting it fall, said: "Now, Tom, the
                                        other;" and up went that also. Then he went around to the other horse, and he
                                        did the same thing in the same gentle and pleased way. "Now turn round and come
                                        on," called out the boy; and instantly, without the crack of a whip or a loud
                                        command, the docile animals turned carefully the wagon, to which they were
                                        harnessed, and followed their kind driver as a dog would have followed his
                                        master. "Thank you, Benjamin," said the lady. "I wanted my friends to see how
                                        much more obedient animals can be made by kind than by harsh treatment." As the
                                        boy drove on with his horses, pleased with the notice that had been taken of
                                        him, one of the ladies said : "This reminds me of a little pony that is managed
                                        entirely without a whip. The pony obeys his master with all the docility of a
                                        dog. He has but to say, 'Tom, come here a little'' or 'Tom, a little farther,'
                                        and pony, just as if he could do everything but say 'Yes' in reply instantly
                                        does what he is told. On being asked one day if he never used the whip, the
                                        driver answered,'Oh, sir, if I were to use a whip, he would feel it,'—meaning
                                        that if he were to strike the pony, the animal's feelings would be hurt as much
                                        as his body-" Hundreds of stories like these could, be told, all showing how
                                        obedient, and gentle horses, as well as other animals, will become through kind
                                        treatment. We have only room, however, lor this short one about a horse which
                                        had a very benevolent master: "A Polish general once sent a man on a message,
                                        and ordered him to ride his favorite horse. When the messenger returned, he
                                        declared he would never ride that horse again, unless he could take the
                                        general's purse along with it. At every.poor man asking alms he met, the horse
                                        would stop, nor would he go on again until he either gave him something, or
                                        pretended to do so." The horse showed plainly the kind of master he had served;
                                        and, if he himself had not learned the Christian lesson of pity for the
                                        deserving poor, he gave his new rider a pretty strong hint of his duty in the
                                        matter.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Carrier dove" TEIform="index"/>Carrier Dove.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Lena;—As I have a little leisure and am..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Lena;—As I have a little leisure and am...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts, September 4, 1882" TEIform="index"/> Harvard, Mass. Sept. 4,
                                1882.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Lena;—As I have a little leisure and am sitting quite alone waiting for you to join
                                me, I thought I would pencil a few lines to you. Just think! I have been with believers,
                                seven years next January, and I never saw Elder Henry, before. I enjoyed the visit very
                                much. I think we should be very grateful for this kind remembrance. I wish we cotild
                                have had a chance to tell him all about the picnic we had with our.Shirley friends. Do
                                you not think he would like to have beard about it? What a good time we had. I wish the
                                day had been twice, as long. Dear sister, I have been thinking while here, how many
                                children there are who would like the privilege that I am enjoying. O I wish that more
                                children were blessed with such a good home, surrounded with so many kind friends, to
                                watch over and to instruct them.' How thankful I ought to be. It is my prayer that I may
                                realize the blessings that are bestowed upon me. I love my home and my friends, and I
                                will try to do so well that they will all love me. With much love I bid you good bye, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rosie" TEIform="persName"/>Rosie--Age, 13.</byline></div3><pb n="285" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Rose;—It was a great pleasure to receive a..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Rose;—It was a great pleasure to receive a...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts, September 1882" TEIform="index"/> Harvard, Mass. Sept. 1882.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Rose;—It was a great pleasure to receive a few lines from you. I have lived in this
                                society eight years and have seen Elder Henry once. We have had a privilege to see many
                                of our dear friends, and I shall remember it with great pleasure. 0 that I might
                                treasure in my heart every good word spoken by those who come to visit us. I often
                                think, how thankful I should be for my good home. ,, We hardly thought when we were
                                enjoying our visit with the friends from New Hampshire that the next day we should go
                                all over the world (as it were) in our Geography with our good Superintendent. His
                                lessons in Geology are very interesting, are they not? Have you solved that question he
                                asked us, "From whence came the soil?" 1 wish we could have asked Elder Henry about it,
                                I guess he would have told us. The little card which I received I prize very highly.
                                Hoping that our Fall term may close as pleasantly as it began, I will now close. Age 13.
                                Your Sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lena" TEIform="persName"/>Lena.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our beloved Elder Henry C. Blinn, accompanied by..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Our beloved Elder Henry C. Blinn, accompanied by...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Harvard, September 9, 1882" TEIform="index"/> Harvard, Mass. Sept. 9,
                                1882.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Our beloved Elder Henry C. Blinn, accompanied by sisters Ednali E. Eitts and Flora
                                Williams arrived at Shirley. Also brother Frank Nowell accompanied by Eldress Isabella
                                Russell and Ednah Colliss arrived at Harvard, Saturday, P. M. The following Sabbath the
                                Harvard shakers accompanied by tlie Enfield visitors attended public meeting at Shirley.
                                Elder Henry delivered a discourse ; the subject being in reference to the Bible. The
                                audience listened with good attention. After meeting was over, bidding a hasty adieu, we
                                returned home. Monday following, Elder Henry and the sisters arrived at Harvard, in a
                                heavy rain. During the afternoon the visitors from Canterbury and from Enfield, also
                                several of the Brethren and Sisters from our own family spent about two hours at the
                                school house. After the exercises were finished Elder Henry, brother Frank and the four
                                sisters, gave the pupils some very good advice that we grate. fully received. After this
                                the Enfield visitors bid adieu to our Harvard home and took the train for Shirley. That
                                evening our Canterbury friends remained at the Office, and we went over to see them. The
                                next morning we parted with them not knowing when we should meet again. But I hope that
                                I may so live, and so prize my privilege, that I may sometime, meet them again. My home
                                withBelievershas been but twc years, but my determination is to be honest and truthful,
                                that I may, win the love of my fathers, mothers and dear companions. fi </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Coeyman, Carrie" TEIform="persName"/>Carrie Coeyman.-— Age, 14.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal" TEIform="index"/>Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">In the Phrenological Journal and Science op Health for November, which has come promptly
                                to hand, we notice an admirable article on "Ernerson's Poetry and Creed," and a very
                                entertaining sketch of Longfellow's Home and every-day life, by one who knew him. The
                                late Berthold Auerbach, so well known to the reader of high-class novels, receives
                                appreciative attention, and so does the lion of the day in European affairs, General
                                Wolseley, whose success in the Egyptian struggle 1 has brought him into special
                                prominence. Dr. William Aikman gives an excellent epitome of the Race Characteristics of
                                the Anglo-Saxon, and an itinerant photographer writes pleasantly of his experiences
                                among the "natives" of Newfoundland, the past summer. In the health department,
                                sufferers from corns and bunions will find "something to their advantage" in the
                                illustrated article with the heading "Where the Shoe Pinches," and the great need of
                                physiological and hygienic information among the people is the burden of "Medical
                                Difficulties." How improper living and the taking of medicines cause illness and disease
                                is the topic which obtains a brief notice in two articles, and then the needs of our
                                table are ministered to in a dozen neat recipes, while the departments of general
                                science and correspondence are filled with pertinent matter. One of the Journal's staff
                                attended the late meeting of the American Science Association, and gives an instructive
                                review of the discussions and liberal entertainment of our Canadian neighbors.
                                Altogether, this is a notable Number and should help the circulation of the magazine.
                                Price only 20 cents, or $2.00 a year, with the last three months of this year free,
                                together with life-size Phrenological Bust free to all subscribers. To find out what the
                                Phrenological. Journal is like, }Tou can send 25 cents in stamps for a trial trip of 3
                                months. Address Fowler &amp; Wells, Publishers, 753 Broadway, New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Saint Louis magazine" TEIform="index"/>The St. Louis Magazine
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The St.
                                Louis Magazine for October contains a splendid illustrated article on the Grand Opera
                                House of St. Louis, several splendid stories, an illustrated Fashion Article and other
                                useful family reading. A sample copy sent on receipt ol two 3 cent stamps. Address T. J.
                                Gilmore, 213 N. Eighth St, St. Louis, Mo. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Homiletic monthly" TEIform="index"/>The Homiletic Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The. following are among the contents of The
                                IIomiletic Monthly for November: Sermonie— "Love to an Unseen Christ," by B. M. Palmer,
                                D. D., of New Orleans; "Personal Virtue and Religion—To Young Men," by C. II. Hall, D.
                                D., of Brooklyn; "Love aii'l I, a Mystery," with a facsimile of the Pulpit Notes used
                                during the delivery of the Sermon, by Rev. C. II. Spurgeon; "God's Way in the
                                Sanctuary," by R. S. Storrs, D.D.; "Activity the Condition of Growth," by Rev. Milton
                                Fiery; "The Completeness of Divine Teaching,"'by Joseph Parker, D. D.; "Coming to <pb n="286" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> 286 SHAKER MANIFESTO. Christ," by E. W. Hitchcock, I). D.; "The
                                Vanities," by T. DeWitt Talmage, D. D. Among a number of interesting papers are the
                                following: "The Advantages of extemporaneous Preaching," No. I, by James M. Buckley, D.
                                D.; "Hints to Young Preachers,' No. II, by Prof. James M. Hoppin, D.D.; "Misquoted
                                Scripture," No. VII, byTalbot W. Chambers, D. D.; "Residuum of Power," by Rev. A.
                                McElroy Wylie. There are a score or more of very suggestive articles, grouped under ';he
                                heads of Preachers Exchanging Views," "Sermonic Criticisms" and "Living Issues for
                                Pulpit Treatment." The magazine is full of interest and instruction to clergymen and
                                other students of Scripture. Price, 2.50 per year; single number, 25 cents. Punk
                                &amp; Wagnalls, 10 and 12 Dey Street, New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Other world order" TEIform="index"/>Other World Order
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Other Wo eld Ordeh; Suggestions and
                                Conclusions thereon, by William White, London 1876. The author claims to be the sun of
                                Quaker parents, but has on his religious pilgrimage through life passed through several
                                of the theological isms, andnow confidently asks,—"Who knows anything of the order of
                                the other world?" He then contends "that there is place and use in the divine economy
                                for all varieties of men and women; and that there is not any one, however perverse or
                                insignificant, who is not created for some function in universal humanity." The whole
                                work breathes a liberality and trust in God that is very acceptable, and must commend
                                itself to the liberal intelligence of the di.y. London; E. W. Allen, 11 Ava Maria Lane,
                                E. C. Cloth, small 8 vo., Price 30.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="History of the English people" TEIform="index"/>History of the English people
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> A. GOOD CYCLOPEDIA. We have heretofore published
                                notices referring to the publication of Green's famous "History of the English People,"
                                which is issued by The Useful Knowledge Publishing Company, of New York. Besides its
                                issue in five handsome "Elzevir" volumes, and in one "Model Octavo" volume, it forms a
                                portion of the Cyclopedia of History, which is being published by the same house. The
                                plan of the Cyclopedia of History is that it shall contain, unabridged, the great
                                standard works of such authors as Green, Macaulay, Grote, Carlyle, Creasey, Schiller,
                                Mommsen, Gibbon, anJ others, with such additions by the editors and special writers as
                                will be necessary to make the Cyclopedia complete and universal in character; unity and
                                convenience of consultation being secured by the publication of the "World's Index of
                                Knowledge" in connection with it.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mechanical news" TEIform="index"/>Mechanical News
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> JL POl'UJLAIft We are in receipt of the
                                "MechanicalNews" for November 1st, published by James Leffel &amp; Co., No. 110
                                Liberty Street, New York, and take pleasure in calling the attention of our readers to
                                the same. With the present number the publishers send out a supplement in the shape of
                                an illustrated Premium List, that reflects credit on the selection of the articles
                                offered and the typographical appearance of the List. Upon application to the publishers
                                this premium List will be sent free to any address, and from its pages useful articles
                                can be secured, with or without the paper, at a reasonable price, and with the certainty
                                of fair treatment, as the subscriber or purchaser will be dealing with an old and
                                reliable business firm. The List will be found very useful to those who live remote from
                                the large cities, for the selection of holiday presents. The "News" is among (he best
                                papers that come to our editorial table filled as it is with original and choice
                                illustrations of the important and novel inventions of the time-s. Its editorial pages
                                are replete with well considered articles of practical subjects, readily understood by
                                any reader; while its comprehensive news melange makes it attractive to those interested
                                in the industrial prosperity of our country—the whole forming a rich store of useful
                                reading, the "News" is furnished at One Dollar per year, including a useful premium.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="home" TEIform="index"/>House-hold</head><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Use of borax for washing" TEIform="index"/> USE 0F BORAX FOR WASHING.</head><p TEIform="p"> The washer-women of Holland and Belgium, so proverbially clean, and who get up their
                                linen so beautifully white, use refined borax as washing-powder, instead of soda, in the
                                proportion of one large handful of borax-powder to about ten gallons of boiling water.
                                They save in soap nearly half. All of the large washing-establishments adopt the same
                                plan. For laces, cambrics, and lawns an extra quantity of powder is used, and for
                                crinolines requiring to be made stiff, a strong solution is necessary. Borax being a
                                neutral salt, does not in the slightest degree injure the texture of the linen. Its
                                effect is to soften the hardest water.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to make tomato figs" TEIform="index"/> HOW TO MAKE TOMATO FIGS.</head><p TEIform="p"> 1'our boiling water over the tomatoes in order to remove the skins ; then weigh them and
                                place them in a stone jar, with as much sugar as you have tomatoes, and Jet them stand
                                two days ; then pour off the syrup, and boil and skim it until no scum rises. Then pour
                                it over the tomatoes and let them stand for two days as before, then boil and skim
                                again. After the third time, they are fit to dry, if the weather is good; if not let
                                them <pb n="287" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 287 stand in syrup until drying weather.
                                Then place on large earthen plates or dishes, and put them in the sun to dry, which will
                                take about a week, after which pack them down in small wooden boxes, with fine white
                                sugar between each layer. Tomatoes prepared in this manner will keep for years.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tobacco-a parable" TEIform="index"/> TOBACCO-A PARABLE.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">TOBACCO-A PARABLE Then shall the kingdom of Satan be likened to a grain of
                                        tobacco-seed, which, though exceedingly small, being cast into the ground grew,
                                        and became a great plant, and spread its leaves rank and broad, so that huge and
                                        vile worms formed a habitation thereon. And it came to pass, in the course of
                                        time, that one came to look upon it, and thought it beautiful to look upon, and
                                        much to be desired to make lads look big and manly. So they did put forth their
                                        hands and did chew thereof. And some it made sick, and others to vomit most
                                        filthily. And it further came to pass that those who chewed became weak and
                                        unmanly, and said we are enslaved and cannot cease from chewing it And the
                                        mouths of all that were enslaved became foul, and were seized with a violent
                                        spitting; and they did spit, even in ladies' parlors and in the house of the
                                        Lord of hosts. And the saints of the Most High were greatly plagued thereby. And
                                        in the course of time it came also to pass that others s miffed it. and they
                                        were taken suddenly with fits, and they did sneeze with a great and mighty
                                        sneeze, insomuch that their eyes filled with tears; and they did look
                                        exceedingly silly. And yet others cunningly wrought the leaves thereof into
                                        rolls, and did look very grave and calf-like; and their sraok? ascended up
                                        forever and ever. And the cultivation thereof became n grt-at and mighty
                                        business upon the earth : ami tl e merchantmen waxed rich by the conmuTee
                                        thereof. And it came to pass that the saints of the Most High defiled themselves
                                        therewith ; even the poor who could not buy shoes nor bread nor books for their
                                        little ones spent their money for it. And the Lord was greatly displeased
                                        therewith, and said, "Wherefore this waste? and why do these little ones lack
                                        bread and shoes and books? Turn now your fields into corn and wheat, and put
                                        this evil thing far from you, and be separate, and defile not yourselves any
                                        more, and I will bless you and cause my face to shine on you." But with one
                                        accord they all exclaimed, "We cannot cease from chewing, snuffing, and
                                        puffing—we are slaves."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian secretary" TEIform="index"/>Christian Secretary</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Washing oil-cloths" TEIform="index"/> Washing Oil-Cloths.</head><p TEIform="p">—Some working girls cannot imagine that they can clean an oilcloth without a pail of
                                strong, hot suds and a good, stiff' scrub brush. Then she puts to her work all the
                                strength of a good, strong, healthy arm, and smiles with great satisfaction at the
                                result of her labors. No doubt for a few moments, till the cloth is dry, the colors
                                stand out clearly and the floor looks fresh and brilliant. It takes but a few of such
                                scrubbings, however, to destroy the best oil-cloth ever made. But take a pail of clean,
                                soft lukewarm water, a nice soft piece of flannel, and wash your oil-cloths ; wipe them
                                very dry so that no drop of water is left to soak in and rot the fabric, and you will
                                have little cause to complain that they wear out fast, provided you select one of good
                                make. After washing and drying, if a cloth is wrung out of a dish of skim-milk and water
                                and the oilcloth is rubbed over with this and then again well dried, the freshness and
                                lustre of the cloth will well repay the extra labor.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What a good cow will do" TEIform="index"/>What a Good Cow will do
                            </head><p TEIform="p">—A good cow will make 200 pounds of butter in a season, and
                                skim-milk, fed to 30 pigs, will grow 200 pounds of dressed pork, or the same skimmilk
                                fed to a calf will put on at least 200 pounds of live weight. A good steer fed in the
                                ordinary way will dress 800 to, 2,000 pounds at four years, having grown on the average
                                250 pounds of meat each year, whereas the cow has made 200 pounds of butter, and the
                                refuse of her milk has produced nearly as much meat in the pork or growth of young beef
                                in the calf as the average growth of a steer for one year.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When we have well done..." TEIform="index"/>When we have well done...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> When we have well done something we dreaded to do, how much better we feel.</p></div3></div2><pb n="288" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watching and waiting" TEIform="index"/>Watching and Waiting</head><p TEIform="p"> Enfield, Conn. Shakers, N. Y. 1. Lord, her watch thy church is keeping; When shall earth
                            thy rule 2. Tidings sent to ev'ry creature, Millions yet have nev3. To the end thy
                            church completed, All thy chosen gath"75 - bey? er heard; ered in, "When Can With shall
                            end they hear their King the night of without a in glory weeping? When shall
                            preacher? Lord Al seated, Satan break the mighty, bound and promised day? give
                            the word, banished sin. See Give Gone the whit'ning the word in forev harvest every na
                            parting, weepguish, Wait tion, Leting, Huning the ger, still the gospel sorrow', lab
                            'rer's toil; trumpet sound, death and pain; Was it vain Witnessing Lo ! her watch
                            thy son's deep anguish? world's salvation church is keeping, Shall the To the
                            Come Lord strong retain the spoil? earth's remotest bound. Jesus, come to reign.
                            WATCHING AND WAITING</p></div2><!--
    <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]<pb id="p30"/>
                            <pb id="p31"/>
                            <pb id="p32"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>