<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2802" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">28</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><date value="18980201" TEIform="date">February 1898</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">17-32</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="28" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
A CONCISE  HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF   THE
 CHURCH,
OK
ILL USTRATIONS
THE  ALTRUIST.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF   THE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS.
" Price, 10 cts.
AND
SHAKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the United   Society   of   Believers   in   Christ's
Second Appearing.    Illustrated.
By Giles B. Avery.
Price,  15 cts.
THE
MANIFESTO

FEBRUARY, 1898.
Juxt. Published.     The book is printed
with large type  and  on  excellent  paper.
It  contains  130 pages and has
"United   Society   of  Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price, 50 els.
of the Shakers and their
The  work  gives  quite an extended account  of  the  Several SOCIETIES,  their
organization and general management.
Price,  50 cts.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all their
property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley, 1Y19 Franklin Ave, St. Louis, Mo.
MILLENNIAL
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
Formerly  Boston  Journal of Chemistry
ENLARGED and IMPROVED.
This popular monthly contains a lar^e n nn
ber of Short, Easy. Practical, Interesting and
Popular, Scientific aitides, that can be Appreciated and Enjoyed by any intelligent reader,
even though he knew little or nothing of Sci
ence. It is intended to interest those who think
Profusely illustrated and Free
from Technicalities
Entirely Different from and much superior to
other papers  with a similar name.
Monthly,   $1.60 per year.
 15 .cts.
Largest Circulation of any
Scientific Paper.
LILLAED & CO.,
108 Fulton St., New Fork.
4g"Mention this paper for u sample copy.
This work sets fortli the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of tin
several
ORDERS    OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES  and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION     AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
the same time, afford instruction to all inquiring minds. Price 5 cts. each, postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
HUMAN NATURE
is an illustrated Monthly, now only 50 cts.
per year, devoted to PHEENOLOGrY.
PHYSIOGNOMY,  HEALTH,   MEDICAL
& SOCIAL EEPOEM.
Would you like a copy?
Send 5 cts. for Sample to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Francisco, Cal.
Oldest      and      Best      Recognized
Weekly    Paper     in    the    United
States.
Improved        Management,         an 1
Methods up to date.
A   Family   Journal
Of Morals and Public Interests,
Newsy, Liteiary, Scientific,
Humorous, Dramatic, Entertaining. Also G. A. R., Masonic
Fire and Society News.
One Copy,  One  Year,  $2.53.
Post yourself on what is going
on  in     New   York.     Address
The   New   York Dispatch
317" Broadway, IVew York.

KNIT GOODS
Gents   ITA^F1 HOSE   and
8"WJ3ATER8, suited to
all   atliletic   sports,
Bloy cling,   Boating fc Base oall.
Made of the best Australian wool in
three gradrs.    Heavy, Medium and Light,
designated as Nos. 1, 2, 3.    Colors, White,
Black and Blue in the above grades.     Tan,
Garnet, Brown and Gray in the medium
only.    Sold at wholesale and retail.
Address Hart & Shepaed,
East Canterbury, N. H.
WONDERFUL strange REVELATIONS,
DANIEL'S & STJOHN'S
PROPHECIES.
48 page pamphlet.     Price 10 cts.
13 for $1.00.
Address,   H. B. Bear, Preston, Ohio.
The New York
Dispatch.. . .
N3-jrsd3alers,
THE SHAKER COVENANT.
EXPLAINING
POPULAR SCIENCE
NEWS
HEALTH
Nature, Invention,
Archaeology, Electricity
Chemistry, Mineralogy,
Health, Hygiene, Medicine--><pb n="17" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progress of shakerism, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>THE PROGRESS OF SHAKERISM. NO. 2</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>Elder Henry C. Blinn</byline><p TEIform="p">IN the forming of the Shaker Communities, ministers, deacons, lawyers, doctors and tradesmen
                            of all kinds were brought together, with their wives and children, and they were quite like
                            those mentioned by the Apostle in Corinthians, Galatians and Ephesians, and like those who
                            are found in every city and village. So soon as the Community was organized a Christian
                            discipline was brought forward, and by multiplied, gradual steps the work has past on
                            through many degrees of religious experience. The sermon on the Mount now became the subject
                            for contemplation, as preferable to the study of military tactics or to the accumulation of
                            selfish interests. "To live righteously, soberly and godly in this present world," became a
                            theme for practical righteousness, as this new family or church of Christ came out from the
                            relations of the old inheritance, and were baptized into that life which comes from God.
                            These old heroes of the Revolution had now enlisted in the army of the Lord, and were
                            fighting as zealously for the kingdom of God, as they had fought for the success of their
                            national freedom. In the service of their country, and in the service of their God, they
                            became the victorious conquerors and could rightfully say with the* Apostle,"We have fought
                            the good fight, we have finisht our course, we have kept the faith." It was a wonderful
                            reformatory work that these soldiers of the cross had entered, and in their zeal to fight
                            against the sins of the world, many things <pb n="18" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 18 THE MANIFESTO. were past
                            over, that at a later date must be brought to the test of a Christian discipline. While
                            there may be much neatness and much kindness among Americans, there may also be much love
                            for tobacco and strong drink. The orators want it when they make a speech, and the ministers
                            of an earlier date wanted it when they preacht a sermon. One of the old poets tells us why
                            tobacco was so largely used, "Men of sound reason used their pipes, For colic pains and
                            stomach gripes." A record of the installment of a Christian minister informs us that two
                            "barrels of New England rum were purchased for the company. During the few past years the
                            temperance people and the anti-tobacco society have accomplisht a wonderful work. It was
                            customary in the earlier part of the century to place before all visiting friends, the glass
                            and decanter. Sometimes it was a glass of common cider, while at other times it was
                            blackberry or strawberry wine, or perhaps a glass of cider brandy. Regular drains of spirit
                            were taken every morning before breakfast, and then more or less cider at each meal. At the
                            lime of establishing the Shaker Community and the accepting of a Christian life or
                            discipline, as leading toward a more spiritual order, all the elements of human nature were
                            brought together. These had existed in the family of man since the day that they entered the
                            garden of Eden. In some communities might be found not less than three hundred people of all
                            ages, of both sexes, and with multiplied religious professions. In the year 1828 a
                            temperance wave past over the United States, and the several Societies of Believers at that
                            time agreed to discontinue the use of the morning dram and the practice of placing wine or
                            cider before any visitors. No spirit was to be drank except by order of a physician; and
                            from this date a markt reformation began. It had, strange to say, taken some forty years to
                            be able to comprehend the necessity of this advanced step in Christian progression. Altho
                            the subject of temperance was more earnestly agitated in England than in America, yet
                            neither those in the Christian church, nor many out of the church made any special change
                            for several years. In 1837 the subject of eating and drinking was agitated and became a
                            matter worthy of consideration by those who had accepted the life of Christ, and were
                            learning how best to accomplish the most good as Christians of the resurrection order. The
                            subject was brought before the people in several Soci*etics, and quite a large number of the
                            Brethren and Sisters abstained from the use of fat and blood and from the grosser kinds of
                            meat that came to the table. Some even abstained from meat of every kind, and no less from
                            the use of tea and coffee. This was in accordance with the spiritual profession of the
                            Shakers and could not otherwise than do a large amount of good. <pb n="19" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 19 Up to this date the majority of good Christian people had given but little or
                            no thought to the subject of dietetics and were quite well satisfied to eat that which was
                            placed before them, asking no questions. A slice from a ground hog was accepted with the
                            same relish as a piece of roast beef, while a "coon" well basted was a tidbit for an
                            epicure. Believers in the Bible must be interested to know that Abraham has the honor of
                            being the first reformer in this line and that he made a radical change from the customs of
                            his day. Moses followed the example of Abraham and made more advanced regulations in
                            dietetics. A most remarkable success attended the children of Israel, the foundation of
                            which was laid whileon their wilderness journey. At the time that Abraham instituted the
                            reformation, the human family ate very much as did the wild beasts, and like them made fat
                            and blood a luxury. The Bible holds on record this remarkable commandment,"Every moving
                            thing that liveth shall be meat for you," and the race has followed this to the very letter.
                            Every thing that could be procured, whether on the land or in the water, whether beast, bird
                            or reptile has probably been used more or less for food. Strange as this may seem, the
                            carniverous, and even the onmiverous habit still rules the human race and so late as the
                            nineteenth century, the civilized nations find appetizing food in the cooking of reptiles.
                            As food and drink have a ruling influence over the mind for good or ill, no Christian can
                            well afford to allow the subject to pass without a thorough investigation. (To be
                            continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enroute" TEIform="index"/>ENROUTE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mace, Aurelia G." TEIform="persName"/>By Aurelia G. Mace.</byline><p TEIform="p">IT was a lovely morning,the 22nd of October 1897when Elders William Dumont and Henry Green,
                            Eldress Elizabeth Haskell and the writer started from Alfred, Maine, for a visit to the
                            Societies of Believers in New Hampshire. Through a clear, crisp atmosphere, the smoking
                            engine hurried us along, over hill and through dale, by pleasant woodlands and cultivated
                            farms to Alton Bay. Then for a number of miles, along the shores of Lake Winnipiseogee,
                            through whose clear, placid waters could be plainly seen the white pebbly bottom of the
                            lake. One view of Mt. Washington, far to the north-west and we are off to Laconia, at which
                            station we are made glad by meeting two Brethren from Canterbury, Elder Benjamin Smith and
                            Brother Arthur Bruce, with carriages to take us to their pleasant village twelve miles
                            distant. We arrive as the shades of evening are falling and are welcomed to one of our most
                            beautiful homes, by our own Brothers and Sisters. All things needed for our comfort are
                            amply supplied by their love and care. The days of our visit come and go, all pleasant days,
                            bringing pleasures and surprises manifold. <pb n="20" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 20 THE MANIFESTO. In the
                            Office of The Manifesto, our beloved Elder Henry C. Blinn, explains to us the machinery by
                            which our thoughts are stampt upon paper, and the little pamphlets are made, which carry our
                            ideas to the Societies of Believers and to the outside world; all done under his watchful
                            guidance. He then took us to his museum where are carefully stored many relics of old, so
                            interesting to us in these latter days. We saw the skeleton in the closet, reminding us that
                            we are "fearfully and wonderfully made," and while these earthly forms are niouldeiing to
                            dust, the spirit, which is the reality, is marching on in the beautiful life beyond. We are
                            visiting with those we have long loved, and surrounded by scenes which call to mind
                            historical events of the old times. Not the least of these is the building in which the
                            Sacred Roll was printed in the year 1843. Before us, we seem to see Philemon Stewart in all
                            the glory of his great inspiration. Of our company, only one can remember those days. The
                            evenings are delightfully enjoyed. One evening we listen to the quartet, to the piano and
                            organ ; the next to the orchestra; but the evening in which the pilgrims marcht to the Holy
                            City, was the entertainment which took the palm. We saw the beautiful city with its
                            battlements and towers. We saw the shining ones passing out and in, guiding the pilgrims
                            along their weary way. We saw Doubt and Scorn and all the powers of evil vanquisht. Then the
                            door was opened to receive them, amid the rejoicing of the angels. At this time there came a
                            scene for which we were wholly unprepared. Elder William Duraont said to Elder Henry Green,
                            "Let us go in, it may be our only chance." So they past in, and "in my dream," I saw them no
                            more. Under the loving control of Eldress Dorothy A. Durgin, these entertainments are
                            perfected and carried out. The magnetism of her spirit smooths down the roughness, always
                            strengthening the weak and drawing out the good. It is the divine Mother Spirit, in her,
                            personified. "Beauty reigns all around thy borders, Where her lovely feet have trod, Peace
                            and order, love and union, In the power and gift of God." As time passes on, the Sabbath
                            comes. This day is marred by no cloud. It is a perfect day. At the appointed hour, the
                            Sanctuary is opened, not only for the Believers, but also for those friends who choose to
                            attend. The singing is in perfect harmony, and most beautiful and inspiring. In this service
                            we had the privilege of listening to a discourse from Brother T. A. Dwyer, late from the
                            outside churches, and now establisht in the New Jerusalem which hath come down from God, out
                            of heaven. The Word is held forth in perfect language, and as the Testimony of true
                            Shakerism falls from his lips, we can not wonder that the two thousand, who listened to his
                                <pb n="21" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 21 pleading tones in the Universalist church in
                            Laconia, turned to their homes in tears of joy and new resolves for the future. Thus will
                            the old heavens and earth pass away and all things become new. This day came to a close like
                            the others, and it will never be forgotten. In the course of the coming week, Elder Henry C.
                            Blinn and Eldress Emeline Hart conducted us to their home in Enfield. Places of interest
                            were pointed out to us along the way. We past the birth-place of the immortal Webster, and
                            the Webster Lake, where, in youthful days, he spent hours of recreation in fishing. The
                            journey was made very pleasant for us, and the time past quickly, bringing us to their home
                            in Enfield. Eldress Joanna Kaime met us at the door, and her kind welcome gave us the
                            assurance that we were not among strangers, but with our near and dear relation. Great
                            kindness is shown to us in this home, where Elder Abraham Perkins spent so many years of his
                            devoted life, the home of his heart's deep love. We remained nearly a week in this beautiful
                            place, visited the North family, which was the home of Elder John Lyou, that great
                            expounder, who kept the sieve full and kept it shaking. Would that he were here now, to
                            continue the work, until the deserted villages were filled with the "Elect," "Sought out and
                            chosen." The scenery here is magnificent. The Brethren of our company went to a lake, far up
                            the mountain, on the west, fifteen hundred feet above the level of the village, from which
                            the Society is always sure of an abundant supply of water. It seems to be in the crater of
                            an old volcano, and there is no danger that it will ever break away and damage property.
                            Elder William Wilson very kindly took us around Mascoma Lake, east of the village, pointed
                            out the spot where the first Shaker meeting was held in New Hampshire, where the home of
                            James Jewett, the first convert, was situated and where John Cotton received faith ; he
                            being the first one to bring the gospel testimony after the order of our Church, into the
                            state of Maine. That meeting was held the 8th of Sept. 1782. We stopt a day over our time
                            that we might meet Eldress Rosetta Cumings and Sister Caroline Whitcher and three young
                            Sisters who were absent from home. We enjoyed a lovely visit with them in the afternoon. In
                            the evening had our farewell visit with the Ministry and Elders, only for the present,
                            however; many meetings are to be in the future. The next day we were taken to the station by
                            Brother George Baxter, and saying farewell to him until our next meeting, we retraced our
                            way to Canterbury. When we arrived in Concord the rain was falling in gentle showers. Elder
                            Henry Green left us at this point for Boston, homeward bound. We were expecting Sister Lucy
                            Ann Shepard and a company of Sisters from Canterbury, who were on their way to Boston. We
                            enjoyed an hour's visit with these loved ones, and then went on to Canterbury with the young
                            Brethren, leaving the Sisters to take the train. When we drove up to the Office, <pb n="22" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 22 THE MANIFESTO. many anxious ones were there to meet us; altho the rain was
                            pouring, the quartet was out singing of the "patter, patter of the rain." One day more in
                            lovely Canterbury, which is to be wA\ improved. We are granted another short visit with our
                            dearly loved Sister, Asenuth Stickney, who is suffering from injuries received by a severe
                            fall; also au additional visit with Sister Harriet Hastings whom we have all known to love.
                            Then we enjoy a delightful season with Elder Abraham Perkins and tell him of our visit to
                            his home in Enfield. He bears up remarkably under his ninety years. By the kindness of our
                            Canterbury friends, Sister Ednah E. Fitts is to accompany us to our home at Sabbathday Luke,
                            stay with us during the winter and teach music. The last morning arrived, and with Sister
                            Ednah we are taken to the station in Laconia. Here we part with Elder Benjamin and Brother
                            Arthur, who have been so kind to us, and we are on our way home. We stop at Alfred over
                            night and go on to Sabbathday Lake the next day. All is well. We again take up the thread of
                            life in the old accustomed way. Our music teacher arranges her classes and commences her
                            labor of love. Music is in the atmosphere and a song of rejoicing in our souls,a song that
                            can only be learned by the hundred forty and four thousand. The half has not been told.
                            Sabbathday Lake, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Praise" TEIform="index"/>PRAISE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Annie R." TEIform="persName"/>By Annie R. Stephens.</byline><p TEIform="p">For the rich autumn days, the summer's rare treasures, That past like a glad spirit's flight;
                            For the gift of our lives, their unfailing pleasures, We thank Thee, O Father of Light 1 An
                            unending chain of mercies eternal From life's rosy dawn to its close, Has filled all our
                            days with blessings supernal, While joy like a fountain o'erflows. We'll count the calm
                            hours of sunlight and gladness, And walk where the hope-light appears, We'll banish the
                            clouds of sorrow and sadness, And praise Thee through smiles and through tears. Then hear,
                            Father, hear our songs of thanksgiving, Accept our sweet incense of praise; Our voices shall
                            tell in the courts of the living, The worth of our fullness of days. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><pb n="23" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Forgiveness" TEIform="index"/>FORGIVENESS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Larkin, Eva" TEIform="persName"/>By Eva Larkin.</byline><p TEIform="p">WHEN an experienced woodsman hews down a tree, he can not only tell the age of the tree by
                            the wood grains exposed by the cutting, but by close observation he can read the history of
                            past seasons. Each has left its impression upon the wood, the dry or rainy, pleasant or
                            dreary periods are plainly discernible. So with our life. Each year adds to our spiritual
                            growth, each trivial act forming a tiny grain, which in the future will tell what the life
                            has been. As the tree grows, each year the outer ring is pusht toward the centre, leaving a
                            place for the nevv growth constantly forming. So our characters are daily adding new growth.
                            What we now give or receive, our thoughts and words, as truly as deeds, in process of time
                            is pusht into the heart-lil'e becoming a part of our characters. As good wood is not formed
                            in constant sunshine, neither is the truest life obtained by continual prosperity. Days of
                            wind and rain, of trial and disappointment are necessary to a full development; and
                            temptation firmly resisted, proves the strengthening tissue. But how often when yielded to
                            they make upon the character, a blemish. We may be rude and ask to be excused, or
                            thoughtless and implore forgiveness until the "seventy times seven" have been fulfilled, in
                            a thoughtless half-hearted manner, but such sorrow does not work repentance. If we are
                            sincerely repentant and in humility, pray for strength to atone for the wrong committed, it
                            will be given. When this spirit prompts a search for forgiveness we own our hatred of wrong,
                            acknowledging before others our standard of right, thus strengthening our purpose to live
                            more perfectly in the future. When again tempted to a like sin, we will think, "I met this
                            evil once and was conquered by it, this time I will be the conqueror, for the seal of true
                            forgiveness is, 'Go and sin no more.' " In the battle of life we often are wounded;
                            sometimes unknowingly, by those around us, while at the same time we may send a dart at
                            another, wounding those whom we hold dear. So it behooves us often to apply to the needs of
                            others the oil of love and forgiveness, that we may in return merit the same. If we are
                            wounded while fighting for the right, so deeply wounded that we feel we can no longer stand,
                            we need not regret it, for it is only by losing the natural life that we gain the eternal.
                            The soldier who returns from battle, bearing many scars as test of faithful service, is more
                            honored than he who flees from the dangers and escapes unharmed. So the Christian
                            approaching heaven's gate, when the battle is ended and the final roll is called, will count
                            each scar an honor, while the dangers are forgotten in the joy of the welcome, "Well done."
                            Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="24" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Everlasting truth" TEIform="index"/>THE EVERLASTING TRUTH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>By Hamilton DeGraw.</byline><p TEIform="p">FOR the advancement of the human soul along the lines which are near, ing that goal, to reach
                            which has bi en the hope of the founders of all forms of religious belief, and the desire of
                            reformers in the political world for ages, organizations have been establisht among men for
                            the purpose of solidifying and making the efforts to that end more effective. In reviewing
                            history it is plainly realized that necessity is the parent of the forces that are evolving
                            human destiny. For a larger scope and a broader freedom that will enable life to realize
                            those conditions which are more favorable for its advancement new sects and parties have
                            been establisht; the result of a breaking away from the old lines of thought which formerly
                            controlled. The effort to attain this ideal is not prompted by the desire to win fame, for
                            the percentage of such lives as have been recognized by their contemporaries is so small in
                            comparison to the whole as hardly to be discerned. When in the course of human events the
                            vestments worn by nations and races, by sects and parties have become outgrown, ragged and
                            moth eaten, there must be a change. It is not merely a question of like or dislike, for from
                            its exalted station the everlasting truth has given the command to advance, and obedience
                            must be rendered. The Reformer who undertakes the beneficent tusk of educating human thought
                            to a higher standard of duty must be a soul that is in close communion with its divine
                            Parentage and can receive its inspiration unmixt with human foliies and wrongs; one who can
                            meet the errors that afflict life with on unflinching look and condemn its infamous reign
                            without cringing. One who has received the everlasting truth in his life and made it his
                            permanent possession. "What is Truth?" This was the question askt of the divine Teacher and
                            is being repeated by every one who realizes that his life is capable of further unfoldment,
                            and is anxious to come into a more perfect knowledge of that power which is able to clear
                            away the debris of false ideas and customs and illuminate the soul with more perfect light;
                            and as that is attained the answer is given. Human progress is not the result of forces
                            moving in a confused and unorganized manner, but like the student in the rudimentary school
                            who is led up to higher grades by a systematic development of the latent powers, so is the
                            unfoldment of truth in its varied manifestations to the soul who is prepared to receive it.
                            We are astonisht at the operation of laws which are evolving from apparent chaos an orderly
                            condition, and call it the mysterious. That border land loses its claim for recognition in
                            proportion as the truth is made manifest. No arbitrary lines can establish the boundary
                            withno further shalt thou gofor being the offspring of the infinite Spirit we can only be
                            satisfied when striving to attain unto our destiny. The advance thought of one generation
                                <pb n="25" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> TL.E MANIFESTO. 25 is the conservative of the succeeding ; for
                            with the experience gaim'd through the success and failures of life conies the knowledge
                            which enables us to understand that the spirit of truth is the one supreme and Almighty
                            power. The environments that to the outward sense control the individual life, many times
                            prevent it from realizing that "there is a Divinity that shapes our ends, rough-hew them as
                            we may," even making the wrath of man or his ambition for personal honor redound to the
                            benefit of his fellow-beings. Bonaparte, the central figure in thoLe mighty events which the
                            opening years of the nineteenth century witnessed is the most prominent one of modern times.
                            The scourging that was given to the effete despotisms of Europe that were styled civilized
                            and Christian governments but whose principle object for existing was to live on the plunder
                            extorted from the people regardless of the cres of the opprest and which compelled them to
                            come to the people as supplicants asking for help to resist the invader, granting
                            concessions which the ruling powers have never recovered, proving that life is more than the
                            result of external forces, and that the immortal principle which alone can make free is the
                            directing power in human events. When all the energy of life is given for the purpose of
                            developing this principle, the question is not askt,Is it popular? What will the people
                            think? But is it right? The uplifting power of truth is best exemplified in the words of the
                            divine Teacher,uIf I am lifted up I will draw all men unto me." The higher plains of thought
                            and life can offer no compromise, and if we would commune with the dwellers it must be by
                            ascending to their ideal. Garrison when he was contending against the powers of slavery
                            said, "I will not retract one word, and I will be heard." Expediency, thou art a delusion
                            and a snare. The honest man is honest whether material gain or loss is the result. Policy
                            can not sit as an honored guest in the parlor of the soul who is entertaining that
                            Comforter, even the Spirit of Truth which alone can grant absolution from the conditions of
                            servitude from which every progressive soul is longing to be free. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/>A PRAYER.</head><p TEIform="p">O Koly Spirit of God take me as Thy disciple : guide me, illuminate me, sanctify me. Bind my
                            hands that they may do no evil; cover my eyes, that they may see it no more ; sanctify my
                            heart, that evil may not dwell within me. Be Thou my God; be Thou my guide. Whithersoever
                            Thou leadest me I will go; whatsoever Thou forbiddest me I will renounce ; and whatsoever
                            Thou commandest me in Thy strength I will do. Lead me, then into the fullness of Thy truth.
                            Amen.</p></div2><pb n="26" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. FEBRUARY, 18G8. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is publisht by the
                            "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all
                            communications to Henby C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. TERMS. .50 One copy one
                            year, postage paid. A cross in the margin will show that your subscription has closed.
                            Remittances for subscription by Money Order should be on the Post Office at Concord, N.
                        H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">December. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Rain. Snow. 1896. 24.42 % in.
                                8.5in. 1897. 29.97 4. " 2ft. 9^" Highest Temp, during this mo. 58 above 0. Lowest " " "
                                " 8 " " Number of rainy days " " 4 " " snowy " " " 8 " " clear " " " 6 " " cloudy" " "
                                13 Dec. 31, 1897. December, with its terminus, passes 1897 into the vortex of by-gone
                                years, laden with two feet of pure white snow for a winding sheet. We willingly bid
                                adieu to the past year with all its pleasantness or unpleasantness. Altho storms and
                                clouds have been superabundant, yet we share one of life's choicest blessings,good
                                health. While sickness is very prevalent, yet, our family have escaped its
                                contamination, for which neglect we are truly grateful. Christmas was a festive day with
                                us. The youth and children did themselves honor and made the day replete with enjoyment
                                by their juvenile manifestations. Our dining-hall was beautifully festooned with
                                woodbine and other ornamentations. While we were seated at the breakfast table, boding
                                no surprise, we were suddenly serenaded by the juvenile company marching into the room,
                                appropriately caparisoned and surrounding an organ they had placed in the room, gave us
                                an unusual musical entertainment both vocal and instrumental. At the conclusion, the
                                band departed as quietly as they had entered. In the evening we met in the dininghall
                                and had a season of enjoyment which was made doubly pleasant by the enthusiasm
                                manifested by the young, even to the least. The meeting was interspersed by .
                                recitations alternated by vocal and instrumental music. An hour or more was filled by
                                the young people, and the ancients of the mansion were made glad by the inspiration
                                which permeated the meeting. At the close of the sociable we were treated to the
                                bounties provided by those in temporal care. In this the young people were the waiters
                                to carry the viands and drink and confectionary about to the company. As pleasant as the
                                entertainment was, the nobility exhibited by the actors, filled the hearts of we
                                recipients with a love and Christian blessing for them that language is incapable of
                                expressing. Calvin O. Heed. South Family. Jan. 1898. Christmas morning dawned cold,
                                clear and breezy. St. Nicholas made his annual visit to our home through th e agency of
                                    <pb n="27" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 27 Sister, Polly C. Lewis, leaving useful and
                                delicious gifts for each member. St. N"ick and St. Polly made Christmas pleasant to all.
                                Sister, Polly has past the eighty-third mile-stone of her earthly pilgrimage. Her life
                                since a child of four years has been spent at the Mt.Lebanon family where she still
                                lives to love and bless all who come within the radius of her benign influence.
                                Christmas afternoon a party from this place attended a reunion and festival with our
                                friends at Second family. The time was devoted to singing, reading, speaking and
                                recitations; the hours glided away all too quickly; the interlude was an enjoy able
                                repast from the liberal supplies of old Santa Glaus, the people's best friend. One of
                                the interesting features of the occasion was the fine violin exhibitions rendered by
                                (brother) "Paul an apostle of Jesus." Each act in the program was perfectly rendered.
                                The family hall was richly decorated with eveigreens artistically arranged, reminding us
                                of the Evergreen shores whei'e the Christinas bells will daily chime and friends will
                                meet in that happy clime. Peogbam. Hail all Hail, Song by All. Introductory Remarks, by
                                the Elders. Life of Christ, Dialogue. Ida and Susie. I Would Rather Be a Farmer, Poem.
                                Violin Solos. Paul. Love Divine, Song by All. The Little Heart, Poem. Lena. Grandfather
                                Snow, Poem. Mabel. The Household Tragedy, Poem. Lillian. Carol, Brothers, Carol, Song by
                                All. I'm Always Well, Poem. Boys. The Question Answered, Poem. Ida. Family Financiering,
                                Poem. Lillian. Bird Song, Poem. Behave Yourself. One Hundred Years Ago, Song by All.
                                Christmas Bells, Song. Little girls. Song of Christmas, Poem. Bessie. Informal Prayer,
                                Poem. Lena. Ding Dong, Song by All. Home, Living Christ, Ida. Susie. Closing Song,
                                Praise ye the Lord. The old year 1897 expired in silence and was buried in a snow bank.
                                The New Year 1898 is hard at work finishing "what 1897 failed to accomplish of blow and
                                snow and bluster. Sunday morning Sister Louisa Rice the family veteran who has witnessed
                                eighty-five winters went weather exploring and returned with the information that the
                                mercury recorded ten degrees below zero. Only a few were brave enough to encounter the
                                cutting atmosphere. Sister Louisa is the good Samaritan of our family. Genevieve
                                DeGrair.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Jan. 1893. The festive season of Christmas and New Year has come and gone*. Its record we
                                hope will be a verdant spot in the memories of those who were the participants. Willing
                                hands placed a beautiful evergreen tree in our chapel, and with its brilliant
                                illumination from the candle lights presented a very cheery aspect. But best of all was
                                the burden of gifts placed thereon by that dear old friend Santa Claus. He must have a
                                splendid memory as no one was forgotten. On Christmas eve we met to receive the gifts
                                that he had to bestow. Hope that every fireside and home in our land was visited. While
                                we step on the threshold of the New Year and find its page clean and white we question
                                what will be its record at the close? Just what we make it. Only one moment at a timp is
                                all we have to carry and the future ceases to be, by becoming the present. As we read of
                                rumors of war and see the belligerent attitude assumed by the dying monarchies of Europe
                                as a bluff to frighten their enemies; at the same time trembling with fear at the
                                portends of the coming revolution which will be their overthrow, we pray that in our own
                                beloved country the counsels of wisdom may prevail, so tha,t her mission can be to
                                direct the nations of the earth to that condition of life which is founded upon the
                                spix'it of love as it is the all conquering power. May all who love the truth be
                                encouraged. We wish all of our gospel friends a prosperous year, and may the cause that
                                we have given our life to sustain be blest as the result of faithful efforts. Hamilton
                                DeGraw.</p></div3><pb n="28" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Jan. 1898. We enter the Home Circle for the first call since 98 has been substituted on
                                the record of time, for the familiar 97 of the past year. That, now, has taken its place
                                in life's history, and the present and future await our writing. May its pages reveal to
                                us the beauty of a life of true consecration, and of Christ-like deeds. As we took up a
                                paper this morning we noticed these words by Phillips Brooks; "What is going to be our
                                truth for the New Year? Is it not that the love which has never deserted us shall come
                                closer to us, because it finds us readier to receive it,-making us better, stronger,
                                purer, nobler, more manly, more womanly, more fit for life. Not because God loves us any
                                more, but because we with new openness are more ready to receive him into our lives."
                                There are beauties in the rocks and stones which we daily see, not noticed, until by
                                careful study we learn of their wonderful formation. The smallest flower possesses a
                                double beauty for us when we analyze each separate part, and realize the use of each in
                                forming the perfect whole; and the dainty flakes of snow, reveal to us history of past
                                miracles, as we investigate the truths of their formation. All around us are hidden
                                beauties which only eyes opened to see, and a mind prepared to receive can fully
                                appreciate. So with our spiritual natures quickened, we shall see in every phase of life
                                the wisdom, love, and power, of an unseen hand. We have had some very cold wintry
                                weather. The snow fell, the wind blew, and the cold was so intense that their united
                                forces nearly formed a blizzard. The thermometer stood at ten deg. below zero at one
                                time which was a signal for all water pipes so situated as to be able to hear of it, to
                                refuse to hold the frozen water within them, until coaxt to resume their work once more.
                                Among the blessings for which we daily are grateful, not the least is the daily addition
                                of strength, which Brother Ira obtains, tho at present not free from suffering, we are
                                glad for all taken from him. Our little girls were made glad on Christmas eve, by a
                                nicely laden Christmas tree, its variety of fruits were eagerly gathered by them. May
                                the coming year be one of true blessing to all of our friends, while each day as a step
                                heavenward, leads to perfect happiness the glory of a Christ-like life. Fidelia
                                Estabrook.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoossa, Florida" TEIform="index"/>Narcoossa, Florida</head><p TEIform="p">Jan. 1898. The tide of winter travel and business has never set so strong toward Florida
                                as it does to-day, all telling a good record for the future of the State. The leading
                                question of the tourist is this,"Is the soil of Florida capable of raising enough to
                                sustain the farmer?" Florida is willing to trust her own unaided charms, even against
                                the false reports that have been made. Let the farmer come and show for himself or go
                                and see what his neighbor has done. The enterprising advertiser of the Pacific coast has
                                caught the men who deal in wheat, and pork and beef, while Florida has done all too
                                little to offset these efforts of the California boomers. Since writing the above we
                                have had another sad experience. Jan. 1, 2, and 3rd. Florida is again visited with an
                                untimely freeze. The mercury fell to 25 deg. below freezing, which killed much of the
                                vegetation that was not protected by fire or shelter. This may, for the present, retard
                                the tide of emigration which has been so strongly turned this way. Like the other
                                states, Florida has a dark side, and has also a bright side. Three years ago we had a
                                big freeze which cut down most of the fruit trees north of the frost line, and the state
                                has hardly recovered from that sad blow. "A smooth sea never made a skilled mariner." We
                                can hardly learn humility and tenderness, except by suffering. Andrew Barrett.</p></div3><pb n="29" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p">North. Family. Jan. 1898. How fast time flies! The years speed by before one has scarcely
                                time to realize they have begun. Another month and a year will have expired since the
                                first Canaanites migrated to the beautiful land of Connecticut. How strange, and yet how
                                real! Once more the holidays have bid us adieu. Christmas was spent in a very pleasant
                                manner. In the a. m. all Enfield attended Service at the Church. In the p. m. an
                                entertainment was given at the North family in which the three families participated We
                                have many blessings for which we need be thankful; one we should prize above all others,
                                is the pure relationship we are called to sustain as Brethren and Sisters in Christ, in
                                whose hearts dwell no envy, anger, nor strife, for this must be consumed by the love of
                                God. Edith Shufelt.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant Hill, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hill, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">Jan. 1898. So far our winter has been quite pleasant. Only a few days since the mercury
                                fell to 10 degrees above zero. Our first snow fall was about Christmas, of some two
                                inches, but in a few days it was all gone. During the autumn we had two months of severe
                                drought, but subsequently the rain and sunshine revived and gladened the fields with a
                                lovely carpet of green. Our apples were almost a failure, but of small fruits and
                                vegetables we had a good crop. During the past season the West family made some needed
                                repairs on several of the buildings, and after the painting had closed a decided
                                improvement was manifest. We have many blessings for which we make many expressions of
                                thankfulness. Nancy L. liupe.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Jan. 1898. "Manlike it is to fall into sin, Fiend-like it is to dwell therein,
                                Christ-like it is for sin to grieve, God-like it is all sin to leave." The above quoted
                                rhyme, is a good one to preface the new year's volume of events, to remind us that
                                virtue pays, and the way of the transgressor is hard. If it is written with the life pen
                                of loyalty to faith, home and associates, it will be worthy of divine acceptance when
                                finisht. To reflect upon the progress and failures made during the past year, will be
                                time well spent, if we reconstruct any wreckage made, strive to make more practical the
                                law of love, that in honor preferreth one another, and endeavor to do what we can to
                                keep pace with the light of our day. One of the gladsome events of the old year,
                                Christmas, we spent in a manner worthy of our calling. Our dining-room was tastefully
                                decorated with wreathes of evergreen, spruce branches and potted plants. While at
                                breakfast, Eldrcss Kosetta Ctimings, read a Christmas essay, after which, six little
                                girls marc'ut around the tables singing a merry Christmas song. At ten o'clock, our
                                North family assembled with us, and we devoted an hour to singing hymns, giving
                                testimonials of faith, and the rendering of two pieces written for the occasion, by
                                Sisters, Abbie Appleton and Agnes Parker. In the evening, the Sisters prepared a
                                surprise oyster and cake supper, after which, we spent an hour in social communion,
                                followed by an entertainment, given by our youngest people, and the unlading of a
                                heavily laded Christmas tree, in whose gifts all shared. With us, the old bell of
                                tradition, tolling out refrains of fear, bigotry and superstition, notes of "sounding
                                brass" denoting ways unprogressive and inconsistent with right living, has been
                                substituted by the one of sweeter cadence, of kindness and deeds that spiritualize and
                                make gladsome home life. Its new strokes, <pb n="30" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 30 THE MANIFESTO. sound
                                the alarm of danger in remaining in the maze of regarding all things as they are, as
                                well, and not passing into clearer and newer conceptions of duty, that "build as the
                                wise build," a character of stronger virtue and larger usefulness, thus bettering
                                society. We wish every reader of The Manifesto a happy new year, and long life to our
                                organ of faith. George II. Baxter.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>OUR EXCHANGES.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religious telescope" TEIform="index"/>The Religious Telescope
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Keligiotjs Telescope of Dayton, Ohio, is an able advocate of the "United Brethren in
                                Christ." Its editorial care is under the management of I. L. Kephart, D. D. A close
                                application to the teachings found in the Telescope would establish a beautiful church
                                of united Christian Brethren and Sisters. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nashua weekly telegraph" TEIform="index"/>The Nashua Weekly Telegraph
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Nashua Weekly Telegraph is publisht in
                                Nashua, N. H. under the direction of the Telegraph Pub. Co. It informs us that it is "A
                                political, Literary and Home Journal." </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sent of god" TEIform="index"/>Sent of God
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Sent of God is publisht in Tabor, Iowa, by the
                                "Hepzibah Faith Home Association." All workers connected with it work free, and trust
                                God for their support. It is indeed, a great mission to be sent of God. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Diocese of Albany" TEIform="index"/>The Diocese of
                                Albany
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Diocese of
                                Albany is a Magazine of Church Literature and publisht in the interest of the churches
                                of the Albany Diocese. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good way" TEIform="index"/>The Good Way
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Good Way is publisht by the "Good Way Association" at College
                                Mound, Mo. This paper is "The Advocate of Holiness, Unity and New Testament Church
                                Order. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Church advocate and holiness banner" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Church Advocate and Holiness Banner
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Church Advocate and Holiness Banner, is publisht by the "Board of Publication
                                of the Church of God," at Fort Scott, Kansas. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Portsmouth journal" TEIform="index"/>The Portsmouth Journal 
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Portsmouth Journal publisht by L. W.
                                Brewster and Son at Portsmouth, N. H. It is a paper of Literature and Politics and for
                                more than one hundred years has been the weekly visitor to a large class of readers. Vte
                                are informed that since the publication of the "Standard Dictionary" by Funk and
                                Wagnalls, that not less than three hundred, including Editors, Publishers, Writers and
                                Speakers, have agreed to adopt Rule 1st in "Simplified Spelling." The change is very
                                slight, and yet a step in advance. J^j^One account says there was in the Ark, 1794
                                snakes and 26G0 crows. jJlJP^Thomas Paine was the friend of Washington, Jefferson and
                                Monroe.//. J. Manyerum. JJ^^Spiders are raised in Philadelphia and sold at $10.00 per
                                hundred. They are used for stocking wine cellars. 5^="A Maltese cat in New York has six
                                toes and from time immemorial these have been regarded as mascots. 2^=St. Peters in Eome
                                is the largest and handsomest church in the'world.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What the hindoos think" TEIform="index"/> WHAT THE HINDOOS THINK.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> That able and learned Hindoo, Mr. Dharmapala, who represented one portion of
                                        India in the World's Congress of Eeligions at Chicago, writing to a friend in
                                        Chicago after his return to Calcutta, said: "It is a sign of the times that from
                                        the reeking shambles of the most inhuman city on the globe there should come a
                                        voice appealing to the tender instincts of man to refrain from destruction of
                                        animal life. If I had the means, I would distribute a hundred thousand copies of
                                        your brochure in that Butcher City of the West Chicago. You have a great
                                        causevegetarianism; and if you could only convert Armour to put a stop to his
                                        unparalleled slaughtering of the dumb beasts, you <pb n="31" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                        MANIFESTO. 31 would go to immortality. It is a shame that the enlightened
                                        portion of the world continues to kill and eat innocent birds and animals "and
                                        it is more shameful still that Christians continue to fatten, kill and eat hogs,
                                        the very hogs that their Bible commands them not to eat. What vices, what
                                        crimes, what sins are Christian nations not guilty of?</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Acrostic" TEIform="index"/>AN ACROSTIC.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Carr, James" TEIform="persName"/>By James Carr.</byline><p TEIform="p">The man who does little things for God with fidelity will be given tlie power to do great
                            things. Happy is he that can look up but to be useful we must look down. Every guide-board
                            pointing toward heaven says, "Start now." Man is not right in his religion when he makes a
                            wrong use of his money. All admire pluck but more like to be pluckt. N"o man can ask God for
                            much who is not willing to do much. It is not what we give to God but what we keep from Him
                            that makes us poor. Faith in God will move mountains, money can only make a tunnel through
                            some of them. Everybody who tries to make others happy gets paid for it in heaven's coins.
                            Some people can trust God as long as they have plenty of money, but when the bank breaks
                            their religion goes with it. Take from love the power to suffer and it could never speak.
                            One of the most terrible things about sin, is that it makes us dissatisfied with God. South
                            Union, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True to life" TEIform="index"/>TRUE TO LIFE</head><p TEIform="p">The editor of the Murfreesborough (Tenn.) News thus accounts for hard times: "We let our
                            timber rot and buy fencing. We throw away our ashes and grease and buy soap; we raise dogs
                            and buy hogs; we raise weeds and buy vegetables ; we catch five- cent fish with $4 rods; we
                            build school-houses and send our children off to be educated, and, lastly, we send our boys
                            out with a $40 gun and a $10 dog to hunt ten-cent birds.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hope" TEIform="index"/> HOPE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="V., J." TEIform="persName"/>By J. V.</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">[Contributed by Eldress Harriet Goodwin.]
                                    Oh! do not trail your banners, But raise them up on high; Shout! shout the glad
                                    hosannas, Immortals never die. With God above, who loves you, Almighty to defend,
                                    Mind not the storms which prove you, He is your faithful friend. Tho on life's
                                    stream your voyage May be fierce and wild and long, Or gentle as a Summer's day With
                                    little seeming wrong; Still, let us take it as it comes, Shun lethargy and hate For
                                    "many mansions," many homes, For those who trust, await. Seek good and true
                                    companions, Be pure in thought and speech, And let the light of reason E'er guide on
                                    sea and beach. This world is but a training school, We can but go through college;
                                    Up yonder's our post-graduate, To seek eternal knowledge.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pilkington, Indiana" TEIform="index"/>Indiana Pilkington
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Indiana Pilkington, at Pleasant Hill, Ky. Dec. 25, 1897. Age 91 years and 7 months.
                                Sister Indiana has been a member of this Society for twenty-nine years. She was a woman
                                of sterling character and of intelligence. All who knew her, loved her and she was,
                                indeed, a Mother in Israel. Death had no terror, and she gladly obeyed the summons,
                                "Come up higher." J. W. S.</p></div3></div2><pb n="32" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Popular monthly" TEIform="index"/>Popular Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">An important and interesting article on Mexico occupies the lending place in Frank
                                Leslie's Popular Monthly for -January. It is written by Frederick Stone Daniel, and
                                treats in an entertaining, manner of the country's history and the character and
                                occupations of the people. There are many illustrations. The third paper of the series
                                on Andrew Jackson is given in this number, and in it Captain John M. Tobin tells about
                                The Military Heroes of Jackson's Time, the text being well sprinkled with gocd
                                portraits. Then there is an article on The Presbyterians, by Rev. D. J. McMillan, of the
                                Presbyterian Board of Home Missions. This is the second of a series of illustrated
                                papers on the Religious Denominations of America. In an article entitled Fair
                                Cincinnati, Charles Thomas Logan describes graphically the attractions of the Queen City
                                of the West. Other illustrated papers are Beet-Sugar Culture in California, by Frederick
                                M. Turner; The Lance in the German A rmy, New Year's Day Festivities, A Probable
                                Giorgione, and The San Carlos Indians. There is an interesting installment of the serial
                                The Catspaw, which appears to be drawing to a close; several short stories, contributed
                                by J. Frederic Thorne, Eleanor C. Scott and others; a number of really good poems, and
                                the always attractive young folks' department.Frank Leslie's Publishing House, New York.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>The Ladies' Home Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The wife of the President has given special permission to John Philip Sousa, The March
                                King, to dedicate to her his new composition, just finisht, and which will be called The
                                Lady of the White House. Mrs. McKinley forwarded her permission last week to the editor
                                of The Ladies' Home Journal, which will publish the Sousa composition complete in its
                                next issue. This magazine has also received for the same number a new and large portrait
                                of Mrs. McKinley, taken a few days ago in the White House conservatory. This is the
                                second photograph which the President's wife has allowed to be taken within ten years,
                                the first portrait taken of her since 1887 having also gone to The Ladies'1 Home
                                Journal, which publisht it in its last October number, causing the entire edition of
                                that issue to be exhausted. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Outlook" TEIform="index"/>The Outlook
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Several illustrated articles of more than ordinary interest
                                are to be found in the Magazine Number of The Outlook for January. Among them is the
                                first installment of Edward Everett Hale's James Russell Lowell and His Friends, which
                                has portraits of Lowell, Emerson and Longfellow, of singular beauty, and unknown to the
                                general public. This series of articles by Dr. Hale will be the most prominent feature
                                in The Outlook for 1S98, just as Mr. Justin McCarthy's Story of Gladstone's Life, now
                                exciting so much attention in its book form, was in F97. The other notable illustrated
                                features are The New York Public Library, by John S. Billings, the Director of thf
                                Library : The Picturesque in American Life and Nature, by Charles Dudley Warner, as
                                interviewed by Clifton Johnson; and Stoyd (tlie Swedish system of manual training,) by
                                W. S. Harwood. With this number begins the publication of Dr. Lyman Abbott's series on
                                The Life and Letters of Paul, ihet delivered as addresses at Plymouth Church, Brooklyn.
                                The fiction of the number is supplied by a short story called Billy-Boy, by William
                                Canlon, author of the charming stories in W. V., Her Book, and The Invisible Playmate;
                                while a most amusing sketch called Little Students in Giiggsville, by the Rev. Uriah X.
                                Buttles, adds to the entertaining element. ($3 a year. The Outlook Company, 13 Astor
                                Place, New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to grow flowers" TEIform="index"/>How
                                To Grow Flowers
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Everyone loves flowers, natuie's sweetest gift to man, but not every
                                one can grow plants that will thrive and bloom. It is the mission of the magazine, How
                                To Grow Flowers to publish, in practical form, such information as will enable even
                                amateurs to have success with flowers. The January number of this publication is an
                                unusually valuable one. Eben E. Rexford, perhaps the highest floral authority in the
                                country, writes clearly and interestingly on "The A. B.C. of Successful Floriculture."
                                Article Mr. Rexford discuss es the first principles of flower growing. Other articles
                                and departments are of timely value. Sweet Peas, Carnations, Roses, Spider Lilies and
                                Flowers at the Nashville Exposition are some of the leading subjects. Five cents a copy
                                at newsdealers or fifty cents a year, with elegant plant premium, of the publisher
                                Springfield, Ohio. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reminiscences of an octogenarian in the field of industrial and social reform" TEIform="index"/>
                                Reminiscences of an Octogenarian in the Field of Industrial and Social Reform
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Reminiscences of an Octogenarian in the Field of Industrial and
                                Social Reform by Joshua K. Ingalls. As the first item of interest was an experience
                                sometime in the year 1821 when the author was an infant of only five years, there has
                                been a long series of years through which to study "The Ways of Man." The closing of
                                this wonderfully interesting story takes place in July 1897. In the experience of more
                                than seventy years the author has walkt and talkt, most familiarly, with many of the
                                leading men of the country, and also become interested in many of the reformatory
                                movements that were agitating Society, so that his book of Reminiscences or the story of
                                his life becomes intensely interesting, especially to those who can bear in memory many
                                of the pleasing incidents which he so graphically narrates. Publisht by the Gazette Co,
                                of Elmira, N. Y. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological Journal and Science of Health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">
                               The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health for January 1898, has
                                for the first article, A Personal Interview with Hon. Russell Sage, by Jessie A. Fowler.
                                This article is illustrated with two portraits. Imitation by J. H. Shubert;
                                PhrenotypesMo.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
19  by H. S. Drayton M. D. with an illustration |
of Henry Gi-orge.
What is (Quality by Jules Buchel;   1'hysiognomicHl Studies of tlie Kar
Herinai) Vezin with illustrations, by D. T.
Elliott.   The Amateur l'hi enologieal Club  by
Elsie <J. Smith.    So it nee of Health which are
truths founded on Fact.   Child Culture by Uncle Joseph, and, indeed, Uncle Joseph has his
article finely illustrated.
Geographical Studies referring" to Calcutta,
etc., etc.
Fowler & Wells Co. 27 East 2lst St. New York
"Home, Mauuiagk, and Family Relations"
by Jatnes Inglis, ami publisnt by H. L. Hastings of Boston, Mass, deals as one sees by the
title page with subjects of vital importance
in the social life of the world to-day.   The
book shows the need there is for a moral revival, the necessity for quickening the ethical
sense of man, and shows parents that the
home furnishes better opportunities for instructions in righteousness than either the
church or school.   This is no new truth but
one that can not be too often repeated.   The
book deserves the attention and patronage of
all who are desirous to know the best way to
give society not only cultured men and women but men and women (if such sterling
moral chaiacter that they will be able to assume the responsibilities of "IIomk, Mauuiaijk
and Family Relations" by lighting baseness
and dishonor.
Newspaper Advertising in the United
States.   A book of two hundred pages, containing a catalogue of about six thousand
newspapers, being all that are credited by the
American Newspaper Directory (December
edition for 18(.)7.) with having regular issues of
maps of each and every State of the American
Union, naming those towns only in which
there are issued newspapers having more than
1,000 circulation.   This book (issued December
15, 1867) will be sent, postage paid, to any
address, on receipt of one dollar.   Address
The Geo. P. Itowell Advertising Co., 10 Spruce
St. New York.
"INTERPKETM PROPHECY"
AND  THE
"Appearing of' Christ,"
is the title of a neat little pamphlet ol
some forty pages, just sent out by A. G.
Hollisteb of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
The many at the present time who are
interested in the fulfillment of prophecy,
and in its mathematical calculation, will
find themselves by the side of the good
old prophet Daniel, and with him illustrating the Coming of Christ so clearly
that no occasion can arise for the least
doubt.                             Price, 10 ots.
WITHOUT   DOUBT
THE BEST FAMILY  PAPE    PUBLISHED
IS   THE
NEW   YORK   WEEKLY   WITNESS.
16 Pages.   Only   t, 1 a year.
The
Has a. very wide scope, comprising as it
does the following departments:
Editorials,
Spirit of the Press,
Scientific and Instructive,
The Odd and Uncommon,
Our Country's Hope,
A. Talk With the Doctor,
Around the Hearth
Little Men and Women,
Weekly Articles by George R. Scott
Talmage's Sermon,
Money and Business,
World-Wide Field,
Our Family Story.
Farm and Garden.
SABBATH READING-.
16 Pages.   Only 50 cants a Year.
An Inter-denominational Weekly Paper.
Sabbath Reading is solely religious.
Nil news; n> p ;itics. A gi'.m I pip^r
for the truth-seeker.    It contains:
C'3ti'iliaii Endeavor Topic,
EjW>rti.l A,'ili;IH*   iV<|iv,
&al>lMf M-McllOOl   JLl-M!>ll,
CJiic   M'ovtry,
Kei>orts of ]VIissions,
 til*;   Jileir'ii.
And a mass of matter  carefully  selected.
Send for free samplo copies of Witnp:ss
and Sabbath Reading. And send for
free sample pages of our Bagster's Bible.
Addi'ess
JOHN DOUGALL It 00., 150 Nassaa SiDOt, Hew York.
HOW TO MAKE MONEY!
If you are out of employment and want
a position paying you 'from $50 to .$100
monthly clear above expenses by working
regularly, or, if you want to increase your
present income from $200 to $500 yearly,
by working at odd times write the GLOBE
CO. 723 Chestnut St. Phila., Pa. stating
age, whether married or single, last or
present employment, and you can learn
how to make more money easier and
faster than you ever made before in your
life.
Editorial.
JWLotSters'  Sl3itU   Aftoi-nooia
VTitil
Foreign News,
WITNESS
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
Royal makes the food pure,
wholesome and delicious.
ROYAL CAKING POWDER CO., NEW YORK.
Absolutely Pure
A  PRIVATE   SCHOOL
For Girls will be opened at
Wit. Lebanon, IS'.  Y.
Oct. 1, 1S97.
Ad.h-css        Eidi-cHx, Anna White,
Mt. Lebanon, Columbia Co., N. Y.
Instructions in English and the Industii il Branches, bo:ird, etc., two hundred
dollars a year, consisting" of two terms of
twenty weeks each.    Fifty dollars to be
]> litl at beginning and fifty dollars at close
of each term.
Competent and experienced instructors
at head of each department.
Location among the beautiful Berkshire
Hills.
Hygienic condition perfect, and all
healthful recreation encouraged.
Careful attention given to moral as we]l
as mental and physical development.
Here are taught hand and machine sewing, plain and fancy knitting.    With help
of instructors each girl will learn to keep
her wardrobe in repair.     Younger girls
will assist in dining-room, duties about
the house, and light ironing;  larger ones
in general house-work; strength and
adaptability being duly considered.
Those who remain long enough will
have unequalled opportunities to become
proficient in the management of households where order, cleanliness and the
best methods are considered of first importance.
No uniform dress required.    Simplicity '
in make and durability in material the
chief requisite.    All articles to be laundered should be particularly plain and
simple.    No jewelry allowed.
50   YEARS'
EXPERIENCE
Trade Marks
Designs
Copyrights &c.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain our opinion free whether an
invention is probably patentable. Communications strictly confidential. Handbook on Patents
sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice, without charge, in the
Scientific flmcricam
A handsomely illustrated weekly. Largest circulation of any scientific Journal. Terms, $3 a
vear: four months. $1.   Sold by all newsdealers.
MUNN&Co.361Broad^-New York
Branch Office, 625 F St., Washington, D. C.
Sketches of Shakers and Siiakerism. A synopsis of the United Society of Believers in Christ's Second
Appearing. Illustrated. B37 Giles
B. Avert.    Price 15 cts.
FREE   EDUCATION.
A n education at Harvard, Yale, or any other
college or institution of learning in the United
States, or in the New England Conservatory
of Music, can be secured by any young man
or woman who is in earnest. Write for, particulars quickly.             JAMES D. BALL,
36 Brornfield Street, Boston, Mass.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>