<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2608" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">26</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><date value="18960801" TEIform="date">August 1896</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">121-136</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="26" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1">
                    <!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
1896.
A. Visit to the
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
Just, Published.     The book is printed                         SHAKERS
with large type  and  on excellent paper,  of EAST CANTERBURY,   N.  H.
It contains  130 pages and has
ILLUSTRATIONS
of the Shakers and their
LLOYD H. CHANDL.ER. U. S. N
The work gives quite an extended account of the Several SOCIETIES, their
organization and general management.
Price,  50 cts.
Address   H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
A SUMMARY VIEW
Liberally Illustrated with half tone
pictures of persons and places.
The Tillage of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the lovliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price,  15 cts.
AUTHORIZED RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   0OMMUNITY.
The religious basis of the Order must
CHURCH,        be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individ
ual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts,
AUGUST,
OF  THE
MILLENNIAL
Or
"United   Society    of   Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price 50 cts.
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
The Pulpit for June begins with a sermon
by Rev. J. B. Whitford,Methodist"The
Conqueror from Edom." A sermon on Contributions" by 
Rev. J. H. McNiel-of the Christian Church. "The Unspeakable Gift" by Rev.
Simeon J. McPherson, Presbyterian. "Wanted a Man," by Rev. F. J. Mullett, Episcopalian. 
"The Father's Honor" by Canon Wilberforce. "The Divine Child" by A. M. Fairbairn, Congregational.        
Published by G.
Holzapfel,   Fredericksburg, Pa.
The Journal of - Hygeio-Theeapy for
June has chapter fifth of the Science of Life,
by T. V. Gifford, M. D. Tonsilitis under Hy
geio-Therapeutic Treatment, by Ella Young,
M. D. The Science of Phrenology, Soul
Growth. A Gentile visits the Mormons, etc.
Dr. T. V. Gifford & Co.,   Kokomo, Ind.
Is the Bible a True Book, is a Lecture by
H. L. Hastings, that was delivered in Liverpool, Eng. The lecturer says that the subject
"is of sulBcient importance to claim our most
careful attention." After an abundance of
testimony from varied interesting sources
which covers some thirty pages, the writer
feeling assured that he has established his
claim of the inspired revelation of the Bible
says in conclusion; "Take this Book and apply
it to your lives, and among all the population
there will not be a liar, a thief, a dishonest
man or a drunkard. Virtue, purity and righteousness will prevail."
Published by H. L. Hastings. 47 Cornhill,
Boston, Mass.
The recent parade of the Street-Cleaning
Department of "New York City, under command of Colonel George E. Waring, has been
made the occasion of an illustrated article on
Cleaning the Streets of New York, in the Illustrated Monthly issue of The Outlook this
month. It is by Mr. William W. Ellsworth,
and is of great interest and significance.
That New York City consumes nine hundred
and sixty million eggs in one year; nearly
three hundred thousand pounds of butter every day ; and as many gallons of milk; it eats
three hundred and five million pounds of beef
in a year seems astounding. And yet these
figures are, in reality, very moderate calculations which Mr. John Gilmer Speed 
has reached upon exhaustive investigation, and embodied in an article on "Feeding a City Like
New York," which he has written for The
Ladies' Home Journal.
Gladiatorial game,game that could give
as well as receive death," is the phrase applied by the late Lieutenant Frederick
Sclrwatka to the whales of the sub-arctic regions. In The Sunday School Times of June
13 is a hitherto unpublished article from the
pen of this well-known deceased arctic explorer, in which he sets forth interestingly
the methods, excitement, perils and profits of
whaling as practiced by the Eskimos.
A little publication, but of value out of all
proportion to its size, is Aldes's Living Topics Magazine. For the ridiculously small
price of 25 cents a year it gives nearly 400
pages of information of interest and value to
every one, and hardly obtainable elsewhere.
The last issue gives just the facts every one
wants concerning the States of Idaho, Illinois,
Indiana, Iowa, Kansas, and Indian Territory.
The statistics are brought right down to date,
generally from one to five or more years later
than the latest cyclopedias. Thus it deals in
every issue with the States of the Union, all
the nations of the world, and other important
topics. Living Topics ought to secure an
enormous circulation. A sample copy may
be had free by applying to the publisher,
John B. Alden, 10 and 12 Vandewater Street,
New York.
Mount LebanonCedar Boughs, is the title
of a neatly bound volume of original poems
by the North family of Shakers, published by
the Peter Paul Book company, Buffalo, N. Y.
The book comprises 316 pages and embraces
315 original poems, from different authors,
both men and "women, who are members of
the home. Some of these verses reach the
higher ranges of poetic conception and expression. They are all fresh and pure as the
white blossoms of early spring. Moreover,
they are clean, freighted with conscience,
and uplifting to the spirit. They will undoubtedly attract a large class of readers
outside the Shaker communities.
In this constellation of gems we are particularly struck with the following: "Money
Changers;" "Two Wheels;" "The Cry of the
Suffering;" "The Millionaire's Daughter;"
"America's Working People;" "Physical Resurrection;" "The Months of the Year;"
"America in Shame;" and "Motherhood."
"Who is a Mother?   She who strongly holds
A little group of ties of kindred blood;
Whose dearest treasures are the hearts she
folds,
Whose one ambition is their joy, their good."
The Temple of Health.   San Diego, Cat.
Many very attractive and beautifully illustrated articles are given in Frank Leslie's
Popular Monthly for July, and also several
excellent short stories. The leading feature
is a description of General Robert E. Lee's
part in the battles of Fredericksburg and
Cliancellorsville, written by Colonel John J.
Garnett, of the Confederate States Artillery,--><pb n="121" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes referring to the early history of the shakers in the United States, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>Notes Referring to the Early History of the Shakers in the United
                            States. No. 2.</head><p TEIform="p">WE put our trust in God and gave our souls to prayer, and in the morning we found
                            the river covered with cakes of ice and seemingly iso secure as to form a bridge. At first
                            we saw great danger in crossing so deep and rapid a stream on broken ice where we could see
                            the water thrown up between them. We prayed earnestly to be protected. I ventured on the ice
                            and jumped from cake to cake and Nathan followed, leading the horse. "We reached the shore
                            in safety and then returned thanks to God for protection and care. Notes by Sarah Kendall. I
                            was with Mother Ann a great deal of the time, during the last two years of her life, and in
                            everything she was a perfect pattern of godliness, in the "manifestation of a Christ-like
                            spirit. I stand as a witness of the work of G-od and of his power through Mother Ann and the
                            Elders for the salvation of souls. To deny this power is to deny Christ, and his witnesses.
                            Mother Ann made the remark, that it would take some persons full twenty years to travel up
                            to the order of nature, after they had been called into the gospel work. It would cause them
                            great tribulation to reach the state where some were when they embraced the work of
                            generation. Reported by Abagail Cooper. At the time that Mother and the Elders visited
                            Harvard, and came to the AUGUST, <pb n="122" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 122 THE MANIFESTO.
                            Square House, they conversed with me upon religious matters and were anxious to know if my
                            religious life made me happy and saved me from the sins of the world. They said that the
                            testimony of Jesus the Christ would bring happiness to the soul. Abigail said, "I have seen
                            a great deal of false religion and do not want to see any more. If you have a new religion
                            you may as well keop it to yourself, as I do not want it, and do not care to extend our
                            acquaintance." After a short visit with the family the Elders asked me if I did not love
                            them. I said, "I do not particularly love your order of religion." Father William Lee then
                            remarked, "We will make you to love us before we leave the place." As they were leaving the
                            house Father William handed me a very nice apple. Although I did not want it, I accepted the
                            gift and placed it on the mantle-piece. Mother Ann and the Elders had been from the house
                            but a very short time before I felt a deep love springing up, and an anxious desire to see
                            them again. I began to love them intensely, and as I could not see the dt-ar friends I loved
                            the apple for their sake, and would occasionally go and see it. I knew they were a good
                            Christian people because I felt such a love for them. I began to wish they would return, and
                            so expressed to others. On their return journey Mother and the Elders again called and 1 was
                            exceedingly thankful to have them enter the house and considered it a great privilege to do
                            some little kindness for them. Sketches by Jemima Blanchard. Daniel Wood was the first
                            person of whom I obtained any knowledge respecting the Believers. He called at my father's
                            house, one evening while I was there on a visit, my home being at the house of Isaac
                            Willard. Daniel informed us that the Shakers taught the confession of sin and were blessed
                            with divine gifts. As the family were out on a visit to a neighbor, my brother Joseph and
                            myself were left to keep house. I listened to the conversation for some time, but it made
                            such an impression upon my mind that I left the house. In conversing upon the subject with
                            my brother, he said he would take me to seethe Shakers, sometime ; but I had no special wish
                            to make the visit. The testimony of these people seemed to be similar to that of Jesus and
                            his disciples, found in the New Testament. I knew they were Christians and Joseph was
                            impressed with the same thought. Daniel then remarked,"Perhaps they may call here and see
                            the family." Several months after this my brother informed me that the Shakers were coming
                            but that he was going on a voyage to sea. He went never to return. I now found work in a
                            family by the name of Cutler. The man was a <pb n="123" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 123 minister and quite wealthy. My friends were interested in my present
                            engagement, as they saw that I was becoming familiar with the Shakers. Daniel Wood also
                            called upon the minister, but I was visiting at the house of a neigh bor, and word was sent
                            to me to remain where I was till the close of another day. As I was not anxious to see
                            Daniel, I remained willingly. When I returned home I urged Br. Cutler to go and see the
                            Shakers. In this his wife joined me, and he concluded to make the visit. He received a
                            favorab le impression. Father William Lee said that God was at work with him and that if he
                            received the gift of conviction he must return and tell them about it. Soon after this while
                            on his way from Harvard to the home of Zacheus Stevens, he received a gift of deep
                            conviction and dismounting from his horse kneeled in prayer. At once the words of Father
                            William were in his mind, but he neglected his privilege and never returned to make the
                            report. I next made a visit to Zacheus Stevens, where I saw some .of the Believers. I knew
                            Father Eleazer Rand. He appeared solemn but heavenly, and I enjoyed my visit very much. We
                            took supper with the family. When they kneeled, I looked at them with wonder, at such a
                            manifestation of goodness. That night I staid at my father's house and in the morning,
                            without company, went on to the Square House. We passed the residence of Jeremiah Willard,
                            where I was well acquainted. Little Oliver was at play near the front door. He ran to me and
                            drew me toward the house. Several Believers had met there, and all spoke kindly to me, : but
                            they all seemed so solemn and strange, that I soon left and went on to the residence of
                            Isaac Willard. As they had accepted the new faith they appeared just as the others did, but
                            said they were glad I had come and asked me if I should attend the meeting. I now thought I
                            would go and see for myself what it was that made such a great change in all my
                            acquaintances. At the Square House I met two young women whom I well knew. They wTere
                            sisters,Deliverance and Beulah Cooper. They invited me into the kitchen where they were at
                            work and I enjoyed a very pleasant conversation. Mother Ann also called at the same place,
                            and her countenance was so heavenly that it absorbed my whole soul, and I scarcely heard
                            what my companions were saying. Mother soon came and taking me by the arm, said, "Wilt thou
                            be a daughter of Zion, and be searched as Jerusalem with candles?" I made no reply to the
                            question as I did not know what to say. Her word seemed like the voice of G-od. I then
                            accompanied her to the meeting, where many of the Believers were assembled. At the hour for
                            dinner the Sisters informed me that it was their custom to kneel before eating, and asked me
                            to conform. I excused myself by saying that I did not wish any dinner. My father saw the
                            point of embarrassment <pb n="124" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 124 THE MANIFESTO. and urged me to
                            attend, but I felt that I could not as quite a company of worldlings were looking on and
                            their countenances were expressive of scorn and contempt. Mother Ann took me by the hand,
                            saying,"It is becoming in all people to render thanks to God;" and as Mother kneeled I
                            kneeled with her. I did not intend to remain at the house over night but the sisters urged
                            me to do so, and at last I consented. In the morning I arranged for an early departure, and
                            had promised to take breakfast with my own parents. I hastily bid adieu to the two sisters
                            in the kitchen, and asked them to say, good bye, to Mother Ann for me. (To be
                        continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ ideal in shakerism, no. 3" TEIform="index"/>THE CHRIST IDEAL IN
                            SHAKERISM, No. 3.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tyner, Paul" TEIform="persName"/>By Paul Tyner.</byline><p TEIform="p">IN obedience to a spiritual leading, Mother Ann came to America in 1774 with her
                            husband and seven followers. Her husband, however, shortly after their arrival in New York,
                            went away with another woman more amenable to marital authority, and Mother Ann came more
                            fully into the persona' freedom her work required. The subsequent rise of the Shaker Church
                            in this country through perils and privations, trials and persecutions; its awakening of
                            thousands of souls to the power and beauty of Truth; its establishment and maintenance, for
                            a century and more, of nearly a score of communities in which their Christ Ideal is made
                            concrete and reduced to practice in daily life and work with ever increasing light; its
                            honorable roll of spiritual-minded, earnest, enlightened and progressive leadersall these
                            make a very interesting story, but one which there is not time to tell in detail here.
                            Suffice it to say that, after ten years of unremitting work in America, Ann Lee passed out
                            of the flesh, feeling that at last her work was done ; that the banner of chastity had been
                            securely planted on the spiritual Zion, and that the work of preserving, continuing and
                            extending the principles of Shakerism would pass into the hands of worthy successors. She
                            had laid a broad and sure foundation in the inculcation by precept and example of the power
                            and happiness of pure living. On her death, the headship of the society passed from a
                            matriarchate into a duarchy, maternal and paternalJoseph Meacham and Lucy "Wright, becoming,
                            as "Father Joseph" and "Mother Lucy," joint leaders under whom the believers in Christ's
                            second coming through Ann Lee were organized and established on a communal basis. In these
                            communities, all things were held in common and each labored for the common interest. Here,
                            for the first time in human history, women enjoyed equal rights with <pb n="125" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 125 men, sharing the duties and privileges, responsibility
                            and government. In fact, a marked feature of the Shaker order and system is the high and
                            honorable place accorded the feminine principle. God is worshipped as Mother as well as
                            Father, and, from the central ministry at Mount Lebanon down to the smallest family, the
                            authority and leadership is equally balanced between sisters and brothers, who act together
                            with the harmonious co-operation of equals. The essence of Shakerism's object and ideal may
                            perhaps be well summed up in these words taken from a brief address made by me at the
                            funeral of my beloved and revered father in the Gospel, Elder Frederick W. Evans : He gave
                            his life unreservedly and absolutely to an idea which Shakerism embodies in its grand and
                            rugged simplicity, the divine idea of mankind's redemption through the purification of the
                            relations between men and women. Seeing the sin of the age, the root of all the evils that
                            afflict humanity in our modern social system to be unchastity, he accepted with all his
                            heart the revelation of the Spirit of Christthe Spirit of Truththrough Ann Lee, that the
                            salvation of the race must be worked out by its purification from sensualism and a return to
                            chastity; by the utter abandonment of all fleshly lusts that war against the spirit,
                            shackling it to earthly illusions and blinding it to the sublime realities of life. It
                            should be kept in mind that acceptance of Ann Lee's revelation implies belief in continuous
                            and progressive revelation, and so in perpetual advance. It would be a grave mistake to
                            suppose that the Shakers regard the measure of Truth revealed through Ann Lee or through any
                            of her successors, as final and irrevocable. On the contrary, it is recognized that the
                            Christ Spirit, lives in every one of us. It awaits only clear recognition to spring into
                            cpnscious manifestation and is exercised in some measure by every believer who preserves a
                            pure soul in a pure body, and faithfully follows Mother Ann's favorite injunction: "Give
                            your hands to work and your hearts to God." To quote from the preface to Ann Lee's
                            "Biography" signed by Elders Frederick Evans, Giles B. A very and Calvin Green"The records
                            of past dispensations are interpreted aright only by means of a present living revelation ;
                            we therefore hold ourselves untrammelled by the letter of yesterday, expressing our views
                            and living in accordance with the increasing light of to-day." And what results has
                            Shakerism to show for its hundred years of effort to reduce the Christ Ideal to actual
                            practiceto embody in every day life that measure of the Spirit of Truth which their light
                            has allowed them to receive and apply ? What is the object lesson which their present
                            condition offers to the world? Briefly, a social and religious organization in which men and
                            women live and labor in peace; to whom lust, envy, avarice, greed, strife, anger, theft,
                            murder, falsehood, cruelty, sloth, jealousy, uncleanness of mind or body, intemperance,
                            gluttony, pride, waste and want, or fear of want are all un- <pb n="126" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 126 THE MANIFESTO. known. In their seventeen communal villages, scattered
                            throughout eight different states, but all under one central governmenta veritable impereum
                            in imperioyou will find no prisoners or paupers, no prostitutes or prostitutors, no
                            millionaires or tramps, no hunger, no rags, no corrupt officials, no wage-slaves, no
                            soldiers or police, no masters or mistresses, no lawyers or parsons, no stock exchanges and
                            no gambling hells, no menials, no smoke, no grime, no dirt. To be sure, these are negative
                            advantages. But it is a striking commentary on our civilization that the abolition of only
                            two of these evils from the modern life of the world in city and country, is just now
                            engaging the attention of the world's greatest reformers and is the object of national and
                            international movements, in which thousands of earnest and enlightened women and men are
                            enlisted. But it would not be fair to consider Shakerism as simply negative in its results.
                            The very negations noted imply conquests of vital importance only possible through the
                            exercise of qualities of a decidedly positive character: absolute and unvarying
                            truthfulness, sterling and incorruptible honesty, industry, thrift, frugality, temperance,
                            brotherly love, justice, self-control, kindliness, forbearance, sympathy, most of the
                            qualities that go to make up true manliness and true womanliness. In my nine months in
                            Shakerdom, I learned to know and to love more men and women of noble and beautiful character
                            than one often meets in a whole life-time in the average town. There are some things lacking
                            in Shakerism which are highly valued by the world and considered essential to the higher
                            life by those men and women in the world whose pure hearts, high thought, deep and wide
                            sympathies, retined tastes, delicate sensibilities, noble achievements, and lofty
                            aspirations make them the fine flower of humanity, the hope of the race. Shakerism is devoid
                            of Art in any form, of architecture, music, painting or sculpture; it is without Literature
                            in any real sense, without the Drama, without Science, and without Learning, and it is
                            without these things because it is without that which has given all these to the world, that
                            which, mocked and blasphemed, as it has been so long, is counted by the deepest thinkers as
                            the source from which all higher human development and human conquests have sprung, the
                            force that enwraps and directs evolution, the force which gave us all of Truth, and Beauty,
                            and Sweetness, and Light, all of Life itself. I refer, of course, to the force of sexual
                            attraction in its highest and purest development in the love and union of man and woman. The
                            Shakers have heldstill hold in large degreethat the peace, plenty and purity of their common
                            life would be impossible at any less cost than the absolute cutting off of all these things
                            which in any way pertain to what they call "the carnal, generative life." So far, I am
                            afraid, it must be admitted that no other community in Christendom has proved them to be
                            wrong by successfully combining purity of social life and sexual love. <pb n="127" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 127 And yet the fuller solution of our social problems
                            which the future holds, mast assuredly rest in such a combination as the Shakers say is
                            impossible, and of which non-Shakers have yet to furnish a successful instance, in a society
                            exhibiting all the strength and beauty and truth flowing from love in its purest expression,
                            and none of the evils flowing from love that is defiled and impure. He would be a pessimist
                            indeed who insisted on a continuation of present evils as a necessary condition of present
                            and future good. We have learned that there may be a State without a despot, a City without
                            a Tammany, Courts without bribery, a Church without a priestcraft. So, in the coming time,
                            we shall have a Society builrled on Love without Lust. Let me quote a hopeful verse from the
                            poems of Charlotte Perkins Stetson, a singer of the new day: "Why not look forward far as
                            Plato looked, And see the beauty of our coming life As he saw that which might be our's
                            to-day? If his soul, then, could rise so far beyond The brutal average of that old time,
                            When icy peaks of art stood sheer and high In fat black valleys where the helot toiled If
                            hefrom thatcould see so far ahead, Could forecast days when Love and Justice both Should
                            watch the cradle of a healthy child And Wisdom walk with Beauty and Pure Joy In all the
                            common ways of daily life Then may not we from great heights hardly won, Bright hills of
                            Liberty, broad plains of Peace, And flower-sweet valleys of warm human love Still broken by
                            the chasms of despair, Where Poverty and Ignorance and Sin Pollute the air of allwhy not
                            from this, Look on, as Plato looked, and see the day When his Kepublic and our Heaven,
                            joined, Shall make life what God meant it? Aye, we do!" Shakerism, as has already been said,
                            being based on continuous revelation is in its very nature progressive. [Note.A few lines
                            near the close of this article have been omitted as they were peculiarly local and had
                            reference only to the domestic relations of one family. We appreciate the kindly and
                            considerate spirit in which the article has been written, and republish it for a more
                            extended circulation among those who are interested to be properly informed. H. C.
                        Blinn.]</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pardon is the most glorious..." TEIform="index"/>Pardon is the most
                            glorious... </head><p TEIform="p">Paedon is the most glorious kind of revenge. Pardon others often, and thyself
                            seldom.</p></div2><pb n="128" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Church of christ" TEIform="index"/>THE CHURCH OF CHRIST.</head><p TEIform="p">IN speaking of the Church of Christ we may not have much to do with the old
                            Testament, as the system of religious life, at that date, had but little in common with the
                            teachings of Jesus. Paul, while referring to the Mosaic Law, says, "The law was our
                            school-master to bring us to Christ." It was the discipline of the law, that brought men to
                            a moral standard, and prepared them to accept a more advanced order of religious
                            obligations. On the journey of this life, every person should have a standard by which to
                            prove the course he is taking, in order to determine whether he is right or wrong. Men do as
                            much as this in buying and selling. They have a standard of weights and measures that the
                            buyer and seller may deal justly with each other. Following this comes the standard of
                            righteousness for the church of Christ. Paul in speaking of this anticipated new order,
                            says, Christ would have it a glorious church, not having spot or wrinkle, holy and without
                            blemish. After studying this definition we well may begin another pilgrimage and make
                            diligent search for the wonderful treasure. Jesus, during his ministry published the word of
                            God as it was delivered to him and in this evangelizing work appointed a class of men to
                            assist him. Three years only were allowed the Teacher in which to establish a system of
                            righteousness that would ultimately revolutionize the whole world. His life was a heavenly,
                            new light that could never be hid. We also have the history of the Pentecostal service and
                            the more permanent establishing of an unselfish Christian church. It was the outgrowth of a
                            life under the ministration of Jesus. The mission of peace on earth and good-will to men. It
                            gave to man a more exalted thought in reference to the fatherhood of God, and of a religion
                            that introduced a* universal brotherhood. Its influence was a light from God that could
                            never be wholly lost. We have also the account of Peter's visit to Cornelius, which
                            establishes the origin of a Gentile Christian church which is partially at variance with the
                            order of the church that Jesus had so clearly established. From this date there were two
                            classes of Christians. One taught the virgin life of Jesus, and a separation from the
                            generative order of the world. Deny thyself, said the Apostle, of all ungodliness and every
                            worldly lust. Through Peter and Paul a sad and serious change took place in the <pb n="129" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 129 order of the church. Of course they were
                            Christians, but in becoming all things to all men they presented a form of saving grace that
                            was not known in the first Christian church. Jesus had said,"Go and sell that thou hast, and
                            give to the poor, and thou shalt have treasure in heaven, and come follow me." Matt, xix.,
                            21. Paul said, "But if any man provide not for his own, and especially for those of his own
                            house, he hath denied the faith." 1 Tim. v., 8. This was in direct opposition to what Jesus
                            had taught, and was the careful fostering of a selfish relation. Jesus said,"Ye who have
                            followed me in the regeneration and have forsaken houses or brethren or sisters, or father,
                            or mother, for my name's sake, shall receive an hundred fold, and shall inherit everlasting
                            life." Matt, xix., 29. Paul permitted the generative life of the world and the selfish
                            relations connected with it, and promised his church a salvation in their selfishness. 1
                            Tim. ii., 15,iii., 2. Paul was a fearless and indomitable worker for what he thought was
                            right, but his Christianity was about as near to that of Jeus as a moderate drinker would be
                            to a strict temperance man. Years past on and the influence of Paul and Peter became the
                            leading feature of the Christian church and Pagan Rome was fast becoming Christian Rome. The
                            testimony of Jesus had become silenced, and the amalgamation of Christianity and Paganism
                            had become perfect. A happy thought now touched the mind of an ambitious general. He said he
                            had seen a vision and heard Jesus say, "Conquer by the cross." This cross was displayed on a
                            banner in the heavens and had the desired effect, and from this date the Christians and
                            pseudo Christians were enlisted in the army of the Roman emperor. This trap to catch the
                            Christians was a sharp practice of the emperor, as he believed they would make the best
                            soldiers, and in this he was not mistaken. Constantine now became a Christian. History
                            enumerates his deeds of cruelty, too vile to be repeated in this place, and yet he was
                            crowned the first Christian emperor. What a change had been wrought in the church of Christ,
                            since that time when Jesus preached the sermon on the mount. Christian soldiers have
                            occupied a place in the army, from that day, and the savagery of war has received the
                            benediction of the ministers of the Christian church. More than this, holy wars have been
                            waged, and the church has felt it her duty to exterminate all who differed from her in
                            points of faith, as infidels and heretics. <pb n="130" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 130 THE
                            MANIFESTO. These Christian fighters, Christian Inquisitors and Christian amalgamators of
                            flesh and spirit were forcing their faith to be accepted as the saving word of God. The
                            church now walked by the side of the world and they have had a most wonderful career. It has
                            been the dividing of houses against themselves. In our modern history we have Calvin and
                            Luther as muscular Christians : who were the representative men of their times, and without
                            doubt did a great deal of good among men as did the English among the Zulus. Calvin dreaded
                            the inquisition of the Catholic church but so soon as he found the opportunity he set up an
                            inquisit 3rial office of his own, and his name has come down to us as a hard-hearted
                            persecutor. Luther has the same name. He may have been a better man than Calvin, but he was
                            a savage disciple of the cross of Christ. Persecuted himself on account of his religious
                            opinions, he in turn persecuted others because they chose to differ from him. This would
                            lead us to ask if the Christian church and the Church of Christ a^e one and the same thing.
                            What of the defender of the faith ? The most high and mighty King, Henry the eighth. We need
                            look back only a few years and find that the Christian church was guarded by a class of
                            characters who might be called savages of the first order, if placed by the side of our
                            North American Indians. One of our own writers, while speaking of the blessings of peace,
                            says, "What millions from sequestered valleys and desolate mountains, from lonely cottages
                            and silent groves, from torture rooms and racks and devouring flames have looked and wept
                            and prayed toward this day of liberty and peace." Paul who was not a stranger to religious
                            persecutions, enumerates his own sufferings at the hands of bigoted religionists, and then
                            states the sufferings of those who would do good. They were stoned; they were sawn asunder :
                            they wandered about destitute, afflicted and tormented. Heb. xi. Less than three hundred
                            years ago, a class of people landed on Plymouth rock. They were a God-fearing, praying
                            people, filled with church ceremonies and psalm singing, and ready to defend their faith,
                            even to the sacrifice of life. Persecuted in England, they fled to America. How we might
                            have anticipated a softened, chastened spirit filled with love and meekness. Great hearts
                            filled with charity for others who were equally as well as themselves serving God. Not so !
                            These sons of the church so soon as they recovered themselves, began to afflict others, and
                            these persecuting Christians could im- <pb n="131" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                            131 prison and brutally scourge a man for not saying his prayers as they directed him. We
                            wonder how such things could take place among a civilized people. Will this harmonize with
                            the standard in Eph. v. "without blemish, without spot or wrinkle." Jesus has said, by this
                            shall all men know that ye are my disciples, if ye have love one for another. It is not the
                            mountain in Samaria nor the one in Jerusalem that will afford any special advantage to those
                            who wish to be pure in heart. Jesus silenced all the disputers of names and places, and
                            those who demanded a recognition of outward forms and ceremonies, when he said to them, "God
                            is spirit, and they that worship Him must worship in spirit and in truth."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Blinn.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Idealize the real" TEIform="index"/>IDEALIZE THE REAL.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/>By Lucy S. Bowers.</byline><p TEIform="p">'Tis earnest strife that wins the shining goal; 'Tis glowing hope that lights the
                            clouded way, And life divine turns darkest night to day. 'Tis patience that brings comfort
                            to the soul, And holy thought holds passion in control. Sweet mercy cometh when we love and
                            pray, And wisdom, when God's law our hearts obey, By these is life made beautiful and whole.
                            Although thy duties lead in lowly lines These heavenly states thou mayst realize, E'en if
                            some obstacle thy power confines Within thy limits thou mayst upward rise, But if thou
                            can'st not reach thy high ideal With love and care, idealize the real. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He that lives up to the measure of Truth..." TEIform="index"/>He that lives up to the measure of Truth...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">He that lives up to that measure of Truth that he has, will be rewarded with
                            further and higher revelations. The highest form of Christian experience, is always in
                            harmony with present duty; It does all things right and well, first, by estimating all
                            things in themselves and their relations just as they ought to be estimated, and then by
                            corresponding to the just estimate, by an equally just conduct. By the repetition of
                            virtuous actions, we gain moral power, and produce a tendency to continue in those acts. By
                            the repetition of vice, we induce a disposition to continue the practice of vice.</p></div2><pb n="132" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. AUGUST, 1896. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by
                            the "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Obdeb and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all
                            communications to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. One copy one year,
                            postage paid. .50</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. June. Thermometer. Bain. 1895. 70.53 5.5
                                in. 1896. 63.93 4 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 84 above 0 Lowest " " " " 42 " "
                                Number of rainy days " " 7 " clear " " " 9 " cloudy" " " 14 C. G. Reed. Nortii Family.
                                July, 1896. In reviewing the past month we recall much of interest, and of pleasure. An
                                eminent Russian writer, Nicholas Maxinoff, who has been in this country three years, and
                                given much thought to communism" is greatly interested in the Shaker Church. He has been
                                with us a week, investigating and writing up Shakerism for a periodical in his own
                                country. Friday evening the 26th lie gave the family a reading in his native tongue
                                interpreting as he read. He is much interested in the great Russian reformer Tolstoi. We
                                have also had with us a niece of Sister Ada Brown, Nellie A. Brown, who is a musical
                                composer and fine pianist. One evening was given to a musical entertainment from her
                                with recitations by members of the family. Spiritual pleasure and enjoyment was found
                                with dear Sisters from Enfield, N. H., not only did we have the satisfaction of a social
                                visit, but added to our treasure of good and our souls were lifted through trusting hope
                                and prayer to realms of eternal riches. May such opportunities be many that we may feel
                                the strength that comes through gospel love. "What a grand thing it is to be loved! What
                                a grander thing still to love." Sarah J. Burner.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North. Family. June, 1896. We write the day after the Fourth. While
                                contemplating what the true intent and purpose of the day should be which is so
                                universally observed; and realizing how little its true spirit is understood; while not
                                wanting to drop into the habit of a chronic fault finder, yet the lines of class
                                distinction based upon wealth which are being more rigidly drawn, causes us to ask why
                                do we celebrate this day? Where are the benefits that we derive from being free from the
                                rule of an hereditary monarch and placed under bondage to political influences that are
                                antagonistic to the principles that the founders of our Republic strove to incorporate
                                in the social and political life of the country? While we love our country and rejoice
                                to see her lead the world in all that tends to advance the race, yet we can not endorse
                                the sentiment expressed by a certain political paper that, "whether right or wrong, our
                                country." June gave us several refreshing show132 TERMS. <pb n="133" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 133 ers which greatly improved vegetation, especially
                                the meadows; at best the crop of hay will be light in this section. We enjoyed a social
                                call from Sisters of Enfield N. H., also a company of visitors from Canaan, N. Y., who
                                spent the Sabbath with us. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1896. The prophetic tone of Sister Aurelia's essay in the July No. is
                                quite encouraging. We long for the strong spiritual battery that will compel us to use
                                the mowing machine "of consistency in all things" to cut away the dead growth of
                                virtueless life which chokes the yield of promising virtue. We hail with gladness the
                                good news from Florida, as given by Elder Louis Basting and hope another year's
                                experience may give even greater prosperity in temporal affairs, and a blessed
                                harvesting of souls who regard life acts of consecration to the principles of Shakerism
                                of more importance than mere talking of faith's ideals. On the evening before the
                                "glorious fourth," the younger members of our home gave an excellent entertainment
                                commemorative of our Nation's freedom from English rule. The chapel was profusely
                                decorated with the national colors, and all things combined to make the occasion perfect
                                in every detail. Especially pleasant was the display of musical talent. The season thus
                                far has been unusually dry, the result of which is a very light hay crop. Early berries
                                quite abundant, but apples and pears will be very scarce with us this season. On July
                                sixth, sowed a second crop of peas. Gospel kindred, it is a very good time to visit
                                Enfield. Why not come? George H. Baxter.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Anger is the fire..." TEIform="index"/>Anger is the fire...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Anger is the fire that consumes the heart of love.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Extracts from letters written to outside friends from a young believer sister" TEIform="index"/>[Extracts from letters written to outside friends from a young Believer
                            sister.]</head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mt. Lebanon, April 1896" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. April,
                            1896.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Friend;I have been in Mount Lebanon now nearly eight months, a sufficient
                            length of time to have learned something of the place and people. Being a lawyer you will
                            like to know my verdict. To me, and to all who know the Shakers, they are living lives
                            actuated by the highest motives and the broadest principles of righteousness and truth.
                            Narrow? bigoted? of this I have seen nothing. Hateful in all its forms is evil to them, but
                            never more so than when manifested in any way that savors of impurity in thought, in word,
                            or in deed. Cleanliness in body and mind is their creed, still tltey are not ascetics,
                            wrapping themselves in uncomfortable sackcloth and living in gloomy sunless cells, looking
                            upon a jest as the rankest profanity, and hugging to their dreary hearts the thorns of life
                            so closely as to crush out forever all the beauty, color and fragrance of the roses. They
                            believe in comfort as well as in kindliness, and to this their well warmed and well kept
                            homes testify, not luxurious exactly, but aglow with the splendor of cleanliness, are these
                            Shaker homes. Do not imagine the Brethren and Sisters to be lacking in knowledge of human
                            nature. I know of few better schools for becoming proficient in just this knowledge. As for
                            liberality of thinking and of allowance for the thinking of others, no church in the land
                            approaches them. But I hope to see you the coming summer and then I will finish this letter
                            and answer the many questions which I know you will ask. From a letter of later date : I am
                            quite at home here now, and think I shall feel more and not less so, as the years go by. You
                            will understand by this that I intend to stay here. Why not? Now that my sister has passed
                            from my earthly sight I shall be happier and more contented here than I can possibly be
                            else- <pb n="134" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 134 THE MA NIFES TO. where. And then I am needed
                            here, just as I need to be here. I am following my old occupation of teaching, and can see
                            stretching before me years of usefulness and beyond those years, dear friend, a home of
                            peace which my life here will help to prepare for me. Why should I have any desire to mingle
                            again in the stir and fret and rivalry of life outside? After it is over what then? At a
                            still later date: jNTo one can understand better than yourself how the days, weeks and
                            months glide away, and not the less swiftly in this quiet Community, indeed it is the calm,
                            tranquil, uneventful days that are the most rapid in flight, as we all know. Mount Lebanon
                            seems to me now like a dear home, so much so that though I expect to visit my old friends of
                            Long Island and vicinity in a few weeks, it is but to settle affairs acd make explanations
                            preparatory to a final return. I must give you a little information concerning this
                            Community, for I can not see you face to face as I soon shall many of my outside friends.
                            This Society, established more than a century ago by an English woman of high aspirations,
                            and an exceptionally strong and determined willMother Ann Lee is for the purpose of
                            beginning on earth a preparatory school for the other life. The Shakers do not believe any
                            more than does yourself, that the transition from this to the other life changes one's
                            nature or one's identity, neither do they believe that any soul is destined to perish, but
                            should we go across the "Border" blinded and warped by years of wrong thinking and wrong
                            doing, the discipline must be severe and the time long and wearisome to bring us up to a
                            height we might have attained in our earth life. To reach this attainable height is the aim
                            of the people of this Community, and in order to accomplish this, purity, integrity,
                            unselfishness, and above all, love and humility that "Low sweet root From which all heavenly
                            virtues shoot," must be carefully cultivated. You ask, what are the necessary requirements
                            to become a member of the Shaker Church? An earnest desire to live the exalted life I have
                            described, first, and a faith, to live such a life, second. This is no reformatory for the
                            vicious, no prison for the criminal, and no hospital for the chronic invalid; neither is it
                            a monastery where in order to be happy hereafter, we must be as miserable as possible here.
                            This is a busy and a cheerful family with every comfort of shelter, bed and board. Those who
                            join the Community are expected naturally to give their all to the spiritual life, and share
                            in the benefits to be derived from community of goods. Of greatest value to them is
                            earnestness of purpose, a capacity of comprehension as to all such a life implies, and a
                            sense capable of appreciating its privileges. You, my dear friend, know something of my
                            independence and the entire freedom of my past life. When I say that not once since coming
                            here have I felt shackled or restrained, you will judge that there must be a decided lack of
                            the unjust tyranny which characterizes many monastic institutions which this is not. Spring
                            has burst upon us at last, and the hills, beautiful at all times, have taken on new charms.
                            The pollard willows bordering the ponds are nests of softest greenery, goldened all over
                            with the sheen of the nestling pussies. The birds are reveling in song, in spite of the
                            saucy little clien, the English Sparrow which has driven so many of his betters away, and
                            the brooks, the sweet laughter of these grave old hills, are joining their rollicking music,
                            to that of the birds, the awakening insects and the low murmurous stir of resurrected life
                            on land, in air and sea. I can imagine your keen enjoyment of this same awakened life in
                            your far away prarie home. May the storm that demolishes, the insects that devour, the
                            illness that crushes hope, all be kept far from my brave cousin. On the bureau stands a
                            glass filled with fragrant pussy willows. One of the little <pb n="135" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFE81 0. 136 boys brought them to me. There are five boys here
                            under the care of Brother Ezra, who is also their teacher. I call them the "tribe of Ezra."
                            We also have six little girls, whose caretakers are two of the young Sisters. The care and
                            love lavished upon these children! They seem very happy and they should be so. Should you
                            know of any children of good parentage, who are left, as they sometimes are, with no one
                            upon whom they can depend, or who can have any claim upon them, what a blessed home this
                            would be for them, where they would be educated in all directions, and surrounded by love
                            and tenderness, and protected from the sins of the world! Of course they do not want any
                            children inheriting evil tendencies, for this is no reformatory no more than it is a prison.
                            They tell me that my dear sister has led me to Mount Lebanon, and I sometimes think it true.
                            She has led me to a beautiful place and to a lovely self-sacrificing people. I am with them
                            in loving all that is lovely and in hating all that is hateful. On this sweet Sabbath air I
                            send you over the hills to the broad prairie^farm of "Rest a while" my love and greeting.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brown, Grace A." TEIform="persName"/>Grace A. Brown.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute" TEIform="index"/>TRIBUTE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Henry" TEIform="persName"/>By Henry Hollister.</byline><p TEIform="p">To repeat choice thoughts from the last Manifesto moved me to write. From the
                            first all impressive article, The editorial, and the subject Trust,all is included, with an
                            especial memory for the line in quotation marks in the subject Tenderness. I would be a
                            vigorous opposer of evil, and a joyful, humble receiver of every light given. From those
                            appointed to disperse light first, and from my daily companions next. This is our Ideal.
                            Sometime, sooner or later, we shall understand and be content that the Truth is unto us and
                            not of us, until nothing weak nor false remains. What though we have fallen short of the
                            great glory in store for the steadfast and innocent souls; there is yet a glory and a work
                            for us wherein our industry can wear out the memory of a wayward past. Have we been saved?
                            Yea, surely! Do we need a continuing salvation? Verily! Obedience was the beginning of
                            salvation and the willing and obedient shall eat the good of the land. Narcoosee, Fla.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Medical declaration" TEIform="index"/> MEDICAL DECLARATION.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> "In view of the widespread suffering, physical disease,
                                        deplorable hereditary results, and moral deterioration inseparable from unchaste
                                        living, we the undersigned, members of the medical profession of New York and
                                        vicinity, unite in declaring it as our opiaion that chastity a pure continent
                                        life for both sexesis consonant with the best conditions of physical, mental and
                                        moral health. The above will interest the Shaker Communities of our countrythe
                                        cleanest and purest organized body of Christian people on earth.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Temple of Health" TEIform="index"/>Temple of Health.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Water is not only the best drink..." TEIform="index"/>Water is not only the best drink...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Wateb is not only the best drink God has made, at least for this world, but
                                the only drink. Whatever mixture we may swallow, and whether the thirst is natural or
                                diseased it is the water alone that can quench thirst. And hence, as the legitimate
                                object of all drinking is to extinguish thirst, we should forever, if possible, exclude
                                all drinks from our interior but this pure native element.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Alcott" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Alcott.</byline></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Japan is a land without domestic animals..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Japan is a land without domestic animals...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Japan is a land without domestic animals. There are no cows.
                                        The Japanese neither drink milk nor eat meat. There are few horses and these are
                                        imported mainly for use of foreigners. The freight cars in the streets are
                                        pulled and pushed by coolies, and the pleasure carriages are drawn by men. There
                                        are but few dogs, <pb n="136" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 136 THE MANIFESTO. and
                                        these are neither used as watch dogs, beasts of burden, nor in hunting except by
                                        foreigners. There are no sheep in Japan, and wool is not used in clothing, silk
                                        and cotton being the staples. There are no pigs. Pork is an unknown article of
                                        diet, and lard is not used in cooking. There are no goats, or mules or donkeys.
                                        Wild anmals there are, however, and in particular bears of enormous size.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="London Tid Bits" TEIform="index"/>London Tid Bits.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth" TEIform="index"/>TRUTH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hamlin, Nellie" TEIform="persName"/>By Nellie Hamlin.</byline><p TEIform="p">Solomon counselled his son, "Let not mercy and truth forsake thee." Wise counsel
                            for the present time. It is very easy to say, and equally easy to think that we will live
                            and speak only that which is true. The teachings of our childhood have been such as tended
                            to develop faculties of honesty. But as we come to an age when we must choose the right and
                            the wrong for ourselves, we learn, and often by sad experiences, that there are many things
                            in life to tempt from the sacred path of duty and virtue. We then realize the value of our
                            early instruction, and the necessity of self-imposed rules for discipline and culture. Truth
                            should be the crown of the Christian; his defence in battle; his shield in danger; a covert
                            from the tempests of earthly strife, and a friend above all other friends. N"o natural
                            talent can take the place of a simple and truthful expression in word and deed. Blessings
                            attend thee, O spirit of Truth! Thou art a royal diadem, Be thou the guardian of my youth!
                            In every hour my steps attend. At thy pure shrine my soul shall bow As youthful days roll
                            on; To thee I pay my humble vow, Through thee tossing the conqueror's song. Harvard,
                        Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Happy is he..." TEIform="index"/>Happy is he...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Happy is he who curbs his passions, and masters his dominant impulses.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Purity" TEIform="index"/>PURITY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Williams, Ella F." TEIform="persName"/>By Ella F. Williams.</byline><p TEIform="p">"Blessed are the pure in heart for they shall see God."Matt, v., 8. Purity is the
                            entwining virtue of modesty and inspires the heart with a love for good company, pure
                            language and refinement. We often hear the passage of scripture quoted which reads, "Out of
                            the abundance of the heart the mouth speaketh." As our future life depends greatly upon the
                            habits formed in youth great care should be taken to implant within the heart, germs of
                            truth and purity, which shall bloom to be flowers of beauty and virtue, exemplifying a
                            Christian life and seeking good in those around us our language will be true and savored
                            with a spirit that is pure for "even a child is known by his doings whether his work be pure
                            and whether it be right. By obeying the voice of conscience and living a noble and virtuous
                            life we are making the kingdom of heaven upon the earth. Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Clergyman--(to a Sunday-school class)..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Clergyman--(to a Sunday-school class)...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> CUrgyman.(to a Sunday-school class:) "Now can any one of you
                                    tell me what are the sins of omission?" Scholar."Please, sir, they're sins you ought
                                    to have committed and haven't."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Sacred Heart Review" TEIform="index"/>Sacred Heart Review.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind words are the brightest flowers..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Kind words are the brightest flowers...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Kind words are the brightest flowers of earth's existence; they make a very
                            paradise of the humblest home that the world can show. Use them, and especially round the
                            fireside circle. They are jewels beyond price, and more precious, they heal the wounded
                            heart, and make the weighed-down spirit more glad than all the other things the world can
                            give.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tyson, Malinda" TEIform="index"/>Malinda Tyson
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Malinda Tyson, at Pleasant Hill, Ky. July 5, 1896. Age 86 yrs, and 6 months.
                                Sister Malinda was the oldest resident of Pleasant Hill. Her parents entered the
                                Society, while she was an infant. She has filled many offices of trust with full
                                consecration. J. W. S.</p></div3></div2>
                    <!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
and forming the sixth paper in the magazine's
great "Lee Series." The article is profusely
illustrated with portraits and battle scenes.
In "A Glimpse of Dungeness" Frederick AOber describes the burial place of "Light
Horse Harry" Lee. Another feature
of this number is an article on "Colonial
Homes of Virginia," by Virginia Cousins
Mayo, accompanied by more than a dozen
pictures. Then there is "The Fothoringay
Tragedy," in which A. Oakey Hall tells of the
last days of Mary, Queen of Scots; Prof.
Sulzbache writes of the University of Heidelberg; a paper on "Canine Warriors" shows
the service rendered by dogs on the battle
field; the Isle of Man is described in an interesting article; Mrs. A. A. Stowe chats enter,
tainly of the Lick Observatory; there is a
spendid department for young people, con'
taining short stories and poems, and the con
tinuation of a serial by Horatio Alger, Jr.;
and there are several other attractive features.
Word and Works for July has an extended
account of the fearful Tornado that passed
over the City of St. Louis on the 27th of May
1896. Another chapter on the same subject is
promised in the August Word and Works,
and the thousands will want to read this
graphic and detailed account of a most wonderful storm messenger, which brought the
death summons to no less than one hundred
and fifty persons, and destroyed property to
the value of many thousands of dollars.
Snap Shotswill be read with interest as
the saints and sinners may all find something
profitable for the mind. "The World's greatest need" is brought forward and then the
"Creamery Craze" and then some "Criticisms," and all may work for good.
"Some things that I have discovered" informs us that the Rev. Brother has been
walking around with his eyes open, and we
are interested with him in what he has discovered. "Our Editorial Passengers" are
very interesting and we shall with them enjoy a pleasant whirling or sailing voyage
around the great central light.
Word and Works has abundant treasures
for the receptive mind.
Word and Works Pub. Co. 2201 Locust St.
St. Louis, Mo.
The Phrenological Journal and Science
of Health, for July has an article on "The
Cuban Struggle" by Nelson Sizer, and it is
very interesting. It is illustrated with the
portraits of Gen. Weyler, Maximo, Gomez
and Jose Antonio Maceo and also a group of
Cuban patriots.
Phrenology and Psychology by John W.
Shu.ll.   The forehead, how to be studied.
Woman's place and Work, by Emma Walker
Herr; Mrs. Flemings Jury, Illustrated.
Gems of the Home by Nelson Sizer and
beautifully illustrated with portraits of the
little folks. Science of Health with a
Phrenograph of Dr. Selden H. Talcott etc. etc.
Fowler & Wells Co. 27 East 21st St. New
York City, N. Y.
m shaker wmn.
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS   OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION     AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
the same  time, afford instruction to all   inquiring  minds.    Price 5  cts. each,   postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
Much knowledge for a few pennies.
Sent Postage paid to any address in the
U. S. We have on hand a few copies of
"Kip Van Winkle and other Sketches."
240 pages, 4xb\                          10 cts.
"A treatise on The Horse," by Dr. B.
Kendall. 90 pages. 5x7J>2- Profusely illustrated.                                  12 cts.
Second vol. of Cassandra written originally in French by Sir, Charles Cotterell.
Published 1725.                                  .25
Sacred Roll and Book written by Inspiration in 1843.    A wonderful Book.     2.00
Hamlet, Prince of Denmark.
From Shakespeare.
.10
An old, brass eight day clock, in long
case, in excellent order.           IT5.00
An eight day brass time piece made in
1810   by Dr.   Thomas Corbett.    $20.00
Several small, old-fashion clocks at reasonable prices.
Address   H. C. Blinn, E. Canterbury, N. H.
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
For information and free Handbook write to
MUNN & CO., 361 Broadway, New York.
Oldest bureau for securing patents in America.
Every patent taken out by us is brought before
the public by a notice given free of charge in the
Largest circulation of any scientific paper in the
world. Splendidly illustrated. No intelligent
man should be without it. Weekly, jgS.OO a
year; $1.50 six months. Address, MUNN" & CO,,
Publishers, 361 Broadway, New York City.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
AND
SH AKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the United   Society   of   Believers   in   Christ's
Second Appearing.    Illustrated.
By Giles B. Avery.
Price,  15cts.
A cream of tartar  baking   powder.
Highest of all in leavening strength.
^Latest   United   States   Government
Food report.
Eoyal Baking Powder Go., New York.
WASTED
Good reliable men, to sell
our Clioice and Hardy
Nursery Stock such as Fruit
Trees, Roses Shrubs and Ornamentals. Ladies make tins business a success. 
Easy work, pleasant, light and profitable. Outfit Frke. Apply at once, with references, and secure choice of territory.
F.  N.   MAY   COMPANY,
Nurserymen  and   Seedsmen,   Rochester, N. Y.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF THE
Principles and. Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OIF1   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
"INTERPRETING PROPHECY11
AND  THE
"Appearing of Christ,"
is the title  of a neat little pamphlet of
some forty pages, just sent out by A. G-.
HOLLISTER Of Mt. LEBANON, N. Y.
The many at the present time who are
interested in the fulfillment of prophecy
and in its mathematical calculation, will
find themselves by the side of the good
old prophet Daniel, and with him illustrating the Coming of Christ so clearl
that no occasion can arise for the least
doubt.                             Price, 10 cts.
*Tea and Coffee Pots that pour by the lid without lifting or tipping.     Simple beyond belief.
Practical and artistic.   Send for pamphlet.
THE ASBURY-PAINE MFG. CO., Phila., Pa.
This is a good thingEd,
POUR
By Pressing the Lid.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>