<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2401" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">26</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">24</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18940101" TEIform="date">January 1894</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="24" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1">
                    <!--
                        <pb id="p1"/>
                                        <p>JANUARY. MANIFESTO PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. VOL. XXIV. " 
                                        Cast thy bread upon the waters
                        ; for thou shalt find it after many days." Eccl. XI: i. East Canterbury, N. H. 1894. THE <pb
                            id="p2"/> THE MANIFESTO. CONTENTS. History of South Union, No. 3. Spiritual Forces, Truth
                        Above Personality, Vanity, The Church of Christ, A Petition, Cyrus, Prepare thy Heart, - The New
                        Year, Music—Gather Home, Notes About Home, Letter—D. Orcutt, Deaths,..... Books &
                        Papers, Page. 3 6 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 1(> I7 23</p>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    <pb n="1" id="p3"/>
                    <div2 type="none"
                        <p>THE MANIFESTO PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES, VOL. XXIV. 'Seek ye first the kingdom of
                            God, and his righteousness."—Matt, vi., 33. East Canterbury, N. H. 1894.</p>
                    </div2>
                    <pb n="2" id="p4"/>
                    --><pb n="3" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="History of South Union, Kentucky, no. 3" TEIform="index"/>HISTORY OF SOUTH
                            UNION, KY. No. 3</head><p TEIform="p">TT1HE journeys made by the Shaker ministers were mostly on horseback, JL and on
                            the 22nd of Sept. 1807, one is recorded where Elder Issachar Bates, Richard M'Nemar, and
                            Matthew Houston rode one hundred miles on a journey from Union Village to South Union. On
                            the 18th of January, 1809, a journey was projected and Elder Benjamin S. Youngs, Issachar
                            Bates and Richard M'Nemar with knapsacks on their backs, and on foot, set out for Busro,
                            Ind., a distance of two hundred and thirty-five miles. "On our first day out we traveled
                            during a severe rain storm. When we reached the river we learned that it had so risen that
                            we could not cross it. After waiting two days we hired a horse and were taken across the
                            stream. We now continue our journey for some ten miles, through dense wood, without the
                            least marking of a path till we reach what has been called the wilderness road, that leads
                            to Vincennes. At night we cut down some trees and split them into boards to make us beds, as
                            we had not where to lay our heads. After building a good fire, we made our beds under the
                            branches of a large beech tree, which had fallen, seemingly for our convenience. Of course
                            we were where there was nothing to harm us nor to make us afraid, and so we passed the night
                            as comfortably as could be expected. "On the evening of the next day we waded across the
                            stream, which was about three feet deep at the place of our passage. With difficulty we
                            built a fire, by which to dry our clothes and to provide warmth during the night. This time
                            we obtained some brush wood of which to construct our beds and on these spread our blankets.
                            JANUARY <pb n="4" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 4 THE MANIFESTO. "Our rest was broken by the heavy
                            rain which fell upon our house that was made of small brush wood. Our meals were provided in
                            the most primitive manner from the scanty supply that we carried with us. "On the morning of
                            the 22nd, which would have been a day of rest, had we remained at our home in Union Village,
                            we found ourselves making preparation for a wet and muddy tramp to our next resting place,
                            wherever that may be. We passed through two settlements of Indians, but were allowed to
                            proceed peaceably on our journey. In the afternoon it began to snow, so that we concluded to
                            build a camp of poles and cover it with some poplar board, which we hurriedly made. We built
                            a fire in our house as the indiaus do, and dried our clothes, and then lay down to rest for
                            the night. "On rising in the morning we found the snow only an inch deep, but the ground was
                            frozen and the air quite sharp. We found that the back waters of the river had frozen, but
                            the ice was too thin to be of much benefit to the travelers. Issachar tied some poles to his
                            feet and took up his line of march. After breaking through several times he was glad to
                            retreat, and patiently wait. We concluded to build a fire and to wait till the ice froze
                            thick enough to bear us over in safety. As our provisions grew less from day to day, we ate
                            less, that we might not be entirely without food while on this long, wilderness journey."
                            Issachar and Richard went a distance of two miles up the river, through hope of finding a
                            better place, where we might cross to the other side. In this they failed of success, but
                            they had the good luck to find the home of a fox, and as Reynard had just stolen a wild
                            turkey, and hurriedly left him on the approach of the Brethren, they confiscated the
                            property and Benjamin dressed and cooked the turkey for breakfast. "It still continues to be
                            cold, but we conclude to start early, and find/the ice bears us safely till we reach the
                            river. We now spend about three hours in building a raft to take us across the stream, which
                            we accomplish without harm to either person or goods. This was an excursion of necessity but
                            not of pleasure. From the shore of the river we are obliged to cross a strip of low wet
                            lands, a distance of five miles. Part of the way it was over cracking ice, and in some
                            places the water was several feet deep. After patient toiling, however, we reached a land
                            that was beyond the river, and began to make preparations for the night. A good fire was
                            soon blazing, some snow melted for our drink, our suppers cooked and eaten, and then some
                            bushes thickly laid on the snow for our resting place during the night. "On the morning of
                            the 26th we found it to be quite cold. We must start early, and before noon reached the
                            knobs or more rising ground. We found to our surprise that we were clear of the waters of
                            the Muskacatuck river, and were so overjoyed that we sang and danced right merrily.
                            Continuing our journey we came to another water course which we crossed with difficulty, and
                            then found the water and ice on the other side extended to a distance <pb n="5" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. ' 5 of some three miles. We traveled over this about as we
                            did over our first water way and were exceedingly thankful when we reached the more elevated
                            land. "Our next day's travel was thirty-three miles, but without any special change. The
                            next day we walked twenty-two miles, growing more and more weary. The weather had been
                            unpleasantly cold for two days, and it was only by our exercise in walking that we were made
                            comfortable. When night came we made us a little shelter by the side of a stream, built our
                            fire, ate our frugal repast, and lay down on our blankets for a much needed rest. "This is
                            our second Sunday in the wilderness. Three wanderers, so far from home and friends, and yet
                            comforted in knowing that we were in the service of the Lori. We thought of those who were
                            in the worship of God, and we shared the spirit of their prayers, which were made in our
                            behalf. We also made our prayers and rendered our thanksgiving for the providential care
                            which was extended over us. "Although it was a day of rest for those at home, to us it must
                            be a day of anxious toil, and when the sun was rising in the eastern horizon, we had already
                            traveled several miles and reached the banks of White River. We looked out upon its waters,
                            but not with even a hope of success. Large cakes of floating ice so dangerously blocked the
                            way that we soon saw there was no possibility of crossing tli2 river. "An Indian came near
                            where we were, but as we could not understand the language of each other, no information
                            could be obtained on either side. For the first time on the journey we were inevitably
                            obliged to halt. No raft could cross the stream, and certainly there could be no other way
                            of passing it. After searching around for some time we espied a cabin much to our relief. On
                            reaching the house we heard the barking of a dog. It was a familiar sound, and in this place
                            unusually pleasant. We were now in need of human kindness, and but for this rude cabin in
                            the wilderness we might perish with cold, as we were so exhausted from our severe journey.
                            "We soon learned that a man by the name of McConn had settled here, and we were invited to
                            enter the home of himself and wife. Here we obtained a good breakfast, which consisted of
                            fresh bear's meat, corn bread and coffee. Never was a breakfast more acceptable and
                            refreshing. By the assistance of this hardy man of the woods we were enabled to cross the
                            river in safety. We paid him for his care and kindness and then returned our grateful
                            thanks. At the close of the day we found we had traveled some twenty miles and reached the
                            house of a man named Palmer, at about eight o'clock, p. m., weary and cold. ' 'Although they
                            had retired for the night we were admitted and soon found ourselves far more comfortable
                            than when lodging in the woods. This ended our eventful Sunday, on which we had heard no
                            preaching, and but little singing. It was a long, cold and wearisome term of service. <pb n="6" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 6 THE MANIFESTO. "On the morning of Monday we reached
                            Jimmerson's and breakfasted. Then we soon crossed the Wabash River in a fiat boat. Again we
                            were journeying through the water and ice for a mile and a half. Here we entered the camp of
                            some Miami Indians, who were very friendly and allowed us to dry our clothes at their fires.
                            The weather continued cold and windy, but we went on some nineteen miles farther and lodged
                            at Booth tavern. "This was the morning of the 31st. It was cold but clear. We started early
                            and walked full two miles before we had our breakfast. This we obtained at the house kept by
                            one Crosby. Traveling five miles more we come to the end of the great prairie. We continue
                            our journey seven miles more over an open prairie, and arrive at the house of Robert Gill
                            about 2 p. m., on the sixteenth day of our perilous journey. "We are now at home, and our
                            thankfulness is unbounded. Elder Issachar and Richard had their frozen feet poulticed, and
                            every provision was made for our comfort, and every kindness in their power proffered that
                            they could bestow, but our greatest pleasure was to find these dear souls steadfast in their
                            faith to the gospel work. (To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritual forces" TEIform="index"/>SPIRITUAL FORCES</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>Hamilton DeGraw</byline><p TEIform="p">"T THANK Thee, O Father, Lord of heaven and earth that Thou hast JL hid these
                            things from the wise and prudent and hast revealed them unto babes; even so Father, for so
                            it seemed good in thy sight." To the individual whose spiritual perceptions are alive it is
                            known what were those gifts that were hid from the earthly mind and revealed to those who
                            humbly come to the Father with a pure heart, earnestly desiring to possess the true riches.
                            Spiritual forces, that vitalizing power that gives life and animation to the universe of
                            mind and matter, is above the comprehension of the one that dwells in the lower elements of
                            soul life. They that bow down and worship the beast and his image never can realize nor know
                            of that spiritual ecstacy those feel who stand on Mount Zion with praise and thanksgiving on
                            their lips and manifesting in their lives the truth, "He that overcometh shall inherit all
                            things." To be able, always, to come in rapport with that power, requires a constant
                            watchfulness lest while we slumber the enemy come and sow tares. Any organization, whether
                            religious, social, political, or of individual entity that does not move with a firm and
                            steady step in perfect concord with those spiritual forces that are leading upward to a
                            higher development ; just so surely will such organizations or individuals become spir-
                            itually ossified; the rust of ages will begin to collect and the refreshing <pb n="7" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 7 showers and vivifying sunshine of angelic
                            ministrations will fall upon stony hearts tiiat are dead to those heavenly gifts. It is not
                            by chance that thp spiritual awakening of mankind has been brought about at different
                            periods of its history when the time-worn creeds and dogmas that furnished them with food
                            had been exhausted leaving only the empty formula that the soul true to its higher
                            promptings, sends out a deep and fervent prayer for something fresh from the tree of life.
                            "Give us this day our daily bread." Any soul that has once realized the divine
                            over-shadowing; or has felt the "powers of the world to come," will acknowledge the truth
                            that the happiest moments of his life were when the soul had been chastened and purified in
                            the furnace of affliction, and in humility of spirit he could cry "Father, not my will but
                            Thine be done." The complete subjection and surrender of the great / am the ego that the
                            earthly mind considers so important, to the Father's will and purpose is not a blind and
                            unintelligent submission, but a loving feeling of concord with the heavenly spirit,—"I and
                            my Father are one." The darkness of the theological night is almost past, and the light of
                            the glorious resurrection morning is about to dawn upon the race; with that increasing light
                            greater responsibilities to rightly use those gifts, and a stern accountability resting upon
                            those who violate the higher revelation that has come to their sou's. How p rfect must have
                            been the ministration that united our Savior with the heavenly hosts, when on the night of
                            his crucifixion, he said to his disciples, "Thinkest thou that I can not now pray to my
                            Father and He shall presently give me more than twelve legions of angels?" Doubtless for a
                            wise purpose he refrained. But is there an individual that has ever seen the heavens opened
                            and felt the "powers of the world to come" that could doubt the fact that the appeal would
                            have been answered if it had been made? Mother Ann told her companions that she knew it was
                            impossible for her enemies to take her life until her work was accomplished, for she
                            realized the overshadowing of the heavenly hosts and felt their protecting power ; and the
                            evidence was so strong that it left no room for doubt. But to realize in its fullness, this
                            divine spiritual baptism, there must be earnest and effective work performed in the
                            direction of spirit unfoldment. Grapes can not be gathered from thorns nor figs from
                            thistles. Neither can the soul that has given its life forces to the building of its lower
                            self-hood feel these higher ministrations. The innumerable host that the Revelator saw in
                            vision that had not bowed down nor worshiped the beast but had come up out of great
                            tribulation and were in truth overcomers; had evolved from their lives the angel, and had
                            wrought out their own salvation. <pb n="8" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 8 THE MANIFESTO. The law
                            of recompense that runs through the Divine plan in its dealings with finite existences is,
                            that whatever is sown will be reaped. No parasites in this kingdom to prey upon the soul's
                            labors and rob it of its rightly acquired power, for when growth has been found in the
                            divine life all the powers of the world can not take it away. It is the "pearl of great
                            price" to purchase which all selfish interests must be sold. The waters of the great deep
                            are being stirred by mighty spiritual forces and among the debris of thought cast upon the
                            shores of experience only to be rejected by the progressive soul, we find priceless jewels,
                            pearls of intrinsic worth that by incorporation in human lives are evolving better
                            conditions in society, working out of crude material the polished product of a higher life.
                            Here the mission of life is revealed. If we can not understand why we catch only a partial
                            glimpse of our unfolding mission, we can use it as an incentive, a propelling power for
                            higher unfoldment. Shakers, N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth above personality" TEIform="index"/>TRUTH ABOVE PERSONALITY</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Offord, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Offord</byline><p TEIform="p">MERE assertion never made truth, nor changed a principle. Man may discover a
                            principle but he never can create one. The simple fact of Jesus, or Ann Lee, or any other
                            human being asserting a truth has nothing to do with creating it. The truth existed before
                            it was proclaimed or recorded in the Bible or any other book. The laws that control
                            existence in this world and the transit to another sphere are impartial upon all. If there
                            is another law by which human beings can be translated other trian the ordinary process it
                            must be proved by actual demonstration. We can do nothing against the truth. When the truth
                            is manifested clearly to our understanding we love it so well that we readily and heartily
                            yield obedience thereto. Example teaches louder than precept, is a true saying and the
                            discipline necessary to protect young people and keep them out of the lusts of the flesh is
                            no cross or self-denial to those who have gained the victory. All such partake of the fruit
                            of self-denial and know the joy of the cross. We enjoy the surveillance of the spirit of
                            truth and purity, not because we are in the flesh but because we are crucifying the flesh,
                            with its affections and lusts. Therefore, we glory in the cross, and love the laws that are
                            as a wall of protection around all whose lives are "hid with Christ in God." Mt. Lebanon, N.
                            Y.</p></div2><pb n="9" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vanity" TEIform="index"/>VANITY</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Frederick, Henry W." TEIform="persName"/>Henry W.
                            Frederick</byline><p TEIform="p">ONE may soon see the pernicious effects of great vices, while some which are more
                            alluring in the beginning, and more gradual in their development, are none the less deadly
                            in their effect. Among the vices of a more progressive nature, we may class pride and
                            vanity. They will as certainly undermine the foundation of character and prosperity, in
                            persons, neighborhoods, states, and empires; as dissention and quarreling will produce war,
                            and war will produce desolation and ruin. Some begin quite early in life to put on airs that
                            are vain and lofty, and to cherish a desire for finery and display. Such soon form a love
                            for exhibiting personal appearance, mingling for vain parade with the multitude, squandering
                            time, poring over foolish, empty, romantic reading, and thus acquiring taste for low,
                            immoral exhibitions. Pride soon lifts them above those around them, and their minds are on
                            the stretch for new worldly notions, exciting adventures. They incline to follow every
                            passion which they imagine will yield pleasure, and vain short-lived enjoyment. Business
                            employment is to them a burden; useful study, a hated task; and the real duties of life, a
                            punishment inflicted by Providence, If such will not be reclaimed, mark their course to the
                            end. As time rolls on, you will see such, having built the foundation of their characters on
                            every thing frivolous, uncertain, empty, and vain; the superstructure is sure to be com-
                            posed of grosser vices, debasing sins and lawless indulgences; which must inevitably result
                            in degradation and misery. On the other hand, observe those who early begin, and diligently
                            pursue the opposite course. Their deportment even in childhood associates with it the
                            budding of something steady, decisive, and regular. They are easily satisfied with life's
                            most simple gifts. They soon begin to discriminate between the real and useful, and the vain
                            and useless, they are easily guided into useful studies, profitable reading, and reasonable
                            recreation. Their time is soon employed in laboring to become useful members of society.
                            They learn to esteem lightly ostentatious display, and all vain parade. Many youth, before
                            they arrive at the age of fifteen years, show great judgment in selecting substantial
                            studies, and in their early preparations for the useful pursuits of life. Whether such turn
                            their attention to worldly, moral, or spiritual matters, they commonly move ahead in useful
                            stations, in the places of trust they fill. They are honored in life, and their removal from
                            earth, often produces mourning and regret; while the passing away of a superficial class of
                            useless beings, is generally considered a blessing to the race. Union Village, O.</p></div2><pb n="10" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Church of Christ" TEIform="index"/>THE CHURCH OF CHRIST</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName"/>Watson Andrews</byline><p TEIform="p">HVTOTHING is plainer than if there is a Church of Christ on earth it is -L ^ the
                            embodiment of his Spirit, and of course under the control of that Spirit; and it is equally
                            plain that a Church or body of people organized as a religious Society, and which is
                            governed by the Spirit of Christ, will, nay must bring forth the fraits of that Spirit. For
                            "If ye have not the Spirit of Chris,t, ye are none of his." Should it be denied that this is
                            divine in- spiration, it can not be denied that it is sound logic; for the spirit of an
                            individual or institution is the life thereof. Jesus promised his disciples he would send
                            them another Comforter, that would "lead them into all truth." Observe now what this Holy
                            Ghost—Spirit—did lead them into. "And when the day of Pentecost was fully come, they were
                            all with ones accord in one place. And suddenly there came a sound from heaven as of a
                            rushing, mighty wind, and it filled all the house where they were sitting. And there
                            appeared unto them cloven tongues like as it were fire, and it abode upon each Of them. And
                            they were all filled with the Holy Spirit, and began to speak with other tongues, as the
                            Spirit gave them utterance." ' 'And all that believed were together and had all things in
                            common ; and sold their possessions and goods, and parted them to ah1, as every one had
                            need." "And they, continuing daily with one accord in the temple, and breaking bread from
                            house to house, did eat their meat with gladness and singleness of heart." • ] The result of
                            this was a number of churches, or more properly, a number of branches of the one Church of
                            Christ, and the ' 'All Truth" Jesus declared the ''Comforter"—could he come nearer
                            suggesting Mother, but his time had not come to say that, as he declared to his mother,
                            "Woman, what have I to do with thee, my hour is not come." To unite with Woman in dispensing
                            the new wine of the Kingdom, let us suppose he meant,—"would lead them into," was the four
                            cardinal features of the life of the little association of which he was the head and leader
                            while he tarried among men; viz. Virgin purity of life, community of goods, parental control
                            and filial respect. Herein is seen the Church of Christ in in-, cipiency, the "foundation,
                            other than which no man can lay," that will stand the test of time. PURITY and EQUALITY;
                            this is the grand motto which, carried out in daily life, can alone secure peace in human
                            society, and where peace is lacking, all is lacking. Upon the four cardinal principles
                            enumerated above, the Pentecostal Church was established by the direct inspiration of the
                            Holy Spirit, and all the branches of that Church, so long as they retained their integrity,
                            taught <pb n="11" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. It and practiced the same. "I came
                            to seek and to save that which was lost," said the spirit of Christ through the mediumship
                            of the wise Nazarene. "I came not to call the righteous, but sinners to repentance." "The
                            well need not a physician, but the sick." Sinners, the morally sick, then, are, those whom
                            he came to call, and of which, it is evident, he is to build his Church. But surely, you
                            will think, the Church of Christ can not be composed of sinners ; certainly not, on any
                            other principle than that sick people form the occupants of an hospital. This proves the
                            Church of Christ to be an hospital. A moral hospital for the morally infirm; and those who,
                            having been admitted as patients, and who have submitted to the treatment sufficiently long
                            to become healed, or even comfortably convalescent, are to be, we may reasonably suppose,
                            retained as assistant physicians, nurses and caretakers of those still suffering under moral
                            infirmities. Hence, wherever the Church is established, it will be known by the
                            characteristics of a well regulated hospital, viz., that of healing the sick. An asylum
                            where the seekers after moral health and spiritual development can be received and treated
                            according to their symptoms by those who have passed through similar experiences, and thus
                            know how to administer to their every need, the only requirement being cheerful submission
                            to the necessary treatment. Here, all being the patients of the Founder of the institution,
                            the "Good Physician," will be equally entitled to all the "house affords." Metaphor aside,
                            the Church of Christ can be no other than his body, animated and hence controlled by his
                            spirit. Of course any member of that body who should refuse submission to those wholesome
                            laws and regulations necessary to secure harmony, and hence peace in society, would not be
                            actuated by the spirit of Christ, and hence would be none of his. Nothing is more certain
                            than where the interests of a community are diverse, complete harmony is impossible; and
                            without complete harmony there can be no complete happiness. Union Village, O.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Petition" TEIform="index"/>A PETITION</head><p TEIform="p">THE year opens as have so many preceding ones, with its burdens for Zion's
                            interests pressing a little heavier than ever before, but though it brings a remembrance of
                            measures imperfectly filled, yet it seems to instill into our souls, new-born strength and
                            grace with which we may press forward into fuller duty, deeper consecration made outwardly
                            manifest by more effectual work. The theme of all themes interests us, our glorious,
                            glorious mission of furthering the gospel testimony which has proved as the savor of life
                            unto life, for upward of an hundred years, and is as replete to-day with <pb n="12" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 12 THE MANIFESTO. soul-saving power, as when first delivered to our
                            honored ancestors. We have no doubt that each Society in our Union, has its outposts which
                            radiate its sympathies and the spiritual solicitude of its members. In union with our people
                            elsewhere, we too are absorbed in the diffusion of gospel truth in many directions. On the
                            Pacific Coast, California, the spirit of God is at work. In the interest of this movement,
                            Brother Arthur W. Dowe, visited East Canterbury, during the past summer and convinced us
                            that God is indeed troubling the face of the waters in that city. It is to this end, beloved
                            Brothers and Sisters, we ask in a special manner, through these lines, that a fervent,
                            united prayer rise from every loyal soul, and continue to rise, asking prosperity to attend
                            this mission, and for strength and wisdom to guide and guard its inspired ones. In the name
                            of our sacred calling, we ask in faith, that with one accord, "Let Zion bowed before God's
                            throne, Raise, O raise one prayer," that the mission above referred to, may develop into the
                            glory of God through the power of his Christ and a perfect revelation and obedience thereto,
                            become the healing of the sin-sick and needy.</p><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Elders" TEIform="persName"/>the Elders. East
                            Canterbury N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cyrus" TEIform="index"/>CYRUS</head><byline TEIform="byline">By Thankful <persName reg="Hale, H." TEIform="persName"/>H. Hale</byline><p TEIform="p">CYRUS king of Persia the type, Cyrus the founder of the Koreshan Unity the
                            antitype. The controversy of late between the "Flaming Sword," and The Manifesto brings
                            these two characters vividly to my mind. Cyrus king of Persia was a blood-thirsty man. His
                            great desire was to conquer all the kingdoms of the world with carnal weapons. He was very
                            successful for a long time, until his territory was very great. He finally attacked a wom-
                            an's kingdom. Queen Tomyris in the north country had a vast dominion. King Cyrus lusted
                            after it. She being a widow, he first proposed marriage to her, thinking by taking her in
                            that way he should get her dominion in a subtle manner. Accordingly he sent an ambassador
                            with the proposition of marriage. She being aware of his intent, returned her refusal,
                            saying, "I am aware that you want my dominion more than you do me." Lust confronted turns
                            into hate, so he was determined to make war upon her, informing her of the same and getting
                            his army ready. She sent an ambassador advising him to give up his determination, as it
                            would be better for him as well as her to do so, but no, he was determined to move forward,
                            so she made a proposition to him, that she would meet him on his territory three days' march
                            from the river which divided them, or three days' march from the river on her dominion. <pb n="13" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 13 He accepted the latter, and when the
                            time arrived for the first battle, she only took one third of her large army, thinking that
                            would be sufficient to demolish his whole army, but not so; he gained the victory and
                            captured her only son, who was to be her successor to the throne, as a prisoner. He became
                            frantic and committed suicide in prison. This enraged the Queen v^ho then put forth her
                            whole army. In the second battle, she conquered and King Cyrus was slain on the battle
                            field. She ordered that his dead body be brought to her with a bucket of blood, and that his
                            head be severed from his body. She then with her own hand, took his head by the hair
                            thereof, and plunged it into the bucket of blood, saying, "Insatiate monster! you shall have
                            your fill of blood." So the great King Cyrus was conquered by a woman. As it was with the
                            type, so it may be with the anti-type, Cyrus. He has undertaken to take the woman's kingdom,
                            first by union or marriage. Not being able fully to accomplish this, that is, to get her
                            dominion through marriage, he has commenced a warfare, but he had better take warning from
                            the experience of the ancient King Cyrus and desist, as it will be better for him, for he
                            will surely lose his life on the battle-field and be beheaded, as was the typical Cyrus. "A
                            word to the wise is sufficient."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prepare thy heart" TEIform="index"/>PREPARE THY HEART</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/>Lucy S. Bowers</byline><p TEIform="p">Be still, ye waves of restless thought and care, Be still, wild winds of worldly
                            strife and woo, Sweet Peace on silver wing is hovering low. Within thy heart a welcome place
                            prepare For her, the subject of thy hope and prayer. Flee every troubling guest thy soul may
                            know, Ambition, Pride, which wander to and fro Despoilers of the bliss which tliou sliouldst
                            share. Let in the angels of Truth, Joy and Light, Who swell the fulness of sweet harmony,
                            Who guard love's ceaseless fountain pure and bright, They are the ministers of God to tliee.
                            Make welcome these, and Peace will find a place, And fill thee with her own unfailing grace.
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Through purest sympathy and an all embracing love..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Through purest sympathy and an all embracing love...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Through purest sympathy and an all embracing love, Christ-like souls are drawn to
                            those less developed in their intellectual, moral and spiritual natures. Their's is the
                            language of Jesus:—"If I be lifted up, I will draw all men unto me."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., C." TEIform="persName"/>C. A.</byline></div2><pb n="14" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New year" TEIform="index"/>THE NEW YEAR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">WITH what rapidity we have passed around the cycle, and on to the end of the year
                            ! Days, weeks, and months have whirled away with wonderful velocity, and where may they now
                            be found? The good and patient Job of Bible story was evidently contemplating this same
                            subject when he wrote the following verse :— "My days are shifter than a weaver's shuttle."
                            That we are here to enter the race for another year is quite certain, and yet the outgoing
                            year carries with it the part that we have acted during those twelve, precious, eventful
                            months. That our lives have been recorded with unerring exactness, is quite evident to the
                            thinking mind, and many are able to see that record in its most minute details. With the
                            past, however, we must make quick and decisive work; confess our faults, drop a penitent
                            tear and then hurry away with new resolves and more intense earnestness to do right, if we
                            expect to keep in the place where life and light has placed us. The Manifesto and its
                            friends have shared a mutual interest during the past year, and corresponding blessings have
                            fallen to the lot of each one. To make our little paper the herald of "good news," to
                            inspire its readers with life that is manifested in goodness toward our fellow man, and in
                            kindness toward the whole creation of God, should be our earnest endeavor. The world should
                            be made better by the presence of every man, woman, and child, and should this fail to be
                            accomplished, sorrow and sin wrould be the consequent result. Our duty in this essential
                            work is apparent. Called of God as witnesses of his love to man; called of God as laborers
                            in his vineyard, our consecration should be full and our life devoted in doing good.
                            Abundant opportunities are offered on every hand, in which to manifest our zeal for God, our
                            consecration to the gospel work and our interest in the promulgation of "peace on earth and
                            good-will to man." "Out of the abundance of the heart, the mouth speaketh." With this love
                            of God in the heart, and a "gentle mind, easy to be entreated," there can not be otherwise
                            than good words and loving deeds. God works in and through his servants, that our lives may
                            be made of value to others ; and that the name of God may be honored through our
                            faithfulness to duty. <pb n="15" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 15 The outgoing year
                            has had its measure well filled with the upspringing remembrances of grateful minds. Honor
                            has been awarded to whom honor is due, for the discovery of this new world. All nations have
                            shared in the blessings of a universal emancipation, and under this cherished protection,
                            have been able to express their appreciation of the loving care of a universal God, without
                            the fear of molestation. Sectarians for once have been forced to admit that "devout men out
                            of every nation under heaven," have preached the true spirit of righteousness and the
                            brotherhood of man. Even some branches of the Church of Christ, known as our gospel home,
                            took thought of the swift passage of time, and lovingly spoke of their early home, and of
                            the zealously devoted laborers who sacrificed their lives for the prosperity and happiness
                            of others. They had closed their record of a century, and many thankful hearts have been
                            filled with expressions of love to God, and with thanksgiving for the unbounded blessings
                            that have been conferred upon our country, and then directly upon our home. Opening our
                            record for new and active inspiration, we look forward with a pleasant anticipation to the
                            time when the "earth shall be filled with the knowledge of the glory of the Lord, as the
                            waters cover the sea." With" this initial number The Manifesto enters upon its twenty-
                            fourth year. In the record of the past will be found many valuable treasures of gospel
                            experience, which were brought forth by consecrated and devoted souls, whose love for God
                            and man filled their whole being. May we emulate thieir example and as God has blest us, so
                            let our light shine in all the earth, for. the peace and prosperity of all mankind. To those
                            who have in any way contributed to the advancement of our little paper, during, the past
                            year, we tender bur kind thanks, and trust that renewed efforts will be made during the
                            present year to make it just what we may wish it to be. Much good may be done in our own
                            home circle, for the writers and readers of The Manifesto, and then it should extend into
                            the world for information concerning our communal homes, and for the peace and blessing of
                            all who may lead a Christian life. If in all this we shall have regard to the ministrations
                            of the Christ Spiritj, we shall seek first the kingdom of God and its righteousness. This
                            will mstipe us-every other needed blessing.</p></div2><pb n="16" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gather home" TEIform="index"/>GATHER HOME</head><p TEIform="p">"For the Son of Man is come to save that which was lost.11—Matt, xviii., 11. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y. 1. From the mount of holiness and love, Goes 2. It thrills like joy from east
                            to west, And 3. The Shepherd's tender voice oh heed, That 4. Come all ye weary and
                            oppressed, Count forth the spiritual call, Tis like a voice from heav'n a echoes from the
                            north to south, It fain would gather fruit the calls for all who've gone astray, To life's
                            unfailing fount he well the cost and pay the price, Then will your souls be sav'd and bove,
                            That speaks to lost ones, each and all. No longer wander, best, That earth's ripe harvest
                            hath bro'tforth. lead, And shows salvation's glorious way. blest, With full reward for
                            sacrifice. come, Oh, come, Our Father hath prepared a home.</p></div2><pb n="17" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manifesto, January, 1894. Office of Publication" TEIform="index"/>THE
                            MANIFESTO. JANUARY, 1894. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION</head><p TEIform="p">The Manifesto is published by the "United Society of Believers" on the first of
                            each month, and is the only work issued regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to
                            furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious views of the Order and to inculcate
                            the spirit of righteousness. All communications should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East
                            Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. ¦TSXI.MS. One copy per year, postage paid .75 " " six months, "
                            " .40</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. November. Thermometer. Bain. Snoiv. 1892.
                                58.12 3.19 in. 0 1893. 37.2 % " 3 in. Highest Temp, during this mo. 56. above 0. Lowest
                                " " " Number of rainy days " " " snowy " " " " clear " " " cloudy" " 16. " 3. 3. 16. 8.
                                C. G. Meed. Dec. 1893. When this number of our Manifesto reaches us, we shall stand at
                                the portal of a New Year, recognizing the fact that this New Year will be to us what the
                                Old Year has made it. If it has been our earnest labor all along the past months to
                                carry out the honest intentions of last New Year, when we could say, "Build thee more
                                stately mansions O my soul, As the swift seasons roll" we are now more fully expanded
                                into a noble Christian character. How beautiful is ideal life as it pictures itself
                                before us, when we are on some "Mount of Transfiguration." But the possession of that
                                ideal comes not through observation. "When the humblest duties of life are performed
                                with a cheerful patience; when the left hand hardly knows what the right does; when we
                                can sacrifice ourselves in little acts in which we feel no glory at all" then the
                                perfect character is growing within us though we may know nothing of it, save the
                                restful assurance that we, by aiming to be faithful in little things, are reaching our
                                highest possibilities. We read with pleasure the Centennial observances, of Enfield and
                                Shirley, and wonder why we could not have done as well, when it was so often agitated in
                                our Society previous to the closing of our Century. Many thanks to the contributor of "A
                                Paraphrase on Taking Offence" in Dec. No. When we have learned this lesson much of the
                                vinegar of life will be transformed to the oil of peace; for the effort to guard and
                                care for "I, mine, and me," is the foundation of most of life's inharmonies.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, Amelia J." TEIform="persName"/>Amelia J. Calver</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Center family" TEIform="index"/>Center Family</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1893. Winter has begun. We are not as fully prepared for it as
                                desirable, still can not complain seeing much has been accomplished. Our farmer deacon
                                has made quite an alteration in the corn barn which we think will prove to be a
                                substantial improvement. The change consists in having stanchions that swing around
                                giving the animals greater liberty of movement of the heads. They are also supplied with
                                pure, fresh water while in the stall. This being Sabbath day we of the Center family
                                attended meeting at the Church and had an interesting season. Several speakers gave
                                voice to sentiments that were profitable and instructive and many if not all present
                                felt it good to be there. <pb n="18" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 18 THE MANIFESTO. Our
                                religious gatherings should always be of an uplifting nature to those assembled. "Gather
                                my saints together they that have made a covenant with me by sacrifice." We make
                                sacrifices with the idea of leaving the inferior and ignoble for the superior and noble,
                                the lower for the higher; hence, we leave the world with its selfishness and wrong-doing
                                for a right manner of life, and to all who wish for a better condition of things than
                                obtains in t!;e world we say, "Come, and let him that heareth say come, and whosoever
                                will let him partake of the waters of life freely."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rayson, Timothy D." TEIform="persName"/>Timothy D. Rayson</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North family" TEIform="index"/>North Family</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1893. Oue ever welcome Manifesto comes to us again full of noble thought
                                and deeds of service. How rich we feel in having the treasures opened to us of so many
                                pure, beautiful and aspiring souls, devoted to the same cause and interest as our own.
                                You all, we presume and trust, had a good, earnest, Thanksgiving meeting, and partook of
                                a good Thanksgiving dinner. We enjoyed the day very much, as we were very kindly invited
                                by our Canaan friends to spend the day with them, which we did, arriving there about 9
                                a. m. Held a good, free meeting, and partook of a beautiful vegetarian dinner. You will
                                say it must have been a vegetarian dinner if it was beautiful, for who would think of
                                describing a table set out with pieces of dead animals and birds, as beautiful? Our
                                table truly was beautiful and replete with good vegetables, breads, sauces, jellies,
                                fruits, nuts, etc., and yet some will say they can not give up the use of flesh as food
                                as they have nothing to take its place. This excuse indicates, we think, a lack of faith
                                and resolution. However, the treat of the day was the afternoon meeting. We were
                                entertained by the members of the "Ethical Floral Circle" who meet once a week under the
                                guidance and training of Sister Emily Offord. Their motto is "Cultivate the intel- lect.
                                Improve the mind. Refine the manners." And we can truly say they give evidence of
                                progress towards their motto. The young Brethren and Sisters, boys and girls, did
                                themselves great credit. It was a surprise and a treat, We reached home about dusk,
                                having spent a memorable Thanksgiving Day. When we think of the blessings and comforts
                                we enjoy, and look beyond into the towns and cities of the children of this world, our
                                hearts ai-e subdued in sadness, and we would that we could do something to help to
                                rectify the wrongs and relieve the oppressions under which the unfortunate, the weak,
                                the ignorant, suffer. Some of us feel concerned about these matters, and think Believers
                                should give time and attention to the study of the methods by which the landlord and
                                usurer filches the produce of the toiler. It certainly is not well for Believers to be
                                ignorant of, and to shut their eyes and ears to the distressful conditions existing in
                                the outer world. The root of industrial distress undoubtedly lies in bad land laws. A
                                system that permits a man to own land upon which his fellow men must earn their living
                                and to tax them on the added value accruing by their labor and the increase of
                                population, is unjust. This and the use of metals as money and the consequent usury laws
                                are the seed bed of millionares and paupers. The law was to go forth from Zion and the
                                word of the Lord from Jerusalem, and Believers certainly should have a testi- mony on
                                such matters. , We would at the opening of the New Year renew with our gospel kindred,
                                our vows of consecration to our high and holy calling, and resolve to do all we can the
                                coming year to bring ourselves and the conditions around us a little nearer to where our
                                faith would have us.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shepard, Walter S." TEIform="persName"/>Walter S. Shepherd</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1893. / Only a few days and the grand Columbian year will have closed
                                its existence. <pb n="19" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 19 It seems hardly
                                possible that its race can have been run so quickly. What joys and sorrows, what hopes
                                and disappointments, what successes and failures, what achievements and deprivations,
                                are chronicled on the pages of its history. The rapidly passing moments silently, yet
                                forcibily seem to say, we are hastily bearing each soul over life's fitful height, to
                                the bounds of eternity. The past few days have produced beautiful weather; and Br. Ira
                                Lawson's verdict is, that sleighing in this early part of the season, has not been
                                surpassed in the past twenty-five years. Present appearances betoken a thaw. The supply
                                of wood for another winter is mostly drawn to the mill, and much of it sawed. Seventy
                                acres of land have been plowed and prepared for the sowing of oats. Eight hundred loads
                                of manure have been drawn and spread on thirty more acres to bring it in condition for
                                the production of other crops. Dairy roof has been newly shingled; and an addition of
                                90x18 ft., to the building used for storage and wood-house, is just completed. May the
                                dawn of the New Year bring the smile of gladness to all the kind readers of The
                                Manifesto, and be fraught with increased blessings for all who are striving to live a
                                life of true holiness.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sweet, Julia L." TEIform="persName"/>Julia L. Sweet</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1893. We have an excellent market for stove and furnace wood. Management
                                means a great deal in poultry business. A good poultry man is as important as good
                                fowls. To feed well is the secret of success. Pure water with plenty of egg-producing
                                food will tell. The needs of the poultry must be studied. Ground meat and ground bone,
                                with milk, are among the essentials in winter food for hens. A sameness of diet should
                                be avoided. Hens will give a good account of their work on a varied diet.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South family" TEIform="index"/>South Family</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1893. The season of Thanksgiving was duly observed and thanks returned
                                for the blessings received. The comforts which are experienced in our quiet homes are
                                the reward of industry and care, as time has swiftly carried us through the harvesting
                                season and filled our granaries and storehouses with a bountiful supply from the Giver
                                of every good and perfect gift. A new elevator is in process of construction which will
                                also add to the many improvements of the year eighteen hundred ninety-three, and all
                                have proved so far beneficial. We have been favored lately with a short but pleasant
                                interview with our highly esteemed Brother Arthur Bruce and also with Elder Calvin Reed
                                and a Brother companion. These seasons of gospel interchange strengthen the bond of
                                union, although the time was too limited to be satisfactory. The Year 1894 is about to
                                dawn. The past, freighted with golden opportunities has gone forever. Its hours we can
                                never recall, but its influence is ours, its spirit abides, though unseen. Even so with
                                those who have left us, they live and are laboring now; their achievements are for us,
                                their inspiration is our portion, our legacy, our New Year's gilt. As a people may we
                                awaken to a vivid sense of our responsibilities, for all we do lives after us. May the
                                Spirit of Truth, Wisdom and Love, be our guide and counsellor through the untried year.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witham, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>Maria Withum</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury, N. H</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. Dec. 1893. In the year that has nearly passed, we can with
                                pleasure look back to the many comforts and blessings, both temporal and spiritual.
                                These, an all-wise Providence has bestowed upon us, to make home pleasant and to draw
                                our hearts to a greater consecration in God's service. For all his blessings we are
                                truly thankful and in the beginning of the glad New <pb n="20" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/>
                                20 THE MANIFESTO. Year would consecrate our souls anew to that spiritual understanding
                                which is given to us through Christ our Savior. Our hearts swell with gratitude, for the
                                pleasant surroundings that encompass us, and for this we would give to God all our
                                services. We are thankful for temporal blessings and for the bounteous harvest we have
                                received. Hay an average crop, and housed in good condition. Apples not abundant but we
                                will be thankful for a few. We harvested a good crop of potatoes, and by the unremitting
                                labors of Elder Nicholas we had a nice family garden and a good yield of lovage. Our
                                door-yard has been made a flowery dell, the past summer, by the Sisters with a little
                                extra help. We thank God for the gifts he has given to us. Let us put these talents to
                                such use that when the Divine Teacher calls we may hear the welcome sound, "Well done,
                                good and faithful servant, enter thou into the joy of thy Lord." Potter Dyball. Weather
                                Eecord for November, 1893. Highest Temp, during the month, 52 Lowest " " " " 9 Mean " "
                                " " 31.3 Snowfall in inches " " " 3.25 Total Precipitation " " 1.87 Greatest " in any 24
                                consecutive hours, .87</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Briggs, N. A." TEIform="persName"/>N. A. Briggs.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1893. Already we have turned the last page, bearing record of the grand
                                old year of 1893, and while we witness its departure, rife with the wonderful events
                                that have marked its progress, our hearts are made glad in the realization that so much
                                is being done by the noble workers throughout the broad universe of God, to spread a
                                knowledge of the truth that maketh free, bringing as a result, righteousness to the
                                hearts of the children of men. Let us awaken, who are called to be the sons and
                                daughters of the resurrection, lest we be found lacking that power which alone gives
                                victory to the soul. We would return our grateful thanks to all who send greetings for
                                the New Year, while we would express the same to our kindred everywhere. Since December
                                came in we have expe- rienced a real touch of genuine winter weather; quite a big
                                foretaste as we view it. We have sufficient snow to make sleighing practicable. Our
                                winter's supply of wood is being drawn to the sheds ready for use, and if the
                                weather-wise have made no mistake, we shall find need for its consumption, before the
                                balmy days of spring visit us again. Our Brethren are in the mill at work on the corn
                                planters; they have a contract for six hundred the present season. Sisters find
                                employment in the various places where duty calls, striving to make the home with all
                                its surroundings an honor to the profession we make, trusting that the blessing of
                                heaven will rest upon every effort in the cause of good.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, Julia" TEIform="persName"/>Julia Russell</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North family" TEIform="index"/>North Family</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1893. In bidding the past year adieu and welcoming the new, we waft a
                                new petition for divine blessing upon our fellow men and our household of faith. "Thy
                                rod and thy staff, they comfort me." True it is that the joys and trials of the past
                                year have proved necessary, developing powers to adjust life aright, and as long as we
                                dwell in the light of God, which casts no shadow, weariness will not unsettle our faith
                                nor obscure from our sight the divine staff of God's supporting love. The December
                                number of our Manifesto, we consider an excellent one to end the 1893 volume. Especially
                                was the Editorial inspiring; inciting the mind to think more of the vital interests of
                                Zion's welfare, in place of valueless forms or methods which savor of "antiquated
                                dogmas." Eepresenting one of the branches of God's stupendous tree of spiritual life,
                                    <pb n="21" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 21 possessing the sap of
                                vitalizing truth and a few dead leaves of error, may we as a Church be more zealous to
                                use the pruning knife of consistency and cut off all that is useless as well as
                                extirpate from within, traits of character offensive to God and our associates. As we
                                do, we shall enlarge our individuality in all that is good and pure as well as in the
                                possibility of God's work of soul salvation. In this we may help to bring about our long
                                desired hope of establishing the kingdom of heaven within.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Baxter, George H." TEIform="persName"/>George H. Baxter</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, New York" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Second Family. Wintek has set in, we have little snow but quite good
                                sleighing. We are busy just now threshing grain. The North Family and we have joined
                                help thereby mak- ing it a little lighter for both. Oats turn out good, but rye rather
                                poor, but as crops on the whole have been quite fair, complaining will do no good. Have
                                cut some tire wood also. As we must soon bid good by to '93 we shall have to prepare for
                                the year '94. May we be careful to make fewer resolves but determined to keep all good
                                ones and add unto them more. Each year is telling either for good or otherwise. There is
                                need of extra exertion and may we begin the New Year with a determination to be
                                consecrated, and not feel, I am only one, it will not matter much. Let us remember that
                                as we are a part of community we should individually feel that there is a duty we owe to
                                ourselves and also to society, which is to do all the good we can and as little harm as
                                possible. Each deed counts either for good or evil. We wish all the household of faith
                                east and west a happy New Year with gospel increase. Therefore, let all in particular
                                study more closely the principles of our faith, that we may not only be better able to
                                give a reason why we are Believers, to candid inquirers, but it will help us to work
                                more understanding^ for salvation and redemption from a sinful life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anstatt, Isaac" TEIform="persName"/>Isaac Anstatt</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1893. Brethren and Sisters of the Household of Faith:— Our good Sister
                                Ada Cummings, who writes our monthly notes for The Manifesto has some trouble with her
                                eyes and therefore must be careful for the present. As she can not write until the time
                                will be past for you to receive our New Year's greeting in the January number, I take my
                                pen to tell you that we, at Sabbathday Lake, wish you all a Happy New Year. It is a hazy
                                Sabbath, not what we would call foggy, for the sun is shining almost through, and it
                                makes us think that heaven is beyond, only a little ways. We attended our religious
                                service and heaven appeared right in our midst, no haze to separate. Eldress Harriet
                                Goodwin spoke beautifully to the youth and children, and said she had noticed a marked
                                improvement in their deportment, and this is what her loving, motherly eye is quick to
                                see. Their Elders and Teachers spare no pains with them, and they show that they are
                                giving good heed to the kind instruction which they receive from day to day. This
                                afternoon I visited Sister Ada and her company of little girls. They were just arranging
                                for a meeting of their own. I asked if I could be a spectator and liberty was granted at
                                once. They had leaders appointed from their own number and the order was perfect. The
                                gifts of the spirit were really made manifest. Toward the close of the meeting I taught
                                them the "Celestial March" and other religious exercises which made the worship of our
                                fathers and mothers so beautiful; and that caused me to think of the pure and holy lives
                                which our fathers and mothers lived. O, how white and clean are the spiritual robes of
                                the children of the resurrection! These are Sabbathday Lake notes and temporal matters
                                are left out. So in the commencement of the New Year, we will seek the spiritual first,
                                then the temporal blessings will be added.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mace, Aurelia G." TEIform="persName"/>Aurelia G. Mace</byline></div3><pb n="22" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="White Water, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>White Water, O.</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. Dec. 1893. We have finished sawing our wood for the winter.
                                Four of the Brethren from the Center family, with their new, fifteen horse traction
                                engine, pulled into our wood-yard early this morning and as the workmen and the
                                machinery were in fine condition, the way the short sticks flew was a caution. While the
                                Brethren were busy outdoors the Sisters were contributing their share indoors, helping
                                on with the good work, by placing before us a most excellent dinner. How well they
                                succeeded, we will leave to the imagination of the readers, as the writer feels that he
                                can not do the sub- ject justice in writing. We have our corn all in the crib. Our stock
                                in shape to be stabled whenever necessary. ****** We had a very good meeting at ten
                                o'clock, Thanksgiving morning. Every one was made to feel that it was a thanksgiving
                                indeed, as well as in name. Why should we not be thankful? We have every thing to make
                                us comfortable, both temporal and spiritual and all that we are required to do for all
                                this, is to take up our cross against sin. Many thanks for the invitation to visit your
                                home at Canterbury. Our school children are making preparations for an entertainment
                                during the holidays. Please accept our gospel love and best wishes for a happy
                                Christmas.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tyler, J. O." TEIform="persName"/>J. O. Tyler</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canaan, New York" TEIform="index"/>Canaan, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1893. Beloved Editor:—We have been silent contributors to the Home Notes
                                for some months by. giving space to others. Through some mistake our last Notes did not
                                enter your Office. They contained a brief account of our terrific hailstorm therefore we
                                felt somewhat disappointed in not having it published. A member of our "Floral Circle"
                                wrote out a description of the storm in blank verse which we enclose for your
                                consideration. [The Storm at even-tide will appear next month. Ed.] On the 27th ult.
                                some of our Sisters were surprised at an unusual, sudden jarring of the house. They at
                                once attributed it to vibrations of an earthquake, in which opinion they were
                                subsequently confirmed by learning that a severe shock was felt in Montreal at the same
                                time. We have spent a very happy and joyous Thanksgiving. Our friends from the North
                                family came to spend the day with us. I do not know as such a thing ever happened
                                before. We have generally been recipients of their hospitality. We had a beautiful
                                meeting in the fore- noon, after which we shared together a bountiful dinner, no lives
                                of poor innocent animals having to be taken to satiate our appetites. In the afternoon
                                the "Floral Circle" gave us an interesting entertainment some over two hours, and we
                                trust all were benefited thereby. Dec. 3. To-day we are right in the midst of a heavy
                                snow-storm, the wind blowing so fiercely as to rock our house. We wish our gospel
                                kindred a happy New Year.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brown, Angelina" TEIform="persName"/>Angelina Brown</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, O.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1893. Beloved Elder Henry :—We are having very slippery weather, at
                                present. Thermometer stands 18 above zero. I have just reached home, having been at
                                Union Village on a visit. I had the pleasure of meeting our beloved Elder Joseph Holden,
                                from Mt. Lebanon. The time spent with him was very pleasant. I also attended religious
                                serv- ice with the Brethren and Sisters and found many well tried souls who were zealous
                                in the cause of gospel truth. I enjoyed the season very much. I was also interested in
                                those who had just entered the gospel work. It is good to know <pb n="23" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 23 that they are bearing a daily cross, and making
                                their lives pure before God. They manifested a desire to support the gospel and were not
                                anxious to introduce the ways of the world. We want the treasures of the Kingdom of God
                                and let the world take care of itself and its ways.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fredrick, Henry W." TEIform="persName"/>Henry W. Fredrick</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South Union, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>South Union, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1893. The corn crop is safely housed; an average yield. Hands are
                                engaged in get- ting in wood for the winter, and in feeding stock. "Weather so far has
                                been beautiful. Ice at present only about one inch thick. Thermometer indicating 14
                                degrees above zero, the coldest for a few hours. Health of Society has been very good
                                recently. The Brethren are engaged in replacing the old steam-plant at the water works
                                with new. Our love and thanks to all concerned in publishing The Manifesto.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Richardson, J. H" TEIform="persName"/>J. H. Richardson</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="December 1893" TEIform="index"/>Dec. 1893</head><p TEIform="p">Elder Henry, Dear Brother:—The Books came safely and I was much pleased with
                                what you have published concerning South Union. We have had nice weather and abundant
                                crops of corn. We have to-day, Dec. 4th, the first snow of the season. It was just a few
                                flakes and did not remain on the ground. Thank you for the return of the Books.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perryman, John W." TEIform="persName"/>John W. Perryman</byline></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">Will the writers of thp "Home Notes" please forward them by the 10th of each
                                month, as additional duties require a change in time. All writers and readers will
                                accept best wishes for the New Year, of the printers and Ed.]</p></div3></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut, January 1894" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station,
                            Conn., Jan. 1894</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Children:—A Happy New Year is the salutation. Look over the resolutions you
                            made last year and see how many were kept. Think of the mistakes you made so often. Begin
                            the year with holy aspirations and let them call forth selfdenying work. Avoid repeating
                            past er- rors. Perform your whole duty and a whole year of happiness will be yours. Your
                            goal on the sea of life is purity. Truth and purity are a sure foundation. Be pure and true,
                            is the warning voice to you. A pure character is capital earthly riches can not represent,
                            and happiness nothing but a pure life can give In character building do your best work. All
                            may walk in Wisdom's path. Ho w delightful is the way! Subdue evil before it gets a firm
                            hold. Firmly resist the allurements of sin, and strive for the prize that is worthy to win.
                            Sin is attractive, but delusive. Too often you pay for simple pleasure in grief. The first
                            step in sin is the hardest. Don't take it. Sin brings trouble, sorrow and pain, "the path of
                            duty" is pleasant and plain. Conscience has a reproof for every wrong. Perform humble
                            service for the home life. Overcome self. Watch continually, for otherwise there is no
                            safety. Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Monroe, Charles" TEIform="index"/>Charles Monroe
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Monroe, Charles" TEIform="persName">Charles Monroe</persName> at Enfield,
                                N. H. Sept. 16, 1893. Age 65 yrs. and 4 mo.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Taber, Ida H." TEIform="index"/>Ida H. Taber
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Taber, Ida H." TEIform="persName">Ida H. Taber</persName>, at East
                                Canterbury, N. H. Nov. 21, 1893. Age 38 yrs. 9 mo. and 14 days.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bussell, George" TEIform="index"/>George Bussell
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Bussell, George" TEIform="persName">George Bussell</persName>, at
                                Shakers, N. Y. Nov. 25, 1893. Age 82 yrs. and 1 mo. Br. George passed away as quietly as
                                a child on going to sleep. H. DeG.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Danforth, Nancy G." TEIform="index"/>Nancy G. Danforth
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Danforth, Nancy G." TEIform="persName">Nancy G. Danforth</persName>, at
                                East Canterbury, N. H. Dec. 13, 1893. Age 70 yrs. 1 mo. and 13 days. Has been a worthy
                                member of the Socie- ty for the last 40 years.</p></div3></div2><pb n="24" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of hygeio-therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of
                                Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mr. Howells' literary autobiography begins in the Christmas Ladies' Home
                                Journal, and will continue through a year's numbers of that magazine. The Journal of
                                Hygeio-Therapy. Dec. Contents. The Use of Drugs; The Efficiency of Hygeio-Therapy; The
                                Folly of Vaccination; A Test Case; An Old Pioneer; Answer to Dr. Stair; Letter to a
                                Young Man, etc., etc. Dr. T. V. Gifford, Kokomo, Ind.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ebenezers or records of prevailing prayer" TEIform="index"/>Ebenezers, or Records of
                                prevailing Prayer
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hastings, H. L." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> "Ebenezers, or Records of
                                prevailing Prayer," by H. L,. Hastings of Boston, Mass., is the title of a Book of
                                nearly 300 pages. It is beautifully printed with clear, large type, which will give a
                                comforting assurance to the eyes of the aged, as well as to the young, as they study
                                these wonderful lessons of faith. Those who believe with the good apostle, that they
                                should give themselves continually to prayer and to the ministry of the word, will enjoy
                                unbounded comfort in the perusal of this little volume. It contains a great variety of
                                interesting matter in prayerful experience and is the whispering of anxious souls for
                                "good-will" to man. A HUNDRED TON MAUA3INE OKDER, An event in periodical literature,
                                n,ot without its significance to the general public as showing the growth of the reading
                                classes, was the receipt on the 9th of November by The Cosmopolitan Magazine of the
                                order given below. A single order from a news company for one hundred tons'of magazines!
                                That is almost an event in the history of the world. A like order has never before been
                                made, and if past ratios be maintained it means considerably more than half a million
                                circulation for the December Cosmopolitan. Yet, when the list of authors and artists in
                                the December number is examined, one is not so much surprised. It contains the only
                                known unpublished manuscript of De Maupassant, illustrated by Vierge, perha-ps the most
                                famous of European illustrators; After the World's Fair, by Paul Bourget, John J.
                                Ingalls, William Dean Howells, Lyman J. Gage, Arthur Sherburne Hardy, Mark Twain, Robert
                                Grant and others nearly as famous, and nearly two hundred illustrations, to which the
                                following art- ists contribute: Hopkinson Smith, Kemble, Harry Fenn, F. O. Small,
                                Attwood, Henckel, Dan Beard, Reinhart and Remington. Think of having the World's Fair
                                done by such expensive men as Howells, Mark Twain and Paul Bourget, and sending such
                                artists as Charles S. Reinhart to Chicago for a single number of a magazine to be sold
                                for only 15 cents, or by subscription twelve and one half cents. A book publisher,
                                preparing such a book would not dare incur these expenses short of $5.00 a copy. Is it
                                not a revolution that is an improvement upon old methods; a revolution of vast
                                importance to the reading public? The order to which reference is made reads as follows:
                                "Publisher Cosmopolitan. Dear Sir:—Of the 200,000 copies of December number to be sent
                                us, please send as follows: 172,650 copies regular edition, 27,250 copies R. R. edition.
                                Yours respectfully, The American News Company." A very interesting account of mind
                                development in the case of a girl born without sight, hearing and speech will deeply
                                affect the readers of the December Phrenological Journal, because of its really
                                marvelous nature. The sketch of Mrs. Kendal, the wellknown actress, is also to be
                                commended as a superior bit of character limning with many incidental points of social
                                interest. How to Study Strangers, the addresses delivered at the Institute Alumni
                                banquet, and other special features must draw popular attention, A sketch of Dr.
                                McClellan, father of Gen. McClellan, and a famous surgeon in his day, adds to the series
                                of phrenological biographies an important member. "Bread Reform" is an appetizing theme,
                                as the writer puts it, and the article on warm water instead of cold, in hy_ dropathic
                                treatment, is in the main sound and comforting. The editor very forcibly scores the
                                conduct of the partisans of silver, and emphasizes the point that a scientist is none
                                the less a citizen because he may be devoted to science. The number is generally a
                                phrenological one and will be eagerly read, we doubt not, by all who are interested in
                                Phrenology, since it is fairly representative of the latter day progress of this science
                                in the civilized world. Price 15 cts; $1.50 a year. Address Fowler &amp; Wells Co.,
                                25 East 21st TStreet, New York. LITERARY NOTE. The Werner Company, of Chicago, is
                                publishing in weekly numbers a report of the proceedings of the World's Parliament of
                                Religions, held in Chicago, in the Memorial Art Palace, under the auspices of the
                                World's Columbian Exposition. The addresses are com- plete, and verbatim, and are
                                illustrated with portraits of one hundred of the principal del- egates and speakers.
                                There are to be eleven parts, and the entire series cost but $1.00, postpaid. THE
                                ALTRUIST. Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic spelling, and devoted to common
                                property, united labor, Community homes, and equal rights to all. It is published by the
                                Altruist Community, whose members all live and work together, and hold all their
                                property in common, all the men and women haying equal rights in electing officers and
                                deciding all business affairs by their majority vote. 50 cents a year; specimen copy
                                free. Address A. Longley, 901 Olive St., St. Louis, Mo. MUSIC. Price, $1.50. SHAKER
                            24</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>