<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2212" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">36</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">22</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><date value="18921201" TEIform="date">December 1892</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">265-296</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="22" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
DECEMBER.
THE
MANIFESTO.
Published by the United Societies,
VOL. XXII.
"For what is a man profited, if he shall gain the whole world, and
lose his own soul? or what shall a man give in exchange for
his soul."Matt. XVI., 26.
Canterbury, N. H.
1892.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
AGENTS WANTED
Salary
OR
Commission,
FOR
. JOHN L. STODDARD'S
"GLIMPSES OF THE WORLD/'THE    WORLD'S   COLUMBIAN
EXPOSITION,    MEN  AND ISSUES
OF '92.
BEST BOOKS.     BEST SYSTEM.
BEST  TERMS.
Address "Willey &c Co., 195197
State St., Springfield, Mass.
1 Trip to tie World's Fair
FREE!
THE FLAMING SWORD
A Radical, Rational  and Racy
Reform Paper.
The bitter foe of every form of social abuse
in church and state, the expositor of Koreshanity, which is primitive Christianity revived, and the promulgator of an equitable
system of exchange which is destined to revolutionize commercial methods and
Crush  the Iniquitous  Money Power
SAMPLE    COPY    FREE.
The (Ming Star Pi. House,
3619 Cottage Grove Avenue.
CHICAGO, ILL.
Xo any   worthy man or woman, Io.r or
girl.   If you wish to visit the          |
WORLD'S COLUMBIAN EXPOSITION
at Chicago, for one week or more, free
of all expense, on easy conditions,
write at once. Enclose self-addressed,
stamped envelope,
World's Fair Entertainment Dept.
1OO3 Monatlnock Building-,
Cor, Dearborn  and  Jackson   Sts.   Chicago,   III.
m*~L L STODDARDS GREAT BOOK-gS
"Glimpses EWorld'
IS A MAGNIFICENT
PORTFOLIO OF PHOTOGRAPHS
Such as the World Never Saw Before.
It seems likely to prove the
GREATEST Subscription Book of the Age.
No Similar Worfe Can Stand Before It.
"What the People Want is FINE Pictubes.
I want that book!" "How beautiful!" "I
must have it!" "Take my order!" are but
sample outbursts of enthusiasm occasioned by
a sight of the Beautiful Prospectus.
0^-AGENTS REMEMBERS
That this rare Book of art gives you an entrance into the homes, and makes you feel
that you are not an intruder; that you can
coin money with it; that we have special
inducements to offer purchasers, which help
our agents; that this is the greatest chance
you ever had; that this agency is what Ministers, Teachers, Students, and others are
looking for; that the first to be in the field
will be sure to reap the Golden Harvest.
Magnificent Prospectus and Outfit, prepaid,
for only 1.50. It will pay you to work forus.
Address, J. K. HASTINGS, Manager of
"THE CHRISTIAN," 47 Cornhilt, Boston, Mass.
(Preserve this, it may not appear again.     Mention IMa paper.)
Tile Celebrated
SiSrattom
BAND  INSTRUMENTS,
Snare and Bass Drums, Flras.   piccolos. Clarionet*, Cym>
Calsand illi other Instruments pertaining coBrass Bands and Drum Corps.
JOHIV F\ 8TRATTON & SOX,
43   &   45   Walker   Sueet    NEW   YORK.
If ror cakitot get them or Tries
THE GEKUIXB       loc-Al.   CALKR8,   WE   \TBJ.   JO> BOM*
WAT  Oftin>PLYHfG  TOD WITB -TBB
STRATTON
RUSSIAN CUT
VIOLIN STRINGS.
Sklen ecd (or Catalogue tad S>rh: Lfac
john f stratton & son,
Musical Merchandise.
42 * 4.> Walker St..         NEW YORK.
IF you wish   to   advertise   anything1 anvVhere at any time, write to GEO. P.
ROWELL & CO., Xo.  10   Spruce St., N. Y.
Vol. XXII.
DECEMBER, 1892.
No. 12.--><pb n="265" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True life" TEIform="index"/> THE TRUE LIFE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/> Martha J. Anderson.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "In Godin goodwe live and move and have our being." The God man that is the spiritual,is
                            paramount to the earth-man, the material. To give up all in the pursuit and practice of
                            truth is noble; true, the physical claims our time and attention m a great degree ; but if
                            we gather to give, and make sacrifice the real use of every self-pleasure, then will the
                            hands be emptied but to be filled, and the soul's wealth increased by continual service in a
                            cause that brings ample reward. Our powers should not be turned to accumulating for self,
                            for if "we live and move and have our being in God," we must claim a relationship and
                            obligation to all souls. "Bear ye one another's burdens and thus fulfill the law of
                            Christ"the God-man. The fretful, fevered state of mind engendered by unprofitable strife,
                            the inharmony of erring passions and the sordid greed for gold, mars the peace of human
                            beings and creates unequal conditions of society. Human nature is alike selfish and grasping
                            among all classes ; the poor envy the rich but only wait the opportunity to wield the same
                            sceptre of power and oppression over those less fortunate. Real virtue is doing right,
                            loving justice and dispensing mercy in the midst of perverse and evil tendencies ; but alas
                            ! how few possess it. If genius and talent had unrestricted liberty of action to work for
                            the good of humanity, how would the world be blest! but, the moment a great thought finds
                            expression in practical form, the ghoul of monopoly snatches it from the grasp of its
                            originator and takes all the benefit, so that mankind in general are no better off. The
                            inventor mayhap dies in poverty, and the poor mechanic and sewing girl get no better wages
                            for all the improvements in machinery. Modern civilization with all its boasted prestige, is
                            a gigantic scheme of selfishness, with this improvement on the past, (?)it has more brain,
                            and wit to carry out its diabolical systems of fraud and injustice. Its root and growth are
                            from the animal instincts of the earth-man. The perfect social compact is formed from
                            within, through the action of the higher law, which disannuls the external rule of brute
                            dominion. "Thou shalt love the Lord, thy God <pb n="266" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> with all thy heart, and
                            thy neighbor as thyself." Herein is the Divine unselfish idea unfolded, and in no isolated
                            natural family relationships can this be fully accomplished. The laying down of the carnal
                            life solves the mystery, and forms the unity and brotherhood of Christ-inspired souls. "No
                            man taketh it, (the generative life) from me, but I lay it down of myself." To consent to
                            die is to enter into the larger life of Pentecostal Communism, "where no man says of aught
                            he has, it is his own." We are but stewards of God's bounties which He has blest us with,
                            and have no right to accumulate for selfish purposes. "God sendeth his rain on the just and
                            the unjust;" so shall regenerate mankind in their beneficent and universal sympathies, seek
                            to ameliorate the conditions that hold humanity in bondage to wrong doing. How many worthy
                            souls have had glimpses of the true life, and in their efforts to consummate the high ideal,
                            have signally failed, for the lack of assistance on the part of those who wanted all the
                            benefits accruing from associated living, without making any of the sacrifices required to
                            sustain such a noble enterprise. The selfish me and mine relation, has not in it the germ of
                            universal love and interest. The divine brotherhood seems yet afar off to the discerning
                            mind, Only as it is developed in the few ascetic Communities that are based on the solid
                            rock of self-denial; but, lofty purpose yet inspires, and many failures may awaken the
                            sanguine to a realization that repeated effort, though abortive, may be salutary in
                            revealing error and convincing the sincere and honest, that in the natural state, man is
                            unable to restrain and curb the selfish propensities, and bring them in subjection to order
                            and discipline in close communal relation. Co-operation alone can be effected on the plane
                            of generation for mutual benefit, in the equal distribution of the gains of industry. The
                            centralization of capital in great business enterprises, gives the few who are shrewd and
                            scheming, power to oppress and crowd to the wall those who are without means to compete in
                            the strife. But the great woe promised in scripture hastens to its consummation, on "those
                            who add house to house and acre to acre," robbing the poor of their just right to an
                            inheritance in the earth and making of them wage-slaves. Never before was there such
                            agitation of thought on subjects that pertain to progress and right living ; souls are
                            patiently looking and waiting for the fulfillment of the great hope that has been nurtured
                            through the ages, the brotherhood of man, the perfected blossom of the tree of life. The
                            righteousness of the outer court and the divine unity of the inner spiritual court, shall be
                            related in harmony of action, and just equation in all their associations and relations with
                            one another. Then shall we see the glory of the New Heavens and the New Earth, in which the
                            true life befitting each order shall be perfectly expressed. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beauty of character is dependent on the equal development..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Beauty of character is dependent on the equal development...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Beauty of character is dependent on the equal development and balance of all our God-given
                            faculties.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline><pb n="267" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Open letter" TEIform="index"/> AN OPEN LETTER.</head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, October 1892" TEIform="index"/> Mount Lebanon, N. Y. Oct.
                                18-92.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Alonzo T. Jones, Editor "American Sentinel," Respected Friend :Enclosed please find an
                                article on the "Sabbaths." If you can make use of it, it is at your disposal; if not no
                                harm done. I should like to know more about you. You are no ordinary man. Your history
                                would be instructive. Have you not sometime been in connection with the Shaker Order? I
                                can not understand, otherwise, how it is you are so logically clear in your theological
                                ideas. You are also a prophet. What will be the end and limit of Church and State union?
                                And how long will it last? have you ever seen "Christ's Second Appearing?" Or any Shaker
                                publications ? You are on the right track. You stand "Stiffly" for principle, regardless
                                of men and women. When you state that, after appealing in vain to the courts and the
                                Constitution, you now appeal to God, as the last resort, you hit the nail right on the
                                head.That appeal will not be in vain. This nation is destined to be the New Earth,and
                                Shakerism will be the New Heavens. That will be the Millennium! In the New Earth, the
                                truths pertaining to the propagative order, advocated by Moses, and by the reformers of
                                all ages and nations, will be reduced to practice-be the law. And the truths seen by the
                                prophet of all ages pertaining to the Resurrection-(Spiritual Order of Shakerism) will
                                be in practical operation. Great Babylonmixture-will be divided into "three parts ;" the
                                generative order,married men and women ; the Resurrection Order, who are celibates,
                                neither marrying or being given in marriage ; and Intellectual Celibates, men and women
                                who will fill all the offices in the New Earth. These three orders will constitute the
                                long expected millennium. In it, the knowledge of the Lord-Truth-will cover the New
                                Earth and fill the New Heavens, as the waters cover the sea. Truly yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder Henry, Dear Brother:--The Oct. Manifesto came to me laden..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Elder Henry, Dear Brother:--The Oct. Manifesto came to me laden...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Oregon, Milton, October 9, 1892" TEIform="index"/>Milton, Or. Oct. 9. 1892.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Elder Henry, Dear Brother : The Oct. Manifesto came to me laden with precious food. It
                                is, indeed, this to the soul seeking righteousness by self-denial in a pure, or virgin
                                life. The article by Br. A. G-. H. is a store of itself, also the article by our late
                                Br. H. L. E. which cannot be set aside nor refuted. In fact every article in the October
                                number breathes forth the inspiration of God to my soul, and to any soul sick of a
                                sinful life. Jesus in speaking to his disciples, said: "If a man will come after me, let
                                him deny himself, take up his cross and follow me." This is laid down as a criterion for
                                each one of us, hence, I feel it a duty incumbent upon me, to take this line of life in
                                a practical sense, in order to be entitled to an inheritance in the <pb n="268" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> kingdom of Christ. Experience teaches that every victory gained over a depraved
                                nature, brings us nearer to God. Light comes into the soul which will dispel all
                                darkness, and the apostle instructs us to "have no fellowship with the unfruitful works
                                of darkness, but rather reprove them." As I have not the opportunity of bearing a public
                                testimony with my Brethren and Sisters in the hour of worship, yet I testify that I
                                pledge myself to live in conformity to the Christ life, as now manifest in a Shaker
                                life, and to this end I earnestly solicit your prayers. Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bellmire, William W." TEIform="persName"/> Wm. W. Bellmire.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our beloved Elder Abraham has just passed his eighty-fifth birthday..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Our beloved Elder Abraham has just passed his eighty-fifth birthday...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Enfield, October 26, 1892" TEIform="index"/></dateline><p TEIform="p"> [Our beloved Elder Abraham has just passed his eighty-fifth birthday and we find among
                                the many other good things which he has written, this beautiful letter which we deem so
                                valuable that we think it will prove interesting to many others. E. G.] Enfield, N. H.,
                                Oct. 26, 1892. Mt Beloved Daughter:During my late visit among friends at Canterbury, I
                                was favored with a very kind, affectionate note (and I think I may be tolerated in the
                                expression) dutiful letter from my daughter Edith. For such lovely and loving
                                remembrances, you ever have my most grateful feelings. Embraced in your beautiful
                                missive, I was particularly impressed with the following saintly lines : ' 'I wish ever
                                to be one of that number who is able to bear the gospel testimony to my own soul." This
                                ability alone constitutes the saint; and no soul can ever reach a spiritual baptism or
                                the abodes of the just made perfect, short of a discipline ministered from within, and
                                bearing from one's own hand the rod of correction. Jesus said,"No man can come to me,
                                except the Father who hath sent me draw him." The first moving power of the soul is from
                                above. Convictions of sin and whisperings of conscience, reminding us of waywardness and
                                short-comings, are the drawings of the Father. These, unheeded and neglected, shut out
                                his spirit, harden the soul, and produce barrenness, dearth and death. Souls may be
                                wonderfully illuminated with beams of light from heaven, and yet, by giving place to
                                pride and worldliness, will find their houses empty, swept and garnished. They then take
                                upon themselves other spirits more "wicked than the former, that will enter and dwell
                                there. You will expect me to tell you what course in life I have found safe and fruitful
                                in blessing in my experience. As in nature, we could have no existence aside from the
                                co-operation of and descent from natural parents, neither can we in the spirit have an
                                existence, unless spiritually begotten and having spiritual parents to lead, guide and
                                teach us. In submitting to a guiding hand in earthern vessels it demands some sacrifice
                                and the staining of worldly pride. What to-day is urbane and respectful in humanity
                                comes through mortals by force of education. Man is enlightened, civilized and
                                christianized only through human agency, by the inspiration of heaven. Therefore, to
                                assume independence, to stand aloof <pb n="269" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> from that channel which is the
                                order of the All-wise for human progress, to admit no light only what is revealed
                                through our own brain is an obstacle to our happiness and impedes growth in good
                                manners, in morals and in religion. The gates of heaven are open to you. By force of
                                will and works of conscience, keep them open. Listen to the voice within, which tells
                                you, not for once disregard the counsel of your spiritual teachers, or say nay to any
                                gospel requirement, care or burden presented as your lot, for the price of your soul.
                                This, Edith has been my principle and my course for years. From it, has come my
                                salvation, a blessing and treasure so rich, so valuable, that rather than lose it, I
                                would sacrifice my natural life. This with cheerfulness 1 recommend to my daughter, as
                                my living and dying words, presenting herewith my everlasting love and blessing. Yours
                                kindly and affectionately,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>Abraham Perkins.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Written for and read at the funeral of sister Amelia Lyman" TEIform="index"/> Written for
                            and Read at the Funeral of Sister AMELIA LYMAN.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Copley, E. S." TEIform="persName"/> E. S. Copley.</byline><p TEIform="p"> How sudden, and unexpectedly, the Lamp of Life has gone out. We have long known that your
                            earth-life has hung by a slender thread; yet you were always so pleasant and so bright, that
                            we were more than willing to put far away the day when we should see you no more. Ah! how
                            sadly we shall miss you, for we were always welcome in your presence. You favored no select
                            company, for we were all yours to love and assist whenever opportunity offered. During times
                            of trial you always found special reason for more thoughtful kindness. If faults were seen
                            virtues were not lost to sight. Do we think you have left us to return no more? Not by any
                            means. You have loved us too long, have shared our joys and drank of our sorrows too often
                            to withdraw your Spirit influence. Even now I can seemingly hear you say, "I have laid aside
                            the poor earth casket; it will return to its kindred dust. My Spirit is free. I will do all
                            in my power to have you share of my care, my interest, and my affection." Farewell, and this
                            we know, you will, for in our "Father's house are many mansions," and among them we feel
                            assured there is one prepared for you. Yisit us often precious Sister, till we meet with you
                            beyond the vale, and while the earth form is taken from our sight, love pleads from the
                            depths of our souls not to be forgotten by dear friends just gone before. Earth's love may
                            sometimes fail us, but we believe, thank God, in a love heavenborn that knows neither frost
                            nor blight, and trust our merciful Father will grant us a portion. Shaker Station, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Questions of the day" TEIform="index"/> THE QUESTIONS OF THE DAY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/> Catharine Allen.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Among all the important themes now agitating the public mind, which calls loudest for
                            immediate attention ? Each bears a relation to all others, but which is the one in which all
                            others centre ? Hark ! to the responses from leaders of various reforms ; and list to the
                            cries of distress coming up from the haunts of poverty and wretchedness! Not there alone ;
                            open the soul-ear as you pass the gilded mansion;listen to the heart-throbs of anguish
                            coming from victims of self-indulgencethe slaves of fashion and of sin ! <pb n="270" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> Each class suffering from this or that effect of one great system of wrong will plead
                            that reformation must Begin by removing those evils from which they are immediate sufferers.
                            Leading minds have become interested, and have formed centres of action around wThich many
                            individual energies have clustered. Behold the valiant bands ! all pressing for victory ;
                            all marching for one goal:Freedom : and each believing that when the giant sin is slain with
                            which they contend, all the lesser ones will soon disappear. As the source of power, all
                            intelligent minds are looking to the government ; therefore the persistent appeals
                            constantly urged by the champions of Woman's Suffrage, International Peace, Social Purity,
                            Prohibition, and the Labor Movement in its various phases, including Single Tax, Free Trade
                            etc. All these are branches of the glorious ' 'Tree of Life whose leaves shall be for the
                            healing of the nations," and which can only flourish in the soil of liberty, where,
                            unfettered by priestly rule, whether Catholic or Protestant, reason and conscience shall be
                            left free to adapt civil, social and religious institutions to the progressive principle iu
                            human nature. Taking a general outlook of society, we behold gigantic monopolies ;millions
                            piling on millions in the hands of a few.Idleness, luxury, dissipation ! Overwork, poverty,
                            degradation! result of a slavery in the wage system which is the sum of all villainies." In
                            many avocations we see women and girls receiving for the same work, only half the
                            compensation of men and boys, and while ignorant foreigners, and the very scum of society
                            are invited to our ballot, in one state only, is woman recognized as a citizen; no matter
                            how intelligent or virtuous, her voice must yet be silent, and we blush, yea, burn with
                            indignation when we realize the shameful servitude to which man's law subjects her in social
                            relations, where she has no legal claim to her own person, property or children. We see
                            misery entailed on the souls and bodies of millions by these twin vices,liquor and
                            tobacco.Insanity, pauperism and crime on the increase, and heavy taxes wrung from the poor
                            for the support of an army and navy; their use, the distraction of life, property, virtue
                            and happiness ! Strange fruits of more than a century's Republicanism in aland of abundance
                            and age of invention, with the privileges of free speech, and free press and free schools !A
                            grave mistake somewhere; can we discover it? First, who planned the Constitution and its
                            laws? Men. Who have been its executors from first to last, in Senate and in House? Men. They
                            have framed all our laws, have mended and amended them as they have thought proper, and what
                            wonder? for ages back they had exercised sole authority in all offices of Church, quite
                            unmindful of the fact that God had said "Let us create man in our own image." ' 'Male and
                            female created He them ;" and also that every atom of the universe, from mineral ore to
                            burning star includes, and is controlled by, dual forces. Men have conceived, (we might say
                            created) a God in their own image, ex- <pb n="271" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> clusively masculine. Men only
                            have recorded and revised those portions of history which they decided contained the
                            inspired "Word of God. From that "infallible Word" they have formulated creeds and religions
                            (?) factions numbering hundreds. Their concepts of Deity, future rewards and punishments,
                            etc., have been so revolting to both reason and affection, that to maintain them, the blood
                            of opposers has been caused to stream down the isles of churches, and in "holy wars"
                            multitudes have been slain in defence of the teachings of the meek and lowly Prince of
                            Peace! Then, when might had conquered and decided who and what God was, and how his Word was
                            to be interpreted, these opinions were forced upon all who had not the courage to endure the
                            agonies of dungeon, rack and stake. The Church usurped all offices of State. Darkest
                            ignorance prevailed, and gross superstition branded its seal upon the forehead of
                            progression. Such have been the fruits of institutions where only the "incomplete masculine
                            mind" has had control. But the oracles of God have been more deeply graven in the hearts of
                            his children than the laws of men. No human power has been able to crush out the image of
                            the Divine. Slowly the burden of the ages has been lifting. The tyranny and midnight
                            darkness of priestly rule was broken by those powerful forces that brought forth the
                            Reformation, and which, later, found fuller and more emphatic expression in the "Declaration
                            of Independence," separating Church and State, and proclaiming liberty of conscience as the
                            right and privilege of all. Those noble patriots whose hands were moved to write that
                            immortal document, had cast prophetic glances into futurity. They were lifted up to the
                            mount of inspiration, and wrote more wisely than they knew. The people were not then
                            sufficiently progressed to appreciate or accept a pure democracy. Institutions however free
                            and just in themselves, cannot emancipate those who are in thrall to superstition and moral
                            ignorance. Before woman could enjoy the privileges which that declaration of rights granted
                            to her as a human being, the laws of custom and public opinion had to be outgrown, with the
                            effects of that false education that had riveted itself upon her religious nature, teaching
                            her that as the "author of evil" she must make atonement through a life of suffering ;that,
                            possessing no rights in and of herself, she must ever be the subordinate of man, in church,
                            in state, and in social relations ;his toy or drudge ;the victim of his caprice, the slave
                            to his passions ! But thank God the chaff of ecclesiastical authority is being separated
                            from the wheat of divine truth, preparing the way for the manifestation of the maternal
                            Spirit in Deity, which is now brooding over the daughters of earth. The breezes of a new
                            inspiration has swept over their souls, fanning to flame those divine energies which have
                            smouldered through centuries of oppression and wrong. To-day woman is exerting a powerful
                            influence for the redemption of the race. She pleads for justice. Heed her cries, for her
                            cause is man's cause. Every obstacle placed in the path of woman's <pb n="272" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/>
                            progress, impedes man in the same degree. The history of ages past has taught us, that the
                            theology of a people bears the most potent influence in the framing of civil government,
                            therefore we are confident that when that grand central truth becomes more widely taught and
                            appreciatedthat God is Dual, that in Him as an all-wise Father and loving Mother, we have a
                            full parentage, then this very natural and beautiful concept of Deity will find reflex in
                            our government, remolding its laws and customs in harmony therewith. Then shall woman be
                            recognized as the co-equal and necessary helper of man in all the relations of life,
                            beginning with the sacred rights of her own being,extending to the highest offices of Church
                            and of State. Not that woman's sphere shall ever be man's sphere; God has marked as
                            unmistakable distinctions in her mentai, as in her physical structure, but, as Horace Mann
                            expressed it, each having an appointed "hemisphere, together make a sphere;"a completeness.
                            When woman helps to frame the laws by which she is governed, the blackened waters of
                            sensuality and intemperance will give place to the crystal river of purity and peace, which
                            shall roll as a cleansing tide throughout all the avenues of society. Those vital forces
                            which are now being so terribly dissipated, will be conserved, giving energy, self-control
                            and strength of will under the guidance of those higher attributes of being, through which
                            the divine spirit can operate, combining wisdom and love in lawTs of equality that shall
                            confer upon every one an equal inheritance to the natural resources of the country, the
                            advantages of a transportation system free from monopoly, and the means of enjoyment in
                            proportion to the service rendered to society. With such a system, all phases of the labor
                            question will be forever settled, and the conditions of peace made permanent. To prove the
                            validity of the premises here taken, we refer the reader to the social purity, peace,
                            temperance and general prosperity of the Society of Friends or Quakers whose obedience to
                            the ' 'light within" endued them wyith so much wisdom and simple justice that, with them,
                            the equality of the sexes was never questioned. Again to the Shaker order (progressed
                            Quakers,) who are "Believers" that the Christ Spirit which descended upon Jesus,
                            representing through him the Fatherhood of God, as truly baptized Ann Lee, teaching the
                            Divine Motherhood. The fruits of her revelations have been manifest for more than a century
                            in a people who have most emphatically recognized the equality of woman with man, and wiio,
                            though numbering many hundreds, have so far removed the causes of evil from among
                            themselves, that there has never yet been an occasion to call upon a civil magistrate for
                            the adjustment of any difficulties arising writhin their Societies. Thankfully, but not
                            boastfully we are able to show that all the fragmentary reforms of the outside world to-day,
                            find in our home a living centre, where they are embodied as a whole in daily, practical
                            oxperience; therefore in answer to the question <pb n="273" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> which opens this
                            article, we feel confidence in saying that the Woman question is the one which, at the
                            present time comprehends all others, and should be urged and pressed with the concentrated
                            efforts of all reformers. As a people we are rejoicing in liberties unknown to the
                            struggling masses, and though called to be toilers in the inner courts of the great temple
                            of humanity, our souls go forth in sympathy, blessing and love to all workers of
                            righteousness. We view the present as a transition period between old and new institutions.
                            Beyond the storm we see the tokens of a brighter day. Behold the gleaming bow whereon is
                            written this glorious prophecy;"Emancipation for all, of body and of soul!" Mount Lebanon, N.
                            Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Memorial meeting" TEIform="index"/> MEMORIAL MEETING.</head><p TEIform="p"> In honor of J. G. WHITTIER, held by the "Self-Improvement Society'1'' at North Family, Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y., Oct. 12, 1892. The seventeen members composing the guild read selections
                            from the good Poet's writings, and original lines either in verse or prose, which are here
                            presented. "The wrong which pains my soul below, I dare not throne above; I know not of
                            God's hate, I know His goodness and his love." Only so far as our characters are moulded by
                            the same exalted principles, can we appreciate the beauty and grandeur of a life that has so
                            sweetly expressed itself in songs that have touched the hearts of millions, prompting to
                            purer thoughts and nobler deeds. C. A. "No task is ill whose hand and brain And skill and
                            strength have equal gain; And each shall each in honor hold, And simple manhood outweigh
                            gold." Whittier's sense of right and justice, was to him, the greatest gift of God. I. M. L.
                            "Though dim as yet in tint and line, We trace Thy picture's wise design, And thank Thee that
                            our age supplies The dark relief of sacrifice." "Thy will be done!" Not my will but Thine be
                            done thro' me, While willingly I suffer, toil and bear, While oft in lone Gethsemane ascends
                            to Thee, The wafted incense of my soul's deep prayer. M. A. B. "The eternal eye that sees
                            the whole, May better read the darkened soul, And find to outward sense denied The flower
                            upon its inmost side." The soul may be thrilled with the songs that were sung While the
                            pulse of the singer was strong, But the echoes of praise which on earth were begun, Still
                            live in the soul of his song. S. J. B. "The world sits at the feet of Christ, Unknown, blind
                            and unconsoled, And feels the heavenly Alchemist Transform its very dust to gold." When I
                            heard that the world-renowned and soul-inspired Poet had passed from earth, I impulsively
                            exclaimed, "It seems as though a near and dear brother of our faith has left us." Pure and
                            truthful singer, may thy beautiful spirit still inspire, and may others be prompted to pen
                            as sweet and noble thoughts. G-. H. B. "Henceforth my heart shall sigh no more For olden
                            time and holier shore, God's love and blessings then and there Are now, and here, and
                            everywhere." <pb n="274" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> The great human family it seems to me is like a garden
                            of varied and beautiful flowers. In the removal of Whittier, our friend and Poet, one of the
                            choicest and purest has been transplanted to the garden of God. L. S. "No truth from heaven
                            descends upon our sphere, Without the greeting of the skeptic's sneer; Denied and mocked at,
                            'till its blessings fall Common as dew and sunshine over all." His heart was filled with
                            heavenly song And love for truth made good his life, To help the right, to conquer wrong He
                            gave his soul in earnest strife. L. S. B. "Through the harsh noises of our day A low, sweet
                            prelude finds its way, Thro' clouds of doubt and creeds of fear A light is breaking, calm
                            and clear." Eejoice faint heart, the pulsing air is teeming With prophecy of truth's eternal
                            good. The midnight wanes, the morning light is gleaming, And God and man are better
                            understood. A. E. S. "The path of life we walk to-day Is strange as that the Hebrews trod;
                            We meet the shadowy rock as they, We need like them the guides of God." A great and good man
                            has 'been removed from the nation's midst, whose power for good came forth from his interior
                            life, and the tender love and justice of his soul. In the sunset of his life glowed the
                            radiance of the higher spheres, giving promise of a bright morning in his new existence. A.
                            L. "Alone 0 Love ineffable, Thy saving name is given; To turn aside from Thee is hell, To
                            walk with Thee is heaven." May we walk in the humble path of duty into which we are called,
                            with that integrity of purpose and loyalty to principle, that filled the mind and soul of
                            our loved and honored friend. M. L. B. "We older children grope our way From dark behind, to
                            dark before, Dear Lord, in Thee the night is day, And there is darkness nevermore." O thou
                            who lived to comfort, love and bless The human family with thy sympathies, Still let the
                            sunlight of thy cheerfulness ; Shine thro' the branches of life's cypress trees. C. C. V. "O
                            brother man! fold to thy heart thy brother, [there, Where pity dwells the peace of God is To
                            worship rightly is to love each other, Each smile a hymn, each kindly deed a prayer." O
                            soulful poet we can not forget thee, On memory's walls thy picture will remain With
                            evergreen and lilies all entwined, Which symbolize thy life so free from stain. J. M. L.
                            ''No offering of my own I have, Nor works my faith to pr &gt;ve, I can but give the gifts he
                            gave, And plead his love for love." Thy character was moulded by God's will, And noble
                            viitues were outwrought in thee, Thy precious words shall coming ages thrill, Thy life was
                            peace and heavenly purity. B. R. "As Thou hast made Thy world without Make Thou more fair my
                            world within, Shine through the lingering clouds of doubt, Rebuke its haunting shapes of
                            sin, Till brief or long my granted span Of life, with love to Thee and man: Strike where
                            Thou wilt the hour of rest, But let my last days be the best." O poet of nature, of home and
                            heart, To thee has come the "hour of rest;" But evermore thy songs will live And many hearts
                            by them be blest. M. L. <pb n="275" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> "The solemn joy that soul communion Immortal
                            life reveals, [feels, And human love, its prophecy and sign Interprets love divine." Thy
                            heart hath throbbed with other hearts When thrilled with hope, with joy or grief, And in
                            sweet symphonies of thought Thy sympathies have found relief. S. B. ' 'Who brooding keeps a
                            wrong in thought Sins much, but greater sin is his, Who, fed and clothed with kindnesses
                            Shall count the holy aims as naught." Forever round thy name so blest The flame of love
                            shall burn, And many from thy melodies Life's sweetest lessons learn. M. R. Two of
                            Whittier's latest poems were read, after which came the closing eulogy. A circular stand in
                            the center of the room held a large vase of flowers (the last bloom of the season,)
                            encircling it was a wreath twined with myrtle and purple asters. Nature symbolizes truth ;
                            her varied forms and colors are a reflection or expression of spiritual things. Humility,
                            constancy and the royalty of the divine man represented in the character of the sweet-souled
                            poet, whose hallowed memory the world honors and reveres, (and to whom loving tribute has
                            been paid on this occasion) are typified in the mystic language of this simple wreath of
                            Myrtle, one of Mother Earth's clinging children. Despite unfavorable circumstances, it grows
                            and spreads and puts forth its delicate purple blossoms, and fills out the unostentatious
                            beauty of that inherent life that is God given. A choice emblem of self-expression from the
                            esoteric side of existence. We twined this chaplet with willing hands and loving impulse and
                            would on this, the occasion of grateful remembrance lay it reverently at the shrine of
                            unsullied genius, while we ask that his highest thought may yet inspire, and flow through
                            channels worthy to receive it. M. J. A.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christmas greeting" TEIform="index"/> CHRISTMAS GREETING.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Goepper, Anna B." TEIform="persName"/> Anna B. Goepper.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "Unto us a child is born, unto us a Son is given, and his name shall be calledThe Prince of
                            Peace." Thrice hail Merry Christmas ! Another year is before us. Grant that I may begin this
                            New Year with new resolutions, and if through infidelity or negligence I forget these good
                            purposes, may my guardian angel awaken in me a sense of my danger. I thank Thee, Father, for
                            the gift of life though life at most bringeth less mirth than sorrow, less rest than labor.
                            Dear Lord, I strike the chord of praise and thanks for all thy fair works ! To me it is joy
                            to listen from trembling throats the silvery notes of the little birds and to see the
                            sunshine on the green earth. I thank Thee, Lord, for joys that have been mine, sunbeams that
                            have pierced through clouds, flinging a mellow radiance over my path ; sweet fragrant
                            flowers twining around my cross, making the burden less wearisome. I thank Thee for my
                            sorrows, tooshadows that over my life have fallen and for the heart wounds. I might grow
                            weary of a waveless sea, yet Lord I would be comforted, with tears unshed my eyes are dim,
                            voices that now are silent, in other days were wont to join <pb n="276" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> me in the
                            family prayer. Of the promise of the rest that is to be and for the hope of death I am
                            thankful. When my tired feet falter it singe th in my soul like a fragrant breath coming
                            from cool shady groves. Teach me to question not, but thankful be while my life's years come
                            and go, for life and death, for joy and sorrow. "O bells! sweet bells of Christmas! King out
                            your gladsome mirth! King peace to sad hearts burdened Ring joy to all the earth!" Union
                            Village, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obedience" TEIform="index"/> OBEDIENCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fredrick, Henry W." TEIform="persName"/> Henry W. Fredrick.</byline><p TEIform="p">If you observe a young friend, or even a companion who strives to be obedient to his
                            instructors and endeavors to please them,mark well that individual. Observe the love and
                            good-will that are sure to flow toward him. As years carry him forward you will see in his
                            course, much, very much that is calculated to make that person respected and happy. You will
                            find no difficulty in determining what occasions the numerous troubles of the wilfull and
                            disobedient. Observe closely these two causes and their effects, and you will never need a
                            teacher to portray to you the satisfaction, comfort and good standing in society, which
                            obedience to good government brings, or the trouble and dissatisfaction that invariably
                            follows disobedience. As you grow older you can easily look, from the rules of men, up to
                            the higher laws of God, and comprehend that if these smaller acts of insubordination, so
                            seriously effect the young, greater acts of inattention and defiance to the laws of God will
                            render those who are older, quite miserable, as they become hardened in their wicked course.
                            Watervliet, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our heavenly mother" TEIform="index"/> OUR HEAVENLY MOTHER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/> Hamilton DeGraw.</byline><p TEIform="p"> All hail, bright diadem in the Infinite crown, so long buried in the materiality that has
                            enwrapped the human soul in an almost impenetrable darkness, preventing it from realizing
                            that without Thee, life would be a blank and fade into nothingness, in both the natural and
                            spiritual world. The most sublime and important truths of our being are easily understood
                            and clothed in simple forms, and for this reason are passed by unheeded by the undeveloped,
                            earthly mind, that is looking for a marvelous manifestation of truth, when all around us
                            innumerable signs are manifest that the maternal principle is the most active and important
                            in the unfolding of life, in shaping its destiny, and developing the resources of both soul
                            and body. As the natural wor^d is but the reflex of the spiritual, and in one we see the
                            fact demonstrated that both the male and female element is necessary for life's development;
                            to be so ' 'born of the Spirit," as to enable the soul to become an heir of eternal life and
                            find an inheritance in the kingdom of heaven, it must have a Mother in its helpless days
                            until it has arrived to the full stature of a son or daughter of God. Father William Lee, in
                            speaking of <pb n="277" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> the "new birth" and in alluding to his spiritual mother,
                            exclaimed; "How could I have been born without a Mother." This sentiment, voices the inmost
                            feelings of every heaven-bound traveler who is seeking the higher illumination, "how can I
                            be born without a Mother." Quickened by the inflowing tide of spiritual power that the new
                            dispensation is bringing to mankind, the maternal spirit is asserting its right to dictate
                            in regard to life's development. That theological monster, a triune masculine God so long
                            enthroned in the intellect, has tended to darken the spiritual perceptions. Through the
                            spiritually undeveloped self-asserting force of the masculine mind, the true order and
                            position of the maternal principle has been held in abeyance, subject to the stronger
                            physical forces of man. All governments founded upon the one-sided theory of the
                            intellectual superiority of man are destined to be overthrown. Our boasted civilization of
                            the nineteenth century is being weighed in the balance and is found wanting in the true
                            elements that constitute an enlightened race. Like ancient civilizations of Egypt, Greece
                            and Rome, it is destined to dissolution unless the principles of eternal progress are
                            complied with. The hand writing on the wall has already appeared and the Belshazzars at
                            their feasts are asking in tremulous tones, "what meaneth all this commotion?" Our
                            civilization of armies and navies, of master and slave, of riches and poverty will be broken
                            and scattered by the powerful strokes of the iconoclast. In this work of the demolition of
                            the old order, woman is taking an active and leading part. The heavenly Bridegroom and Bride
                            have appeared, standing upon the Mount of Divine Love and unity, revealing to the world the
                            true order of life ; and the counsel of peace is between them. The reasoning faculties of
                            man and the intuitional in woman rightly balanced and harmoniously adjusted in the coming
                            cycle of the unfoldment of the race will be the great propelling power that will finally
                            evolve from the discord of the present conditions and possibilities of life as far
                            transcending what they now are, as the brightness of the noonday sun surpasses the twilight
                            of morning. We greet thee Divine Mother, who, with a heart full of love and compassion for
                            thy erring children, turning none away and seeking by the power of thy love to draw them,
                            where they can dwell in the fulness of thy presence and partake of the blessings of thy
                            bountiful store. Sonyea, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mount Lebanon" TEIform="index"/> MOUNT LEBANON.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/> Lucy S. Bowers.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Blest Holy Mount ! thy summits grandly rise Amid the circlings of the clear pure air; No
                            warmer sunlight gilds God's earth so fair Than bathes thy slopes in daily glad surprise.
                            Fruit, that no Tropic gift in worth outvies Richly the pendant branches freely bear Which
                            all thy habitants in fulness share, In Christian harmony that never dies. Down come the
                            rains upon thy harvest fields, Oft build the singing birds among the leaves, Peace, gentle
                            peace its holy sweetness yields, And love amid it all its glory weaves. The gratitude and
                            happiness each spirit feels Are praise, for this their home, which God receives. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p><pb n="278" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> THE MANIFESTO. DECEMBER, 1893. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by tlie
                            "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All
                            communications should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. One
                            copy per year, postage paid, .75 " " six months, " " .40 Send for sample copy, free. Entered
                            at the Post Office at East Canterbury, N. H., as second-class matter.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial.</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christianity has found, and no doubt to its great sorrow..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Christianity has found, and no doubt to its great sorrow...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Christianity has found, and no doubt to its great sorrow, that rnany of its worst
                                enemies were among those who made the strongest profession of allegiance. As unfortunate
                                as this may seem, the history of the church tells the story so plainly that we cannot
                                hesitate in its acceptance. In the eagerness to promote that part which becomes most
                                congenial to the mind, more or less systems were devised and creeds established which
                                have embodied the mystical theology or talks about God, instead of accepting the
                                religious element and striving to make the life of man one of practical righteousness.
                                The study of Christianity through its theology, has sadly bewildered the minds of men
                                and has forced upon them more plagues than ever were heard of among the Egyptians. God
                                has been presented to man in every type of character that he has been known in the human
                                race. The narrow-minded, vindictive and selfish teachers have represented a great
                                personal God so much like themselves, in all things, that the "Creator who is blessed
                                forever," has been hid from sight by the presence of the Creature. That there should be
                                among men, varied opinions upon these subjects, and an earnest manifestation of this
                                feeling spread before the world, is not in the least, a source of surprise. It is only
                                by the out-pushing of the mind and the entering into that state which permits one ' 'to
                                grow in favor with both God and man," that better and clearer gifts of the Spirit can be
                                accepted and appropriated for the advancing and developing of the life of mankind. Men
                                to live aright must think, and the thinking must culminate in action. Rays of light from
                                the spirit of God must make them living, thinking, active beings, who are placed on this
                                earth with a mission of "good news and glad tidings." In this they recognize the hand of
                                God and become of one faith to wTork out the gift of salvation that is to <pb n="279" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> overshadow the race. No union should be lost on account of the presence
                                of some non-essentials. That an article as the stove may be black to one person, and the
                                same article is said to be white, by another person, is not a case of heresy, nor an
                                error of the heart, but simply a defect in a very small phrenological faculty. The
                                variations of opinion which occurred in the minds of the apostles while in Galatia,
                                creates no thought of wonder in our mind. It was the out-flowing of conditions that had
                                been generated in those earnest workers. It was the active manifestation of the position
                                which they occupied at the time, as may be instanced in the meeting of Peter and Paul.
                                Unfortunately, however, this was the triumph of modern Christianity, if triumph it may
                                be called, of wrong over right, and aided essentially, in extinguishing the beautiful
                                light of the gospel of peace, that was through the life of Jesus, placed before the
                                world. It was timidity in the one who desired the peace of the church above all things.
                                "Blessed are the peacemakers," was the life of his soul, wThile the other apostle so
                                determined on evangelizing the Gentiles, forced his language beyond the bounds of
                                propriety, and ultimately gained his point. No one will presume to say that the apostles
                                were bad men. They saw Christianity through differently colored glasses and each
                                contended that he was right. "Agree to disagree, but keep your union," is the Shaker
                                rule, and this no doubt, wTas the course adopted by Peter and Paul. They were earnest in
                                their mission for the church of Christ, as they had accepted that mission. It was their
                                only hope of salvation for a lost world. At an earlier date the divine Teacher, in his
                                overflowing kindness for poor humanity had made this charitable remark:"All men cannot
                                receive this saying," they are not prepared; they do not comprehend its import. To deny
                                themselves and take up the cross of Christ was a lesson they had not learned. Paul
                                accepted the fellowship of the Church, in a way of his own, and quite different from the
                                twelve disciples. He could however, say of himself, "I was not a whit behind the
                                chiefest apostles." To him the salvation of the lost sheep of the house of Israel was a
                                secondary matter. He had arranged for a great spiritual work and would save all men.
                                Large plans were projected and much skill displayed in the general management. Of Jesus
                                it had been said, "He shall save his people from their sins ;" but Paul would save them
                                from their sins, if consistent, but if not he would save them in their sins, and this
                                descending from the cross was the opening of a dark day for Christianity, as it was soon
                                called to cover the <pb n="280" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> world, the flesh and the devil, with its
                                ecclesiastical cloak, as may be seen in the world to-day. Good and earnest men, who are
                                contending for more light in their pathway toward God, are all around us, with their
                                specialities of good gifts. God bless their efforts to make the world better. And should
                                we go out after the "Lo, here, and Lo, there," contrary to the admonition of our divine
                                Teacher, would it not be well to bear in mind the foundation upon which we should stand.
                                "Hold fast that which thou hast gained, let no man take thy crown."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> We have received from the pen of Elder Frederick W. Evans, a beautiful article in memory of
                            Elder Daniel Boler. As it reached us too late for this number it will appear in the
                            Manifesto for January, 1893, as wall several other articles bearing upon the same subject. A
                            number of pieces must be carefully laid away for the present, as our December paper is
                            already full of good things.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="''Our Confederation''--whatever that may mean..." TEIform="index"/>
                            ''Our Confederation''--whatever that may mean...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> '' Our Confederation"whatever that may mean,as hinted at in the "Flaming Sword," may need to
                            be analyzed if such a thing exists. I wonder if those who have eyes to see on one side, can
                            see equally as well on the other, and then note if this does not sound like "an indulgence
                            in a little, subtle sarcasm ?"</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If any of the celibate bodies of the present..." TEIform="index"/>
                            If any of the celibate bodies of the present...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> ''If any of the celibate bodies of the present, imagine, and some of them seem to, that
                            their condition, which is only a stepping stone, * * * to the glorious state of the sons of
                            God, * * * is the ideal one, they are doomed like the apostate churches to be greatly
                            disappointed in the near future."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/> NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/> Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Average of Weather at Mount Lebanon. October. Thermometer. Rain. 1891. 41.41 2.22 in.
                                1892. 47.65 1.25 in. Highest Temp, during this mo. 68. Lowest " " " " 30. Number of
                                rainy days " " 1 C. G. E. 3NTortli Family. Nov. 1892. "What solemn feelings rise . And
                                flow through every sense; Who can behold without surprise The passing great events." We
                                certainly are living in very extraordinary times, and a mighty revolution is upon us.
                                The conditions are upon us that will try men's souls and women's too. Every thing,
                                external and internal, is calling for energy, and the consecration of our best talents.
                                No time to waste in idle dreaming or vain speculation. The revelation of truth, and a
                                practical application of it to every-day life is the only thing that will save from sin
                                and bring the kingdom of righteousness in the earth. They that do right are righteous:
                                those who compromise with the right for expedience, or worldly advantage, are heaping up
                                fuel that will burn only to their discomfort. Let us be careful, watchful, and
                                prayerful. The year is drawing to a close. I wish all my gospel friends a healthy,
                                temperate thanksgiving, a truly pentecostal <pb n="281" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> Christmas and a New
                                Tear filled with the glory of God's summer that has passed and the harvest that has
                                ended. We have many things to be thankful for, a few to regret, which in the coming year
                                we hope to improve; and some bright hopes that fill our souls with courage and
                                determination to work more faithfully in the vineyard of the Lord, and bring about that
                                good thing which will make this earth a paradise, and thus fulfill the prayer of the
                                Savior. We have our Separator set up, and in fine working order. We obtained a fourteen
                                inch Motor of our Koreshan friends, set it up temporarily to prove it on the Separator,
                                and found we had more than double the power we needed. Having a twenty-two inch Backus
                                Motor to drive our sewing machines, and it not giving us quite as much power as we
                                wanted, we took it out and set up the Teed Motor, and found to our surprise that the
                                fourteen inch Teed Motor gave us more power than the twenty-two inch Backus, with the
                                same size stream of water, and the same pressure. The size jet used in both wheels is
                                three eighths of an inch under about sixty pounds pressure. D. O.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, New York" TEIform="index"/> Watervliet, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Second ITamily. Nov. 1892. It is now Nov. 10, and the beautiful fall weather that has
                                been so universal throughout the country has been ours to enjoy up to present date.
                                To-day instead of green grass that was just beginning to assume a sombre hue, a mantle
                                of snow is seen and we realize that the first snow of the season in this section has
                                fallen. But as our crops are secured, and we have a goodly store, we are not wholly
                                unprepared for the cold weather should it abide with us. Our gospel kindred from
                                Groveland, are moving to this Society as fast as consistent. A company of six Sisters
                                and two Brethren arrived here on the 31st. ult. and were warmly welcomed by our good
                                Ministry and the Brethren and Sisters. Elder Joseph in our first gathering with them
                                welcomed them to our home, now their home. Eldress Harriet said that Believers should be
                                one, no north, south, east or west, but all should be as one great family of Christ and
                                Mother. Eldress Augusta also made them welcome in her mild and pleasant manner, and with
                                these remarks, the Elders, Brethren and Sisters were united. May they be welcomed in the
                                full sense of the word, for we feel that we have added to our numbers, spiritual
                                strength, and may we grow and increase in all that tends to eradicate selfishness, and
                                bind us together as the "heart of one." Health of Society good. Br. Chauncy Miller is
                                still improving in health for which we are thankful, as he has been and still is a
                                bright star in our temporal and spiritual firmament. t</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/> "West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> Nov. 5, 1892. Foe three days it has drizzled, with a smart'shower at long intervals to
                                vary the monotony. Once the sun really peeped out, but was evidently disheartened by the
                                general dreariness of the aspect, as it soon disappeared, swallowed up in a big, black
                                cloud. We made some philosophical reflections on the fleeting nature of all earthly
                                things. As we picked our way along the muddy street, swaying umbrella in hand, we were
                                grateful that the sunshine of our lives was not wholly dependent upon atmospheric
                                conditions. Nay, we have within ourselves every element necessary for a firstclass
                                "Sunshine Factory," and we may keep a supply in reserve, to use when the elements
                                without are not propitious. The rain may be very much needed to replenish the springs,
                                as water, in most streams and lakes in our vicinity is quite low. It is said that the
                                water in Pontoosuc Lake was never so low. This lake is about two miles north of
                                Pittsfield. Its banks are shaded by pine trees, and throughout the summer a steamer and
                                many row-boats are in constant requisition, as it is the pleasure seekers favorite
                                resort. We had excellent weather in which to <pb n="282" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> gather the crops.
                                Apples prove to be more abundant than was expected at first; potatoes also are very good
                                in quantity and quality. We were somewhat alarmed about ten days ago at seeing flames
                                rising in the woods north of us. All who were able hastened to assist in putting out the
                                fire, but in spite of vigorous efforts, it continued to burn for several days until
                                quenched by the rain. Br. Ira says it burned a section of nearly fifty acres, but thinks
                                no great damage was done, as it did not burn so deeply as to injure the growth of the
                                trees. A fresh coat of paint on some of the buildings at Second Family makes them
                                brighter and more home-like. The discovery of this great and beautiful land was honored
                                by our scholars with appropriate exercises. Our neighboring city, Pittsfield, carried to
                                a successful close quite an interesting programme. About thirty business men had floats
                                in the Grand Parade of the day to exhibit their varied kinds of goods. At the
                                solicitation of the Committee of Arrangements Br. Ira permitted his millers to turn out
                                our mill team and take part with the others. By placing boards across the top of the
                                carriage, a platform was made on which to set a huge mill-stone, the "sign of the honest
                                miller." Barrels of flour and bags of corn were open to show their contents, while
                                polished scales and shovels, added to the beauty of the float. Bunting and flags were
                                profusely used in the decorations. The carriage was drawn by six large horses, and
                                presented a very fine appearance. Others evidently agreed with us, as it was assigned a
                                place at the head of the long line of floats. E. B.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ayer, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/> Ayer, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> Nov. 1892. Grand, indeed, would be this world if all would live to tlieir opportunities
                                of usefulness. Happiness would be more universal and misery would have a smaller space
                                in the lives of men. The old maxim, "The more good you do, the more good you'll be,"
                                lias much truth, if not poetry. We find every time we attempt to carry grace and
                                sweetness into the lives of others, we have imparted to our own lives a brightness and
                                buoyancy that will increase with every such act, and be to us a continued growth of
                                goodness. Our opportunities for doing good, are far more plenty than for which we give
                                credit. We have always among us, the aged, whose long life of usefulness begins to tell
                                upon them physically. Their infirm condition calls for many little acts of kindness; let
                                us assist them all we can. Every kindness done to others is one step nearer the life of
                                Christ. How good I feel enthusiastically exclaimed a little boy, who had helped a
                                class-mate over a rough obstacle,"I wonder why it raises one up so to help any one who
                                needs help." And others, older in years and experience have wondered. "What I give, I
                                take with me when I cross the dark river." This is a great truth. Our good Eldress Ellen
                                Green, has been very ill for some weeks past. Our little school observed Columbus' day,
                                and the children did honor to themselves and teacher. A. D. B.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canaan, New York" TEIform="index"/> Canaan, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Nov. 6, 1892. The first snow-storm for the season occurred on the 5th., accompanied by
                                high winds; one would think that the winter king had come to stay; but one bright day
                                dissipated the spotless robe that was cast over hill and dale. We have been blest with a
                                bountiful harvest and realized fully the fruition of the promise that they who toil
                                unselfishly in the vineyard, shall be blest in their basket and store. Of garden
                                vegetables we have had a liberal supply. The early Euby tomato is a fine assortment for
                                ripening early; we had five other sorts all of which yielded sufficiently to sell, a
                                great many being in constant demand; small fruits rather scarce; more apples than we
                                anticipated, our crop of potatoes fell somewhat below the mark of our expectation, but
                                will have enough for home consumption. <pb n="283" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> Our Society meetings have
                                closed for the season and we shall realize more the quiet of undisturbed seclusion for a
                                few months, with but an occasional call to and from our dear friends at the North
                                Family. We are three miles from our gospel relation, and this necessitates a little
                                extra exertion on our part to keep in harmony with the leading ministration; we desire
                                to accomplish the race and keep pace with the progress of the glorious work of
                                redemption, believing that where two or three are met in the name of Christ there, he
                                will be in the midst. That the avenues of our spiritual perceptions may be opened and
                                the baptisms of divine power and glory may infill our being and lead us to the knowledge
                                of wisdom and truth to which there is no end, is our earnest prayer. A. B.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p"> Nov. 1892. The delightful weather of the past month has proved favorable for the
                                securing of crops and making preparations for the coming of winter. Some repairs are
                                being made on barns and other out buildings. The year which is drawing to a close has
                                been crowned with blessing in every way. Health has been the fullest and best. At all
                                times would we appreciate the innumerable blessings bestowed upon us, and the love which
                                passeth understanding and would ever trust in those promises which never fail. M. W.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/> Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p"> Nov. 6, 1892. We have just finished gathering in the harvest. Of winter apples we had an
                                abundant supply. Christmas week the apple dealers are to take many bbls. away to the
                                market. We receive $1.85 per. bbl. Plenty are left for family use until apples grow
                                again and many bushels have been dried. To-morrow commences the cider making; from about
                                1,000 bushels of the smaller ones. The cider will be condensed five bbls. into one, and
                                stored away for Shaker Apple Sauce of which we hope to have many orders from our
                                customers during the winter. Our good friend Barker Holt and companion, of New
                                Gloucester, came to visit us one day. They have always been very friendly to Believers.
                                The children went to the Office to sing to them, and they in return instructed them very
                                wisely. Friend Holt made a special prayer, asking God to bless and prosper the little
                                ones and their teachers and indeed, all who were so kind as to take the children in and
                                give them such a good home and loving care. The winter term of school commences the
                                coming week. The house is all prepared, decorated with evergreens and fir boughs.
                                Mottoes of autumn leaves and bright colored tissue paper are on the walls. Contrasting
                                with the green it makes the room attractive. With all this to encourage us we hope to
                                have a pleasant and successful term. These "Notes" are the last for 1892, and now we
                                will bid you farewell until we greet you in the New Year. A. S. C.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/> Union Village, Ohio.</head><p TEIform="p"> Nov. 1892. "Time flees away as a morning dream, With all its burden and sorrow; And
                                faith illumes with a ioyous gleam The beautiful eye of to-morrow." This is the language
                                of optimism. It is so much better than forever hanging out blue lights. We have not had
                                an inch of rain since the middle of July. But what of that? November will doubtless give
                                us plenty. If we would only go to the trouble of rebuilding the wasteway of our milldam
                                we might have about thirty-six acres of water 10 to 25 feet deep. And all this for $500.
                                We are made glad in 1800 bu. of beets for the cows, for our winter supply and Elder
                                Joseph has just completed a grand root-cellar capable of holding not less than 4 or
                                5,000 bu. It is an annex to the barn. We are once more in our old new Office. It is
                                perfect, nothing could be added to its beauty, comfort or convenience. Our dwelling or
                                center house has <pb n="284" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> undergone much repairing and modernizing this
                                summer. But O the cement and sawed-stone walks all around the Office and dwellings. We
                                shall not attempt to describe the glory of these walks. Our corn wTill be a tolerably
                                fair crop. Potatoes may possibly last through the winter. Wheat rather poor, but we
                                shall have plenty and perhaps some for the market. Our English Sparrows mean well but
                                they eat the blue-grass-seed about as fast as we sow it. But "Don't kill the Birds;"
                                they are so cheerful and chipper in the dreary days of winter. We are sowing this
                                bluegrass seed on our newly leveled door-yard. I generally read the Manifesto with
                                eagerness as soon as it arrives. But one thing I regret very much: that is, the
                                substitution of Initials instead of full names under the articles,Poems, Home Notes,
                                etc. Western people would be glad to have the full name of each writer. There is a
                                disappointment when we read to the end of a sweet poem, a pure, spiritual essay, a racy
                                Home Note, and find no name we can decipher nor any reference to the worthy author that
                                we can understand. Well, this is enough, may be too much. We are all quite well and most
                                heartily bid the Manifesto and all its promoters a God speed now and forever. We lately
                                were uncommonly blest with a visit from our most worthy Sisters, Eldress Elizabeth
                                Sears, and Sister Cornelia French of Mount Lebanon, our dear Mother Church. Our meeting on
                                the Sabbath was a feast of good and refreshing inspirations from the store-house of
                                their long travel and experience gathered from the bright fields of the higher life. We
                                sincerely hope they will not stay away so long again; but if they must, that they will
                                send some equally entertaining substitutes. Best love and good wishes to all. O. C.
                            H.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p"> Nov. 14, 1892. We think the suggestion made by the good Brother, that we endeavor to
                                make restitution and correct all mistakes before the closing of the year, with a view to
                                making surer progress in the future, wrorthy our acceptance; since we claim to be the
                                followers of Christ, living in unity as brothers and sisters of one household. Some
                                weeks since we were privileged to have with us, beloved Elder Henry C. Blinn from
                                Canterbury, N. H. He came full of hope and courage; his ministrations the same as in
                                former days, exhorting us to look carefully to the interests of our home; earnest to
                                keep unbroken the Covenant we claim as the foundation upon which our Church is
                                established: holding steadfastly to the principles our Parents taught. On the 12th.
                                inst., the Angel Reaper came, taking to his spirit home, our venerable Elder Timothy
                                Randlett of Second Family; a sheaf fully ripened for the harvest; well we know his
                                reward will be abundant blessings for consecrated service. Two of our Sisters, Caroline
                                Whitcher and L. Curtis have just returned from Boston. During their absence they must
                                have exprerienced all the weathers accredited to our New England climate; but happily
                                for them neither tempest of wind nor rain harmed them, so we have only thanks to render
                                to the giver of all good for their preservation. We send kindly thoughts to all our
                                kindred far and near, wishing that health, prosperity and peace be the light and joy of
                                every home. ' J. R. INor-feh. ITamily. Nov. 1892. The forming of "Home Notes," for
                                Thanksgiving month floods our minds with vivid scenes of the past as well as present
                                blessings. This prompts us to carol peans of grateful praise to the dispenser of all
                                good gifts for guidance along life's pathway which through graciousness of the Infinite
                                Spirit has been illumed with soulsaving light. May this continue, insomuch that no one
                                who would accept the yoke of Christ shall seek in vain for redeeming wisdom or find us
                                poor in soulwealth. We well know that active veneration <pb n="285" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> develops
                                and sanctifies intellect, the true indicator being broadness of mind and goodness of
                                soul. As constant devotion in spiritual and manual labor garnishes the soul with
                                Christ-like traits, so does constant respect one toward another, prove to be the golden
                                clasp that links soul to soul in true Christianity. No lengthy chronicles can we give of
                                manual duties, harvesting days being over and farming implements housed for the winter.
                                Our Dock root yielded us 5,300 lbs., and of excellent quality. On Nov. 2nd, we had the
                                first snow-fall of the season, a foretelling messenger of what is to be. We can but hope
                                that the wintry winds will not waft to our shores our former unwelcome visitor "La
                                grippe" unless he has changed his name and character. In closing, we breathe a fervent
                                prayer that our gospel kindred East and West may have a gladsome, prosperous winter
                                season, not forgetting those not of us in faith and life works, for we would "Scatter
                                seeds of kindness, In another's path to bloom, And fill the hours with gladness, While
                                we wait the harvest home." G. H. B.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/> East Canterbury, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p"> Weather Record, for October, 1892. Highest Temp, during the mo. 68. Lowest " " " " 28.
                                Mean " " " " 44.5 Mean Maximum and Minimum, 45.8 Total precipitation 1.31 in. Number of
                                days in which .01 in. or more fell, 8. N. A. Bkiggs. Nov. 1892. The last month of autumn
                                was hardly ushered in before we were visited by a slight snow-storm which fell on the
                                morning of the 2nd. inst. This was followed on the 5th. inst. by a storm of snow and
                                wind, giving one the impression that it was the first of December, rather than the first
                                of November that was upon us; the windows of the dwellings having quite the appearance
                                of a winter morning. We finished the cutting of apples the 3rd. of present month leaving
                                us once more free to hold our regular evening meetings for religious, social, and mental
                                improvement. We think the social, no less than the religious life of a people should be
                                well known to prevent misconception in the mind of any person. For this reason we value
                                the department of "Home Notes" in our little monthly, keeping us informed, as it does,
                                of the events occurring in our many homes. The wise saying of Mother Ann, "Do all your
                                work as though you had a thousand years to live and as though you knew you were to die
                                to-morrow," is an excellent guide in every undertaking and one which all may safely
                                follow. On the 12th. inst. Elder Henry C Blinn, Elder Nicholas A. Briggs, Eldress Joanna
                                J. Kaime and Eldress Eliza A. Stratton left this place for Mount Lebanon to attend the
                                funeral of our beloved father, Elder Daniel Boler. They returned the 17th. inst. and
                                reported the largest gathering of Believers ever assembled at Mount Lebanon.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Modesty" TEIform="index"/> MODESTY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lane, Mabel E." TEIform="persName"/> Mabel E. Lane.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "I saw an angel in the moenlight shade, A wreath of lilies on her brow was laid, Upon her
                            breast a pearl of snow-white hue, Within her hand a bunch of violets blue. I cried in
                            rapture, "who, o# who is she," A passing zephyr whispered,Modesty." The beautiful picture
                            this stanza, brings before my mind shows me the loveliness, the purity of this noble virtue
                            ; modesty is not only appropriate in childhood, but it is the ornament of every period in
                            life, and I desire that the folds of its mantle may ever fall around me, and its sweet
                            substance develop in my spirit. <pb n="286" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> Far more than personal beauty or the
                            riches and treasures of the world, do I choose the modest mien, the quiet demeanor of a
                            purely cultured and refined character. There are those who may have all that would please in
                            a sensuous way, who, if they are talented and accomplished and situated in the midst of
                            luxury may appear attractive and please for the time, but ah! what a blighted hope, wiiose
                            misfortune it is to be bereft of this humble goodness which far outweighs the merit of
                            greatness or glitter. Surely a youth who possesses the gentle and reverent heart, clothed in
                            a "garment of meekness which is woven of pure thoughts and chaste desires," is greatly
                            preferred. It seems that where modesty abides in the heart there is no space for the baser
                            elements of pride and contempt, that even when we receive injuries we are not offended, or,
                            if revenge is exhibited, the Christian does not retaliate ; indeed, it may be compared to
                            some of the sweetest flow'ers, which when trampled upon yield sweet fragrance. This brings
                            to mind an incident I read concerning Plato, the eminent Grecian philosopher. He was a man
                            remarfable for learning and virtue ; for his refined and modest manner and the innocency of
                            his life. He one day invited, Diogenes, the Cynic, and some Sicilians, his friends, to
                            supper, and caused the banquet room to be adorned in respect to his guests. Diogenes,
                            displeased with the finery of Plato, began to trample upon the carpets and other goods, and
                            said very brutishly, "I trample upon the pride of Plato." But Plato replied, wisely as well
                            as meekly, ' 'True, Diogenes, but thou tramplest upon it through greater pride." How we
                            admire the humble and wise who strive to keep their virtues in disguise, they are like the
                            beautiful blossoms which send forth their rich perfume long before their beauty is seen. He
                            who is ever boasting of his merits, praising his own works and glorifying his own name, does
                            not recommend himself to others and fails to receive that recognition for which he strives.
                            So may I mold my character. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Poet Whittier" TEIform="index"/> THE POET WHITTIER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="De Vere, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/> Cecelia De Vere.</byline><p TEIform="p"> He was the wonder of his peers If peers in aught but age they were; Those friends who
                            watched his rolling years As desert travelers watch a star. They on the dusty, heated plain
                            Or 'neaththe palm trees cooling shade Spoke of his hearts ennobling strain, His words of
                            light that could not fade; And marveled that when war was red, His pen undaunted by its
                            breath Crept through the lines, till slavery dread Was reached, unveiled and pierced to
                            death. They knew he had a poet's eyes To penetrate each opaque cloud, And see the hidden
                            prospects rise That mists of coming day enshroud. A royal gift, a sage's mind, Whose realms
                            of thought, O who could trace, It held the truths that angels find, He set them forth with
                            hallowed grace. A poet's spirit more than these They recognized with joy and pride, And felt
                            that nature's sacred keys In love to him she did confide. And yet they said his austere
                            school Had wrought for him its meed of harm, <pb n="287" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> Nor deemed that gentle
                            Quaker rule Gave to his life that nameless charm. They had the world's unbounded scope, Its
                            hights, its depths, its utmost rim, Uuhampered fancy, flashing hope, But not the substance
                            found by him, The fear which is the love of God, The bond which is the Golden Eule, The Holy
                            Spirit deep and broad, Form not for souls an austere school. Beligion never was a creed, It
                            is from heaven, a deathless flame, A quickening pulse, a living seed, In every age and clime
                            the same. We, sheltered in our Zion home, Guess dimly at the bitter strife, Where raging
                            billows lashed to foam Mark progress to a better life. We bless the workers of the world Who
                            toil amid the breakers roar, With bright "Excelsior" unfurled And compass pointing to the
                            shore. To him who in the darkened hour Still raised the lily as a sign, That right and
                            purity had power Which must be pledged in heavenly wine. Our Whittier, may we make the
                            claim, When he his world-wide feelings gave To hold man's brotherhood the same From reigning
                            potentate to slave. Unselfish, universal good From us, from him, uncramped must flow, Till
                            nations in one sisterhood Shall kinship and its blessing know. Oft when the beacon fires we
                            feed, Or lamps of faith revive and fill, We feel the earth's'great pressing need And God's
                            great loving, saving will. Above is Revelation's star, That heralds the advancing sun,
                            Beneath whose glory near and far That saving will shall yet be done. And as we climb the
                            path of right Our spirit's journey not alone, Nor doubt we that the mountain's height Is
                            God's Eternal Throne. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Henry E. Baggs of Sheffield defines money as an article..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Henry E. Baggs of Sheffield defines money as an article...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Henry E. Baggs of Sheffield defines money as an article which may be used as a universal
                            passport to every where except heaven, and as a universal provider for every thing except
                            happiness.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Two views of life, or the living and dying" TEIform="index"/> TWO VIEWS OF LIFE, or the
                            LIVING and DYING.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> [Contributed, by Genevieve DeGraw.J Two men stood upon the bank of a river. On
                                    the head of one of them the hoary frost of years had gathered. The other exulted in
                                    the vigor of early manhood. The older was in the act of disrobing, preparatory to
                                    entering a small canoe, that was to bear him across a wide expanse of waters, to a
                                    shore but dimly seen in the distance. He paused for a moment, and turned to his
                                    companion; "Farewell!" said he, as he affectionately pressed the hand of the other.
                                    "We must part for a short season; but it will only be a very brief parting; for you
                                    know you are soon to follow me to the land whither I am going." Tears gathered in
                                    the eyes of the younger. "We shall miss you much, my friend and father," said he.
                                    "We shall miss much the arm that has helped us so often across the sloughs of the
                                    valley, and up the rugged hills over which we have traveled together." "He who
                                    conducts himself aright," replied the old man, "will never want for an arm to
                                    support him and help him through all the difficulties of life, arms far more
                                    powerful than mine will uphold him in all his ways." "But, father, it is a very
                                    pleasant land you are leaving," said the younger. "A land of clouds and storms,"
                                    replied the other. "A land that yields many a beautiful flower," continued the
                                    younger. "And many a prickly thorn," added the older. "Sweet is the murmur of its
                                    rills, and refreshing are its gentle dews and its vernal showers." "And harsh and
                                    loud is the roar of the cataracts, and wide the desolation of its sweeping floods."
                                    "You will leave behind you, father, many a faithful and affectionate friend." "And
                                    many a wily and vindictive foe." "Those friends will bewail your absence." <pb n="288" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> "And those foes will rejoice at my departure." "Many shall
                                    pluck fruit from trees of your planting and bless you." "Many shall tread upon the
                                    thorns of my strewing and curse me." "You leave behind you many a proud monument
                                    that will perpetuate the memory of your wisdom and virtue." The old man heaved a
                                    sigh, as he replied: "They will perpetuate the remembrance of my folly and
                                    infirmities." "To cheer you in this solemn parting hour, turn father, and take a
                                    last look at those monuments; and listen to the sounds of admiration that come from
                                    the crowd who are surveying them with delight." "Alas!" replied the old man, "they
                                    can afford me no pleasure in the retrospect. They are composed of mouldering
                                    materials, and already I see in them signs of decay. As I gaze upon them, I fancy,
                                    too that I hear issuing from the midst of them sounds that are far from cheering to
                                    my heart. They seem to be sighs of murdered moments, and the groaning of souls that
                                    perished while I was amusing myself with the erection of those frail and perishing
                                    monuments." "Look then at the beautiful mansion you are leaving. Many a happy scene
                                    have you witnessed beneath its roof." "And many a painful scene of sorrow and
                                    suffering." "Many a joyful echo has reverberated within its walls." "And many a wail
                                    of woe." "Of many a good deed have those walls been witnesses." "And of many, very
                                    many an evil one." "Consider, father, the hoarded treasures within them, and the
                                    costly raiments that hang around the apartments you have left." "Those treasures
                                    have been too highly prized, and the value of those raiments have been
                                    overestimated. Already the gold is cankered and the raiments motheaten. Look at this
                                    little boat. Not a particle of those treasures, not a thread of those raiments, can
                                    I take with me into it." So saying, he began to divest himself of the robe which was
                                    wrapped loosely around his frame. "Stop father," said the younger, "Do not cast
                                    aside your robe, chilly are the waters over which you are about to pass." "More
                                    chilly is the land I am leaving," replied the old man. "Kaimentless came I into this
                                    world, and raimentless shall I return thither; for we brought nothing into this
                                    world, and it is certain we can carry nothing out." He threw off his robe and
                                    stepped into the boat. It darted from the shore. A dark mist arose behind it. The
                                    younger man stood for a moment gazing on the mist; but his vision could not
                                    penetrate it. The form of his old friend was hid forever from his view. He dashed a
                                    tear from his eye, and turned away, a more thoughtful man than he had ever before
                                    been.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whole of it" TEIform="index"/> THE WHOLE OF IT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Jackson, A. W." TEIform="persName"/>by Rev. A. W. Jackson.</byline><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by J. J. Kaime.] Two golden texts, two truths,one for the mind, The other for
                            the heart: the two combined, All higher guidance in them may we find. Deeds done by which
                            earth's praises may be earned, Poor fed, the body given to be burned, If cold the heart, are
                            surely all in vain; Our God's approval they shall nowise gain; In deeds no worth their
                            motive fails to attain. In bonds we are, and some time, soon or late, In falsehood leai'n
                            ours is the slave's estate. Nay, howsoe'er content we may remain, A pleasing error's but a
                            pleasing chain. "This know," saith Christ, "all ye who follow me; Love doth the law fulfill.
                            The truth shall make you free."</p><pb n="289" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memory of our departed sister, Amelia Lyman" TEIform="index"/> In Memory of our departed
                            Sister, AMELIA LYMAN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hopkins, Margaret" TEIform="persName"/> Margaret Hopkins.</byline><p TEIform="p"> One more beautiful example of a true Christian lias gone to meet her reward, and to find
                            prepared a beautiful mansion. She has been a faithful laborer in the vineyard of the Lord.
                            At the age of ten years she came into this Society, and was a remarkably active, kind, and
                            sympathetic youth, and as she matured in years, she also matured in all the Christian graces
                            which so endeared her to us, that although the summons has come for us to part, we find our
                            hearts deeply pained to say adieu, and to realize that we shall hear her cheerful voice in
                            love and encouragement no more. Having been intimately acquainted for the past fifty years
                            with our departed Sister, I can say she was a patient sufferer for many years, but was ever
                            cheerful, Avilling to do good whenever able to be in duty. Her life of self-sacrifice was
                            becoming the profession she held so dear. We shall long hold our beloved Sister in sweetest
                            memory. "Bear up, bear on, the end shall tell, Tb(e dear Lord doeth all things well."
                            Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>KIND WORDS.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Elder Henry:--I send a little article..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Beloved Elder Henry:--I send a little article...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, October 1892" TEIform="index"/>Mount Lebanon, N. Y. Oct.,
                                1892.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Henry:I send a little article which you may be interested to peruse. The
                                Manifesto comes laden with good cheer and consolation, which truly lifts the soul to
                                higher joys, and helps one to set out afresh on life's journey with more zeal to live
                                closer to the faith of the gospel of Christ. This is the prayer of your friend.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Van Houten, Phebe" TEIform="persName"/>Phebe Van Houten.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Elder Henry:--We wish personally to thank you..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Beloved Elder Henry:--We wish personally to thank you...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Sonyea, November 1892" TEIform="index"/>Sonyea, N. Y. Nov. 1892.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Henry:We wish personally to thank you for the excellent appearance of our
                                "Manifesto," and hope you may be sustained in your labors. The last number, when I
                                opened it and read articles from our beloved Elder Abraham Perkins and Elder Oliver
                                Hampton, I felt that I was in the presence of the "redeemed from among men," and was
                                thankful to be counted worthy to sit at the feet of such purified souls and receive
                                their ministration. Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, H." TEIform="persName"/> H. DeGraw.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.
                        </head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Haskins, Orren" TEIform="index"/>Orren Haskins
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Orren Haskins at the Church, Mount Lebanon, N. Y., Sept. 15, 1892. Age 76 yrs. 9 mo. and
                                12 days. The record of his life will pass the seat of judgment creditably. C. G. R. [The
                                above has just been received.] </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Daily, Henry N." TEIform="index"/>Henry N. Daily
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Henry N. Daily, at Pleasant Hill, Ky. Oct. 18, 1892. Age
                                77 yrs. Br. Henry lived in the Society at Busro, Ind., when a child. He subsequently
                                moved to Pleasant Hill, Ky., where he has spent most of his life. He was faithful to
                                duty and true to his trust. Peace to his memory. J. W. S. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brown, Olive" TEIform="index"/>Olive Brown
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Olive Brown, at Church Family,
                                Mount Lebanon, N. Y., Oct. 25, 1892. Age 86 years and 1 month. Sr. Olive has long been a
                                helpless, patient sufferer, very unlike her many and active years, both spiritually and
                                temporally. A. J..C. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lyman, Amelia" TEIform="index"/>Amelia Lyman
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Amelia Lyman, at Shaker Station, Conn. Oct. 30., 1892. Age 61 yrs.,
                                1 mo. and 7 days. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boler, Daniel" TEIform="index"/>Elder Daniel Boler
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Elder Daniel Boler, at Mount Lebanon, N. Y., Nov. 11, 1892. Age 88 yrs.
                                6 mo. and 9 days. [Notices referring to the life or death of our beloved Elder Daniel
                                will be found in the January Manifesto of 1893. This course is adopted that the articles
                                may be largely, in one number. Ed.]</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Randlett, Timothy" TEIform="index"/>Elder Timothy Randlett
                            </head><p TEIform="p">  Elder Timothy Randlett, at Enfield, N. H. Nov. 11,
                                1892. Age 85 years and 11 mo.</p></div3><pb n="290" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Chosen" TEIform="index"/> CHOSEN.</head><p TEIform="p"> "I have chosen you out of the world." John, xv., 19. Canterbury, N. H. I walk thro' the
                            valley and meet Thee there, I rise to the mountain, still feel ing Thy care, Amid throng or
                            desert thrilling whispers declare "I have chosen thee, come follow me, I have chosen thee,
                            come follow me." me." <pb n="291" id="p29" TEIform="pb"/> CHOSEN. Follow Thee, follow Thee ? my whole
                            soul replies, I grasp the hand outstretched and stand with the wise, with the wise. Tho'
                            calm may succeed, tho' calm may succeed or fearful tempest rise, In truth shall my spirit
                            follow Thee.</p><pb n="292" id="p30" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="World's Columbian exposition illustrated" TEIform="index"/>
                                The "World's Columbian Exposition Illustrated
                            </head><p TEIform="p">THE COLUMBIAN EXPOSITION. The "World's Columbian Exposition Illustrated" had the honor
                                to be appointed the official photographer of the dedication civic and military parades.
                                As a result the November issue is replete with rich copperplate illustrations showing
                                prominent portions of the great celebration. Among the views are General Miles and U. S.
                                Regulars, Vice-President Morton, Ex-President Hayes, Foreign Diplomats, Connecticut
                                Guards, Illinois National Guards, Governor Fif er, as they appeared in the processions,
                                large view of reviewing stand, photographic view of interior of Manufactures Building
                                during dedication; and among other plates is the Vermont State P.uilding, the Governor
                                of the State, also Norway Building. A large photograph of Mrs. John A. Logan makes the
                                frontispiece. The great orations delivered on the occasion and the addresses of the
                                Exposition officials are given in full. The Woman's Department is full of interesting
                                information, and also contains Mrs. Potter Palmer's dedicatory oration. This paper is
                                making the only authentic History of the Exposition, and will form a complete guide to
                                all visiting the Fair. In short, the November number is a rich recapitulation, in words
                                and picture, of the dedication of the Fair. One issue alone of this paper is worth a
                                year's subscription. Single copies, 25 cts. Address, J. B. Campbell, Publisher, 159
                                Adams St., Chicago, 111. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We find the Phrenological Journal and Science of Health up to
                                date in its consideration of current events. For instance, The Late Arctic Expedition
                                and its commander, Lieut. E. E. Peary, receive an appreciative notice with several
                                illustrations. Then follows a sketch of the doings in Chicago, touching the Columbus
                                Exposition; several of the large buildings are given, and a portrait of the President of
                                the Directory, Mr. Higinbothams. A sketch of Mr. Whittier, with excellent portrait
                                follows. The Poet is very popularly termed "Poet of Freedom." In the department of
                                practical, mental science, a story of school experience commends itself to the world of
                                teachers, viz: "Out of Darkness into Light," and the reflections on the faculty of
                                Sublimity show a nice, critical sense. The essay on Reverence hits the times well, and
                                so does "An Open Letter" to mothers, which especially shows an exceptional courage in
                                both the writer and the publisher in appealing to the popular common sense with regard
                                to a most important yet most sedulously avoided subject. Dr. Handford discusses health
                                and disease in his usually practical manner, and in the same department is an article on
                                the usefulness of the enema as a preventive or remedy in many diseases. A careful
                                reading of the Notes in Anthropology is advised, as several items of much value are
                                recorded in that department. The best advice is, the whole of this November number of
                                the veteran magazine should be read by all. It is published at $1.50 a year or 15 cents
                                a month. The last three months of this year free to new Mibscribers. Address Fowler
                                &amp; Wells Co., publishers, 25 East 21st Street, New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alden's cyclopedia of history" TEIform="index"/>
                                Alden's Cyclopedia of History
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> A GREAT POPULAR HISTORY
                                OF THE WORLD. The story of the world's history, is, after all the most interesting and
                                most instructive story which has ever been told. It was probably never better presented,
                                for general reading and reference, than in Alden's Cyclopedia of History, recently
                                published. Every nation of the earth, ancient and modern, is treated in its alphabetical
                                order, excepting, only, the United States, which is to form a separate work. You have
                                ancient history as far back as B. C. 5004 and modern history down to A. D. 1892. All
                                countries are described in their physical aspects, as well as historically, so you have
                                the equivalent of a book of travels round the world. There are many illustrations, none
                                for mere ornament, but all helpful for instruction. Considering the magnitude of the
                                work, its small cost is astonishing. The entire history comprises about 800,000
                                wordsequivalent, you will find by comparison, to about 10 volumes of ordinary sizeand
                                yet is issued in two handy volumes, in small but clear type, well and handsomely made,
                                and sold in cloth binding for only $1.25 for the set, plus 20 cents for postage, if by
                                mail. For 10 cents the publisher sends post-paid a paper-bound volume of 160 pages,
                                containing the complete history of several nations, by which you can judge of the
                                character of the entire work. Every home ought to have a good Universal History; this is
                                probably the best for general use. The publisher's catalogue of choice books, over 100
                                pages, a rich feast for book-lovers, is sent postpaid for 2 cents. John B. Alden,
                                Publisher, 57 Rose St., New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New England magazine" TEIform="index"/>New England Magazine
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The November number of the New England Magazine i,s a
                                Whittier number. The frontispiece is from a rare photograph of the poet taken about
                                1855, and the opening article takes the reader in and about the New England country,
                                which inspired so much of Whittier's poetry, and is so associated with him as a man. It
                                is by William Sloane Kennedy, whose monograph of Whittier was so well received. Another
                                article deals with Whittjer as Poet and Man, and is by Frances C. Sparhawk. Allen
                                Eastman Cross contributes a line poem, "The Passing of Whittier." Mr. Edwin D. Mead, the
                                chief editor of the magazine, deals with Whittier's life, work and influence in his
                                Editor's Table. The articles are finely illustrated throughout. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Al-modad, or life scenes beyond the Polar Circumflex" TEIform="index"/>Al-modad, or Life Scenes
                                beyond the Polar Circumflex
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Al-modad, or Life Scenes
                                beyond the Polar Circumflex, is a work just issued from the press, at Shell Bank, La. It
                                is a Religio-scientiflc solution of the Prob lems of present and future life, and
                                contains some 200 pages. Published by M. Louisa Moore and M. Beauchamp. Paper Covers. 75
                                cts. Cloth, $1.00.</p></div3><!--
<pb n="293" id="p31"/>
INDEX.
Page.
Address by F. E. Willard,                 106
Angel, The face of an                        261
Appeal, An                                       202
IB.
Baptisms, Seven                                   5
Brooks, E. C, In memory of              33
Brainard, Marietta, In memory of       69
Briggs, N. A.,Letter,                      112
Bowie, S., In memory of                   179
Bible, The                                         212
"    No 2.                                219
Bygones, Let Bygones be                  237
Booker, Annie, In memory of           250
Bellmire, Wm, W.Letter,               267
C.
Call, Our Roll                                       5
Clapp, Charles, In memory of             68
Choir, The angel                                 76
Christians, Hindoos and                    116
Christ, Give to the cause of               116
Confirmation, Certificate of              220
Curiosity, A Literary                        227
Chastisement,                                    242
Church, The Head of the                  245
Consideration,                                   259
r>.
Discourses, Dr. Cyrus Teed,                66
Dark, It was now                               104
Disguise, Blessings in                        194
Dispensations, The                            195
Deity, Our Mother in                        238
DeGraw, Hamilton,Letter,             247
Day, The Questions of the                269
Editorial,        12, 38, 60,   84,   108,   132,
156, 180, 204, 228,  252, 278
Eads, H. L., In memory of         81,   135
Evolution,                                          127
End, Foretells the                              165
Evans, F. W.,Letter,      173,    220, 267
Evans, Tho.       "                            222
Ferguson, Katie, In memory of           13
Flint, Wm. G.Letter,                        34
Faith, Charlie's                                   94
Faith, Dual,                                       128
Fry, Nathaniel, In memory of           158
Forces, Forms and                             243
G.
God, Keep near to                             105
Greeting, Christmas                          275
H.
Home, Notes about        14, 39,   62,   86,
110,  136,   158,   182,   205, 231,   254, 280
Hollister, H.Letter,                  7,    174
Hastings, M. E. In memory of            78
Health-Notes, Mount Lebanon         92, 100
Home, My                                         149
Hymn, A child's                                155
Honesty,                                            226
I.
Inquiry,        82,    133,  164, 188,  212, 260
Interest, Home                                 103
Idealistic, Which the Real or            124
Institutions, Perpetuity of Human    200
J.
Jackson, R.Letter,
21
Page.
<pb n="294" id="p32"/>
Page.
Kentucky Revival, The       1, 25, 49, 73
97, 121, 145
I,.
Love,                                                   10
Late, Too                                            20
Life, Little Things of                          83
Light,
Life, The Resurrection,                     106
Letter, A Christian                            116
Light, Spiritual                                 151
Letter, An Open                                154
Life, The Hill of                               189
Last, At                                            247
Cord, I asked the                              251
Love, The first of all                         202
Life, The Web of                      '         203
Life, Renewed                                   231
Life, The True                                  265
Lyman, Amelia In memory of   269, 289
Life, Two views of                            287
ivr.
Moore, N. E., Diary of         20,    58,    78
Messiahs,                                             77
Meditation, Fruits of                         241
Marriage, A Civil Right                    250
Maxims, Mentor's                              259
Meeting, Memorial                            273
Mother, Our Heavenly                      276
Mount Lebanon,                                277
Modesty,                                            285
New Tear, The
New Lebanon,
Order, God's
Offering, Christmas
Orcutt, D.Letter,
Orange, Not for an
Oats, Sowing Wild
O- - - - -Letter,
Offord, D.Letter,
Obedience,
O.
 11
 101
 28
 29
 70, 179
 143
 165
 225
 248
 276
Perkins, A.Letter,                 129,    268
Parentage, Spiritual                          170
Peace and War,                                  189
Psyche,                                              190
R.
Rest, The Secret of                            169
Retrospection,                                    177
Rules, The Three                              200
Removal,                                           253
S.
Sermon, Farewell, H. L. Eads,      31, 52
Stroud, T. J.Letter,                         36
Shakers, Alfred, Reports of                68
Spectacles,                                          70
Spirit, Which                                      82
Salt,                                                   117
Something New,                                130
Sin, Confession of                              149
Shaker, To be a                                 177
Strowbridge, E. C. In Memory of,       "
Shakers, The Early                    '         193
Suffering, Perfect through                 195
Shakerism,                                        217
Shakers, The                                     250
Serenity,                                            251
T.
Thought, Religious                             11
Testimony,                                          57
Texts, Scripture, 133, 164, 188,  212, 260
Thoughts, Twilight                           153
They Say,                                          227
V.
Vance, M. P. In Memory of        45,    59
Wentworth, L.Letter,                      10
Wickersham, G. M. In Memory  of,      45
W.- - - - - -L. D.Letter,                          46
World's Fair, Closing the                    55
Words, Kind,         81, 166, 188,  214, 289
Weatherford, S. A. In Memory  of     134
Wayne, A. M. In Memory of,            153
N-.
p.
Page.
<pb n="295" id="p33"/>
Work, Finish thy
Whittier, The Poet
Whole of It, The
Page.
166
286
MUSIC.
"The Landing,"
Farewell Vain World,
Bright Day,
Bountiful,
Morning Herald,
Looking Upward,
Ministration,
Jordan,
Stewardship,
Chosen,
DEATHS.
Burgess, Harriet,
Brooks, Emory,
Brainard, Marietta,
Byron, Eliza M.
Bowie, Samantha,
Beal, Thomas,
Booker, Annie,
Boler, Elder Daniel
Brown, Olive
Clement, Moses,
Clapp, Charles,
Coburn, Clark,
Cantrell, Henry,
Dutcher, Maria J.
Doane, Laura Maria,
23
47
71
95
118
167
191
239
263
290
24
48
72
166
190
238
262
289
289
48
72
120
214
120
144
DeGroat, Orpha W.
Daily, Henry N.
Edwards, Mary
Eastin, John W.
Evans, Emily S.
Ferguson, Katie
Foster, Laura
Fry, Nathaniel
Granger, Anna
Gilbert, Richard
Hart, Harriet P.
Haskins, Orren
Leecth, Charlotte
Lyman, Amelia
Miner, Samuel
Norton, John
Preter, Charles J.
Page, Mary
Rhodes, Nazar
Robinson, Deborah
Randlett, Timothy
Shepard, Mary
Straw, Minerva D.
Strowbridge, Evelyn C.
Sauerborn, John
Trousdale, Martha
Taylor, Fannie
Vance, Mary P.
Wickersham. Geo. M.
Weatherford, S. A.
Wayne, A. M.
Page.
238
289
72
96
238
96
>
166
96
120
24
289
72
289
.214
.262
72
190
72
262
288
48
120
190
1,1
72
238
48
144--><pb n="296" id="p34" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every-day biography" TEIform="index"/>Every-Day Biography
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Every-Day Biography. Containing a collection of nearly 1400 brief Biographies, arranged
                                for Every Day in the Year, as a Reference for the Teacher, Student, Chautauquan, and
                                Home Circles. By Amelia J. Calver. A large handsome vol., nearly 400 pages, handsomely
                                bound; price, $1.50. "Every-Day Biography," is an outgrowth of the increasing popularity
                                of observing the birthdays of noted people. Nearly 1500 names are here found,
                                representing sovereigns, rulers, statesmen, founders of colleges, institutions, etc.,
                                besides pioneers in every art, science, and profession. To Chautauquans it will prove
                                invaluable, since every week will bring some name to mind prominent in that universal
                                study. This work will be found a valuable addition to any library or collection of
                                books. Agents wanted to introduce this, and take orders for it. Sent by mail, postpaid,
                                on receipt of price, $1.50. Address, F0WLEK &amp; WELL'S 00., 775 BK0ADWAY, New
                                York.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hymns and anthems for the hour of worship" TEIform="index"/>
                                HYMNS AND ANTHEMS FOR THE HOUR of WORSHIP
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> HYMNS AND ANTHEMS FOR THE HOUR of WORSHIP. The above is on the title page of a
                                beautiful book of 144 pages just issued from the press at East Canterbury, N. H.
                                Containing as it does some of the inspirational thought of the gospel of Christ, it will
                                be in direct harmony with those who love to do good. Price, 50 cts. &amp; 7 cts.
                                postage. Address, H. C. Blinn, East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Summary view of the millennial church" TEIform="index"/>
                                A SUMMARY VIEW OF THE MILLENNIAL CHURCH
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> A SUMMARY VIEW OF THE MILLENNIAL
                                CHURCH, OR "United Society of Believers" It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
                                Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony. Price 50 cts.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Biographical sketch of Daniel Fraser of the Shaker community, of Mount Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>
                            BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH OF DANIEL FRASER Of the SHAKER COMMUNITY, of Mount Lebanon, N.Y
                            </head><p TEIform="p">BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH OF DANIEL FRASER Of the SHAKER COMMUNITY, of Mount Lebanon, N.
                                Y. o By Catherine Allen. Price, 10. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Testimony of Christ's second appearing" TEIform="index"/>
                                THE TESTIMONY OF CHRIST'S SECOND APPEARING
                            </head><p TEIform="p">THE TESTIMONY OF CHEIST'S SECOND APPEARING.
                                Exemplified by the Principles and Practices of the true CHURCH of CHRIST A History of
                                the progressive work of God, extending from the Creation of man to the "HARVEST,"
                                comprising tjie Four Dispensations now consummating in the MILLENNIAL CHURCH. Price,
                                $1.50 </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Interpreting prophecy and the appearing of Christ" TEIform="index"/>
                                "INTERPRETING PROPHECY" AND THE "Appearing of Christ,"
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"INTERPRETING PROPHECY" AND THE "Appearing of Christ," is the title of a neat
                                little pamphlet of some forty pages, just sent out by A. G. Holljster of Mount Lebanon, N.
                                Y. The many at the present time who are interested in the fulfillment of prophecy and in
                                its mathematical calculation, will find themselves by the side of the good old prophet
                                Daniel, and with him illustrating the Coming of Christ so clearly that no occasion can
                                arise for the least doubt. Price, 10 cts</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker's answer" TEIform="index"/>A Shaker's Answer
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> 
                                A Shaker's Answer to the oft-repeated question,
                                "what will become of the World if all become Shakers?" Price 10 cts. OF</p><pb n="296a" id="p35" TEIform="pb"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Birds of North America" TEIform="index"/>The Birds of North America
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A WONDERFUL WORK. The Good Citizen. "The Birds of North America." A magnificent imperial
                                quarto volume. Contains ONE HUNDRED AND NINETEEN engraved plates, representing all our
                                birds, colored from nature, including a reliable and interesting account of their habits
                                and characteristics. Edition limited to 1,000. Subscribe early and secure a copy tor the
                                holidays. The work is sold to subscribers, bound handsomely and substantially, at
                                following net prices; fine Russia Seal, or Turkey Morocco half bindings, gold gilt edges
                                $40.00; full bindings, same materials, $45.00 ENCOMIUMS FE0M THE PEESS. "A superb
                                Work."Publisher's Weekly. "A great work."National Teacher"A magnificent Ornithological
                                Work."TurfField and Farm. "It is one of the most ambitious publications ever attempted
                                in this country or abroad." Cleveland Leader. "It is a marvel of beauty and excellence."
                                Ohio State Journal. "&gt;'o work evincing such perfect care and finish, at such a
                                reasonable rate, has ever been published either in this country or abroad.' Inter-Ocean,
                                Chicago. COMMENDED BY THE HIGHEST AUTH0KITY. From Ex-President Hayes: "It is a valuable
                                work. I have subscribed for two copies." Dr. Elliott Coues, author of "Birds of the
                                North-West," says: "It is a really notable work." Prof. C. J. Maynard, author of the
                                "Birds of Eastern North America," says; "Contains the best pictures of the species which
                                I have ever seen." Dr. J. S. Newberry, President Academy of Sciences, says: "The work is
                                accurately and tastefully prepared, and I take pleasure in recommending it as the most
                                attractive popular exposition of our ornithology yet given to the public." From Prof.
                                Wm. D. Hornaday, Taxidermist, N. S. National Museum: "I have carefully compared the
                                figures in 'The Birds of North America,' with those in Audubon's great work, and am free
                                to say that they are more accurate in outline as well as more faithfully colored to
                                nature." "A careful examination of this beautiful work has given me much pleasure.
                                Indeed, it is a great gift to those who love the study of Ornithology." Editor,
                                Manifesto. Samples of plates and text sent to any address on receipt of twenty-five
                                cents in postage stamps. Good active representatives can have steady employment and earn
                                fair compensation by receiving orders for this work with a specimen book furnished on
                                receipt of one dollar by the NATURAL SCIENCE ASSOCIATION, 114 Fifth Ave., New Yokk. The
                                present of a beautiful Printing Press "Optlmus" lies on our table. A very pretty, glass,
                                "Paper Weight" from the Babcock Printing Press Co., New London, Conn. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of
                                Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Hall's Journal of
                                Health. Nov. Contents. Fashion; School Cramming; Natural Sleep; 1000 Feet Under Ground;
                                A Human Magnet; Nature Makes Glass; The Insect World; Single Beds; When Forks Came in;
                                The Cigarette Evil; Walking for Health, etc., etc. Office 206 Broadway, N. Y. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of hygeio-therapy" TEIform="index"/>The
                                Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The
                                Journal of Hygeio-Therapy. Oct. Contents. Treatment of the Sick; Perils of Childhood;
                                Remedy for Sprains; Flesh Brush; Dietetic Errors; Cholera; Born in a Dungeon; Starving
                                for Food; Griddle Cakes, etc., etc. Dr. T.*V. Gifford &amp; Co. Kokomo, Ind. When a
                                woman of such unquestionably high position in New York society as that occupied by Mrs.
                                Burton Harrison consents to define the best and most careful social laws for girls, our
                                young women can well afford to listen and remember. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>The Ladies' Home Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">There is every indication for a most
                                agreeable interest in the series of articles on "The Well-Bred Girl in Society," which
                                Mrs. Harrison will begin in the November issue of The Ladies' Home Journal. Mrs.
                                Harrison will, in this series, take tip every phase of a girl'-s life in society, and
                                point out to her principally the mistakes it is wisest for her to avoid. A A OfmUc i oar
                                *t j ' for TtuCuct j. 20 Complete Courses \{ for Student and Teacher. AH instruc- q tion
                                by mail. Send stamp for catalogue. $ American forresr ondence Col!ea:e: n S. Dansville,
                                New York.</p></div3></div2><!--
OLD STAMPS WANTED.
Send for list of prices  paid and   mention
Manifesto.
Wm. R.  Farris, South Yarmouth, Mass.
Home study
<pb n="" id="p36"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cream -jf Luvtui- hsikiug Powaui1.   Highest of   all   in   leavening   strength.Latest
United Stales Government Food SZeport.
Royal Baking Powdku Co., 106 Wall St., N. Y.
Scientific American
Agency for
CAVEATS,,
TRADE  MARKS,
DESIGN PATENTS
COPYRIGHTS, etc.
Fop information and free Handbook write to
MUNN & CO., 361 Broadway, New York.
Oldest bureau for securing patents in America.
Every patent taken out by us is brought before
the public by a notice given free of charge in the
Largest circulation of any scientific paper in the
world. Splendidly illustrated. No intelligent
man should be without it. Weekly, $3.00 a
year; $1.50 six months. Address MUNN & CO.,
Publishers, 361 Broadway, New York.
Should have the beautiful 36-pag-e Monthly
= XTTSTBATED HOME JOURKAI> =
50 cts. a year.   Sample free.   Agents wanted.
THOMAS G. NEWMAN & SON,
CHICAGO, ILL.
JOHN F. STRATTON a SON,
43 & 45 Walker St.
 N EW YORK.
MUSICAL MERCHANDISE,
Violins,   Guitars,   Banjos,
Accordeons, Harmonicas, &c.
All kinds of STRINGS, etc., etc.
VA/ANTTlV^ide-awake workers  everywhere for
wnni i cu "shepp's photographs of ma world"
cue greatest book on earth: costing- 6100,000;
PUrnD'Prel;ilil at *'-">> ca*h or installinr r r \uients; mammoth illustrated
\/lll_l I ^circulars and terms free; daily
output over 1500 volumes. Ag-ents wild with
success.     Mr. Thou.   L. Martin,  of  CentreOF THE WORLD.
days ;
rMissBi0se
Adams,
Woosti-r, <>., 823 in40 minutes; Rev. J. Howard
Madisox,  Lyons,  N. Y.,  8101 in 7 hours ;   a bonanza; magnificent
outlit only 1.00.
Books on credit.
Freight paid. Ad. GLOBE BIBLE PUBLISHING
00,, 723 Chestnut St., Phila,, Pa., or 358 Dearborn
St., Chicago, 111.
A NEW BUSINESS
FOR
Men,  Women and  Boys,
Is just being developed, which can be
carried on at home and will prove very
profitable. Honesty is the only capital
required.
Full particulars and a free sample will
be sent you on receipt of two 2-cent
stamps.    No postal cards answered.
Address,    GEO. E. KALB  & CO.,
Ohio.
THE  ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley.
901 Olive St.,   St. Louis, Mo
 By
 UsinS
 USY WORK
AWpjATlEijCE j
A copy, FREE, oi KorKial Instructor, the best educational
paper in America,will give lull particulars. ansville, K.^ ,
ville, Texas, desired
8711 in nine
PHOTOGRAPHS
TIME. STRENGTH
SERIES
RUSHVILLE,
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>