<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0503" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><date value="18750301" TEIform="date">March 1875</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">17-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="17" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">Vol. V. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. Mt- Lebanon, Col. Co. N. Y. March, 1875. No. 3. Sixty Cents per annum.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gift of tongues" TEIform="index"/>GIFT OF TONGUES</head><p TEIform="p">'' I saw an Angel flying in the midst of Heaven — the religious world in man — having the everlasting Gospel to
                            preach unto them that dwell upon the earth — to every nation, kindred, tongue and people." The preaching was to
                            fear God and worship him — not to worship the beast and his image. Here is the patience of the saints who keep
                            the commandments of God and the testimony of Jesus, which is the spirit of prophecy. There appeared a white
                            cloud with a woman sitting upon it, like unto Jesus. That cloud was composed of persons, "clothed in fine linen,
                            clean and white"—with characters, like the woman. She thrust, into the earth, a sharp sickle, to reap it — the
                            testimony of Jesus against generation. The sign of the first Gospel degree, was the Gift of Tongues — Mother Ann
                            spake in seventy-two different languages, thus showing that she was in rapport with the representatives of the
                            nations, who needed the Gospel in the spirit world, and that to all of them the Gospel would be preached, and a
                            crop gathered therefrom, of such souls as were ripe unto the harvest. Throughout the sounding of this first
                            testimony the gift of tongues invariably rested upon those whom the Spirit raised up as leaders to preach and
                            minister the Gospel, from Mother Ann, to Samuel Johnson and Richard Bushnell, who were greatly gifted in
                            tongues.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gift of healing" TEIform="index"/>GIFT OF HEALING</head><p TEIform="p">This Gift will be the sign of tlie second Gospel testimony, as the Gift of Tongues was of the first. When the
                            Spirit begins to raise up the leaders of the new faith, they will be endowed with the Gift of Healing, in a
                            pre-eminent manner. This will be both as a sign and as a ministration of intrinsic good. A sign that the Gospel
                            has increased — progressed from faith to faith, and that health of body is, hereafter, to be conjoined to health
                            of soul. And as powerful and heart-searching testimony will be borne against the tributary lusts of the mind and
                            the flesh, as the first witnesses bore against the consummation — fleshly lusts and generation. In her day,
                            Mother taught that all should build their faith upon the Gift of God — Revelation — and not upon her personally,
                            much less upon the persons of her successors. This is the Rock of the Order —the Foundation of the Gospel — and
                            from it cometh the Gospel increase. Paul found some, who asked, "How are the dead raised, and with what bodies
                            do they come forth? " A rational, scientific inquiry, which he essayed to answer, according to the light of that
                            day, to him vouchsafed. His argument was, that there was a natural body and a spiritual body. If we call the
                            soul the spiritual body — perfect in all its parts — clothed upon with the natural body, we have a basis for the
                            materialization of Moses and Elias. The Apostles saw them, as we saw the Spirits at the Eddys — except that we
                            witnessed the materialization of many Spirits, who appeared as perfect human beings, as were any of the company
                            present. The reanimation of dead bodies, and the materialization of disembodied spirits, ledthe Apostles to
                            believe for a time, in the physical resurrection. Faith and Physiology have grown together, in each of the
                            dispensations, toward a time, when none shall say, I am sick—"and neither shall there be anymore pain,"
                            indicating that the natural body is out of order — Divine Order. After the temptations of Jesus, '' he went
                            about all Galilee, teaching in their synagogues, and preaching the gospel of the kingdom and healing all manner
                            of sickness and all manner of disease among the people. And his fame went throughout all Syria; and they brought
                            unto him all sick people, that were taken with divers diseases and torments, and those that were possessed with
                            devils, and those which were lunatic, and those that had the palsy; and he healed them. And there followed him
                            great multitudes of people from Galilee and from Decapolis and from Jerusalem and from Judea and from bevond
                            Jordan." Matt. 4: 23-25. This was the good he did. It was practical. "After the baptism which John preached, God
                            anointed Jesus of Nazareth with the Holy Ghost and with power; who went about doing good and healing all that
                            were oppressed of the devil" Acts 10: 37, 38. He contended against the actual existing evils of society, by
                            which his people — the Jews — were afflicted. " Ought not this woman, whom Satan hath bound, lo! these eighteen
                            years, be loosed from this bond on the Sabbath day? " Luke 13: 11-16. His mission was to destroy the works of
                            the devil — diseases — the result of Mosaic sins. "When a strong man armed keepeth his palace his goods are in
                            peace; but when a stronger than he shall come upon him and overcome him, he taketh from him all his armor
                            wherein he trusted, and divideth his spoil." Luke 11: 21, 22. Even the Gentiles were allowed to gather the
                            crumbs that unbelieving Jews had carelessly thrown away. Jesus and Disciples went all through the cities of
                            Judea. If there be no gift of healing, not under law, we see how much we have got to learn. May we not say with
                            the poet, the proper study of mankind is man ? The same power of organization, or clothing, that could reanimate
                            the whole body of a dead person, or that can clothe the whole soul with a natural body, as in materialization,
                            could restore any one part of the physical body, that was apparently missing, or repair one that was deranged or
                            disorganized. For we must constantly bear in mind that the spiritual body is whole — perfect. How often,
                            persons, who have had a limb amputated, assert that they feel it to be there as real as ever. Hence faith, in
                            the patient, to take on materialization, is almost, if not quite, a necessity. And that faith — the vitalizing
                            element in the gift of healing — should rest in God, as the source of all good.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Great health revival" TEIform="index"/>Great health revival...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">[From the Oneida Circular.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">THE GREAT HEALTH REVIVAL. "When he had called unto him his twelve disciples, he gave them power
                                    against unclean spirits to cast them out and to heal all manner of sickness, and all manner of
                                    diseases." Matt. 10: 1. His command to them was: "Heal the sick, cleanse the lepers, raise the dead,
                                    cast out devils: freely ye have received, freely give." Matt. 10: 8. This was evidently a commission to
                                    do all that he himself had done. Mark says: "He called unto him the twelve, and began to send them forth
                                    by two and two; and gave them power over unclean sjnrits." Mark 6: 7. Afterward Mark says: '' They went
                                    out and preached that men should repent. And they cast out many devils, and anointed with oil many that
                                    were sick, and healed them." Mark 6: 12, 13. Luke says: '' Then he called his twelve disciples together,
                                    and gave them power and authority over all devils, and to cure diseases; and he sent them to preach the
                                    kingdom of God, and to heal the sick. Luke 9: 1,2. "And," (he adds), " they departed and went through
                                    the towns preaching the gospel and healing everywhere." v. 6. At a later period Jesus organized a second
                                    mission of seventy disciples, and sent them into the field with the same power and the same
                                    instructions. It is probable that this movement was made when the demand for healers, excited by the
                                    previous labors of Jesus and the twelve, had reached a pitch of fervor that went beyond all possible
                                    supply: for Luke says: '' After these things the Lord appointed <pb n="18" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 18 SHAKER other
                                    seventy also, and sent them two and two before his face into every city and place whither he himself
                                    would come. Therefore said he unto them, The harvest truly is great but tlie laborers are few." Luke 10:
                                    1-9, as though the great crisis of the revival had come, and he had but a meagre force of seventv men to
                                    send into it. His instructions to these missionaries were, as before, '' to heal the sick in every
                                    city." And, "they returned again with joy, saying, Lord, even the devils are subject unto us through thy
                                    name." We have now before us the outlines and superficial elements of the Great Health Revival, from
                                    which we are to form a conception of its dimensions. The time of the whole movement was about three
                                    years. That Jesus worked steadily at his business of healing, up to the very last day of his career, is
                                    evident from the message he sent to Herod just before his final arrest: '' Go tell that fox, Behold I
                                    cast out devils and I do cures to-day and to-morrow, and the third day I shall be perfected." Luke 13:
                                    32. The Great Health Revival was enacted in all the important cities and villages of Galilee, Samaria
                                    and Judea, and extending to the regions beyond Jordan on the east, and even to Tyre and Sidon on the
                                    north. Among the towns, expressly mentioned, are Jerusalem, Capernaum, Jericho, Cana, Bethany,
                                    Bethsaida, Sychar, Nazareth, Nain, Cesarea, Philippi, Dalmanutha and Decapolis. The excitement caused by
                                    his cures extended far beyond the scene of his personal labors. It is said, for instance, that '' his
                                    fame went throughout Syria;" and again, that great multitudes sought him out, when he was preaching and
                                    healing at a certain place, and '' followed him from Galilee and Judea, and Jerusalem, and from Idumea,
                                    and from beyond Jordan, and they about Tyre and Sidon." Thus we cannot estimate the extent of the region
                                    covered by the Great Health Revival as less than the whole of what is now called Palestine, including
                                    Idumea on the south — a total area of more than 11,000 square miles. It is about 200 miles long and 60
                                    broad. It had a population of 6,000,000, which is nearly double the present population of the State of
                                    New York. How often the evangelists repeat that he healed '¦'¦all manner of sickness," '¦'¦all sick
                                    people taken with divers diseases and torments, every sickness in all villages and cities," '' the lame,
                                    the blind, the dumb, the maimed." The diseases specially named in the lists of his cures, are leprosy,
                                    palsy, fever, dropsy, blindness, deafness, demoniacal possession, lunacy, chronic issue of blood,
                                    withered hand, and death itself. Knowing, as we do, the infinite miseries of disease, and the enormous
                                    amount of human desire that is everywhere groaning for just such medical help, we must imagine, as well
                                    as we can, the height and depth and length and breadth of the life-commotion in Palestine, which we call
                                    the Great Health Revival.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Oneida circular" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Living truth" TEIform="index"/>LIVING TRUTH</head><p TEIform="p">It is one of the peculiarities of literature, to continue in use certain phrases, full of ambiguities and
                            indecision. Living truth is not intended as the opposite of dead truth, for there can be no such idea existing.
                            What then is the best definition of Living Truth ? If a definition of truth is the absence of all that is
                            erroneous, we, taking as the standard of judgment, the highest, brightest light in our souls, will find that
                            life is truth; and that truthful life is not an ambiguity. Truth can have no better illustration than the
                            continual relinquishment of our errors. The relinquishment of wrong, however, does not necessitate a positive
                            advance in the right. Take the Spiritualists, for instance, some of the errors that have been popularly idolized
                            in Babylon, are rejected with alacrity by them and none are more unhesitating in their denunciation. The
                            furniture that decorated the past temples of worship, is less than useless in the present degrees of light. The
                            Spiritualists have not accepted some advanced truths, with nearly the eagerness, that they have forsaken the
                            man-made theologies. Our God is a most reasonable being. We feel that ere he calls souls to come up from the
                            greatest of Babylons —churchal theologies — there is already prepared a home for their reception, replete with
                            substantial truth. And ere the good Father and Mother ask them to forsake the old arks of unwholesome doctrine,
                            they have prepared new mansions there, and new food for spiritual progress. Any thing that is living grows into
                            something better; and living the truth, necessitates something more than the cessation of doing erroneously.
                            That Jesus, under Christly instruction, was " the possibility of the race, made real: " the embodiment of truth
                            in his personal character — let us not doubt, until we can find a better— " I find in him no fault," — said
                            Pilate, faultless the exemplification of truth. If the life of Jesus is the best mode of truth now known, have
                            we not the key to unlock the secret, — what is living truth ? Our ships must each have rudders. Let Christ be
                            the light of our passage o'er the sea of life, and in seasons of darkness and storms. We have forsaken, may be,
                            forever, the old theologies of error. But have we got out from Babylon, or do we rest dabbling with muddy waters
                            between two shores, the old and the new ; little thinking1 that the waves on either side are held providentially
                            open for our safe transit into Canaan? And now, the waves are closing ; and myriads, who have heard the call:
                            "Come out from her my people!" are going down with the Goddess of lusts, occupying their heavens, and with the
                            carrion of Egyptian flesh-pots sticking fast in their teeth. Such have denied and do deny truth in their lives.
                            Truth has a living expression ; and we are more than once dead, if we do not give that expression, a growing
                            illustration in our lives. Christ is that expression, and whoso lives as did the spiritual Jesus, and the
                            converted Ann, will be a living demonstration of the truth — "a living sacrifice " unto every unspiritual
                            thought, word and deed. It is a fact to be gloried in, that such multitudes have left the old arks of Babylonish
                            theologies ; yet it is a fact to be mourned, that such have made so little difference in their lives as to be
                            any thing rather than a living representative of truth — any thing but a standing rebuke to the multitudes of
                            former associations. Sufficient light has been shed upon us, to lift our characters to the heights whence Jesus
                            was lifted up. Shall this light become our darkness, by neglect and disobedi ence ? Let the things and loves of
                            the old creation be of the past. Let us be determined on a further resurrection. Let purity, peace, brotherly
                            love, equality with " unspottedness from the world " be a reality unceasing within us, then shall we, too, be
                            "without fault," and enjoy that unperishable reward—the happy consciousness of doing right, by living the truth.
                            To see the right and to do it, to know the truth and to live it ; to discover the wrong and rebuke it, to hear
                            duty's voice and obey it, to meet the world and shame it, to feel the cross and love it, to rise above passion
                            and rule it, and to love Christ's life as to die to self daily — these call for martyrs in the cause of Truth,
                            equal to any that grace the history of the past. And yet what will humanity not do for the truth ? Will they not
                            preach, pray, write and fight for it ? Will they not die for it ? More, will they not do any thing and every
                            thing for it, before they will live for it f Let us have a change. Let us commence by living the truth, and then
                            Living Truth inerasably affixed to our banners, will comprehend every thing else.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. Loomis, Shakers, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="English and American shakers" TEIform="index"/>The following article has been sent to the London Times: ENGLISH
                            AND AMERICAN SHAKERS</head><p TEIform="p">I have been abundantly supplied with English papers and extracts from English papers, giving the history of the
                            ejectment of the " Bible Christians " — called " Shakers," by the English press. I have received not less than
                            twenty different accounts. This shows both the unusual nature of the event, and the deep and general interest
                            taken in it, by all classes of people in England. In America, the exchanges of the Shaker and Shakeress contain
                            detailed accounts of the sad event, with much editorial comment. This breakup, by the sheriff, of the community
                            Home, of the " Bible Christians," at New Forest, near Lymington, Surrey, is the present sensation. It would be
                            but a feeble expression of our feelings to say that we, the Shakers of America, sympathize with those sincere,
                            desolated enthusiasts, who were, by due course of law, thus ruthlessly, to the number of one hundred and
                            fourteen, men, women and children, turned out into the highway, in a cold, stormy night — their goods and
                            chattels piled up by the road side. In justice to the present generation of English people, we are happy to say,
                            that throughout the whole history of those people — logical from a certain stand-point — no appearance of
                            religious persecution has been visible. Great forbearance, by the magistrates, who have often been called upon
                            in relation to the " Walworth Jumpers," as they were also called, has been uniformly manifest. In this we see
                            that real progress has been made in religious toleration. England has learned to be patient and long suffering
                            with religious fanatics. This is well. So far as fanaticism goes, these " Bible Christians " have not been much
                            worse than were the Shakers, when the Shakers were as young. The Shakers, with Quaker proclivities, were so
                            impracticable, shouting, shaking, and dancing on the Sabbath day — at that time a very dreadful thing—sometimes
                            interrupting the services of the hireling Priests, in their own steeple-houses, that finally they had to leave
                            the country entirely. And in America, Ann Lee and her Elders passed a tithe of their time in its various
                            prisons. If these people have, in them, as they claim, the basis of a new order of things, that will fulfill the
                            prophecies and meet the wants of our race, God is in it. Man cannot overthrow it. We do not question their
                            faith, zeal, earnestness of purpose and devotional endurance, manifested throughout their two, or three years'
                            history. These are virtues we love. But, in theological theories — theology — either the Jumpers, or Shakers are
                            wide of the mark, on some essential points. Cannot the facts be come at ? The Girley woman, who is the mother of
                            these people, holds, with the Protestants, Catholics and Greeks, that Jesus was the very Christ — that his dead
                            body was raised from the tomb — that such rising was the true and final resurrection — that his body was
                            spiritualized — that after this pattern, all human bodies, however long dead, are to be resurrected. She claims
                            to be resurrected, in like manner, with this slight variation, as expressed by Paul — " We shall not all die,
                            but we shall all be J^NID <pb n="19" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> changed." She is " changed." Her followers are also being "
                            changed," without going through the process of physical death. Such is the ground of their faith, that nothing
                            can harm them, physically. " See," they said, '¦ that after being exposed to the rain and cold, all night, wet
                            through and through, none are inj ured — none taken cold even ! " To them, the second appearing of Christ is the
                            second appearing of Jesus — personally. And is not this Orthodox ? The Second Adventists held to, and looked for
                            his personal appearing. Were they less fanatical than these more modern Second Adventists ? Some Millerites
                            prepared robes in which to ascend and meet the Lord in the air, at his advent, when the great Trumpet of the
                            Angel Gabriel should sound. We believe Christ is a spirit sphere, with things and persons in it — interior to
                            all other things and persons — that Jesus was born and educated a Jew — saw the travail of his soul towards that
                            sphere, and into it was finally baptised, through John, the end of the Law and the last of the Prophets, coming
                            down from Melchisideck — the Heathen — who baptised Abraham, the ancestor of Jesus, and father of the whole
                            Jewish people, into a seed — faith — of Spirituality. That Germ of Spirituality expanded and grew, coming down
                            through the Prophets, to John, and culminated in Christianity. In Jesus, that Christianity was as an Acorn to
                            the Oak — a little Leaven to the whole mass — a mustard seed to the plant — a grain of sand to the seashore—a
                            little stone to the Mountain that is yet to fill the whole earth, as the waters cover the hills, valleys and
                            rocks of the sea-basin. The two Peoples agree in the fact of a Second Coming of Christ, and differ as to who and
                            what Christ is — and in the time and manner of his second coming. Both hold celibacy as a necessary condition of
                            Resurrected Souls. But while Shakers respect the injunction— "Not to touch a woman"—Girleyites seem to consider,
                            that being now resurrected, they can throw off restraint. They do not hesitate to practice great sexual
                            familiarity in public meetings. Respecting the ownership of land, in large quantities, and the monopoly of life
                            elements — holding that community of goods is a Christian virtue, the Shakers and Bible Christians are at one
                            again, showing there are important elements of union. While one party take the Scriptures as the infallible Word
                            of God, and the physical resurrection as the final resurrection of glorification, the other party, reasoning
                            from facts and principles, regard the Scripture records as illustrative of the then present faith of the writers
                            and actors, to be interpreted by those facts and principles, regardless of persons and old theories. Both agree
                            that the dead are raised, and may re-animate their physical bodies, if not too much decomposed for their
                            reparation, under the laws of materialization. But the Shakers assume that such re-animation is but a first
                            resurrection, to prepare the human mind for the second — the first is abnormal — temporary. The second is
                            normal, and may become universal, to the human race. As there is no permanent physical resurrection, so neither
                            will there be a personal re-appearing of Jesus, as the Christ. If Jesus and the Apostles, who saw and knew only
                            in part, and prophesied as through a glass, darkly, did so understand, up to the time that they passed into the
                            spirit world, and as nearly all the so-called Christian world have understood, and yet understand—such
                            understanding no more establishes the fact, than it establishes the fact, that his Kingdom was to be of this
                            world, when the facts were, His Kingdom was to be set up and established in the world of Spirits, on the basis
                            of the Mosaic Law, and to be composed of the twelve Tribes of Israel, upon which the twelve Apostles would sit,
                            as upon twelve thrones. That was the Man-child — a male church — a continuation of the Jewish Pentecostal
                            Christian Church, caught up to God, away from the persecuting power — Dragon-Rome and the Gentile Christian
                            Church on earth. That Gentile Christian Church included generation, private property, war, and Church and State
                            governments. It has had its reign, 1260 years. It is now being broken. The fragments, of its Monarchical
                            Kingdoms, lie around loose — broken, by Republican Principles, as concentrated in the Infidel Governments of the
                            United States. These are breaking, in pieces, all other Kingdoms and Governments, because Christ, having made
                            his second appearance — spiritually— has begun to organize a Gentile Pentecostal Church, on the earth, under the
                            protection of a New Earth Civil Government, which secures liberty of conscience, as a Right. The Marriage of the
                            Lamb and Bride will be effected through Spiritualism. It will be a union between the Jewish Pentecostal Church,
                            in the Heavens, and the Gentile Pentecostal Church on Earth. After the marriage of the two churches is
                            perfected, their united testimony will be against all evil that afflicts humanity — physical and spiritual. They
                            will sing the song of Moses, the servant of God, and the Song of the Lamb —" In thy light we behold light."
                            Could the English Shakers, some of whom have visited us, see things in this light, good homes await the whole
                            ejected company. And what appeared to be their total ruin, may thus be turned to their temporal and eternal
                            gain.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editors of shaker and shakeress:" TEIform="index"/>Editors of Shaker and Shakeress :</head><p TEIform="p">The writer, as you are aware, is an outsider. He, nevertheless, takes an abiding interest in the great work of
                            love and wisdom you appear to be prosecuting with steadily increasing vigor. I have read every line of your last
                            issue with interest and admiration — I hope, with present and future intellectual and spiritual profit. I
                            congratulate you on the remarkably high standard of literary merit your publication has attained, treating
                            subjects of the highest practicable moment to the great human family of to-day. The last number, especially, is
                            rich in important matter. Your articles on the vital subject now demanding and arresting the attention of the
                            civilized, world, yet to play so important a part in its higher evolvements, are masterly in a high degree —
                            vigorous, but in the Christ Spirit — evincing a cool, but determined championship for the truth. When soldiers
                            of this campaign, their leaders paralyzed, demoralized, desert the ground already won, you step forth alone,
                            renewing the attack vigorously and persistently. Then there are the excellent, the meritorious articles of your
                            outside correspondents, evidently the productions of men of noble hearts and bright intellects, earnest
                            co-workers with God in his evolving work for the elevation of the race. The article entitled " Gospel Travail"
                            is beautiful in its simplicity and practical bearing on our every-day life. It is a subject of vast import, not
                            to your people only, but to all people. It demonstrates the necessity of looking well to thought, as the source
                            of feeling, word and action. The article entitled "A Happy New Year," teems with sound, practicable ideas,
                            creditable alike to the head and heart of the writer. They are specially intended for the young of your Order.
                            They are of vital importance to young and old of all Orders. The Editress gives a clear, well thought-out essay,
                            as are all her articles, evincing a philosophic mind and catholic, Christ-like spirit, a guarantee of the
                            capabilities of the sex, for the special work the redemption of the world requires of them. The subject is of
                            vast importance to the public at the present time. Of the " Influence of Kindness," " Contribution," and other
                            articles, as of the Poetry and Music, much might be said to their credit. I hope your interesting little
                            periodical will go on. Its influence is beginning to be felt. It promises to become an acknowledged leader in
                            the labor of Wisdom and Love for Human Elevation. You stand on vantage ground, high as are the heavens above the
                            earth — not inspired by the mighty dollar, but by the mightier Wisdom and Love — the Sublime Centre of all
                            vitality. Yours, with admiration and love,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Robert" TEIform="persName"/>Robert Stephens</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New York, January 9, 1875" TEIform="index"/>41 West 26th Street, ) New York, Jan. 9th, 1875</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Father Evans :—Your note is at hand. I will try and prepare a short statement of my visit to Eddys for the
                            Shaker and Shakeress. They have made a thorough convert of me. There are startling changes to take place soon
                            now. The fundamental principles of the Shakers, it seems to me, will become more or less prominent in the new
                            order of things. We must have a new religion, based on Physiology. Old things will pass away, and all things
                            become new. A new Heaven and a new Earth are to be developed. There is a most gigantic power being manifest
                            through these Eddy's, and if it can be controlled for good, it will be a great thing. I have arranged with
                            Horatio to have a record kept of all their manifestations every day. I think it will be a matter of great
                            interest to the whole human family. Dr. Beard is all wrong in his scientific exposition of these manifestations,
                            and has shown himself a great-----, in my estimation in the positions he has taken. With kind wishes to all the
                            friends there. I am truly yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Miller, E. P." TEIform="persName"/>E. P. Miller</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, Shirley, Massachusetts, December 14, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, Shirley, j Mass.,
                            December 14, 1874</head><p TEIform="p">Kind and Respected Brother, John Greaves:—Yours, of Nov. 30, came duly to hand. The information about the
                            manifestations in Vermont is highly appreciated by the Brethren and Sisters. Accept thanks for the rich store of
                            Love, from yourself and others. To stir one another up to a realization, that we are in a work — a dispensation
                            — where the prevailing sentiment is Love, is doing good service. The seal of love is self-sacrifice. We,
                            thereby, increase our own happiness and the happiness of others. The order of our Gospel is the product of, and
                            is sustained by, self-sacrifice. I thank you for the sacrifice you have made, and for the continued kindness you
                            have manifested. They who give their all, and maintain a uniform kindly bearing, are, to-day, glorious. Happy to
                            hear of the young Brethren and Sisters — of the Aged, and also of those who bear the burden of to-day. They are
                            my relations. With them, I am happy in blessing and being blessed. Your visit, to the Eddys, was seasonable. I
                            feel assured it will be of much importance in the future. I hope an account of the manifestations, witnessed by
                            Elder Frederick and yourself, will be recorded in the Society. The extraordinary manifestations bother
                            scientists. They have neither science enough, nor time enough, to settle one phase of Spiritualism, before
                            another presents itself. Spiritualism will humble the pride of all flesh. To maintain a humble attitude, is to
                            be in union with the work of to-day. We all thank you for the pains you have taken, to give us such full and
                            satisfactory account of your visit, and of the manifestations. Though outward, they are doing an important work,
                            in reference to a coming day. Modern civilization is beginning to feel the power of Spiritualism. I am on the
                            watch-tower, looking for the next wave from the spirit land. The first, enlightened the understanding. The
                            second, will touch the heart — cause conviction and repentance. The sentiments of to-day and of the past, which
                            have produced a state of things, called civilization, will undergo great changes. Prevailing sentiment being
                            changed, on important fundamental points, they, who do not take hold and embody the increasing light, favorable
                            to moral and physiological integrity, bearing on the good time coming, will be left out in the dark, to die out,
                            as did the flesJi-pot loving Hebrews of former times. May that not be the case with us, either collectively, or
                            individually. Communicate largely of our love, and accept, for yourself, a full measure. Our most loved Ministry
                            add theirs.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Fraser</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wanted, 12 articles and 1,000 subscribers..." TEIform="index"/>Wanted, 12 articles and 1,000 subscribers...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Wanted, 12 Articles and 1,000 Subscribers for the Shaker &amp; Shakeress.</p></div2><pb n="20" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Baptism of Jesus" TEIform="index"/>BAPTISM OF JESUS</head><p TEIform="p">There is but one faith and one baptism that can save us from sin, and that is the faith and baptism of Jesus,
                            into and unto Christ. Jesus believed and testified that all mankind were deeply lost from God. He believed that
                            all were out of the way, going astray in sin and darkness. Jesus believed in a new birth, and a Spiritual
                            Resurrection ; that there was only one way for mankind to be saved, and this was the way he opened and walked in
                            himself. He believed it was necessary to deny self, of all the carnal pleasures of this world, to be saved —
                            believed it necessary to leave father and mother, wife and children, houses and lands, and his own life also, to
                            inherit the kingdom of Heaven. He believed it necessary for him to obey and keep his Father's commands strictly.
                            He also believed it necessary to crucify the old nature with its affections and lusts, also his own will and
                            selfishness. He believed there was not one Christian in all the race of Adam — that all belonged to the world.
                            He believed and testified that the marriage order did not belong to his kingdom — no husband nor wife known
                            there — but fathers and mothers, brethren and sisters, those who practiced the words and character of angels.
                            This was the faith of Jesus. No one can be a Christian without that faith. Every one that possesses this faith
                            and practices it is a true follower of Jesus. The church of J erusalem had that faith, and did practice it, for
                            some time. But when that church fell away, the faith of Jesua departed from the earth, and when he came the
                            second time he did not find one who kept his faith. Ann Lee received that faith by revelation, and by obedience
                            to it, she became a mother in the new creation — 0 how beautifully bright and shining are her children. All true
                            Shakers are the offspring of the same parentage of Jesus and Ann — Celestial parents. Blessed and holy are all
                            those who have received that faith of Jesus, and the holy baptism of Father's and Mother's Spirit, because they
                            have power to rise above the earth and walk, as the angels, in Heaven, and to overcome the world in themselves,
                            as our Heavenly Father and Mother have done.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Erickson, Lasy" TEIform="persName"/>Lasy Erickson, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What are we doing?" TEIform="index"/>WHAT ARE WE DOING?</head><p TEIform="p">Brethren and Sisters : What are we doing? Are we keeping the way of God, in its purity, according to the teaching
                            and example of our Gospel Parents? In our daily vocations, whatever they may be, are we faithful according to
                            our best abilities, being careful and prudent in whatever of temporalities with which we have to do ? Are we
                            meek and gentle in our deportment, manifesting a kind and forbearing spirit toward one another, striving always
                            to make as much allowance for the weakness of others as for our own ? Having gained a good degree of mastery
                            over our baser appetites and passions, are we alive to the fact that we have but entered the portico of the vast
                            temple of spiritual refinement, but just entered the forest, cleared away the coarse, natural growth,
                            preparatory to. cultivating the fields of illimitable improvement ? When we see pride, arrogance, envy,
                            superstition, jealousy, anger, hatred, impatience, disrespect, loquacity, indifference to the feelings of
                            others, idleness, or any other of the heads of the hydra, cropping out, are we aware that we are merely looking
                            into a mirror ? Are we aware that the more we are under such influences, the less patience and forbearance we
                            have with the shortcomings of others ? In this day of materialization, do we comprehend the vital importance of
                            the fact that God is manifest in humanity ? That as we respect the Holy Eternal Parents, in our Elders, Sisters
                            and Brothers, even so may we be respected ? And do we further comprehend that love of God in humanity need not
                            be limited by sectarian bars ? Are there not sheep that are not of this fold—is there any living thing God has
                            made that is not entitled to sufficient respect, to be treated with kindness ? My dear Gospel Kindred, is not
                            this a good time for me to examine myself— to prove my own self to see that I am not only in the faith some time
                            ago delivered to the saints, but in the increase of God ? I think it is.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Martin" TEIform="persName"/>Martin Andrews, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Telling experience" TEIform="index"/>TELLING EXPERIENCE</head><p TEIform="p">Editor Shaker and Shakeress : I see your radical paper contains no advertisements, not even " Purely Vegetable
                            Bitters," nor New Sunday School Music Books. Of course it lacks one source upon which other periodicals largely
                            depend. May be you can spare room for this communication. I wish to publish some of my religious experience. I
                            am a beginner. I am desirous to encourage the youth, by pointing to those whose example has been blessed to me.
                            Let me say to you, Obey the plain teachings of Truth, and you can succeed in keeping in the very foot-prints of
                            our Saviors, who go before us. For several years I have been trying to "follow Jesus"—or thought I was. A
                            crooked path I made, stumbling over temptations I willfully ran against, and prayed to be delivered from—trying
                            to smooth over incongruities, until nearly discouraged as to the possibility of ever reaching my Ideal. I must
                            also confess that I excused myself from much of the " burden " and the yoke — self-denial — by belief in the
                            Divinity of Jesus — that his miraculous conception enabled him to resist sin — a power not vouchsafed to me, a
                            poor sinner. Then came to my weary, sin-sick soul, the Truth as it is in Christ — practical Christianity —
                            practical Christianity in the United Society of Shakers. I read all the Shaker Books and Papers I could get. New
                            Light sinned upon my path. The absorbing question was — Is it true, that the Millennial Church keeps, in its
                            purity, the faith, once delivered to the Saints ? I visited this branch of your Society, as an inquirer. Soon,
                            the Ministry, from Mt. Lebanon came. The preaching, daily walk and conversation of Elders, Eldresses, Brothers
                            and Sisters, confirmed me in the faith. During the first two weeks, I had such constant feeling of peace, and of
                            the Love of God, that I wondered if Heaven had already begun. Is the cross so soon a crown ! — the yoke so easy,
                            and the burden so light! — While I lie down in green pastures, beside still waters, let me not forget the giver
                            of all good. By childlike obedience—by close union with my Elders — may I be prepared for temptations, by which
                            my faith must be tried. Then, though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I will fear no evil.
                            Never before was my sky so clear. No doubts becloud my pathway. No incongruities to smooth over. No stumbling
                            blocks. A straight, narrow path leads steadily upward. A Light, shining brighter and brighter, unto the perfect
                            day.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fletcher, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>Richard Fletcher, Sonyea, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio, December 25, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Union Village, Ohio, Dec. 25,1874</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Frederick and Companions in Gospel Order: I am much pleased with your "Sev en Testimonies," in the
                            Jan. 75, No. of S. &amp; S. It is all very good. When the First Testimony was proclaimed, by Mother Ann,
                            against Generation, its vitality depended on its advocates Living it — reducing it to practice, by bearing a
                            cross against works of concupiscence. Had they not done so, their mission would have been of little account to
                            humanity. The power We exercise, for good, at the present time, is in our united effort to carry forward that
                            same testimony. If we ever take a step, in advance of that testimony, that step will be taken in the same way
                            the first step was taken, in the first Testimony —¦ by reducing it to practice. It is well to have time to
                            consider the philosophy of the situation, but have we not had all the themes digested, leading to the second
                            step in the drama ? Who wants to be convinced now, that a poor, weakly, diseased man, or woman is a poor medium
                            for God, or Angels, to work through ? Nearly every one believes improper aliment is the cause of very much of
                            the physical evils we are laboring under. Yet there are as many excuses, for continuing to do as our fathers
                            have done, as were found among the Ohio New Lights, when John Meacham, Issachar Bates and Benjamin S. Young told
                            the people they would have to quit sleeping with their wives. Oh ! what a lamentation ascended from Turtle Creek
                            Valley, when, Testimony of the first Thunder was proclaimed. The flesh was held in as high estimation by
                            Preachers Stone, Thompson and their coadjutors, as are Superfine Flour, Tobacco, Tea, Coffee, Flesh Meat and
                            cognate unphysiological diets and indulgences, by many, among Believers, in this day. And as it took the force
                            of Truth, to separate tJwse from their Idols — so will it take the force of uncompromising truth, to separate
                            —to emancipate souls, from the Idols of this day — to let in the light of the second Testimony, against
                            unphysiological living. You say our Fathers and Mothers confined their work to one testimony — the Testimony
                            against the work of concupiscence. That was wise. Now, what if we should confine our efforts to the duties of
                            the second Testimony, and let the rest go, until we feel that we have made sure, solid ground to stand on. And
                            in order to do this, let us establish a working Power, in every Society, ©f such as are willing to live out the
                            principles of their Testimony, unitedly. What chance would there be, for a young man, or woman, to bear the
                            cross, surrounded with the temptations found in the higher walks of city life ? Hence the call, " come out from
                            among them, that ye be not partakers of their sins." Such, were the conditions of success, in the First
                            Testimony. Shall we not follow the same rule, in every advance movement ? Let the few, who are ready to take
                            this step, and keep this Testimony, " Gome out," and form a Family, and live the Testimony of the Second
                            Thunder. Let this be called the First Order. I could see some sense, in such an arrangement as that — but can
                            see no sense in the present arrangement of 1st Order, 2d Order 2d Family, or Gathering Order. Let me
                            congratulate you on getting up a good Paper, for January, 75. Our hearts are overflowing — gushing out — with
                            Love, for Elder Frederick and his dear good People. Do receive.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reynolds, William" TEIform="persName"/>William Reynolds, Union Village, 0.</byline></div2><div2 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The grasshopper plague results from killing off the prairie hens..." TEIform="index"/>The grasshopper plague results from killing off the prairie hens...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The grasshopper plague results from killing off the prairie hens for eastern markets. Save the birds and the
                            birds will save the crops.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fire" TEIform="index"/>FIRE</head><p TEIform="p">Since our form was made up, there has occurred, in the centre, or Church Family, at Mt. Lebanon — on February 6 —
                            the greatest and most destructive fire ever experienced by Believers. Eight buildings — dwelling-house, Sisters'
                            shop and wood-house combined, icehouse, storehouse, barn, cart-house, cider mill, gas-house and shed, entirely
                            consumed. Two other buildings, with their contents, damaged. Total loss estimated at $100,000. Pittsfield, eight
                            miles distant, was telegraphed and sent fire brigade, with engine and 1,000 feet hose, which came through in
                            fiftyfive minutes, and did good service in extinguishing the fire. The neighbors turned out in mass. The Tildens
                            came in force, bringing a good supply of fire extinguishers, with parties to use them. To all, we tender our
                            grateful acknowledgments, for aid and sympathy. Young George Tilden was efficient in saving the infirmary. To H.
                            A. Tilden, Marvin Sacket and H. Whiting, we are indebted for valuable suggestions in saving other buildings,
                            especially the Meeting House. INCIDENTS AND ACCIDENTS. Elders Daniel Boler and Daniel Grossman, both injured.
                            Andrew Barett, collar bone broken. Eldress Harriet Gooodwin was barely saved by being taken, by ladder, from an
                            upper window. No insurance — internal or external — the loss presses heavy upon the whole Order. Prompt payment
                            of debts due to Shakers, would much relieve.</p></div2><pb n="21" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: the word of God" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: THE WORD OF GOD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">What is the word of God ? How spoken, heard, or understood ? Is it the Bible, as a whole, or any part of it ? The
                            apostle John said, '' In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God." According
                            to that definition, the outward universe of matter is His Word, an out-growth from the Universal Mind, which
                            existed anterior to all bibles — the soul of all things; and although imperceptible to the outward senses, is
                            the moving cause of all existence within the spheres of God's creation. The Word of God has been heard and felt
                            in every land and clime, and by all nations, ever since the foundations of the earth or heavens were laid. He
                            has spoken, and continues to speak, through the rocks, plants and flowers; through the sapling and the
                            full-grown tree, with its wide-extended branches, and roots deeply imbedded in the soil. God's Word is
                            indestructible. The laws of gravitation, of expansion and cohesion never change. They are facts — laws which
                            pertain to the universe — a portion of God's outspoken Word, to the visible, from the unseen worlds. In all
                            their evolutions they are upheld by his power, and caused to move in harmony ; and the relations which they
                            bear, one to the other, are perfect. God does not speak as with human voice, but in acts — works — and through
                            human agencies and invisible intelligences. While we must acknowledge that God has spoken through Nature —
                            through the earth and its products — through the sun, moon and starry heavens, we can but admire the wisdom with
                            which He has meted out his Word, down through the ages, to meet the developed and ^-developed condition of the
                            people. In the childhood state, He spake in whispers — modulated tones. Yet Truth, abstractly considered, never
                            changes. In all essentials it is the same. Cause and effect stand in corresponding relations the one to the
                            other, in the past, as in the present. Health-producing and health-destroying causes always bring forth the same
                            results, whether in a physical, moral, or spiritual point of view. Every departure from law makes its impress
                            upon the being. Physical disease marks its victim. Sensuality dwarfs the intellect and mars the image of the
                            heavenly, which should be reflected in the countenances of all who are created with the inherent germs of
                            immortal life. We do not need that some messenger from the high heavens should come to our sphere to point out
                            the debauched, those who have departed from rectitude. John the revelator, spake of the servants of God, who had
                            the Father's name, (character), written in their foreheads;" and of those '' who had not received the mark of
                            the beast." The life deeds, whether good or evil, are delineated in the countenances and felt in the exhalations
                            that go from them. What a boundless field of thought, of contemplation and study, is open to the human mind, in
                            searching to understand God's Word, manifest in works — outspoken, and what remains to be spoken, the written,
                            and the yet unwritten, which pertain to future, unborn ages. The past, contrasted with the future, is only as
                            drops of water when compared with the ocean. An eternity lies before us. Sacred, and what is called profane
                            history, touch at different points upon the origin, life and progress of nations and kingdoms, and of the rise
                            and fall of empires. But how fragmentary it must of necessity be; mere atoms when compared with the indivisible
                            whole. Every thing in the past, as far as we have knowledge, as well as in the present, avows one fixed
                            unvarying principle or law, that is applicable to all nations and peoples. All true records of events, past or
                            present, concerning natural or spiritual things, should be received and treated with respect and due
                            consideration. Mortals can neither make nor destroy truth. They may lend their aid to strengthen, or to weaken
                            it; but its course is onward, and it is omnipotent 1 No book, however inspired, or well written, can contain all
                            truth, or fix the boundary lines of its increase. The bibles, of different nations, all have recorded truth,
                            more or less, as revealed to, and interpreted by, them; but if all the bibles, ever written by Greek, Catholic
                            or Protestant, of every land, should be burned to-day, not one particle of God's Word, which is quick and
                            powerful, would fail or be destroyed. All the truths which those bibles contain, were in existence, in some
                            form, before they were revealed to mortals, and would remain, subject to the law of revelation, in God's own
                            time and manner. God's agencies, through which he speaks and works, are multitudinous. Countless numbers of
                            purified spirits are sent from the inner spheres to speak the Word of God to those in the earth sphere who are
                            the most spiritually progressed, and the farthest removed from sensuality and selfish loves. These are the ''
                            angels who fly in the midst of heaven," preaching the Word in the highest, purest form, that mortals are
                            prepared to receive. They are God's ministers of spiritual truth, sent from the heaven of resurrected souls, who
                            have been baptised with the Christ baptism, which is, '' fire and the Holy Spirit." They are over and around the
                            pure in heart who can see and hear God's voice through messengers whom He sends. Nothing can exceed, in
                            excellence and beauty, the utterances of Jesus in his sermon on the mount: '' Blessed are the pure in heart; for
                            they shall see God." They are in communion with angelical beings, they list for the sound of cherubic wings, and
                            hear the voice of God when He speaks.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notice" TEIform="index"/>NOTICE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">" Money orders" made payable to F. W. Evans, New Lebanon Post-office.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Heaven" TEIform="index"/>HEAVEN</head><p TEIform="p">Where is heaven ? and when shall we find it 1 The impression generally given in speaking of heaven^ is, that it
                            is something in the future — a place where the departed good assemble, or rather which they inhabit — whose
                            employments are prayer and praise ; living very harmoniously together, up somewhere in the New Jerusalem —¦
                            whose streets are paved with gold ; o\«r which they march with the harps of God in their hands. To many, these
                            are sickly sentimentalities—words Without meaning—-the region of Utopia, All that reason can depict for the
                            future, should have an eternal now. If purity and goodness are the foundations of a heavenly structure, should
                            they not be laid in every heart ? " Ye are the temple of the living God ; and whosoever denies this temple, God
                            will destroy •" or annul, as being unfit for the building. Again, this heavenly city is to be illumined by the
                            light of God. A city is made up of people and houses being in close proximity to each other ; they differ in
                            magnitude, according to location and enterprise. By these we only get an idea of the city above. It is a time
                            when public attention is being largely drawn toward the subject of materialization ; and we propose to have the
                            New Jerusalem so materialized, that it will be a tangible existence — a reality — to be enjoyed in the present
                            time. We are told that God is Love ; and that heaven is His dwelling-place. If the love of God can enter the
                            hearts of men and women, that they will be drawn together, to carry out this good spirit of love, so that the
                            light which illumes this city or people, may be the light of every heart; and so that every evil and discordant
                            element may be banished, it will be a beautiful, present reality, rather than an anticipated future prospect.
                            Let the experiment be tried ; and if it do not succeed, then there is a work to be done, to fit and prepare
                            individuals for a higher life, even a heavenly one. On the earthly plane, two individuals were to become one
                            flesh; on the spiritual and heavenly plane, these will form one united and harmonious spirit, which will blend
                            all into one body of good, whether there be two, ten, or ten thousand, who shall make up the kingdom of heaven.
                            Jesus, in giving instructions of heaven, says, " It is within, or among you." Any one who will forsake all
                            earthly goods — all earthly relationships which are selfish — for the one grand object of living godly in this
                            present evil world, will find that heaven has in very deed commenced in one soul: and the more there are
                            possessed of this spirit, the more enlarged heaven will be ; and there will be no great change from the heaven
                            of this world, to that in the world to come; it will be in degrees of happiness, not in any change of
                            principles. We read of heaven, and the heaven of heavens; which admit of a large increase of that spiritual
                            light and power, which will cause any soul to take the first step heavenward. The greatest good will yield the
                            greatest happiness in physical things, as in spiritual things. The epicure, who takes the greatest pleasure in
                            the indulgence of his sordid appetite, often finds the effect pain and misery ; delighting in present
                            gratification, at the exSHAKEEESS. 21 <pb n="22" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 22 SHA.KKR pense of future happiness; and those who
                            stimulate themselves with poisonous narcotics, and spirituous beverages, must have these increasingly to keep up
                            the excitation ; when this ceases, then happiness is at a discount; so their heaven cannot be welling up
                            continually, as in a soul full of self-denial to every thing that does not centre in God ; for no one will
                            believe these things are an emanation from Him. Souls must of necessity look far into the future, for
                            substantial happiness. It occurs to me, that any one bound to habits detrimental to physical health, or
                            spiritual growth, has a very limited idea of that high estate, which we term heaven ; and the sooner he or she
                            begins to expunge those things from his or her life-practice, by strictly denying self of tliem, the higher up
                            on the ladder, reaching from earth to heaven, will he or she find him or her self.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bullard, Harriet" TEIform="persName"/>Harriet Bullard, Watervliet, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eldress Antoinette:" TEIform="index"/>Eldbess Antoinette:</head><p TEIform="p">My Dear Sisteb — I have a sweet good morning for you. I am always happy to meet you face to face, and with
                                you feast on heavenly food, and dwell upon themes relating to the Angel life. Those seasons are refreshing.
                                When we cannot thus meet and commune, we are glad of the pen medium to convey our thoughts. " The pare in
                                heart, see God." Where do they see Him ? Do not those who walk in the footsteps of the meek and lowly Jesus,
                                reflect the image of the Heavenly, and become one with him, even as he was one with the Father ? If this be
                                so, then we see and feel God in all who live godly lives ; and it matters little whether they are in
                                material form, or freed therefrom. In spirit and essence they are one. I love to commune with such
                                spirits—to mingle my thoughts and feelings with theirs— and from them draw strength and inspirational power.
                                It is invigorating to drink of spiritual waters which flow in such channels, and to be immersed in them. Do
                                we not, at times, see and feel the Christ spirit — in dove form—coming to bless and approve, when we receive
                                the same baptisms that Jesus was baptized with ? That spirit leads to humility — loving simplicity — devoid
                                of worldly pride and haughty mien, in thought, word and action. When selfishness and vain ambition are
                                subdued, then is the soul exalted, and made noble. I am thankful to call all such by the endearing name of
                                brother and sister. They are bright lights in the pathway of weary pilgrims, who are journeying to their
                                heavenly home, and who joyfully bear the Christian's cross, for the sake of the reward that it brings. I
                                want to tell you that now, while I am writing, I feel the spirits, of many of the dear departed Saints,
                                gathering near, and their influence over me is like the breath of the morning — healthful — and inspiring. I
                                am impressed that the present, to them, as to us, is a season of great interest; it being the Centennial
                                anniversary of the arrival of these messengers, to Columbia's shores, who brought the glad tidings of full
                                salvation from sin, by the cross of Christ. Is it not their present mission to infuse new life into the
                                testimony which they then bore, and to give new impetus to the work which they, by the revelation then
                                given, commenced ? They planted the seed, and left it to be cultivated by their successors, who would be
                                aided by increasing light of divine revelation. Jesus told his disciples, that after he had passed from
                                their visible presence, they would be empowered to perform greater works than he had done. The first
                                founders of the Millennial Church, virtually left the same testimony. They said, while looking through
                                prophetic lens, " We see the Church of Christ's Second Appearing, rising in glory and beauty! There is glory
                                beyond glory; and to its growth in goodness and perfection, there will be no end! Its increase, at the
                                commencement, was necessarily slow. The religion, which those Witnesses taught and lived, was unpopular, and
                                unpalatable ; for it was like a sharp sword to divide " flesh and spirit;" and the pharisaical priesthood,
                                churchgoers, and lovers of sensuality, were alike strong in denunciation and persecution. The little Band
                                had to work their way through privation, toil, suffering of soul and body, which few of the present
                                generation are able to realize ; but they were visited and fed by Angels, and were thus sustained. They
                                passed through great tribulation, but continued faithful to the charge committed to their trust, until they
                                had finished the work on earth given them to do. May the present toilers in the field never grow weary in
                                well doing, nor lose sight of the deep humility and dependence, on a higher power, that our first parents
                                possessed, in the earnestness of spirit which they manifested at all times — morning, noon and eventide. May
                                we also possess and show forth, in practical life, that we have been baptized with the same spirit. Then, we
                                shall be lifted above earthly attractions and walk with them in white, as they were lifted up to walk with
                                Christ and his angels. I am aware that many, outside of Zion, and some of the young within her courts, are
                                asking, What of the future? "We know not what a day may bring forth ; " but we do know that the powers of
                                the invisible worlds are moving; and if we watch and wait and have our lamps trimmed and burning, and are
                                clad in virgin purity, we shall be ready to advance when the Spirit calls us to come up still higher on the
                                plane of angelic life. Selfdenial, faith in God, and a dependence upon his power, will bear us onward, and
                                still onward, to rest in truth — in God. Fraternally thine,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Adams, Hester A." TEIform="persName"/>Hester A. Adams, Alfred, Me.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love that is true" TEIform="index"/>LOVE THAT IS TRUE</head><p TEIform="p">" True love worketh no evil." In meditating on the subject of true love, we find, in its meaning, a growth of the
                            higher life — a depth of pure aspiration, in which the inner feelings of the soul work in harmony with the
                            spirit of eternal good ; an element, which is intuitive in every human being, as an attribute of the Divine
                            Creator. As " the tree is known by its fruit," so is true love by its workings in the soul; which secure eternal
                            treasures, not only to individuals, but to the grand whole as one ; for its power is Omnipotent. Do we not learn
                            the lesson of love, from the example of our Savior? His life was a living testimony of this most noble
                            principle. And what were his workings ? Why, he toiled assiduously, for the benefit of humanity — for the
                            development of higher principles of enduring worth. At the expense of personal comfort, through sorrowing of
                            spirit, and trouble of soul, incessantly, he labored for the reclamation of virtue, — for the promulgation of a
                            pure religion, in which the souls of humanity, should work deeds of righteousness. And later, we are informed of
                            many, Christian pioneers, whose life-records, were filled with noble deeds, wrought through the spirit of true
                            love. Such characters claim our highest admiration. Much has been spoken, and written on the subject of love;
                            but where in its meaning known—its power felt? In the hearts of Christian toilers, whose endeavors are
                            concentrated in the ever progressive work of truth. Christ has said : " By this shall all men know that ye are
                            my disciples, if ye have love one for another." Here, then, is where we find our relation to the God-spirit.
                            True love is manifested in deeds of charity,—words of kindness — and acts of pure philanthropy. When we see the
                            effects of love's genial influence, on the sorrowing heart, how happy we feel ! Its cheering rays often permeate
                            the darkest recesses of life; and the shadows are bid to flee by its imperative, yet always soothing tones. The
                            grieved and oppressed, are caused to look up through the eyes of joy, and behold the dawn of a brighter day,
                            that is not to be followed by the night of sorrow. Again we perceive its workings, for reclamation. We see it
                            clasp the erring one, in its loving embrace, and mildly chide the evil power, that would tempt the soul from
                            virtue's path, and lead it in the broad road to destruction. And though gentle in its varied manifestations, its
                            influence is strong, and its power mighty; for it often conquers the most stubborn will — moves even the
                            universe by its magic touch ! It has achieved victories where its opposite spirit has suffered well-merited
                            defeat. Oh, blessed are the fountains of love ! from which the soul can sip, and be filled to overflowing. But
                            dreary, desolate, and sad is life,—void of its true meaning, where this most coveted gem is wanting. Love is the
                            rich soil, where grow the choicest plants of truth, on which the brightest flowers of virtue boom. And its
                            substance is the same, in the sunshine and storm. And, though the sun cease to shine, and Earth pass away, the
                            principles of true love will endure forever. And when the souls of humanity shall have attained a condition of
                            purity — then shall they know the supremacy of true love, over the false, earthly element, that so often claims
                            this title ; but which is only a spurious article at best. True love, is the Christ-spirit, working in, and
                            through the soul, leading it ever onward, even unto perfection.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Neal, Sarah Ann" TEIform="persName"/>Sarah Ann Need, Watervliet, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Time, improved, is wealth" TEIform="index"/>TIME, IMPROVED, IS WEALTH</head><p TEIform="p">The proper improvement of time is a subject upon which much has been said and written ; the importance of which
                            cannot be over-estimated ; for the weal or woe of our race depends upon it. The necessity of hand labor, also
                            the advantages derived therefrom, both in a physical and moral point of view, calls for earnest thought. The
                            scripture injunction, " They who will not work neither shall they eat," is as just as it is wise. Could the
                            public be brought to understand and feel, that no person, possessing physical and mental ability, should be
                            considered a good citizen without working at some useful employment, of what incalculable benefit it would be to
                            all classes. Soon would the wilderness bloom like Eden, and barren lands become a terrestrial paradise. It
                            should be borne in mind by all, rich and poor, that honest laborers in the community, are the heart— the
                            sustaining element in our Republic. Those who are young in years would do well to give attention to the
                            cultivation of the mind, as well as to proper physical labor. Both are essential to the formation of good and
                            true characters. Young people who perform little, or no manual labor, are apt to neglect the mental exertion
                            which is necessary to govern the thoughts; and they are left unrestrained to roam at large, and build air
                            castles, and form plans for after life, which, at more mature age, are found to be impracticable. In imagination
                            they rise on fancy's J^NT) <pb n="23" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> 8HAKEEE88. 23 wings and explore unknown regions — launch out
                            upon creation's broad expanse — thus giving latitude to thoughts which are fallacious, and no one can tell where
                            they will lead. In this way, the mind oftentimes becomes confused, and exhausted ; when it should ever be kept
                            vigorous, and receptive to good and true influences. Youth, is a good time to curb the thoughts — to direct them
                            aright and cause them to flow in a proper channel. They, who are wise enough to pursue thig course, while
                            forming their character, will find true enjoyment; and as they develop, will become more and more beautiful in
                            the sight of men and Angels. Passions, indulged in the mind, generally lead to action. Thought, plans the deed,
                            whether good or evil; and crime of almost every grade is the product of idleness. Watts said truly — "Satan
                            finds some mischief still, for idle hands to do." It is true that some, who have been thus led astray, in their
                            youth have by the aid of friends and great exertions of their own, become good members of society. But, ask them
                            what it cost to retrace their steps and return to the path of rectitude ? They will tell you, the cost cannot be
                            counted; and if they had learned the important lesson of governing their thoughts they would never have wandered
                            into the paths of sin and demoralizing habits. And be it ever remembered, that every evil, withstood, gives
                            additional strength and power of resistance; while every indulgence detracts therefrom. Each step in the
                            downward track, must not only be repented of, but must be retraced. Thus great delay is caused in the soul's
                            ascension to the higher plane of life; and many times courage fails in the attempt — the fruit of wrong-doing ;
                            whereas, every evil passion denied, gives impetus to progression; and souls will ascend from one degree to
                            another, till they reach the goal of perfection.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bathrick, Eunice" TEIform="persName"/>Eunice Bathrick, Ayer, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reverie, or vision" TEIform="index"/>REVERIE, OR VISION</head><p TEIform="p">At an early hour of the morning — while the dew was yet upon the tender grass — my spirit seemed to take flight
                            and wing its way over hill and dale. The birds were singing merrily, — the air was filled with sweet melody,—
                            and my mind was replete with heavenly sensations. At length, I seemed to near a beautiful grove, surrounded by
                            hills; and my angel guide, who had accompanied me, said, " The name of this place is Canaan." I there saw
                            stately forest trees — wild flowers — bubbling rills ; and every thing around appeared green and living, and
                            filled with the spirit of praise. I was charmed with the beauties above me, and on every side, and I exclaimed,
                            0 beautiful land of Canaan! what glory do I behold in thee ! I was lost in admiration. All was calm. A holy
                            stillness seemed to pervade, as if angels bad descended to bless ; and in gentle tones they whispered, " This is
                            hallowed ground ! " And they spread a covering over the consecrated spot, as if to shield from the scorching
                            rays of the sun, and protect from storms that might arise. As I stood gazing, I heard something that sounded
                            like the tramping of horses' feet, and of chariot wheels — then the footsteps of an army followed— and anon, I
                            beheld beautiful forms, and bright faces, and heard voices. I listened to catch the sound. They were not strange
                            voices to me, I recognized most of them ; and learned that some of the goodly shepherds from the Mount, had come
                            down with their flocks, that they might feed in green pastures, and rest at noon-day. One could hardly refrain
                            from calling to mind the words of the prophet Jeremiah, when he foretold the return of Judah, and Jerusalem from
                            captivity, and God would accomplish the good thing that He had promised. " The Branch should grow up unto David,
                            and judgment and righteousness be executed in the land." Then, He would bring health and cure to Judah and
                            Jerusalem, and the scattered flocks should be gathered, and again pass under the hand of the prophets. And they
                            should dwell in safety; the voice of joy and gladness would be heard; the voice of the bridegroom and bride ;
                            and the voice of them that say — praise the Lord. Again, as I looked upon the dear ones in human form, I said, "
                            These must be numbered with some of the fairest flowers that ever bloomed on Zion's soil; here too, are many
                            opening buds of promise." Parents and children have here joined hands, and each has a blessing for the other.
                            Early vows of consecration,—to live innocently before God, and all the brethren and sisters — are renewed. All
                            speak peace, courage and strength, the one to the other, and point out the shining way of purity which leads up
                            to the golden gates of the city of God, No uncleanness — nothing that is false — that would create strife and
                            division, and hurt or harm in this holy mountain of God, which rises above all other hills, will be suffered to
                            pass through those gates. While I was listening to the sweet strains of music, a voice said to me, " Contrast
                            the two planes of life — the natural and the spiritual. By the fruits produced, you may know them. One is light
                            — the other — dark. They who sow to the fleshly lusts of generation, from that source reap corruption and
                            sorrow. While those who lay down their selfish, carnal lives, and sow to the spirit, reap joy — peace — and life
                            everlasting." It would be vain for me to undertake to narrate all the interesting incidents — pleasant scenes —
                            instructive lessons, and soul communings, which I saw, heard and felt, while I tarried with the lovely company
                            in that goodly land. When my guide reminded me that the day was far spent, and that other duties required my
                            attention, I reluctantly said, " Farewell." And as I wended my way homeward, I remarked, " Science, theology,
                            and all branches of literature which tend to uplift humanity, have my high esteem and appreciation. But the
                            lessons that I have studied and learned to-day, are dearer to me; for they are so simple, direct and truthful,
                            that they come right home to the soul. They are sweet, like angel music to the ear, — and balsam to the heart.
                            The richest tones of music that I ever heard, were the effusions of hearts and voices, whose lives were in
                            harmony with truth, and one continual song of praise to God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gillespie, Mary A." TEIform="persName"/>Mary A. Grillespie, West Gloucester, Me.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Testimonial" TEIform="index"/>TESTIMONIAL</head><p TEIform="p">Eldress Antoinette : Dear Sister. — I feel moved to give expression to a few feelings which swell up from my
                            heart at this time, relative to our aged brethren and sisters who have been pioneers in the Gospel work in our
                            own day — faithful guides and shining lights in our path-way. I feel that I owe to them a great debt of
                            gratitude, and would gladly offer a tribute of love and thanks not only to those in my own loved home, but to
                            all of the aged believers in Zion, who have so earnestly done the work of their time, and been noble examples of
                            godliness to the rising generation. It has been my privilege to spend about forty-four years of my life, where I
                            have had daily intercourse with a large class who might properly be called the Ancients of the present spiritual
                            Israel of God. My testimony regarding them is, I have never seen a carnal action in them — have never heard a
                            carnal speech from them. They have been examples of humility, and patterns of truthfulness to me. They toiled to
                            lay a foundation, in temporal and spiritual things, that a temple might be built — a home prepared — for honest
                            sin-sick souls to gather to, away from Babylonish captivity, and the fierce storms of passion that are raging
                            without. They sacrificed their own personal comfort for the good of others. And shall not those who have reaped
                            the blessings which they sowed, return blessing for blessing, and revere their memory ? They are now leaving the
                            shores of time — passing from our midst one by one ; but few of that class now remain with us, and those we hold
                            as a special blessing to the whole household of faith. I have witnessed the departure from the scenes of time of
                            many of those dear fathers and mothers, and their spirits were peaceful, calm and triumphant. The mortal part
                            was feeble, faint and weary ; but their spirits were strong and vigorous. Like fledged birds, they were ready to
                            respond to the spirit's call, and wing their way to a new home in the spirit land — there to commence a new
                            travel, and progress to still greater attainments in light, life and love. ] never heard any one of them express
                            the idea that they were perfected in truth, and that there was nothing more for them to attain unto. But they
                            have done the work of tlieir day, and we speak peace unto them, and would suffer much, rather than to do or saj'
                            aught to wound or grieve the feelings of one of those goodly servants of God, and we believe that the angels
                            will say, " Well done ! " The prophet Esdras was inspired to compare the judgment work to a ring : " Like as
                            there is no slackness in the last, even so there is no swiftness to the first." We are indebted to all the
                            prophets, the saints and seers of the ages ;— all have had their mission to perform. The Jews received laws
                            relating to agriculture and physiology, and their attention was chiefly turned to external natural truths
                            pertaining to material things. In the beginning of this Gospel work, the attention of the first toilers in the
                            field was directed to the soul needs, and to do the battle against inward foes ; even the king of all passions,
                            " fleshly lusts which war against the soul " Each was accepted in his or her work. Now if the time has come or
                            is approaching when their successors in the field feel called upon to combine the physical truths of the Jewish
                            dispensation with the more spiritual work of the Christian era, can we not recognize therein the prophetic ring,
                            as one continuous work of God through succeeding dispensations ? no slackness to the last, even as there is no
                            swiftness to the first. Paul said of God's suffering witnesses and the martyrs of former ages, "that through
                            faith they obtained a good report; but without us could not be made perfect." While they would have need of the
                            more spiritual soul work of the latter day saints, Is it not quite possible that we may also learn something of
                            the Jews in relation to agriculture and physiology ? If this be so, then we understand how the "judgment work"
                            may justly be compared to a " ring." Hence, when we say that the Jews, as a people, who abstained from sin by
                            compulsory law, need also, by greater love to truth and purity, to learn the Christian principle of crucifying
                            the nature whence sin proceeds ; we do not diminish their glory, neither take away their reward. And should we
                            say that Believers may learn of the Jews in many things pertaining to the physical, it would not detract one
                            particle from the beauty and glory of their lives, nor the spiritual renown which they have justly earned. So we
                            repeat, honor, peace and blessing rest upon the aged worthies in Zion — our pilgrim fathers and mothers.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brainard, Jane M." TEIform="persName"/>Jane M. Brainard, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><pb n="24" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home of peace" TEIform="index"/>HOME OF PEACE</head><p TEIform="p">Home, home, home I There's beauty rife on every side, At golden morn and even-tide ; Home, sweet home I And music
                            in the tranquil air, That floats around thy borders fair, Home, sweet home ! The world has lost its charms for
                            me, For purer joy I find in thee, -*----*—. O, home, sweet home ! Joy which the world can never know, In thee
                            from sacred love doth flow, O, home, sweet home ! A holy peace unmarred by sin, Is graven on thy walls within ;
                            And sacred orders guard thee round, And safely shield on hallowed ground, Home, sweet home !</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peebles, J.M." TEIform="index"/>J. M. PEEBLES</head><p TEIform="p">How prospers the Shaker and Shakbress ? In this transition state of tlie world tlie newspaper lias become the
                            missionary — the avenue of knowledge to the unsettled unsatisfied masses. Many will read a daily paper or a
                            monthly journal, that would not hear a sermon or attend a leeture. It was a timely move, the starting of the
                            "Shaker." It has comforted the sad, strengthened the weak, encouraged the disheartened, revealed the heavenly
                            genius of the order, and enlightened multitudes, who as yet choose to walk in the outer " Courts of the
                            Gentiles." This is a period of progress. It is a very little thing to be a bit of fossil, and not much more to
                            be an oyster. To say that oysters move, or that oysters come out when raked out, is not saying much in their
                            favor; and so for (an individual or) a society to advance only as 'tis pushed or pulled by noble reformatory
                            souls, all aflame with inspiration, is paying it no very high compliment. God, by the voice of immutable law, or
                            by revelation, says progress or die. Inaction is death. " Go on," said the apostle," unto perfection "— " from
                            that ye may obtain "— " press on toward the mark "— the import of these passages, with the " issuing waters,"
                            seen in Ezekiel's vision cannot be mistaken. The true man, it seems to me, must be both conservative and
                            radical, both continuous and progressive. While holding on with a terrible tenacity to the good of the past, he
                            must have an open mind for the reception of every newly demonstrated fact in science, or truth in religion.
                            Revelation is perpetual. God is not asleep, nor are the angels dozing under shade trees in glory. The
                            progressive spirit that pervades a large portion of the Shaker and Shakeress charms me. I trust that its
                            circulation is rapidly increasing. Can you not enlarge it ? The world needs its teachings. I was delighted with
                            your articles in the New York Tribune upon the materialization of spirits. Will you not publish them in the
                            Shaker and Shakeress 1 They cannot have a too wide circulation. Since conversing with Prof. Crookes of London
                            and visiting the Eddys in Vermont, I have not had a doubt of the fact that materialized spirits again walk the
                            earth, as in the days of the patriarchs and prophets. The signs of the times are ominous. Already the " fig-tree
                            puts forth." The angels are crying " Come up higher." Are our " lamps trimmed and burning ? "</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good editor" TEIform="index"/>A Good Editor.</head><p TEIform="p">A journal has made the discovery that "it is easier to find a dozen good newspaper writers than it is to find one
                            good newspaper editor." This will hardly be regarded in the light of an important discovery by the public at
                            large, for it requires but a very slight knowledge of newspapers to know that their success depends not so much
                            on the ability of the individual writers, as upon the tact and generalship of their conductors.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Davis, Philena" TEIform="index"/>Philena Davis
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Davis, Philena" TEIform="persName">Philena Davis</persName>, April 8, 1874, at Enfield, N. H., aged 73
                            years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bartholomew, Judith" TEIform="index"/>Judith Bartholomew
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Bartholomew, Judith" TEIform="persName">Judith Bartholomew</persName>, August 15, 1874, Enfield, N. H., aged 88
                                years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Russell, Mary" TEIform="index"/>Mary Russell
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Russell, Mary" TEIform="persName">Mary Russell</persName>, Sept. 1, 1874, Enfield, N. H., aged 62 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Parkhurst, Hannah" TEIform="index"/>Hannah Parkhurst
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Parkhurst, Hannah" TEIform="persName">Hannah Parkhurst</persName>, Nov. 1, 1874, Enfield, N. H., aged 88
                            years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Simpson, Olive" TEIform="index"/>Olive Simpson
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Simpson, Olive" TEIform="persName">Olive Simpson</persName>, Nov. 16, 1874, Alfred, Maine, aged 70 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Frost, Joseph" TEIform="index"/>Joseph Frost
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Frost, Joseph" TEIform="persName">Joseph Frost</persName>, Dec. 6, 1874, West Gloucester, Maine, aged 81
                            years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Parsons, Elce" TEIform="index"/>Elce Parsons
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Parsons, Elce" TEIform="persName">Elce Parsons</persName>, Dec. 16, 1874, Enfield, Conn., aged 75 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="McQuier, Minerva" TEIform="index"/>Minerva McQuier
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="McQuier, Minerva" TEIform="persName">Minerva McQuier</persName>, Jan. 4, 1875, Harrison, O., aged 83 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Williams, Sylvia" TEIform="index"/>Sylvia Williams
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Williams, Sylvia" TEIform="persName">Sylvia Williams</persName>, Jan. 9, 1875, Hancock, Mass., aged 75
                            years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wentworth, Isaiah" TEIform="index"/>Isaiah Wentworth
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Wentworth, Isaiah" TEIform="persName">Isaiah Wentworth</persName>, Jan. 10,1875, Enfield, Conn., aged 58
                            years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Crouch, Martha" TEIform="index"/>Martha Crouch
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Crouch, Martha" TEIform="persName">Martha Crouch</persName>, Jan. 12, 1875, Harvard, Mass., aged 66 years and 6
                                months.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bridges, Hannah" TEIform="index"/>Hannah Bridges
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Bridges, Hannah" TEIform="persName">Hannah Bridges</persName>, Jan. 13, 1875, Harvard, Mass., aged 93 years 9
                                months and 2 days.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To our gospel kindred of the household of faith" TEIform="index"/>TO OUR GOSPEL KINDRED OF THE HOUSEHOLD OF FAITH</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Friends. — The Society of New Gloucester, Maine, have had the misfortune, to lose, by fire, their
                            extensive cooper-shop, with its machinery for manufacturing shook, together with a large quantity of staves.
                            Loss, over $3,000. They have previously, at different times, suffered losses in personal estate by fraudulent
                            agents, in amounts, large to them. They have rigorous climate, sterile, rocky soil—poor buildings, which they
                            are unable to repair or rebuild. One dwelling-house now occupied, is almost uninhabitable from its dilapidated
                            condition. For the last few years removal from Alfred and West Gloucester has been contemplated, but not
                            consummated. The project is now abandoned, it being determined to remain, repair and rebuild, as they can
                            accomplish. They need help from without. If believers will unite and contribute of their consecrated property
                            according to ability and gifts of charity, from one dollar to two hundred dollars from each family, to the West
                            Gloucester family, it will be highly appreciated, and the greater blessing of the giver over the receiver will
                            rest upon the whole Order. A beginning of $ 100 made.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ministry at Mount Lebanon" TEIform="persName"/>Ministry at Mount Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker music books" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER MUSIC BOOKS</head><p TEIform="p">For the use of schools among Believers. Contains all the pieces that have appeared in the Shaker and Shakeress
                            and some forty new songs. A beautiful book. Published by Weed, Parsons &amp; Co. Price 40 cents. A.ND 24</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>