<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2502" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">25</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><date value="18950201" TEIform="date">February 1895</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">25-48</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="25" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
FEBRUARY.
THE
MANIFESTO
PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES.
Vol. XXV.
" Cast thy bread upon the waters ; for thou shalt find it after many days."
Eccl. XI: i.
East Canterbury, N. H.
1895.
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
cAVEATSJRADE MARKS
COPYRIGHTS.
sell our choice aim
hardy ISTursery Stock, and Seed 1"Vioes, full and complete line.     Many vaeties can  only be obtained through us.
ouimission or  salary  paid  weekly, and
promptly.    Exclusive and choice of  territory given.     Don't delay,    write  at om-i
for terms.
ALLEN NURSERY CO.
Rochester, N. Y.
CAN I OBTAIN A PATENT? Fora
prompt answer and an honest opinion, write to
M UNN fc CO., who have had nearly fifty years'
experience in the patent business. Communications strictly confidential. A Handbook of Information concerning Patents and bow to obtain them sent free. Also a catalogue Of mechanical and scientiflo books sent free.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
pecial notice in the Scientific Aiiiericnn, and
thus are brought widely before the public without cost to the inventor. This splendid paper,
issued weekly, elegantly illustrated, has by far the
largest circulation of any scientific work in the
world.   $3 a year.   Sample copies sent free.
Building Edition, monthly, $2.50 a year. Single
copies, iJ5 cents. Every number contains beautiful plates, in colors, and photographs of new
houses, with plans, enabling builders to show the
latest designs and secure contracts.  Address
MUNN & CO., New Youk, 3<J1 BROADWAY.
WANTED!
Agent to sell our new book, Dictionary of
United States History, by Prof. J. Fkanklin Jameson. Needed by every teacher, pu"
pil, and family; indorsed. Agents selling fifty books per week. Successful agents wilj
be made general agents.   Higr pay.
PURITAN PUBLISHING CO., Boston. Mass.
THE DIVINE AFFLATUS,
A
FORCE IN HISTORY.
Price, 10 cts.
THE   ALTRUIST.
1.8 a, monthly paper, partly in 1'honei->aspelling, and devoted to common proper
ty, united labor, OoinnmnHy homes, am!
"ltia.1 rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members ail
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in tilling
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. ">0 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Lonuley
2 N. Fourth St.,   St. Louis, Mo.
A
SHAKER'S   ANSWER
To  THE   OFT   KEI'EATEl)   QUESTION.
"What   will    become   of   the
World, if all become Shakers?"
Price, 10 cts.
the shaker covenant.
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS   OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES  and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION     AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
the same time, afford instruction to all  inquiring  minds.    Price 5  ets   each,  postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
CONTENTS
Reliable men
WANTED.
Music, Life's Infinity
Home Notes
Exchanges
Letter  D. Orcutt                                                                 !
Glorious Cross
Whatever is the Best.                                     IH
Books & Papers
The Mind
Sunshine and Shadow
Household of Faith
History of South Union, No. 16
Christian Faith
Confession
North Family
Preaching
Page--><pb n="25" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="History of South Union, Kentucky, no. 16" TEIform="index"/>HISTORY OF SOUTH UNION, KY. NO.
                            16.</head><p TEIform="p">NOV. 28. 1862. Some chicken-thieves break into the building where we keep our fowls, and
                            appropriate for their own use not less than two dozen nice chickens. To-night the
                            post-office at the station is entered and the mail bag cut open. Papers, envelops and
                            postage stamps are scattered about ths floor. They obtained a light by filling an old hat
                            with paper and then setting it on fire. It is a wonder they did not set the building on
                            fire. A paroled soldier from the company of John Morgan, calls at our Office to see some
                            children. Dec. 1. Two Federal soldiers, on beautiful horses ride through the streets this
                            evening. Soldiers come from Col. Shackelford's regiment. The Col. has been shot in the foot
                            and is lame. They tell of several persons who were executed, because they were true to the
                            Union flag. For many months we have been annoyed by the Confederate army only, but at
                            present we are visited from day to day by both armies, and at times it is difficult to tell
                            which makes us the most trouble. Following these armies are more or less lawless characters,
                            who under the name of soldiers either steal or rob as circumstances offer. Several of the
                            Brethren are at times engaged for days in search of stolen horses. For the food and lodging
                            of some seventy or more soldiers, we are unable to get any compensation. The government
                            Officers say we must run our own risks, if we provide food for the soldiers we must look to
                            the soldiers for pay. The cabins of the negroes are examined by Confederate men, and
                            FEBRUARY, <pb n="26" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 26 THE MANIFESTO. their trunks searched, but we have no
                            knowledge what it is for. Elder Solomon Rankin who went to see what was being done, said it
                            seemed very much as though they were searching for money. They pretended to fear an uprising
                            among the negroes. Dec. 23. Six negroes from our hired help, serenaded us, last evening at
                            about ten o'clock. They made of it quite a pleasant and lively time. Many of the poor
                            creatures are anxiously looking for the time to come when they shall be free. Br. Urban
                            Johns has been several times to Louisville to purchase some things for the Society, but it
                            is with extreme difficulty that he is able to have them brought home. The soldiers control
                            the freight cars and use them for transporting army supplies. Gen. Morgan and his soldiers
                            have been the surprise for several months. His rapid movements from place to place is an
                            astonishing phase in his career. As his soldiers are sometimes dressed in the uniform of the
                            Federals, they make captives very easily. The negroes are often hunted by these soldiers,
                            like wild beasts. While Elder Harvey Eads was at Bowling Green he tried to obtain a
                            newspaper that was published at Nashville, Tenn., but was unable to procure one. The dealer
                            in papers said there were five hundred applicants for two dozen papers. JANUARY, 1863. Jan.
                            1. The new year begins rather unpleasantly. Extensive warlike preparations are being made by
                            both the North and South, and the destructive battles are still going on. Human life is at a
                            fearful discount, and to execute men or to shoot them down for expressing an opinion, is an
                            occurrence of every day. The country is overrun with wild, reckless characters, who are
                            committing every form of crime and then go unpunished. Revolvers and bowie knives are
                            flourished in the faces of old and young alike and he is a fortunate man who escapes with
                            either his life or his money. Jan. 9. Nine refugees from Georgia pass through our Village.
                            These persons are almost destitute of money or clothing. All these conditions come from the
                            savagery of war, which is more cruel than the grave. Thirty-six Union soldiers, who are out
                            on a foraging expedition, make a halt for the night in our door-yard and order a supper for
                            the men and forage for the horses. They request lodging and breakfast and then make free to
                            say that they shall not pay for it. Some of the Brethren think this worse treatment than
                            they have received from the Confederates. The southern soldiers generally ask permission of
                            the Brethren, but these Michigan soldiers demanded what they chose. All are however
                            comfortably provided for, and we prepare a supper of new buscuits and corn bread, fried
                            pork, sausages, sassafras tea with sugar and cream, and a good supply of fresh milk. They
                            also have the best of sweet potatoes and several gallons of <pb n="27" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 27 canned peaches. The Officers took their supper in the Trustees' office, aud
                            fan d more sumptuously. Jan. 10. This morning the soldiers take breakfast, and have loaf
                            bread and new buscuits, corn bread, sweet potatoes, fried pork, eggs, sausages, onions,
                            stewed apples, butter, sassafras and sage tea, with cream and sugar and a liberal supply of
                            milk. We may hope that after all this care and kindness, they go will away to their duty, a
                            better class of men than when they came to us. They are ready to march at about eight
                            o'clock, a. m. and the Officers are in a very pleasant frame of mind. The Lieutenant
                            jokingly remarks, "Well, you have fed thirty-six men and they are all leaving you in a
                            pleasant mood, and you have just that many more friends. You may yet need our assistance,
                            and if any of you will come up to our camp we will treat you." That was but poor
                            compensation for our services, yet it was the best we could get. On referring this case to
                            Brigadier Gen. Munson, he said, "Those wagoners and soldiers went off without orders, and I
                            will arrest the Officers. If they had been sent they would have presented printed vouchers.
                            I will send a guard to your Village and prevent any further trespass." Feb. 25. Sunday.
                            While we are in meeting two hundred soldiers pass through the Village. They loiter in the
                            street and about the well, and finally march on at the sound of their fife and drum.
                            Fourteen army wagons soon follow the soldiers. In February, the guerrillas set fire to the
                            R. R. station and destroy two thousand bu. of corn, three thousand bu. of wheat, several
                            hogsheads of tobacco and some bales, of cotton cloth. In all, the loss was some $6500.00
                            After the burning of the station and the corn, a company of Union soldiers were sent to look
                            after the government property, and not finding horses enough for their present use they came
                            to the Village and ordered us to let them have two. Feb. 27. Some of these stray
                            Confederates set fire to fifteen cars that are filled with mules for the Federal government,
                            and they all perish in the flames. It is a cruel death, but war turns men into brutes. As
                            Kentucky is again in the hands of the Union soldiers they are very active in their search
                            for the outlaws and indeed for all who rebel against the government. The soldiers are
                            engaged in war as much on Sunday as on any day of the week. Christian soldiers are Sabbath
                            breakers, and breakers of the sixth commandment, "Thou shalt not kill." April, 1. These are
                            terrible times and the state of society seems like a whirlwind. The storm comes upon us
                            without mercy. Coffee in Richmond is one dollar a cup. Flour is seventy dollars a bbl. and
                            in some places bread is one dollar a pound. April, 12. We enjoy a very pleasant season of
                            worship, although we are <pb n="28" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 28 THE MANIFESTO. ' visited on the Sabbath, as
                            on other days, with every grade of company. May the dear Lord watch over us and protect us
                            from all harm. April, 22. Not less than sixty guerrillas are in the woods about some four
                            miles distant from our Village. They use very strong, threatening language and by this
                            frighten a great many people. They steal all the horses they can, and if resisted murder the
                            people. April, 23. Wars and rumors of wars are on ev^ry hand and the horrors of war are a
                            daily occurrence. Five Federal soldiers went to the house of a doctor by the name of
                            Merrill. The Lieutenant walked in and informed the doctor that they had come to arrest him.
                            "I will not be arrested," said the doctor. "By what authority do you come here ? " The
                            Lieutenant drew his six shooter and presenting it said,"This is my authority." Instantly a
                            ball struck the doctor in the breast, who as suddenly jerked the pistol from the Officer and
                            shot him dead. The doctor then killed another soldier and mortally wounded the third. The
                            other two soldiers fled. The above is a representation of southern life at the present time.
                            Murder and robbery is the work of every day. April, 30. A day for National Fast, agreeably
                            to a proclamation by the President. The Society meet at 10 o'clock a. m. and hold a
                            religious service. May, 4. Six suspicious characters enter our Village to-day and seem to be
                            making quite a close examination. As several Brethren are at home, the strangers do not
                            attempt to do any harm. (To be continued.) [NOTE, referring to the History of South Union:
                            January, 23rd, on page 174, should be inserted on page 151. Page 197 which has January, 4th,
                            should be January, 28. The date, 1864, on page 269 should be 1862.]</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian faith" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN FAITH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sutton, Elizaette" TEIform="persName"/>By Elizaette Sutton.</byline><p TEIform="p">THE views and practice of our people seem so consistent to me with the life of Christ, that I
                            feel to write an article on "Christian Faith," which has wrought a continuous work in me for
                            over half a century. Now, in my advanced age, the living panorama moves before me as a clear
                            mirror, showing the successive steps taken, fitting me for a true membership in the kingdom
                            so faithfully won by our Savior. He was a celibate of the highest type; renowned, praised
                            and worshipped for nearly nineteen hundred years as a Redeemer of mankind. His fame <pb n="29" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 29 and labor began with the lowly of earth's
                            inhabitants. He gathered a class of poor fishermen around him, and led them in the paths of
                            peace, lie taught them to beat their swords into ploughshares and their spears into
                            pruning-hooks and to live in a brotherhood association, acting upon the principle of
                            communism. He taught them to lay a broad and everlasting foundation for Christian faith
                            where love is enthroned, dominating over animosity and war. Following this rule, that
                            "whosoever shall smite thee on thy right cheek, turn to him the other also." This puts an
                            end to strife and establishes harmony on earth. How does faith and doctrine impress mankind
                            to-day ? The prophecy was of the little stone cut out of the mountain. It should grow and
                            fill the whole earth; Can this be understood as a legal statement? Jesus said, emphatically,
                            if you would be my disciples, you must take up the cross and follow me. The Christian's hope
                            is not languishing. Pentecostal fires are still burning and signs are given, that the
                            nations are flowing together, under one banner singing God's praises. "Bring your tithes
                            into the store-house and prove me herewith, saith the Lord; I will pour out a blessing that
                            there shall not be room enough to receive it." Faith that blossoms, will bear its legitimate
                            fruit unto eternal life. The call to a Christian life is constant duty, so pure, so high, so
                            noble, so grand, we may say, thatxsome people feel that they can not attain to it. The
                            pleasure of duty is to be learned, to have it a success. We see, we desire, we act upon it
                            and half the battle is fought. Faith is like a diamond cut by love and purifies the heart.
                            The cost of this substance, is the whole of self. Without faith, it is impossible to please
                            God. Nothing but the cross of Christ, will bring us into his life and character. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Confession" TEIform="index"/>CONFESSION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sevester, Edwin P." TEIform="persName"/>By Edwin P. Sevester.</byline><p TEIform="p">VTTE read in the Old Testament that the Mosaic law required if any had V V transgressed, that
                            the transgressor offer upon the altar an animal, confessing his sins before the High-Priest
                            and the people, and slaying the animal as a burnt-offering to God. (Lev. i, 45.) This is a
                            type of our own fallen nature ; this is the animal we must lay upon the altar of Truth, and
                            slay by confessing our sins before God's Witnesses. This was done in the third dispensation;
                            but was shamefully abused by antichrist and was restored in its purity in the fourth
                            dispensation. Having confessed and forsaken our sins we walk in the regeneration, having put
                            off the old man. <pb n="30" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 30 THE MANIFESTO. We manifest this in our outward
                            deportment, living a pure, el &gt;au life, a healthful spiritual atmosphere surrounding us and
                            others who lik us stand confessed before God. Born as we art with appetites at variance with
                            the will of God, which it is not easy to conquer; for they struggle for life, and the longer
                            we indulge in passion, the stronger and the deeper the roots are growing. But if we gain
                            Eternal life, we must lose the natural, carnal life, for Jesus said, "Whosoever will save
                            his life, shall lose it; but whosoever shall lose his life for my sake and the gospel's the
                            same shall save it." The Apostle Paul, whose epistles I love to read, speaks frequently of
                            the dying of the old man, the dying of the body of sin. Put off the old man according to the
                            deceitful lusts and put on the new man, which after God is created in righteousness and true
                            holiness; old things have passed away, behold all has become new. The Jewish wars and the
                            destruction of their enemies, are symbols of the warfare against our imbred foes and the
                            destruction of our evil nature. But we can never gain the saving power over sin and a carnal
                            life in this present time, but by an honest confession of sin before God bringing to his
                            judgment our weaknesses and errors, with a full determination to forsake them forever. Souls
                            may seek to climb up some other way, but those who would be saved must enter in by this
                            "Door of Hope." Mother Ann and her faithful followers, all who have followed in her
                            footsteps, have found a power over all evil. This was gained only through faith, through
                            confession, through prayer and through struggle of soul. If we are faithful, power shall be
                            given us likewise to rule all nations. To be pure in heart, pure in thought, word and deed,
                            acting from right motives, rising above a fallen, evil nature, by obedience to the Gospel
                            with its discipline and regulations for our protection ; taking up a full and final cross
                            against the lawless passions of men. This brings peace and satisfaction to the soul, giving
                            more pleasure, more enjoyment and comfort than all the glittering pleasures of the world. I
                            can not offer sufficient praise to my Heavenly Parents for the surroundings of a good, pure
                            home, where are influences that attract the spirit upward, heavenward. For all this and my
                            association with the loved ones of the household I am deeply grateful. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North family" TEIform="index"/>NORTH FAMILY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>By Martha J. Anderson.</byline><p TEIform="p">~T~TTTTH loving greeting and a heart-felt wish for a happy and prosperVV ous year for our
                            fellow-laborers and co-workers, we, your devoted spiritual kindred of blessed Mt. Lebanon,
                            send this salutation and message <pb n="31" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 31 to all the churches
                            of our precious faith; a faith founded in practical righteousness, and the exemplification
                            of every Christian virtue. To the noble founders of our Order be all honor given; to their
                            faithful successors all praise. May the substantial good they have left as an inheritancethe
                            accumulation of a century's consecrated toilnever be scattered by unhallowed or unworthy
                            hands. They who would set aside as non-essential that which preserves unity and conformity,
                            are rather destroyers than builders; we all need wisdom and knowledge, and above all a
                            desire to conserve the good that has been attained through individual sacrifice and
                            selfsurrender. May our interest be for the larger life of pure, unselfish living; and our
                            love be broadening to the universal; then though the call may be to us to gather together in
                            closer fraternal relation as Societies, we shall feel that we are of one heart and mind,
                            Brethren and Sisters of the one fold of Christ. We are striving to be active and earnest,
                            have a desire to scatter abroad the knowledge of our Order, and for this purpose have had
                            several new tracts printed. The spirit of inquiry is abroad, have many letters to answer and
                            a goodly number are "almost persuaded," yet just miss of entering the strait gate and the
                            narrow way that leads to eternal life. Our family can report usual health, neither colds nor
                            sickness ; it is an unusually sickly time in the neighborhood; high altitude and hygienic
                            living exempt us from the plagues of Egypt in a great degree. With especial remembrance and
                            thanks to our good Editor and his worthy corps of helpers, for their labors in making our
                            monthly paper a light and a love-bearing messenger, we will close our rather lengthy
                            article. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Preaching" TEIform="index"/>PREACHING.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Danforth, Nancy G." TEIform="persName"/>By Nancy G. Danforth.</byline><p TEIform="p">WHEN quite young, more than fifty years ago, I attended a meeting where the preacher took for
                            his text the words from Revelation "Behold I come quickly; and my reward is with me, to give
                            to every man as his work shall be." Assuming the judgment-seat, he placed his audience on
                            the left and began dispensing the rewards. Presently a man in the audience arose and
                            exclaimed, "If you have got any of the love of God why, for God's sake don't you preach it
                            and not preach hell and d- - - - - - - - -n all the time ?" Though I was very young in
                            Christian experience it taught me a lesson which I have never forgotten, that we are all apt
                            to preach by either word or action whatever we possess. Then as servants of Christ it
                            becomes our duty to labor for that degree of the love of God that it will be easy to
                            manifest it at all times. We sometimes sing of the ' 'Better land where the fountains of
                            God's eter- <pb n="32" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 32 THE MANIFESTO. nal love overflow on every side." Why
                            not bring the "better land" to us now, by showing the love of God in all we do and say ? L?t
                            the fountains of love overflow to all, that they may know that we aro indeed the disciples
                            of the loving Teacher. Then there will be found no room for condemnation of brother or
                            sister when with that love or "charity which covers a multitude of sins," we turn from
                            beholding the faults of others and closely investigate our own with the view to
                            self-improvement. Then we can preach the love of God in such a manner that it will be felt
                            and acknowledged that there is a power above the powers of earth. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mind" TEIform="index"/>THE MIND.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>By Alonzo G. Hollister.</byline><p TEIform="p">IF the mind does not immediately grasp a truth presented to it in proper form of expression,
                            by meditating on the expression, or simply by now and then referring to it in thought, the
                            understanding will grow to its perfect comprehension, silently and unconsciously, as plants
                            grow from germination to flower and fruit. How often has the mind puzzled over an abstruse
                            or intricate question until quite confused, and after resting awhile without thinking of it,
                            being occupied with other matters, on taking it up again found it all clear. There is an
                            interior mind and memory, and an exterior mind and memory to each individual. The interior
                            pertains to the realm of spiritual ideas and existences. If it be sought unto, and
                            spiritual-mindedness cultivated by the interior, it will expand the exterior, or natural
                            understanding and impart knowledge of many things not otherwise perceived. Isaac Newton said
                            his great discoveries were made, by intending his mind upon the subject in hand. Just so a
                            spiritual idea faintly perceived, by intending the mind upon it, increases in clearness,
                            till it is fully revealed in the outer understanding. Faith is planted as a grain of mustard
                            seed, and is nourished by reflection and good works till it brings forth fruit to eternal
                            life. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Public spirit" TEIform="index"/>PUBLIC SPIRIT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>By Martha J. Anderson.</byline><p TEIform="p">fTlHE more we expand in spirit and feeling toward others, the more their JL interest becomes
                            ours, and we know no selfish sphere of duties and obligations. The man or woman who, having
                            great wealth, wisely considers some plan for its distribution, and dedicates a portion for
                            building and endowing an <pb n="33" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 3^ extensive
                            institution,either charitable or educationalis called a public benefactor. To be able to
                            become the liberal patron of art, science and literature, so that their benefits may be
                            extended for the uplifting and civilization of the musses, redounds also to the honor and
                            glory of those who gather but to give. All have not fortunes to disburse in vast enterprises
                            and thus win favor, and find a niche in the temple of honor; or leave a memorial that shall
                            inspire future generations to perpetuate his or her image in marble or bronze. Yet those who
                            can not do large things, can in small ways, add to the general good anil welfare of others
                            as far as their influence and assistance can be reasonably extended. The quiet Sister of
                            Mercy, who in plain garb and modest demeanor, goes from ward to ward among the poor and
                            afflicted, where danger lurks in foul disease, ever ministering help and consolation, while
                            she is rigidly denying self; sacrifices more for public weal, than he who gives a mun ficent
                            fund to build the hospital. The farmer who stops to mend a dangerous place in the road,
                            where he has just escaped accident, and fears lest his neighbor's horse may be injured ; who
                            throws a stone aside from the highway, or rights up a broken fence where cattle may escape,
                            is by small acts, nobly performing the part of the philanthropist. So also is the woman, who
                            with loving heart and constancy of purpose, goes about the house day by day, faithfully
                            performing the menial services that bring comfort to the home and peace to the family; and
                            when her soul expands beyond the narrow sphere of imposed duty and obligation, with what
                            pleasure she devotes her spare time and means to ameliorate undesirable conditions among
                            those less favored than herself. Trivial as may seem the amenities of life, who has not felt
                            blest by the tender word of sympathy, the gracious smile of favor, the helpful hand of
                            blessing, and affection's watchful care? All can not do gi'eat things; yet many through
                            ambition chafe under the bondage of allotted tasks, vaguely dreaming and trusting that some
                            broader field of labor will be open to them, wherein they can do something great to serve
                            and bless humanity, and while they are idealizing, perhaps they are neglecting to take up
                            the threads of life's work that lie tangled in their pathway, and which claim assiduity and
                            patience in the straightening out process. Some are over-anxious to distribute to the poor,
                            yet do very little toward furnishing the means. It is easy to say give, but while our hearts
                            wax warm, let our fingers respond practically, that we may sew, knit and mend; thus have of
                            our well-earned substance to produce in time of need; this is the true spirit of
                            benevolence. While in the orderly arrangement of a communal household, there are cer- <pb n="34" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 34 THE MANIFESTO. tain duties devolving upon each member, which must
                            be performed with regularity and precision ; yet, to the stronger or more capable, there
                            always comes a greater share, and double care; and while some toil a few hours, others know
                            no limit as to time, in the round of pressing business. How good it is for each one to be so
                            consecrated to the interest of the whole, that he will seek ways and means to quietly
                            relieve his brother or sister by doing some kindly act, thus help to lift the burdens. Some
                            individuals who are admitted into our well-organized families are at first greatly pleased
                            with the practical results of united effort, and think it delightful that every thing should
                            move so harmoniously. They would certainly be willing to work for others, and have their
                            allotted duties, it would seem so much easier than the way people generally labor. But when
                            they find that there is no remuneration of dollars and cents, and no spur of necessity
                            goading them, their zeal soon slackens, and they seek ways and means to evade labor as much
                            as possible; growing weary with the least effort ; keeping self uppermost, they fail not
                            only in doing that which is apportioned to them, but add nothing to the general good by
                            rendering assistance here and there when extra work is to be done. Some even who are quite
                            zealous in the general business fail to take cognizance of little items that need attention,
                            and by so doing manifest a public spirit. Who does not feel ashamed and rebuked, when he
                            sees some dear brother or sister who has toiled assiduously all day, and has deprived
                            themselves of the coveted morning nap, taking the outside door broom and sweeping the walks,
                            because they have the accumulated dirt of a week through which we have unconcernedly walked,
                            never thinking that it was as much our interest as theirs to have the yard kept tidy.
                            Thoughtless gardeners throw leaves, stones and sticks in the paths around the flower
                            gardens, or leave pots, boxes etc. for days, despoiling the beauty that might otherwise be
                            enjoyed unless some one shows the public spirit and hastens to set things in order. If all
                            would attend to the simple rule of putting every thing in its place, (as there is always a
                            place provided) then there would be less labor and confusion, and this rule applies to every
                            department, and apartment in our home. "Bear ye one another's burdens and so fulfill the law
                            of love" is opposed to the spirit that boastingly says, every individual can look out for
                            number one. The God-Hfe is embodied in the former, while the latter is the personification
                            of the selfism that rules the world, and holds mankind to the lower plane of being. Our
                            existence in this rudimental sphere is for a high and noble purpose, that we may unfold and
                            progress. Being creatures of free-will it lies in our power to extend the lines of worthy
                            action as far as our capabilities and powers will admit, and thus grow in the divinity of
                            our higher nature by the exercise of God-given faculties. <pb n="35" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 35 In our communal relation there is room for culture and improvement in a
                            liberal self-sacrificing spirit. We need not go very far to ascertain how much good we may
                            do, but let each morning bring to our hearts a new resolve, that shall prompt to the
                            exercise of a disinterested spirit of generous loving service. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sunshine and shadow" TEIform="index"/>SUNSHINE AND SHADOW.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webber, Sadie" TEIform="persName"/>By Sadie Webber.</byline><p TEIform="p">NATURE manifests to us in all her works that a combination of these elements is essential to
                            perfectly developed fruit. We all have had the misfortune to behold gardens upon which the
                            sun has poured forth its glory, from day to day, without the least intermission of shade;
                            but do they compare in beauty with those which have withstood both sunshine and rain? What
                            if the foliage does droop beneath the weight of moisture, a renewal of sunshine is able to
                            revive it again, which proves that the shadowy element, to a certain extent, is not
                            destructive. Now if sunshine and shadow thus favorably effect nature in more material works
                            are they not just as essential to the perfect formation of a Christian character? Can we
                            reasonably expect to be developed by a single force? The sunshine Christian can not bear
                            burdens and disappointments or baffle elements foreign to his disposition, for like the
                            flower which has received only the sunshine, he is deficient in the strength of character
                            which is derived from trial and testing of the spiritual ability. But we would not infer
                            that the sunlight is not essential, for we know the sullenness of dispositions which never
                            have been touched by it; life seems to them a burden; their tale is always of woe and their
                            very breath heaves the sigh of discontent; the shadows which were only blessings in
                            disguise, have been brooded over uutil they have created a morbid condition in the soul,
                            when if accepted in the spirit of "Thy will, O Lord, not mine be done," they would soften
                            the rough outlines and the peace of God would bring a recompense for the burden borne. For
                            beauty we would prefer a picture delicately tinted by lights and shades, so the soul is most
                            beautiful that endures both in sunshine and shadow, until molded from its own, into the
                            image of God. If we find circumstances which cause us to feel gloomy, let us remember this
                            quotation. "Disappointment, is a little black seed, which when planted in the soil of a
                            resigned heart, and warmed with the sunshine of hope will blossom into a sweet-scented rose
                            of delight and beauty." Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good temper is like a sunny day..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Good temper is like a sunny day...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Good temper is like a sunny day, it sheds its brightness on every thing.</p></div2><pb n="36" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Household of faith" TEIform="index"/>HOUSEHOLD OF FAITH. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">AS good as man may have been created "in the beginning" and holding as he did the privilege
                            of conversing with God, it is quite questionable if it ever occurred to him to form a
                            "household of faith," and it is equally questionable if the thought ever entered his mind,
                            either before or after the wonderful fall which he sustained, till he had passed through an
                            experience of at least four thousand years, the animal man in common with all other animals,
                            was more interested in asserting that "might was right" only and in obtaining rights and
                            privileges, than he was in letting fall what he already held in his grasp, to penetrate into
                            an unseen realm for treasures that do not minister to an animal existence. "An eye for an
                            eye and a tooth for a tooth," as a matter of business could be demonstrated to a
                            mathematical certainty and it was not till the great reformation of Moses was brought to
                            bear upon his life, and man was raised a few degrees above the "beasts that perish," that
                            they could be induced to study a more humane procedure and even under the ameliorating
                            influences their idea of faith was thoroughly amalgamated with that of selfish rights. The
                            destruction of cities with the indiscriminate slaughter of all the inhabitants, and the
                            savage cruelties that were inflicted by the victorious armies were no more calculated to
                            awaken the mind with a confidingfaith in that savage age than they would be to develop the
                            same quality of mind in the brutal representative of man at the present day. Moses presented
                            to the world a most wonderful work, of the disciplinary power over man. He accepted the
                            Hebrews as a nation of slaves and made them a victorious nation of free men. He found them
                            through the indulgence of eating and drinking, lost in all the excesses of the Egyptians,
                            and no less inheriting all their diseases ; but through a forced hygienic system of bread
                            and water, he took them from all sickness and made of them a nation that has been a wonder
                            on the earth. And yet they never heard of the "household of faith" till long after the
                            advent of Jesus. To create this household was not less a mirace than was the crossing of the
                            Red Sea. The man of righteousness and of faith had sown the seed, and the good husbandman
                            had cared for it till the day of its fruition, and then the Apostle in his glorious triumph,
                            could inspire his followers with a faith corresponding with that which he had l'ect ived.
                            a&amp; <pb n="37" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 37 ''Let us," said he, "do good unto all
                            men, especially unto them who are of the household of faith." Paul was as generous as he was
                            full of faith, he excluded no one from his good thoughts and good deeds, in that he exhoi-ts
                            his Church to do good to all men. Then comes that gospel relation for which he had forsaken
                            all the pleasures and treasures of this worlda relation just as near to him as was the
                            salvation of his own soul. From this relation "neither life nor death, nor principalities,
                            nor powers," ever could separate him. It was his love for God in Christ. It was included in
                            the mission of Jesus to go about doing good, and we can not very well become his disciples
                            unless we embody so important a work for the good of humanity into the life work which we
                            have accepted. The Christian's mission certainly is more than to eat and drink or to
                            accumulate the treasures of this world. All these may have their legitimate places in the
                            economy of life and if "used as not abusing them" may prove very acceptable. Although it
                            became the duty of Jesus, as a teacher, to encourage all that led to paths of righteousness,
                            yet he was severe in his rebuke of that which led to unrighteousness. "Except your
                            righteousness shall exceed that of the Scribes and Pharisees ye shall not enter the kingdom
                            of heaven." Jesus would have his disciples, who had received greater light from God, walk
                            more circumspectly before men. In this way they would let their light shine which they had
                            received from God. It was an active goodness that was demanded of these followers of Christ,
                            and certainly no less of the spirit of righteousness can be demanded of all who now name the
                            name of Christ. The "household of faith" is still a living reality in the hearts of the
                            faithful and with its sacred covenant is working for God in the interest of humanity. We
                            shall not hesitate to say to St. Paul that we will carefully concede to his wishes and
                            remember in a special mariner our beautiful "household of faith," in which may be found so
                            many earnest, anxious workers for peace on earth and good-will to all men. Our Church
                            Covenant which has been published recently in pamphlet form should be carefully studied by
                            every member of our gospel home. No excuse, except ignorance, can justify any Believer in
                            not being fully informed on this subject, as a copy can be obtained free by simply
                            addressing The Manifesto. A faithful continuance in well-doing by the covenantal members of
                            our gospel home must insure a continued peace and prosperity to our Community.</p></div2><pb n="38" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life's infinity" TEIform="index"/>LIFE'S INFINITY.</head><p TEIform="p">'Stand still and consider the wondrous works of God."Job. xxxvii., 14. Mt. Lebanon. N. Y. 1.
                            Where e'er with yearning hope we turn, We find some lessons new to 2. This universe so broad
                            and grand, Is but a shadow of that 3. The outer sense can ne'er reveal, The substance of the
                            true and learn, Far in blue depths are stars that burn, Obscured by night's dark brow, land,
                            Where beauty, life and soul expand, Eclipsing scenes of time, real, Or picture here the vast
                            ideal, Of life's infinity; And flowers spring from nature's sod, Where mortal foot has never
                            The mind from truth's deep fountain draws, Within that glorious world of Beyond the glory of
                            the stars, Beyond all earthly bolts and trod, And wondrous miracles of God, Are wrought we
                            know not how. cause, And gains a knowledge of God's laws, In templed homes sublime, bars,
                            Where naught the spirit dims nor mars, Rules perfect harmony.</p></div2><pb n="39" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. FEBRUARY, 1895. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the
                            "United Society of Believebs" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Okdeb and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All
                            communications should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. .75
                            .40 One copy per year, postage paid " " six months, " "</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. December. Thermometer. Rain. Snow. 1893. 29. % in. 15%
                                in. 1894. 25.6 % " 1934 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 48 above 0 Lowest " " " " 8
                                below" Number of rainy days " " 1 " " snowy " " " 5 " " clear " " " 13 " " cloudy "" " "
                                12 C. 6. Beed. Jan. 1895. At our last writing of Home Notes we were in the midst of our
                                first heavy fal) of snow, and long seemed what are called the "dead months" before us;
                                and now when these Notes appear, we shall be greeting according to old-timed ideas, the
                                first of the "living months" when slumbering vegetation begins to stretch and yawn
                                underground, preparatory to awaking to duty. Our Christmas this year as in other years
                                past, was made particularly pleasant, by the efforts of our young people to give us
                                pleasant surprises. When the family assembled for breakfast, we found a pretty group of
                                whiterobed young Sisters and girls and little boys wearing "Merry Xmas" badges standing
                                statue-like around an organ over which was a beautiful arch of evergreen, white paper
                                chains and glistening with tinsel balls and bells. After prayers they sang an original
                                Christinas hymn, the six boys keeping time on the chorus, with little bells. At the
                                close of the meal, another hymn was sung, and the chorus of this was timed by a chime of
                                bells, by the young Sisters. On the last verse they marched off to the farther part of
                                the house that the sound might end in a cadence. Our Christmas forenoon service, was as
                                usual beautifully appropriate to the day, proving to us that even centuries can not
                                erase the lesson taught by the Prince of Peace. At the hour for our evening meal, the
                                organ again called us to the dining room, where we were treated to vocal and
                                instrumental music, recitations, etc. by the young people. Meanwhile physical needs were
                                not forgotten; for between the acts, dainty and simple refreshments were served, and we
                                pleasantly passed two and a half hours. It is right to have the young imbued with the
                                idea that it is their duty and pleasure at Christmas to contribute to other's happiness,
                                instead of feeling that they must be the recipients of some costly present, at the
                                sacrifice of hard-earned means, needed for their necessities. Emerson said "That is no
                                real gift, which is not produced by the giver." Thus skillful fingers can often create a
                                gift precious both as a token of love, and an object of use. It is also pleasant that
                                the efforts of the young find appreciative responses, in the hearts of the older members
                                of our family, who love and bless every endeavor to TERMS. <pb n="40" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 40 THE
                                MANIFESTO. make home happy. Reciprocity intensifies the pleasure of doing good. We were
                                blest with the presence of our loved Ministry, and their words of love and
                                encouragement, greatly enhanced the pleasures of the day. Amelia J. Culver. South
                                Family. Jan. 1894. "Christmas 1894" will long be remembered by our home circle. The tide
                                of holiday feeling which prevails throughout on that memorable occasion was felt long
                                before its real advent. Finally the longed for day had come. All the stockings had been
                                filled, good measure, pressed down and shaken together, and we had a foretaste of the
                                good things to come. Our forenoon meeting was one of those rare occasions of complete
                                union of feeling, which makes you feel as if sitting in heavenly places. The opening
                                testimony was "Forgive and Forget" and proved to be like the touch on the button of an
                                electric battery; all seemingly made it a thought whereby to profit the coming year.
                                Articles appropriate for the occasion were road inspiring us to more "Faith" in the
                                "Saving Power of Christ." A quartette sang a new piece, "Peace and Praise" adding to the
                                good already prevailing. We retired from our Father's table filled with thankfulness and
                                joy, refreshed, renewed and quickened to good works. More was to come. Of course we
                                suspected it all the time, for a week ago I overheard two boys "telling their piece."
                                Then the young people went to the locust grove, in spite of the crispy cold, in search
                                of evergreens, ferns and moss, and Christmas eve: such a hammering, running and thumping
                                could be heard in the meeting-room, almost till midnight, that any person with average
                                common sense could draw up a conclusion as to what was going on. And it did go onit was
                                a great success and lasted fully three hours before we saw the end. But let me tell you
                                of the beginning. At five o'clock the family gathered into our meeting-room which was
                                tastily decorated. The arrangement was evidently made for a double purpose. We were
                                conducted to chairs at the south end some of which may have endured the burdens and
                                friction of nearly a century, while others were the latest products of upholstery,
                                massive in their cushioned elegance, desirable Christmas presents for the veterans of
                                the family. A group of young Sisters, robed in spotless white, opened the entertainment
                                by the ensuing colloquy, which was rendered with ease and grace and was a most
                                creditable expression of the pure and practical views of young women reared and
                                influenced by gospel principles. Friendship, Love, Charity, Humility and Sunbeam were
                                the speakers. From the many items read, spoken, sung and played only very few can be
                                mentioned. "The Bridge" by Longfellow was sung to organ accompaniment by a treble singer
                                with elegance and precision. The reading of several humorous articles, alternated by
                                recitations, closed the first part of the programme. At the usual hour for supper we
                                were transferred from the intellectual to the physical department. A placard with "Free
                                Lunch" in bold lettering pointed to a group of tables laden with a repast worthy of the
                                most sanguine vegetarian. All tropical fruits seemed to have appointed this their place
                                of rendezvous and were cordially welcomed. After this, not unpleasant interruption, we
                                resumed our programme. Little "Sunbeam" a child of seven years disguised as an angel,
                                asked sympathetically "Little lamb who made thee?" An imitation of all musical
                                instruments including the bagpipe, on the organ entitled, "Wandering Minstrels" excited
                                considerable hilarity by its "telling" and skillful rendering. Among the pieces read was
                                one I can not help mentioning for its importance. "How to cure gossip" tells of an
                                unfailing cure of this wide-spread plague. We are willing to send it free of <pb n="41" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 41 charge to all afflicted (please enclose stamped
                                envelope.) It is not "Beecham's pills." Two songs, "Good Night" and "We'll never say
                                good-by," intimated that all things, even Christmas entertainments must come to an end.
                                After a few remarks of satisfaction and the wish expressed by many for a repetition of
                                such gathei'ings we retired with thankful hearts to the Giver of all good things. Nor
                                did we wait a long time before the above wish was fulfilled. The Old Year had to be
                                marched out and the New Year welcomed. For this purpose we assembled the first evening
                                of the New Year. After some instrumental music two representatives of the Old Year
                                exchanged with two representatives of its successor their different views concerning the
                                past and present, hoping the best for the time to come. After this two groups were
                                formed which in calisthenic marching keeping time to song and music marched out the Old
                                and marched in the New Year. A quartette sang "Fear not" (Canterbury leaflet) and a
                                selection from the "Overland Monthly" entitled "Good Night" was repeated in unison. This
                                was a fair imitation of the New Year, which for all of us will, as we resolved, be a
                                time for true intellectual and spiritual culture. Ernest Pick.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Second Family. Jan. 1895. We are experiencing snug winter weather, with the thermometer
                                around the zero point: 14 below was the coldest. We are busy securing our supply of wood
                                for next winter. Sleighing has been poor. We felt a slight shock of earthquake Dec. 17th
                                between the hours of 3 and 4 a. m. The writer and several others were awakened from
                                slumber by the rattling of doors and windows, and could not imagine what was the cause.
                                It was felt, we learn, in different parts of the state, although our neighboring city
                                Albany doubted the report. Christmas, the Society met for worship at our family, and we
                                enjoyed a spiritual feast. In the evening all the young people were invited by the
                                Church family to share with them a social entertainment prepared for the occasion. It
                                consisted of singing and speaking, with refreshments at the close. Many that were older
                                turned the dial of time back to youth, and graced the occasion with their presence. All
                                were well pleased and each performed the part allotted, well. New Year's eve, we
                                returned the compliment and invited all to come and enjoy a similar entertainment, which
                                our young Sisters and children had planned. We had singing and speaking. All had learned
                                their pieces, and spoke them well without any hesitation, very much to their credit. We
                                enjoyed the entertainment; and the last act was not t'se least, refreshments, not
                                winebut pure lemon-juice from Florida, with cake. We also had a surprise to find
                                numbered in our midst Beloved Elder Joseph Holden. So in blessing we were blest. Isaac
                                Anxtatt. North Family. Jan. 1895. The festive seasons of Christmas and New Years are
                                past and we are introduced to the varied panorama of the new year. Christmas was
                                observed by a Society meeting at the Second family at 10 o'clock a. in. Many good and
                                earnest thoughts were expressed and resolutions to obey more faithfully the inner light
                                that is calling higher, and we felt the presence of that cloud of witnesses which attend
                                the Pentecostal season. It was an hour of holy communion. In the evening a social
                                entertainment was given at the Church family in which the Society was well represented.
                                This included dialogues, poems, and original essays in which the youth and children took
                                part with great credit. <pb n="42" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 42 THE MANIFESTO. The following is the
                                programme; Opening Address. "The Purest Pearl." "Playing at School." "Guilty or not
                                Guilty." "The Three Wishes," or "Visit to Fairyland." "Why do you Fear?" "The Happy
                                Child." "An Address to the Young." "Voice of Silence." "How Lulu knocked at the gate of
                                Heaven." "The Seasons." "Little Froggie." "The Weed." "Saint Nicholas." RECITATIONS.
                                "The Frost." "The Sun." "Childhood Hours." "The Peasant's Christmas." "The Music Stool."
                                SONGS. "The Christmas Greeting." "Our hearts beat gladly." On the evening of New Year's
                                day we had a social reception at the Second family where poems and original essays were
                                read and spoken and the time passed pleasantly by. We were favored with the company of
                                our Beloved Elder Joseph Holden who at the close gave a very instructive address,
                                followed by remarks from different Elders bearing upon our duty the coming year. The
                                counsel fell upon good soil and time will show that it has borne fruit. Our fine, mild
                                winter was rudely broken on the 27th ult. when we had almost a foot of snow with heavy
                                winds. On the morning of the 28th the mercury registered 8 deg. below zero. Hamilton
                                DeGraiv.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Jan. 1895. Like a tale that is told the book of the Old Year is written. Each of its
                                three hundred and sixty-five pages bears its message, and now "Finis," is signed, the
                                book closed, and sealed with prayer, is sent speeding on its way to eternity, joining
                                others, each numbered volume bearing the history of our lives. As we open the new book
                                entrusted to our keeping, bound so closely that we can see but one page at a time, let
                                us entitle ; "Noble Endeavor," and, dedicating it to God and friends around us, write
                                the pages with devotion and care. As a New Year's present, the brown, bare earth around
                                us, was given a garment of glistening snow. To be sure, it has grown rather dingy in
                                appearance, and many thin places are visible, but we think soon another will be
                                provided. With a view to improving each opportunity, sleighing parties were organized,
                                and three double loads, on as many days, went to enjoy a ride over the snow. Each trip
                                was pronounced a complete success, and enjoyed to the utmost, especially by the
                                children. To-day the men have commenced filling our new Cold Storage with ice, which I
                                hear is about 12 in. thick. On the 3rd inst. the State board of highway commissioners
                                arrived at our place. The object of their visit being to inspect the road leading from
                                Hancock to Lebanon, preparatory to building a continuation of the State road now
                                commenced in West Pittsfield. Elder Joseph, of the Central Ministry, and several
                                Brethren from Mt. Lebanon, were also here. They drove over a route leading across
                                meadows, and through woods, finally coming into the highway, thereby securing a grade
                                more even and less dangerous, than the regular road over the mountain. Though no
                                decision was made, it is quite certain that a better road will be the result. Fidelia
                                Estabrook.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct.</head><p TEIform="p">Jan. 1895. How comforting is the thought that salvation is free to all who work for it.
                                "Work out your own salvation." It requires the crucifixion of all sinful elements to be
                                a true cross-bearer. Cross-bearing insures eternal life. First the cross, then the
                                crown. "If any man will come after me let him deny himself and take up his cross and
                                follow me," said Jesus. The injunction is plain, and how pleasing it <pb n="43" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFES TO. 43 should be when we know that self-denial will yield happiness and
                                heaven. Denying self is a Christian duty. How sweet are the hours we spend in God's
                                service. We can not do too much for the cause of truth and virtue, though we toil
                                incessantly. One virtuous person may turn many others heavenward. There is no safety in
                                sin. As we go through each day, let us think of coming days, and make provision foi
                                their trials, crosses and duties, by doing our very best work at character building.
                                "Dimensions of Westminster clock, London. Diameter of dials, 22 ft. The minute hand is
                                16 ft. long, the hour hand 9 ft. and both weigh 200 pounds. Length of pendulum 15 ft;
                                weight 680 lbs." "Diameter of the dial of the clock in the new city hall, Philadelphia,
                                27 ft. "The largest hanging bell in the world is in China. It is 18 ft. high and 45 ft.
                                in circumference and is of solid bronze." Daniel Orautt. South Family. Jan. 1895. Once
                                more we are on the verge of a new year with its hopes, and aspirations. The one that has
                                so quickly passed has been crowned with blessing, peace, and plenty, and we would render
                                thanks for the mercies bestowed upon us by the bountiful Giver of all good. Christmas
                                was made a joyful occasion. A general invitation was extended by the Church Elders to
                                all of the Society, to spend the day with them, which was accepted. A very impressive
                                Service was held. It was truly commemorative of the life Christ taught and lived, while
                                on earth. May it prove a profitable season to those present. At 12 o'clock we were
                                invited to a sumptuous repast of which we partook with thankful hearts, not unmindful of
                                those whose lives were full of want and poverty. At 2 p. m. we all convened in the
                                dining hall to listen to music, and to the speaking of pieces taken from Scripture, also
                                reading from the older class, for all took some part, which made the occasion very
                                interesting and useful. At the close of the entertainment presents were distributed from
                                a heavily laden Christmas tree which stood waiting to furnish many valuable and useful
                                gifts; all were remembered. A lunch was served and at 5 o'clock we returned to our homes
                                made happier and wiser for the Christmas of 1894, and also with many thanks to those who
                                contributed to our comfort and pleasure. Sleighing is very good, with the prospect of
                                more snow. On the 3rd inst. a party of ten went on a sleigh-ride, and returned reporting
                                a very pleasant time at Broad Brook, Ellington and Rockville. Chopping in the woods
                                gives employment at present to the farmers, also the preparing of corn fodder by
                                machinery. Our stock are thriving well by their good care, as the abundant supply of
                                cream from twenty cows proves the value of sparing no pains for their comfort, and
                                keeping everything in order; 3,500 spaces of cream in October; 3,465 in December; so it
                                goes care, care! The ice harvest commences on the 7th inst. under favorable
                                circumstances, as we have snow for sledding. Improved machinery aids in getting ice; we
                                put up about 209 tons as easily as we formerly put up 50 tons. At present, ice is a
                                necessity for the dairy and the refrigerator; but we believe electricity will make us
                                independent of ice in a few years; it is in the air, that creamers and coolingrooms,
                                will be refrigerated by machinery. Maria Witham.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Jan. 1895. In the Home Notes of a recent number, reference was made to a new order of
                                meeting for the young people. Hoping to interest the readers of our paper, I send a
                                condensed account of the last one for the year 1894, conducted by Br. George Kirkley.
                                For each meeting, a different theme is <pb n="44" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 44 THE MANIFESTO. chosen
                                upon which to elucidate. The forementioned one bring,Rest. The meeting opened with
                                reading of the 4th Chap, of Heb., followed with singing the anthem, "Bow down Thine
                                Ear"' from the Choral Tributeand after rendering a short prayer, the following remarks
                                were made by our Brother. "We have the assurance of perfect rest and peace of mind, not
                                by merely professing to be followers of our Savior, but by fulfilling the duties of a
                                Christian with a willing heart. We can not suspend the struggle for victory over sin and
                                find this perfect rest, for when we cease to resist evil, we become an easy prey to the
                                power of darkness. The Christian's rest is not mere cessation from labor, but a
                                tranquility of spirit that is ever present with those who have a confidence in the
                                promises of God. In these the Christian finds a rock of safety in seasons of trial and
                                temptation. A person endowed with the gift of riches, having no object in life but to
                                please himself, can not find this rest, because every wish is gratified by paid
                                attendants; consequently a state of lassitude ensues which is overcome only by rest in
                                action. So with the Christian; unless we have an ambition to become better day by day,
                                we lack the rest of spirit that comes only by the activity of the purest attributes of
                                our nature." Following these remarks, was singing, interspersed with the reading of the
                                following texts, with explanation by the Brother. Psalms, lv., 6. Here we have the cry
                                of David when sorely oppressed by his enemies; and this has been the cry of many an
                                earnest seeker after righteousness, since his day. We may not have to contend with
                                personal enemies, but the enemies of good in our own hearts often cause us to sigh for
                                that divine rest which becomes the Christian's hope. Matt, xi., 28-30. Here we have the
                                assurance, that the way of life is easy, when we walk in it aright. Much of the burden
                                of life comes from our own transgressions. "My yoke is easy;" but it requires Christian
                                fortitude to keep it thus under all conditions of life. Faithfulness to God and our
                                associates makes our way easy, while that of "the transgressor is hard." Psalms,
                                xxxvii., 7. This lesson teaches us to bear with patience the ill-treatment of our
                                enemies. "Fret not thyself because of evil-doers." Wait patiently for the reward of
                                well-doing. John, xiv., 1. "Let not your heart be troubled." Here we are commanded to
                                keep our souls at rest in Christ, remembering that he that endures to the end, shall be
                                saved. Isaiah, xiv., 3. Bondage comes from trying to serve two masters. When we give
                                ourselves wholly up to the Christ life, freedom of spirit is ours, and we enter into
                                divine rest only as we are devoted to the precepts of the gospel. Isaiah, xxxii., 17-18.
                                We can well say these texts are exemplified in our home. Our dwelling-place is sure and
                                the soul finds rest from the sorrowing and strife of a worldly life. The recorded
                                exercises, combined with appropriate remarks from different speakers upon the chosen
                                theme, occupied the allotted time designed for Sunday evening service. We rejoice to
                                state that these meetings are appreciated by all, and we rest in the hope that our lives
                                are being enriched by the knowledge herein obtained. George H. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Jan. 1895. We now begin a new page in the great book of years. May our effort be to write
                                on its unsullied pages naught but goodness, blessing and prosperity. On the 22nd ult. we
                                occupied our new barn. It is well built, and as near like the one we had last, as
                                possible, making a nice appearing structure. Our foreman on the farm, who has been with
                                us twenty years, gave a weather vane with the design of a cow, which looks fine standing
                                on the top of the cupola. <pb n="45" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 45 Christmas has come and
                                gone, leaving, we hope nothing in its wake but joy. We had the usual memorial meeting in
                                the forenoon, welcoming the Christ spirit and seeking to receive it into our hearts. The
                                Sisters faithfully performed their part in making the day happy, feasting us with oyster
                                soup, plum-pudding, cake, pie and as many more good things as health would admit. In the
                                afternoon we were interested by our young people with singing, dialogues and selections
                                appropiate to the occasion, Near the center of the room was a beautiful tree laden with
                                fruits of all shapes and shades which Santa Claus proceeded to unload and distribute
                                among the audience. Every one left the room happier for having been there. The first day
                                of the year the farmers commenced fitting our new ice-house. They cut 2,200 blocks of
                                the beautiful productions of the frost king, from 10 to 14 inches in thickness; 792
                                blocks were stored at the North and South. The attention of the laborers is now turned
                                to providing wood for next year. As the year has commenced, so may it end, in happiness.
                                Marcia M. Bullard.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/> Union Village, O.</head><p TEIform="p">Jan. 1895. Highly Esteemed Elder Henry;I was greatly rejoiced at your New Year's
                                appearance. I was fearful some Florida fever had attacked the good people of East
                                Canterbury; it would be all right if it had, but I beg you, "don't abandon the
                                publication of The Manifesto,nay not for one month if possible to avoid it. It is one of
                                the strongest if not the strongest guarantee of our solidity. It is a perfect bulwark of
                                strength at that point. It not only makes us much better acquainted, but cements our
                                union and interest in each other. The value of The Manifesto in these particulars for
                                the last twenty years can not be told. It opens the way for the ventilation of many
                                excellent inspirations and sentiments which, in all probability would have remained
                                latent with many good Brethren and Sisters of our fraternity only for the invaluable
                                instrumentality of our Manifesto. Moreover it has developed the faculty of many to
                                expx-ess themselves correctly anl even elegantly in composition which the skillful pens
                                of many ready writers witness to every month. It also gives expression to many domestic
                                felicities and home enjoyments so reciprocally identified that we feel as though we were
                                one family and distance almost annihilated. The most important item of regret we have to
                                chronicle since November set in, is the departure of our good and valuable Bro. Ezra T.
                                Leggett. One of his many admirable qualities of character was his constant unswerving
                                loyalty to the cause of the Gospel. Being extremely well-read and acute in the law, he
                                was said to have saved our Society not less than 30,000 during his useful and honorable
                                life of thirty-six years at Union Village. He never manifested rebellion or resistance
                                to the gift of the Ministry, Elders or Deacons under any circumstances. He only wanted
                                to know what was desired of him and he cheerf ullj complied. He never sought promotion
                                of any kind, yet was in both Eldership and Trusteeship for some years and discharged his
                                duties therein with fidelity. In his last Office of Postmaster, he was faithful and
                                exemplary, so that the Postmaster General or his Deputy, took the pains to compliment
                                him in a letter, wherein he stated, that the Post Office returns by Br. Ezra for the
                                year ending 1893 were the most correctly and systematically reported, of any that had
                                reached him. Is not the memory of such like "ointment and balm?" Our winter so far has
                                furnished but one or two zero days, but we have had an abundance of rain within the last
                                ten days. We are mostly well. Any exceptions to this I will not name, for I am a
                                Christian Scientist (albeit not of the Eddy stripe) and we C. S. don't allow ourselves
                                to talk <pb n="46" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 46 THE MANIFESTO. about sickness and pain but only health
                                and consolation. Conning over symptoms, is one of the most fruitful ways to create
                                sickness on earth. I enjoy the society of the good Brethren and Sisters here at Union
                                Village wonderfully and think it quite praiseworthy that peace and union dwell with us.
                                I never did, and never will go back on our own folks but try to encourage the good in
                                every one. We see the necessity for greater zeal and faithfulness. I wish all God's
                                creation, friend or foe a happy New Year. 0. C. Hampton.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South Union, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>South. Union, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1894. Fakewell, Dear Old Year, thou art dying, dying: thou art fading, while around
                                me the evening shadows softly fall. I sit alone watching the tall stately pines bend and
                                bow to each gentle breeze, the sun reflecting its soft mellow light over our landscape
                                and it presents a picture too lovely for description. I wonder how many at this sacred
                                hour are turning over the pages of their past history, calling to memory the good and
                                noble deeds they have done. Beautiful old year. While we list to thy last faint whisper,
                                no tear-stains are upon our cheeks, no bitter regrets. Let us not mourn thy departure
                                but let us be glad with new and firm resolutions for the New Year. Let us so live that
                                in after years we will sweetly cherish thy remembrance. Help us to be wise, patient,
                                kind, gentle and charitable. True charity attempts not to close our eyes to the
                                distinction between good and bad; toward our enemies it inspires forgiveness and a
                                solicitude for their welfare; it forms gentleness of temper, a comforter of the
                                afflicted a protector of the oppressed. Farewell Old Year! with glad tidings for the
                                happy new. May health, peace and prosperity be tended to all. Accept much love and good
                                wishes with respect and gratitude. Birdie Henderson.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>EXCHANGES.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our dumb animals" TEIform="index"/>Our Dumb Animals
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"Our Dumb Animals" is under the editorial management of George T. Angell, of Boston,
                                Mass. The whole paper is in the interest of Prevention of Cruelty to Animals. It is
                                beautifully illustrated and should find a place in every home. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Freedom's banner" TEIform="index"/>Freedom's Banner
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"Freedom's Banner" is
                                edited by T. S. Givan of Louisville, Ky. This paper has for its motto,"One people, one
                                language, one flag, even justice, equality and fraternity." </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Words of faith" TEIform="index"/>Words of Faith
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"Words of Faith" is edited
                                and published by G. W. McCalla.of Philadelphia. The Editor says that "the publication is
                                a work of Faith," and is "for the Unfolding of Spiritual Life and Light." </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Young people at work" TEIform="index"/>Young People
                                at Work
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"Young People
                                at Work" is published in the Interests of the Young Peoples' Societies of the Churches
                                of Hartford, Ct.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="American federationist" TEIform="index"/>American Federationist
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"American Federationist" is edited by Samuel Gompers and published by
                                the American Federation of Labor, of New York. The paper is in the interest of the Trade
                                Union Movement. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religio-philosophical journal" TEIform="index"/>Religio-Philosophical Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The "Religio-Philosophical Journal" in speaking of itself ay-s,"Truth
                                wears no mask, bows at no human shrine, seeks neither place nor applause; she only asks
                                a hearing." The Journal is an independent and uncompromising exponent of the
                                spiritualism of to-day. Its field of labor may be a little less than that mentioned in
                                the Bible,"twelve thousand furlongs square," as it becomes an advocate in an "Open
                                Court" and introduces us to "The Transcendental Community at Brook Farm." Published in
                                Chicago, 111. by B. F. Underwood. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian" TEIform="index"/>The Christian
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"The Christian," including the "Christian Safeguard,"
                                "Armory," &amp; "Common People." is an illustrated, religious, temperance paper. In
                                this pamphlet may be found music, poetry, true stories, religion and common sense, while
                                sectarian controversy, politics, patent medicines and pious novels are excluded.
                                Published by H. L. Hastings, 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Flaming sword" TEIform="index"/>The Flaming Sword
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"The Flaming Sword" is "the
                                expositor of Koreshanity,the bitter foe of every form of social abuse in church and
                                state,primitive Christianity revised." It is published at Washington Heights, Chicago,
                                111., where the leading Society is located.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every where" TEIform="index"/>Every Where
                            </head><p TEIform="p">  "Every Where" is conducted by Will Carlton
                                and published in Brooklyn, N. Y. It is a beautifully illustrated paper of 18 pages. The
                                choice variety of subjects to be found in its columns can not fail to please those who
                                may read.</p></div3></div2><pb n="47" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Children:--'One year more is quickly numbered..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Dear Children:--'One year more is quickly numbered...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Shaker Station, January 1895" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct. Jan.
                            1895.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Children: "One year more is quickly numbered, With the ages of the past, And you
                            scarcely heed the moments, As they pass you by so fast." It is always in order to turn over
                            a new leaf in the volume of your lives. The crosses and trials of the old year are past, and
                            the firm resolve that the clean page before you shall be free from blots, will give hope of
                            spiritual victory. In commencing the New Year with good desires and corresponding efforts,
                            there is an inspiration that gives new life, strength and courage. Afflictions and troubles
                            will come, but press heavenward, asking God to bless your efforts. A good beginning is an
                            essential element of success. Victory in the Christian warfare is the result of soul labor,
                            the application of energy and the right improvement of time. Let your endeavor be to grow
                            better each year, for brief is the time that you journey here. Only as you grow better do
                            you really live. Perform your whole duty, for little omissions of duty; small acts of
                            disobedience, as they may seem to you, will prove a sexious obstacle to your happiness.
                            Beware,"There is a way that seemeth right, but the end thereof is death." Well improve each
                            passing hour, watch, and foil the tempter's power. You will never regret constant
                            perseverance in the right path, and though the progress you make may not seem to be very
                            great, at times, yet if it be sure and steady, you will win the reward. It is wisdom to live
                            the greatest number of good hours in a day. Improve this moment while you have it, and the
                            next as it comes, and so on, and you will have no regrets. Be rich in good works and strive
                            for the treasure, lasting and eternal, that will insure you happiness. Childhood is a fit
                            time for the reception of virtue and truth. So let purity be your guiding star and you will
                            overcome all evil if you persevere.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Glorious cross" TEIform="index"/>GLORIOUS CROSS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/>By Lucy S. Bowers.</byline><p TEIform="p">Glorious cross of Christ! what power In thee lies, Virtue sought and treasui-ed through thee
                            Never dies. Hights of truth's eternal glory Rise to view, [life's When by thy righteous
                            power we strive Journey through. Ages that live but in story Tell of thee, Name thy name,
                            but know not of thy Purity. Carved on palace walls and temples And still tombs, Carved to
                            last perhaps for ages Through earth's glooms; But not in symbols dull and olden Art thou
                            known, With the true cross is Christ's presence Fully shown. Shown, by working souls'
                            salvation From all sin, Known, by giving through each trial Peace within. Talisman against
                            all evilBlessed cross! Be my whole life's light, still leading From all loss. Leave thy mark
                            upon my forehead There to shine; Firm control of thought and feeling Oh be mine. Set thy
                            seal upon my spirit Through the light, And when fadest out the sunshine Keep the night. Oh I
                            seek thee for thy power, not For a crown, Though with thee a blessing surely Cometh down,
                            But for the good thou workest in me That my soul Loosed from its tetherings may attain Its
                            perfect goal. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Industry is a perpetual..." TEIform="index"/>Industry is a perpetual...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Industry is a perpetual and sure safeguard against temptation.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="R., B." TEIform="persName"/>B. R.</byline></div2><pb n="48" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>The Ladies' Home Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">MAGAZINES ARE COSTLY THINGS. Albert Lynch, the famous French artist, who received the
                                Salon prize for his panel of "Spring," has been engaged by The Ladies' Home Journal to
                                draw a series of designs for the cover of that magazine, which as the reading public
                                knows, changes its cover design each month. Lynch is, perhaps, one of the best-paid
                                artists in France, and these covers will cost The Ladies' Home Journal nearly $1000
                                apiece. But this only demonstrates the enormous expense, to which magazines are put in
                                the production of their numbers.R. H. Stoddard, in New York Mail arid Express. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of Hygeio-Therapy" TEIform="index"/>The
                                Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">. Jan. Contents. Origin of the Bloomer Costume; The American
                                Costume; Foundation Principles, No. 9. Phrenology; The Good that a bad Arm did; That
                                Impure Virus; Outlook for the New Year; Our College Prospects; Sanitation; Letter from
                                Dr. L. Gossmann; Temperature of the Body; Dress Notes; etc. etc., DrT. V. Gifford,
                                Kokomo, Ind. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gathered gems of song and story" TEIform="index"/>Gathered Gems of Song and Story
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Gathered Gems of Song and Story. It is not every day that we are so
                                fortunate as to obtain this form of treasure by the expenditure of a little sum of
                                money. A book of gems is far more valuable than a necklace of gems, as one may beautify
                                the immortal mind, while the other can only afford a transitory pleasure in adorning the
                                body. It is a treasure-house of stories that every boy and girl will want to read, and
                                in which more mature minds will be intensely interested, among which may be found "The
                                Little English Drummer Boy," "Kittie's New Song," and "The Wooden Indian." Published by
                                II. L. Hastings, 47 Cornhill Boston, Mass. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological Journal and Science of Health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and Science of
                                Health for January appears in a new, elegant, "up-to-date" dress, and the contents are
                                equally fresh and attractive. The Hon. Chauncey M. Depew, L. L. D, is the subject of the
                                frontispiece and a closely ana. lytical phrenograph from a personal examination by the
                                editor, Dr. Edgar C. Beall. This will prove exceptionally interesting to the many
                                admirers of the brilliant orator, and to all students of character reading as a science
                                and an art. It is also of value as an explanation of some important elements of social,
                                political and financial success. Miss Alice E. Ives, the well known journalist, very
                                intelligently discusses Man versus the New Woman; George Manson reviews the strange
                                superstition of "The Evil Eye;" and Mrs. Charlotte Fowler Wells sketches the eminent
                                advocate of phrenology, Dr. J. V. C. Smith. Prof. Nelson Sizer elaborately phrenographs
                                the well known clergyman. Frederick D. Power, of Washington, from a personal
                                examination, and contributes live pages of most interesting illustrated matter to the
                                department of Child Culture. The latter will be eagerly read by all parents of bright
                                children. Dr. H. S. Drayton and others furnish excellent ideas on hygiene, notably on
                                Eye Disease from Catarrh, Remedial Appliances in Fevers, Whole Wheat Bread, etc., etc.
                                The editorials include illustrated studies in physiognomy and cheirognomy, with
                                portraits of the noses of Mr. Gladstone and Mrs. Langtry. The publishers promise added
                                improvements in future numbers. Price 15 cents, $1. 50 a year. Address The Fowler
                                &amp; Wells Co., 27 East 21st St., New York.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whatever is, is best" TEIform="index"/> WHATEVER IS,IS
                            BEST.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">[Contributed by Genevieve DeGraw.] 
                                    I know as my life grows older, And mine eyes have clearer sight, That under each
                                    rank wrong, somewhere There lies the root of Right; That such sorrow has its
                                    purpose, By the sorrowing oft unguessed. But as sure as the sun brings morning
                                    Whatever is,is best. I know that each sinful action As sure as the night brings
                                    shade Is somewhere, some time punished Though the hour be long delayed, I know that
                                    the soul is aided Some time, by the heart's unrest; And to grow means often to
                                    suffer But whatever is,is best. I know there are no errors In the great eternal
                                    plan, And all things work together For the final good of man. And I know when my
                                    soul speeds onward In its grand eternal quest; I shall say as I look back earthward
                                    Whatever is,is best. I know on the shores immortal Where God and his angels reign We
                                    shall see not through a glass darkly But a brighter vision there claim. And I know
                                    in the land of Beulah In that peaceful land of rest; When earth and its burdens are
                                    ended We shall meet with all that is best.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p27"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Piihlished.      The  book is printed
with large type  an-,I  on  excellent  paper.
It  contains   180 pages and has
ILLUSTRATIONS
or rhe Suakk;;s and their
The   work   givrs   quite an extended account of  the  Several SOCIETIES, their
organization and general management.
Price  in cloth 75   cts;   in boards 50 cts.
Address    II. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
AUTHORIZED RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY.
The religious basis of the Okdeh mustbe a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which piinciple is (Jo 1.
This should rule the life of t'lj   in iivkl
ual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price,  10 cts.
NE DOLLAR MUSIC BOOK.
FREE
                   Inone hour you can lean
to accompany on tlie l*iHii<>or
Or&'un by n.-inK ("UirU's Li.ahtning (J!nu\l
M^thol. Ito Tvachci' A>ciMiiry, Slioul 1
be on every iMano or Organ. A limited number given away to introiiucc Tlie ]:r;cc or
this book is $1.00, but if you will talk it up and
sluns it to your neighbors, we will mail you
iie copy free. Send one dime for mailing.
Address, Mu-ical Guile Pub. Co., Cincinnati,
Ohio.    Mention this paper.
SHAKERS'
COMPOUND CONCENTRATED       *
SYRUP of SARSAPARILLA,
With 1 oz. HrDEIODATE OF POTASSA to 12 Bottles.
PREPARED AT
Shaker UHlage, Merrtmach So., 1%.
This medicine has proved to be most
valuable in the following diseases :
Chronic Inflammation of the Digestive
Organs ; Dyspepsia, or Indigestion; Weakness and Sourness of the Stomach; Rheumatism ; Salt Rheum ', Secondary Syphilis;
Functional Disorders of the Liver  Chronic
Eruptions of the Skin, and all Scrofulous
diseases and disorders arising from impurities of the blood. It is also an eorcell- ':. .smedy for the Erysipelas, Asthma,
Dropsy, Dysentery, and Diarrhoea, and
for the complicated diseases of females,
so apt to end in consumption.
DoseFor an adult,  a teaspoonful
four or live i iint-s a day, with or without
a little water, which may be increased to
a tablebpooui'ul, ut-j best suits the patient.
To guard against counterfeits, observe
the signature of the inventor on each
label and on each wrapper.
Should have the beautiful 36-page Monthly
= JXiUSTBATED HOME JOtrHJTAX =
O eta. a year.   Sample free.   Agents wanted.
THOMAS a. JTEWMABT ft SOH,
CHICAGO. ILL.
HUMAN riATIIRE
is an illustrated Monthly, now only 50cfs.
per    year,    devoted   to   PHBEI0L03Y,
PHYSIOGNOMY, HEALTH, MEDICAL
& SOCIAL EEFOSM.
Would you like a copy?
Send 5 cts. for Sample to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Francisco, Cal.

<pb n="" id="p28"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cres;rn of   tartar   baking   powder
ILii'l.e^l of   all in   leavening strength.
Latest   United   States    Government
Food Report.
Roy.iL Baking Powdeis Co.,
106 Wall St., N. Y.
HO W I CAME
TO   BK
Much knowiedge for a few pennies.
Sent Postage paid to any address in the
U. S. We have on hand a few copies of
"Kip Van Winkle and other Sketches."
240 pages, 4xf>.                          10 cts.
"A treatise on The Horse," by Dr. B.
Kendall. 90 pages. 5x7)4. Profusely illustrated.                                  12 cts.
Second  vol. of Cassandra written originally in French by Sir, Charles Cotterell.
Published 1725.                                  .25
Sacred Roll and Book written by Inspiration in 1843.    A wonderful Book.     2.00
Hamlet, Prince of Denmark.
From Shakespeare.
.10
Price 5 cts.
An old, brass eight day clock, in long
case, in excellent order.           $70.00
An eight day brass time piece made in
1810   by Dr.   Thomas Corbett.    $20.00
Several small, old-fashion clocks at reasonable prices.
Address   H. C Blinn, E. Canterbury, N. H.
3 American Bee Journal,
(Established 1861.)
IS Oldest, Largest, Best,
Cheapest and the Only
weekly Bee-Paper in all
America.  32 pages. $1.00
a year.   Send for Free Sample.
$1.00 BEE-BOOK FREB
i. W. YQSE & CO., 199 Randolph St., Chicago, 111.
PLAIN TALKS
ON
PRACTICAL RELIGION
Being    Candid   Answers  for Earnest
Inquirers.
By Geo. A. Lomas.
Price, 10 cts
A.   SHAKER.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>