<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2612" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">26</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><date value="18961201" TEIform="date">December 1896</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">185-200</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="26" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
 1896.
A Visit to the
of EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
BY
LLOYD H. CHANDLER. U. S. N.
Liberally Illustrated with half tone
pictures of persons and places.
The Village of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the lovliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price,   15 cts.
Address   H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
AND
SHAKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the United   Society  of   Believers   in   Christ's
Second Appearing.    Illustrated.
By Giles B. Avery.
Price,  15 cts.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF  THE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS    OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVlLEGES  and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION    AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
the same time, afford instruction to all  inquiring  minds.    Price 5  cts. each,   postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.               >
DECEMBER,
THE SHAKER COVENANT.
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
Only a few remain who can recall the marvelous enthusiasm which attended Jenny
Land's first appearance in America, in the old
Castle Garden, in 1850.W hen she arrived fro m
England 50,000 people were at the dock to greet
her. That night 30,000 people serenaded her in
front of her hotel. Seats for her concert
sold at fabulous prices. On the night of her
first American concert over 5000 people had
gathered in the Battery before Castle Garden
by six o'clock, although the concert did not
begin until eight. When the doors were opened
the crush was terrible, and within fifteen minutes every available inch of room, other than
the reserved seats, was occupied, and 10,000
people were outside unable to get in. Then
every rowboat, sailboat and steamer which
could be pressed into service was engaged to
lay iii the water by the old Garden Hall
crowded with people who could only hear the
strains of Jenny's voice as it floated through
the opened windows. The whole scene has
now been repictured by Hon. A. Oakey Hall,
ex-Mayor of New York City, and he gives a
wonderfully graphic recital of the event in
the November Ladies' Home Journal. The actual scene of Jenny Land singing her first song
to her wonderful audience of thousands is
shown in a picture copied by De Thulstrup
from a photograph made at the time.
The Outlook for October is a beautifully illustrated Magazine. The leading features of
this number arePrincetons 105th Anniversary. By Henry Von Dyke, with nine illustrations. The Boys' Republic. By Washington
Gladden with twelve illustrations. A Poet's
Workshop. By R. T. Zueblin, with five illustrations. The Founder of the Y. M. C. A. By
Lord Kinnaid with nine illustrations. Published by the Outlook Co. 13 Astor Place, New
York City, N. Y.
Yale university is the subject of an interesting article in the November number of
Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly. It is
written by one of the senior students, George
Henry Nettleton, and is profusely illustrated
with views and portraits. It is the first of a
series of papers on "American Universities
and Colleges," to appear in successive issues
of this magazine. Another attractive and well
illustrated article in this number is "The
Stage Debutante," by Arthur Hornblow, giving portraits of many of the younger actresses. Then there is a description of Madagascar
and the Malagasy, by Mary Titcomb; an arti.
cle on Mrs. Robert E. Lee's life in Richmond
during the war, by Sally Nelson Robins; a
paper on "Egg-hunting on the South Farallon,"
by C. H. Thompson; the continuation of Edith
Sessions Tupper's stirring serial, "Father
John;" a graphic account of the "Twin Cities,"
Minneapolis and St. Paul, by Charles Thomas
Logan;  an article on the Gold Standard, by
Henry Cabot Lodge; short stories and poems
by John Gilmer Speed, Captain Jack Crawford, Lurana W. Sheldon, Ella Higginson,
Louis Pendleton and Clifford Howard; the Department for Boys and Girls, with contributions by F. A.Ober and Horatio Alger, Jr.,
etc. The quality and quantity of the illu trations in this number are particularly notices! ble.Frank Leslie's Publishing House, Kew York.
The Errors of Evolution by Robert Patterson of San Francisco. The errors of evolution like the mistakes of Mosts, will be t-tU' lied
with deep interest. Mo-.es, the wonderful
Jewish Prophet, still remains the same wonderful man while his mistakes grow less and
less as time moves on, and the errors of evolution will, no doubt, rise and fall in the minds
of men as the Creative work is understood or
misunderstood.
The work before us is divided into four parts
and published in four books. Part first is on
"Scientific Star Building." Part second on
"Geological Evolution." Part third on "Th"
Origin of Life."   Part fourth on "Darwinism."
A careful perusal of these very interesting
subjects, may afford a fund of information
that would be diflicult to obtain from any
other source. Published by H. L. Hastings,
47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass.
The Phrenological Journal ash Science
of Health for November, has an article on
The Organ of Human Nature, by Jes.-ie A .
Fowler. This is liberally illustrated and the
Photo of special interest is that of Dr. Francis
Joseph Gall, the Founder of Phrenology.
Mrs. TrellaFoltzToland. A personal Examination by Prof. Sizer. Phrenotypes -accompanied by several illustrations. Child Culture
by Prof. Sizer. This presents a most interest
ing chapter of the little folks, and one in which
there will be a general interest. Science of
Health. For this department, M. L. Holbrook
M. D. has written a very interesting and instructive chapter. The Foot anil its ti eatment
needs careful study. Other subjects of interest may be found in this same number. Fowler & Wells Co. 27 East St. New York City,
N. Y.
Sunday School Times for Nov. 7th, has an
excellent article on "Who should Preach?"
and concludes with this very liberal remark.
"Every one of us has a mission to be a preacher. If all of us were preaching as we have opportunity, how greatly the power of the
church would be increased, and how much
of good might come to the needy." John D.
Wattles & Co. Publishers.   Philadelphia, Pa.
The Pulpit for October. Onr Enemies
Themselves being Judges, by Bishop Fowler,
of the M. E. Church, Buffalo, N. Y. In Essentials Unity; in Non-essentials Liberty, by Rev.
W. H. Roberts, Presbyterian. The Grand
Army in Prophetic Vision, by Rev. G. C. Lorimer. The Peace of God, by Rev. Calvin Gerhard of Reading, Pa. Published by G. Holzapfel, Fredericksburg, Pa.--><pb n="185" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Coming new year" TEIform="index"/>THE COMING NEW YEAR.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pick, Earnest" TEIform="persName"/>By Earnest Pick.</byline><p TEIform="p">ANOTHER new year ! and another! and another! How many new years we have experienced, each one
                            of them new; rather strange that all together they should make us old, each one making us
                            older in spite of it being new. But "getting older" is of no great consequence, even if we
                            lived the age of Methusala. Are we "growing better" is another far more important
                            consideration. If we cut the trunk of a tree in two, crosswise, we find a number of
                            concentric rings indicating the age of the tree. Each year's added growth is thus plainly
                            indicated. At the same time the sap of the tree rising between the bark and the wood proper,
                            bursts and breaks the bark, thus making room for a further growth, the old bark being thrown
                            off by a gradual peeling process. A valuable lesson is contained in this process of nature.
                            Reviewing the old year in this correspondence we may aptly ask ourselves; How much new
                            growth have we to show for the last year ? How much good is there newly added within the
                            circumference of our last year's increase? And again, how much of the old bark that enclosed
                            our former growth, are we about to break and throw off, to give room for further expansion ?
                            For move on, we must, or retrograde; there is no stand-still; grow we must, or sure decay
                            will follow. Paul says;"When I was a child, I spake as a child, I thought as a child, but
                            when I became a man, I put away childish things. For now we see <pb n="186" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 186
                            THE MANIFESTO. through a glass darkly, but then face to face, now I know in part, but when
                            that which is perfect is come, then that which is in part shall be done away." This is the
                            outline of the growth and progress of a true Christian. The sincere seeker of Christ will
                            determine and set out anew to put aside all temporal obstructions. If we wish to be true
                            servants of God, we can not make any reserves, which would hinder us from our final
                            redemption. Though we may feel on that phase of our travel, as stepping down from the solid
                            earth into the bottomless darkness, and may feel completely helpless and alone, we need just
                            then stretch out our hand and grasp the right arm of Him who promised ever to hold and guide
                            us. If these promises are as true to-day, and I doubt not, as they were nineteen hundred
                            years ago, there is no reason for looking backward to a Savior of the past, who has left us
                            his memory alone to adore.and to be petitioned unto, but he must be living among mankind
                            to-day, his spirit diffused among all his true disciples, and what is more, his saving power
                            accessible to each one desirous to give up all in order to follow Him. His very presence
                            ought to be felt to-day as of yore, and we ought to be able to touch the hem of his garment
                            and feel the touch of his healing hand whenever we desire, in boundless faith, to be freed
                            from the bondage of sin and disease. "Who forgiveth all thme iniquities, who tu'aleth all
                            thy diseases."Ps. ciii., 3. And so it seems to be when viewed from another point.
                            Continually we see and hear his name aud his spirit abased and persecuted for his very
                            righteousness. Forever we see him betrayed and sold for more or less silver-pieces, and
                            continually we witness him crucified amidst a thieving and a murderous spirit of the deluded
                            human race. But forever and ever we see him ris? above all this in immortality, pointing the
                            penitent mortal up to heaven his place of birth and final destiny. In godlike patience and
                            long-suffering he is forever leading mankind by slow degrees of inner enfoldment to the
                            realm of his salvation. Ever present to-day as he was centuries ago, ever powerful, ever
                            ready and willing to forgive, to heal, to save each and every one willing to forsake the
                            evil ways of fallen nature. This living Savior is among us to-day, and here, as I faithfully
                            believe ; trusting in his power to save, all who sincerely seek, and when found, follow him
                            without reserve, I go on to victory. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Men and women fail to reach..." TEIform="index"/>Men and women fail to reach...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Men and women fail to reach the highest and best gifts for humanity, because their selfish
                            individuality claims not only recognition, but supreme adulation.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is becoming..." TEIform="index"/>What is becoming...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">What is becoming, is honest, and whatever is honest must always be becoming.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cicero" TEIform="persName"/>Cicero.</byline></div2><pb n="187" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christmas poem" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTMAS POEM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, Isabella" TEIform="persName"/>By Isabella Russell.</byline><p TEIform="p">What means this strong and mighty host, Of prophets, martyrs, bards and seers? Who've left
                            their battlements on high To dwell amid Earth's darkened spheres; Whose clarion notes of
                            peace and joy Resound thro'out Earth's vast domain; The blessed promise is fulfilled, Christ
                            in his glory comes again! He comes, as in the olden time To meet our wants, our human needs,
                            Comes, disregarding priestly rule, Ignoring useless man-made creeds, And in the spirit, and
                            the power, Of consecrated Mother-love, Earth's erring children kindly leads To higher, purer
                            joys above. The selfish plane of hoarded wealth, With all that follows in its train, True
                            honor, virtue, manhood lost, Sure tell-tales of ill-gotten gain , The cry of poverty and
                            woe, Has reached at last the Mother-heart , And Christ has come to rule and reign, Where
                            woman wills, and acts her part, In consecrated deeds of love, In faithful service freely
                            given, Foreshadowing Christ's kingdom here On Earth, as it is found in Heaven. No more a
                            slave to any power, That bids her yield to man's control The gifts and talents God has given
                            To bless and beautify the soul. In her own right she stands endowed With power and wisdom
                            from on high, All ready at the Master's call To answer truly "Here am I," To dare, to do,
                            for thee and thine, To minister to those in need, And in thy honored, sacred name, The naked
                            clothe, the hungry feed. <pb n="188" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> ,188 THE MANIFESTO. O waft ye winds to
                            distant islesy The glad triumphant song of peace "Which ushers in the newborn day, When love
                            shall rule and discord cease. O spread the tidings far and near, Christ in his glory comes
                            again ! Let every living thing rejoice, Let all the people say, Amen. Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes referring to the early history of the shakers in the United States, no. 5" TEIform="index"/>Notes Referring to the Early History of the Shakers in the United States. No. 5.</head><p TEIform="p">X TOTHING could exceed her love for Mother Ann and the Elders, and for _L ^ the upbuilding of
                            the gospel which they came to establish in America. In the time of trouble she stood on the
                            side of right, and her zeal and courage never abated. When those who were false-hearted
                            turned away, and attempted to deprive them of the consecrated property, Jemima would speak
                            encouragingly to the young people, and to those who were weak in the faith, and tell them
                            that better times were before them. "Never fear," she would say, "I know that the foundation
                            is sure, and I know that God who has sustained the Believers through all their sufferings
                            and toil will never suffer the gospel work to go down." There was no name so dear to her as
                            the name of Mother Ann. She would often relate the scenes of suffering Mother was called to
                            endure; her seasons of sorrow, and scenes of joy., her words of instruction and admonition,
                            and encouragement to her children, till it seemed that her soul overflowed with a heavenly
                            love. Many times while speaking of these things her soul would be carried beyond earthly
                            scenes, and she would seem to be exploring the heavenly world where Mother dwelt. No one
                            present who had any degree of love to the way and work of God, could avoid feeling a measure
                            of the same apirit with which she was inspired. When preparations were being made to build
                            the Square House, she said, '"I came to the spot selected for the purpose in company with
                            Sister Hannah Willard, the daughter of Isaac. It was then a dense forest, and I gathered
                            boxberries on the spot where the house now stands. I saw the trees that were marked to
                            designate the place, and I felt inwardly impressed at the time. It was unlike anything I had
                            ever felt before that time." "Such peace and quietness pervaded the wilderness that I was
                            perfectly <pb n="189" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 189 charmed. I had but little thought of the
                            great work which was to take place, but when Mother Ann and the Elders came here to take up
                            their abode, I then thought of my early impressions." The writer of these notes, was with
                            her on the evening that her life closed. "Never did I witness a scene like this. Her soul
                            was spent in prayer and supplication, not wholly for herself, but for others. She prayed for
                            the whole household of faith, and then prayed for all mankind. She then fell into a sleep
                            from which there is no waking." The End.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="From death to life" TEIform="index"/>FROM DEATH TO LIFE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="McKechnie, Frederic" TEIform="persName"/>By Frederic McKechnie.</byline><p TEIform="p">The year is dying; the harvest is done ; The corn field, reaped, stands grey in the sun, And
                            the swallows are gathering, one by one. A low wind stirs, but its breath is chill, It blows
                            o'er the brow of the bleak, east hill, Where the moon is rising so ghostlystill! "O, what
                            Presence is this?" I cried in my dread, A Voice in the wind, blew, "Summer is fled, And I,
                            Death, "Winter, am here in her stead; And the grass of the field shall fade away ; And the
                            flower shall perish in cold decay ; And songsters cease, from the iron day. My seal shall be
                            set on each running river, And man shall cower, and beasts shall shiver, And the kingdom and
                            power shall be mine forever." And I heard the Voice, but I made reply, "That which liveth
                            can never die; Thou shalt not triumph utterly The river that flowed, shall flow again,
                            Heaven shall send its gentle rain, And the grass and the flowers re-clothe the plain. Though
                            the spell thou weavest be fast and strong, And quench in silence, the sound of song, It is
                            not for long,it is not for long. For Summer comes, and the slumbering earth Shall wake again
                            into joyous birth, And the wide world ring with the voice of mirth. And yet again, there
                            shall come a day, When thou, O Death, shalt be done away, And Life be ours, for aye and for
                            aye." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="190" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ann Lee" TEIform="index"/>ANN LEE.</head><p TEIform="p">nnO a company that visited Mother Ann and the Elders, she said, JL "You should let your light
                            shine, that others by seeing your good works may be led to glorify your Father in Heaven."
                            This was a lesson in religious discipline, and Mother Ann was anxious to have those who came
                            to see her, learn something that was profitable. The words were the same that had been used
                            by Jesus more than a thousand years before her time, and for aught we know, may have been
                            used a thousand years before the days of Jesus. That they were eminently appropriate to be
                            spoken before a company who had asked the fellowship of the church, may be readily admitted.
                            Mother Ann did not assume to teach a new, exclusive doctrine. The spirit of God gave her
                            power as a witness to stand upright, and she brought out, anew, the revelation of the Christ
                            of God. The foundation of the work which was to make man in harmony with Christ, had already
                            been laid. It was denominated the power of God unto salvation. Already it had wrought so
                            effectually for the purification of the soul that many faithful witnesses had been known
                            among men as the sons of God. That foundation remained sure and needed no human agency to
                            attempt the rebuilding. It was at the hands of its own brethren, however, that it suffered
                            the greatest neglect. Other foundations were built so near that the hay, wood and stubble of
                            the Nicolaitans, the Jezebelites and those of the synagogue of Satan obscured the cross and
                            the testimony of eternal life. The counterfeit has borne the name of the true life, the same
                            as the church of Pergamos bore the name of Christ while it occupied the seat of Satan.
                            Mother Ann arose in the light of the revelation of God and through the ministration of
                            Christ, taught her followers to build on the true foundation ; to keep the heart pure and to
                            deny themselves of all ungodliness and every worldly lust. She urged that they should make
                            themselves so acquainted with the gospel testimony that they could give a reason for the
                            hope that dwelt within them. That they were to be made anew and become the children of the
                            regeneration. This testimony enkindled a fierce opposition and the Believers suffered much
                            abuse at the hands of their enemies. Cruel mobs surrounded their dwellings, bursting open
                            the doors and breaking the windows; while <pb n="191" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 191 many
                            individuals suffered imprisonment and much injury to their persons and property. All this
                            transpired in a Christian country and against those who were zealously advocating the gospel
                            of our Lord, Jesus Christ. The Believers were aGcused of breaking up families and destroying
                            the domestic peace. So far from doing this, they only preached Christ and him crucified and
                            there left the order of life to be lived with the converts. After listening to the good news
                            as taught by Jesus, they were free to serve God or mammon. Mother Ann taught that the work
                            of Christ was the work of regeneration. That those who accepted it must separate themselves
                            from a worldly life. Generation was the old Edenic story. The whole world from the days of
                            Adam had made itself acquainted with its every shade, and was astonished when it learned
                            that all those old things were to be done away, and that all things were to become new. A
                            new heaven and a new earth were to be created wherein should dwell righteouness and peace.
                            Jesus had said, "Verily I say unto you, Ye which have followed me in the regeneration when
                            the son of man shall sit in the throne of his glory, ye also shall sit upon twelve thrones,
                            judging the twelve tribes of Israel." Mother Ann taught the same doctrine and it was to her
                            a representation of the life of Christ. In the order of generation the circle of mine and
                            thine,the selfish propensities dominated. Every man must care for his own little circle. In
                            that order it is just and right that he should. Generation demands that interested care and
                            has a right to see it faithfully regarded in the father, mother, sons and daughters. Its
                            law, its rule and regulations will be found in the Mosaic code. It is the inspired word of
                            God for all who enter the order of generation and by a careful observance of these, it
                            becomes, as said the Apostle, a school-master to lead souls to Christ. In the Christian
                            dispensation we find a new doctrine, a new way of life, and to those who have been faithful
                            to follow, Moses and to keep the law and the commandments, Jesus says, "Follow me ! I am the
                            resurrection and whosoever liveth and believeth in me shall never die." Mother Ann taught;
                            "As you enter the work of regeneration, the relations change from the old inheritance of the
                            flesh, to the relations of Brethren and Sisters in Christ." The evangelists have written for
                            us several of the visits that were made to the Teacher. One disciple who had asked to be
                            admitted as a member into the little band, had arranged in his mind to return to his <pb n="192" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 192 THE MANIFESTO. home and after attending the funeral of his aged
                            father he would be quite free to accept the duties of a disciple, and follow Jesus. From the
                            beginning they had been warned not to look back after having accepted the cross, and Jesus
                            with the authority of a divine Teacher said to him, Let the dead bury their dead : it is
                            your duty to go and preach the kingdom of God. Mother Ann and the Elders taught the same,
                            and the Believers were accused of teaching their members to hate their parents and to become
                            misanthropes. Read what Jesus taught and then go and do likewise. Another disciple, who was
                            of a social turn, thought it would be a nice thing to go and visit his friends and bid them
                            a kind farewell, and then he would be ready to follow Jesus. This was another form of
                            sustaining a union with the generative order of the world, and quite different from the work
                            of regeneration, into which he had been called. The answer that Jesus gave was to the point,
                            although he neither commended nor condemned the course that the young man had suggested. "No
                            man," said Jesus, "having put his hand to the plough, and looking back is fit for the
                            kingdom of God." It would seem that the Teacher was anxious to* impress the disciples with
                            the great importance of serving the Lord their God with their whole soul, and making no
                            reserves for a selfish interest. If the gospel stood above the Law in its blessings, it must
                            also stand above the Law in its sacrifices. When Elijah, under the direction of the spirit,
                            passed through the field, where Elisha, the anticipated prophet, was ploughing, he cast his
                            mantle upon Elisha and, no doubt, said to him,Follow me. Obedient to the call Elisha left
                            his work in the field, and ran after Elijah, as most men would, to obtain permission to do a
                            little visiting. "Let me, I pray thee, kiss my father and my mother and then I will follow
                            thee." Elijah instead of granting the request, administered this well deserved rebuke. "Go
                            back again, for what have I done to thee?" He had placed upon Elisha the anointing oil of
                            the Lord God and it must not be slighted. Elisha omitted the visiting but returned to the
                            place where he had been anointed and sacrificed to the Lot-d a yoke of oxen, and burned the
                            instruments in which they had worked. He then sought Elijah and studied with him to become a
                            prophet in Israel. Those who accept the teachings of the Bible as the word of God, will
                            appreciate these lessons of self-denial and of consecration as leading to something higher
                            than the life of an animal on the generative plane of existence. <pb n="193" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 193 Men who assume to teach a life of holiness before God have all reason to be
                            ashamed, as they flatten the people to read and accept the life of the sensual Corinthians,
                            in preference to the life of Jesus Christ. We may go back to the time when Aaron's sons were
                            appointed to serve before the altar of the Lord. Two of them neglected their religious
                            obligations and willfully trespassed against the Law by the offering of strange fire. For
                            this serious offence they lost their lives. Their bodies were carried out of the camp. Moses
                            then spoke to their father and the other sons. "Uncover not your heads, neither rend your
                            clothes, lest ye die, and ye shall not go out from the door of the tabernacle lest ye die."
                            "The day cometh that shall burn as an oven and all the proud, yea and all that do wickedly,
                            shall be stubble and the day that cometh shall burn them up ; it shall leave them neither
                            root nor branch." The Lord's servants had no time to waste over the death of the willfully
                            wicked. Throughout the whole history cf God's work with man, a consecration has been
                            demanded, that would be a distinguishing mark between the children of God and the children
                            of this world. The testimony of Mother Ann Lee is the spirit of Christ, which will burn as
                            an oven, and of which we may speak with confidence having the assurance that it will
                            establish every honest soul on a foundation which will insure peace and prosperity in time,
                            and in the world to come, eternal life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Blinn.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Who can tell the value of a smile..." TEIform="index"/>Who can tell the value of a smile...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Who can tell the value of a smile? It costs the giver nothing, but is beyond price to the
                            erring and relenting, the sad and ch erless, the lost and forsaken. It disarms malice,
                            subdues temper, turns hatred to love, revenue to kindness, and paves the darkest path with
                            gems of sunlight. A smile betrays a kind heart; the pressure of the hand, an affectionate
                            brother; a cheerful word, a friend in n^ed; kind and courteous deportment toward all, a
                            Christian heart. Kindliness adds a charm to beauty, and adds beauty to a homely face.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vain glory blossoms, but never brings forth fruit..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Vain glory blossoms, but never brings forth fruit...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Vain glory blossoms, but never brings forth fruit. Vanity makes men ridiculous ; Pride,
                            odious. Beware lest you think yourself to be something when you are nothing. The peacock can
                            display much tine plumage, and strut about with much pomp,beware. Before deciding on your
                            own merits, enquire what the world in general think of you. The praise of a friend will do
                            you no harm, and the opinion of an enemy will do you an immense amount of good. The refusal
                            of praise or commendation, often proceeds from a desire for more.</p></div2><pb n="194" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. DECEMBER, 1896. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the
                            "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Okder and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all
                            communications to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. One copy one year,
                            postage paid. .50</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. October. Thermometer. Rain. Snow 1895. 44 4 in. %in.
                                1896. 46 m " 0 Highest Temp, during this mo. 66 above 0 Lowest " " " " 26 " Number of
                                rainy days " " 10 " clear " " " 9 " cloudy" " " 12 C. G. Reed. Nov. 1896. Editor of the
                                Manifesto;Time's shuttle has filled the tissue of another solar month. As we take no
                                note of time, but by its passing, it is well that our Monthly Periodical includes a
                                space for the several families of each Community of our Faith. Not to be found derelict
                                in duty, I present a synopsis of such events and incidents as may be of general interest
                                to the readers of The Manifesto. 1st. The Weather. People generally, are interested Pro
                                et Con, with regard t) the weather. It is either too hot or too cold; too wet or too
                                dry. We had rather a dry Summer; but since Autumn set in, sve have had a superabundance
                                of rain. These extremes cause some people to query whether an over-ruling Providence
                                does, or does not control the weather. 2nd. The Crops. Potatoes have not done as well
                                this season as they did last year. A blight struck them. Other crops, genrally, have
                                been excellent. Small fruits a failure. Br. Benjamin Gates writing from Florida, says;
                                "Our crops never looked better, and as it now appears, we shall have enough to sell to
                                purchase our needful groceries, etc. We have no hired help to pay. The pine-apples at
                                Russel's Orchard, Orlando, I saw last week. He will have 30,000 to 40,000 pine-apples
                                this season. Last year Russel sold $20,000 worth of pine apples and ships to other
                                parties to set new orchards. All this off of eight and one half acres. This season he
                                will sell $30,000 worth of apples and plants. All the hired help he employes is three
                                men. You see he produces from eight and one half acres more net profit than all the
                                Societies of Shakers." It costs us in Lebanon to raise oats about sixty cents a bushel.
                                We can buy them for twenty-five to twenty-seven cents a bushel. 3rd. School. Our school
                                opened Oct. 25. Ada Brown and Rosette Stephens are the teachers, and they are A. No. 1.
                                They have forty scholars under training. 4th. Election or Politics. With all the
                                innovations adopted by the Shakers, eminating from the World of Fashion, ultimately, are
                                we to enter the Arena of Politics and vote? Jesus said; "My kingdom is not of this
                                world, if my kingdom were of this world, then would my servants fight that I should not
                                be delivered to the Jews." The political campaign just closed has been called an
                                educational one. What have the people learned? The coming four years will exhibit its
                                wisdom or its folly. 5th. Health. The present status of TERMS. <pb n="195" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/>
                                THE MANIFESTO. 190 physiological uprightness is quite apparent. Except transcient
                                influenzas there is nothing to indicate debility of body or mind, except old age! 6th
                                Hands and Hearts. So far as hands are considered, there are no idle ones among us. Every
                                individual is giving his or her time and strength in devotion to daily duty in the field
                                of manual labor. Hearts! who can fathom their depths? It is safe to say there are many
                                faithful souls, striving to sustain the cause of truth and righteousness. If there are
                                those who are otherwise inclined, surely they will meet their just recompense and reap
                                the harvest they sow. Calvin G. Heed. North Family. Nov. 1896. Beloved Elder Henry ;I
                                feel it a pleasure, bordering on duty, to express, in brief, our feelings of gratitude,
                                so far as I can convey them on paper, for your unabated interest and labor in sustaining
                                our monthly, The Manifesto. Small, though it is, yet with your other arduous duties, the
                                tax must be heavy upon hand and brain,it can not be otherwise. At this time, when
                                nearing Thanksgiving day, we think it a fitting season to remember in love and sympathy
                                the Editorial department. Next, to extend through its columns, greetings of love and
                                blessing, hope and joy, strength and courage to every Brother and Sister contributor or
                                non-contributor from Maine to Kentucky. To each Zion-bound traveler we hold out the
                                signal of "good cheer." The old ship with her trusty few has weathered the storms for
                                over a century, and is still beating against the tide of innovations that would, if
                                allowed, swamp her and thus bring destruction and ruin upon the whole crew. The old
                                Captain and comrades know every reef, every danger that besets their course, and when
                                urged upon to change it is their duty to give an alarm and it should be given with no
                                uncertain sound, irrespective of place, position or personalities, lest disaster follow
                                in their wake. We have known of a time when naught but the hand of the Lord intervend to
                                save; Aye, times without number. When in the channel of communication with his agents we
                                place ourselves in a position to be saved, but, let our bark drift iuto unknown seas
                                then we break the connecting links and we h.ive n.&gt; promise of security. We have
                                undergone radical changes in the past for the betterment of Society, but never once have
                                we changed our courseour principles. We still hold ourselves ready to meet the incoming
                                tide of moral and spiritual reform which will be sure to hasten our progress toward the
                                goil of destination and triumph, and we throw out our colorsour thoughts to the winds of
                                heaven that we may catch the spiritual breezes and be waited safely into the harbor of
                                peace and salvation. And more than all, that others outside of our domain may see and
                                fee! the power existing within, which calms the troubled waters i&gt;f discontent and
                                strife, and Lids all the tempestuous elements in t^e human heart to cease forever by the
                                sweet persuasive voice of, "Peace be stili!" In the somhrii days of Thanksgiving time we
                                are madu glad by the thought that not an arrow has been sent, nor an ax uplifted, nor a
                                hook inserted to take life with the idea of giving life, realizing that even the pots in
                                the kitchen should be like bowls before the altarholiness unto the Lord. In the joyous
                                Christmas-tide when the Christ comes to us in hisin hersimp^ mien, teaching us the all
                                important lessons of the hourlessons which need to be reiterated in order to be
                                thoroughly understood and retained, we come into greater light, as we receive this
                                Christ anointing through the Divine unction of the Holy Spirit, manifested in his Order
                                upon earth. This new revelation teaches that God is dual, Father and Mother; that Christ
                                is dual, Bridegroom and Bride. This is God's plan and. we can not change it if we would.
                                The serpentine nature <pb n="196" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 196 THE MANIFESTO. wriggles and squirms and
                                trys to invent "some other way," but all to no purpose. Beware then, that we "crucify
                                not the Son of God afresh and put Him to open shame," nor the Daughter of God who is
                                sent to redeem man from his lusts, and stands to-day like Bartholdi's statue of liberty,
                                pointing upward to heaven, and who is here to preserve chastity, and who will cleanse
                                and purify all those who will come unto her. In this bond we are united ; it is the sign
                                by which the true Believer is known; it is the bond of our union, and we must keep it
                                unbroken. Trusting that you will continue to share in heaven's richest blessings bounded
                                only by your capacity to enjoy; I am through Christ, your gospel Sister, Anna White.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. Nov. 1896. One more stroke of the annual timepiece, and, to use an
                                electrical phrase, the circuit will be closed with the record of the past year. Its
                                anticipations and disappointments, in our material life we are glad to let go where they
                                will take their place with the mouldering volumes of the receding years. The future is
                                before us; but only in the present moment we live, To the student who pursues the
                                religious and political writers of the day with a desire to come into rapport with
                                living and moving thought, must notice that there is an anticipation of something beyond
                                the ordinary: that the hour of destiny has struck, and the old must pass away, that the
                                new may have room for development. We trust it will not be in the whirlwind or the
                                tempest, but in the still, small voice which is the only medium through which can come
                                the highest manifestation of divine truth. We are enjoying a delightful autumn which is
                                giving farmers an opportunity to perform the duties necessary: to closing the
                                agricultural campaign of the year. The "Hints to Writers and Speakers" in the Nov.
                                Manifesto is acceptable, and we will boil down our subject; and when we have finished,
                                be sure and stop. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1896. Among the pleasant things to note is the presence of Elder Calvin Reed of Mt.
                                Lebanon, N. Y. Having spent a few days in the Society at Enfield, N. H., he has called
                                to see his gospel friends in Canterbury. We learn that 1160 bushels of apples have been
                                prepared for the kiln. This affords about 200 bushels of dried apples. Our school is in
                                session and twentyseven pupils are present. Henry C. Blinn.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant Hill, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hill, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1896. Providence has dealt graciously with us the past season. Since early May until
                                October we have had a bountiful supply of fruits and vegetables. Strawberries, cherries
                                and peaches have been very plentiful and a daily supply of peaches from the first of
                                June till the first of Oct. Apples have been a limited crop. The beautiful green grass
                                is now supplemented by the various tints of the autumnal leaves which the eye is not
                                tired of seeing. The potato crop, both sweet and northern has been of the best quality.
                                The roofs of several of our dwellings have been painted and beside the preservation of
                                the buildings it adds very much to the beauty of our gospel home. N. L. Rupe.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1896. November is here with its rains and winds. Already the trees are stripped of
                                their leaves, showing to the careful observer that they are preparing for the oncoming
                                winter. <pb n="197" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 197 While we look over the past
                                preparatory for our annual Thanksgiving we will thank God for the dear ones in our own
                                loved home circle. Dear aged fathers and mothers who have toiled through the heat of the
                                day! Faithful middle aged ones who now are bearing the burdens of life, and loving youth
                                and children that our homes are blest with to-day. All these make up the hundred-fold
                                relation that is promised as the heritage of God's people. We find none to spare, yet
                                Br. Samuel Kendrick and Sr. Lydia Mariner are both sick and nearly helpless and we can
                                not expect their tarry with us will be much longer. They have every care from loving
                                Sisters and Brothers and they well deserve it. Sr. Aurelia Mace has recently returned
                                from a visit to Alfred where she stayed a week. We hear that all were blessed by her
                                visit and she in return, received blessing. We forcibly realized our loss while she was
                                absent. On her return, Elder Henry Green accompanied her to our "home for a visit. He
                                tarried but a few days, then returned to his people, leaving with us his good and pure
                                influence. The heating apparatus at our Greenhouse is undergoing repairs. We are having
                                a hot water heater of home manufacture put in and hope it will prove satisfactory. Ada
                                S. Cummings.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1896. "God loves the cheerful giver." In taking a retrospective view of the years
                                which reveal advancement of the various causes that have benefited mankind, we readily
                                see that it has been the generous givers who have endowed humanity, transformed the
                                wilderness of antiquated dogmas and human selfishness, into realms of practical good
                                sense and human rights. And should not the people of God rank first as generous Saviors?
                                thoughtful and kind in their dealing both in the human and animal kingdom. Through the
                                scarcity of apples this season, we have become the recipients of kindred generosity. Our
                                kindred at Mt. Lebanon, and East Canterbury, donated forty-five barrels of extra fine
                                apples. Language with fine embellished sentiment could express our grateful feeling for
                                the gift, but true gratitude is more than mere sentiment, as religion is more than an
                                seolian harpsound that thrills only the heart of man. Not less than twenty barrels of
                                pickles and one ton of beet seed have been sent to market. Another silo of sixty tons
                                capacity has recently been added to our cow barn; and with the large lot of ensilage,
                                one thousand and fifty bushels of turnips have been housed as food for the cows. By
                                request, on the evening of Oct. 25th a company of eight attended service at East
                                Lebanon. A quartette of Sisters rendered several of Zion's inspiring songs. So we would
                                by union of spirit and sentiment, blend with the laws of God, so grandly revealed in the
                                four seasons. In the green of Spring, new life, in the beauty of Summer, the harmony of
                                right living, in the gold of Autumn, the fruits of good industry, and in the white of \V
                                inter, emblems of Christ's purity; features of the soul enrapport with God's
                                commandments. George, H. Baxter.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rankin, Kate" TEIform="index"/>In
                            remembrance of Sister Kate Rankin, who passed away Oct. 11, 1896.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Goepper, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>By Anna Goepper.</byline><p TEIform="p">After being afflicted for two years, she has passed to the higher sphere of being, completing
                            a sojourn on earth of seventyeight years. She has borne her burden of suffering with the
                            cheerfulness characteristic of her bright and hopeful spirit; ever patient and more
                            solicitous for the happiness and comfort of others than for herself. While loving hands
                            anxiously sought to make reposeful the conditions of transition, she looked up, with a smile
                            on her <pb n="198" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 198 THE MANIFES7 0. face never again unclosing her lips in
                            speech. Our Sister was born in Liverpool, Eng. and has been a devoted, quiet, peaceable
                            Sister for many years. I have known her from my childhood and feel perfectly justified in
                            saying she was a brilliant star, an example of patience, a thorough Christian, and an
                            accomplished scholar. It was entertaining to me as a child, to hear her repeat poem after
                            poem, and long lectures from memory. Indeed, she was an extraordinary individual. I felt
                            that I would really be out of my line of duty to refuse to contribute a few words of love to
                            one possessing such a beautiful spirit. "Give her of the fruit of her hands, and let her own
                            works praise her in the gates." "Rest in immortal realms above, Must be forever more as
                            here; "Tis but the Ministry of Love, In this and every sphere; The only rest from care and
                            strife Is Love's sweet harmony with life." Union Village, O.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Onion as a nervine" TEIform="index"/>ONION AS A NERVINE</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Onions are almost the best nervine known. No medicine is so useful in cases
                                        of nervous prostration, and there is nothing else that will so quickly relieve
                                        and tone up a worn out system- Onions are useful in all cases of coughs, colds
                                        and influenza; in consumption, insomnia, hydrophobia, scurvy, gravel, kidney and
                                        liver complaints. Eaten every other day they soon have a clearing and whitening
                                        effect upon the complexion.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York medical times" TEIform="index"/>N. Y. Med. Times.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The above is opportune..." TEIform="index"/>The above is opportune...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The above is opportune. Many a reader will lovingly whisper thanks to the New York
                                Medical Times for placing before him so delectable a dish, with the assurance that it
                                will not only act as a panacea for our long catalogue of ills, but will a.lso rejuvenate
                                the system and beautify the complexion. Indeed, whether boiled, baked, fried, roasted or
                                even raw, onions must be the veritable "Elixir of Life." This will please our good
                                brother John Bradford, who has raised hundreds of bushels of onions this season and
                                obtained a premium for them at the Vermont State Fair.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Blinn.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Why is it?" TEIform="index"/>WHY IS IT?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ryan" TEIform="persName"/>Father Ryan.</byline><p TEIform="p">Some find work where some find rest, And so the weary world goes on. I sometimes wonder which
                            is best. The answer comes when life is gone. Some eyes sleep when some eyes wake, And so the
                            dreary hours go. Some hearts beat where others break. I often wonder why 'tis so. Some will
                            faint where some will fight; Some love the tent and some the field. I often wonder who are
                            right The ones who strive or those who yield. Some hands fold where other hands Are lifted
                            bravely in the strife, And so through ages and through lands Move on the two extremes of
                            life. Some feet halt where some feet tread, In tireless march, a thorny way; Some struggle
                            on where some have fled; Some seek when others shun the fray. Some swords rust where others
                            clash; Some fall back where some move on; Some flags furl where others flash Until the
                            battle has been won. Some sleep on while others keep The vigils of the true and brave. They
                            will not rest till roses creep Around their name above a grave.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rankin, Kate" TEIform="index"/>Kate Rankin
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Kate Rankin, at Union Village, O, Oct. 11, 1896. Age 78 years.</p></div3></div2><pb n="199" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">INDEX. Page. A Autobiography, C. D. Hampton 9, 41, 57 73, 89, 105 Ages, Christ of the 45
                            Aitkin, Fred - - - - 144 Acrostic, An - 168 Ann Lee, - - - - - - 190 Baptism - - - - - - H
                            Basting, LouisLetter - - 117 Brown, G. A. " - - - 133 C Civilization, What constitutes - 61
                            Ceasing, Pray without -!, - . - 107 Christ, The Church of - - . 128 Character, Thoughts on -
                            - 142 Coming, Our Mother is - . - 158 D Duty - - . - - - - 7 Days, Youthful - - - - 28
                            Dispensation, Angels of the New - 107 E Emancipation, The ... 155 Emery, Simon,Letter . - -
                            198 w ' . Father, Smiles of the - - - 3 Faith, Belief v. s. Intelligent - 76 Gethsemane - -
                            - - 14 Page. Home, Notes About 17, 36, 51, 67, 83, 99,. 115, 132, 148, 164, 178, 194
                            Haskill, C. P.Letter - - 87 Home, A few days from - - 117 Influence - - - , - 146 I Jesus -
                            - '- - - - 81 Loyalty 7 Leap, Look before you - - 33 Love, Tribute ofE. Offord - 151 Light,
                            Life in the ... 159 Lilies, Day - - - - - 161 Light, Let there be ... 174 Love, A tribute
                            ofW. Dunn - 176 Life, What is true - ... 177 Life, From Death to 189 Memory, To theR. Blake
                            - 38 Meditations,..... 46 Memorium, InC. Van Houten 55 Memory, InJ. B. Vance 71, 87, 93. 103
                            Memory, InDavid Ray - - 103 Mackie, IsabelLetter - - 143 Muggletonians, The ... 102 N Night,
                            A watch in the - - 72 Nobility - . - - - 184 <pb n="200" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 200 THE MANIFESTO. Page.
                            Page. o U Orcutt, DanielLetter 39 Unselfish - 28 Osgoodites, Among the - 52 V P Vance, J.
                            B.Letter - 31 Powers, C. R.Letter 44 Vance, J. B. ... 64 Prayer, New Year's Patience .... 47
                            w Pickpockets .... - 56 Words, The power of - 10 Words, Kind ... 39, 104 Purity..... 136
                            Peace, Rest in ... - 156 Wright, Remarks of Mother Lucy 169 65, 113, Powers, Untried 172
                            Way, Whichever - 120 Promises .... - 173 Whittaker, Father James - 181 Poem, Christmas ...
                            187 Writers and Speakers, Hints to 184 A Relations, Natural and Spiritual 25 Repose,
                            Christian ... - 32 Year, The Coming New 185 Repentance, Ninevah brought to 55 z Reynolds, M.
                            L.Letter - 70 Zion ..... - 92 Real, Idealize the 131 Remembrance,Kate Rankin 197 MUSIC Songs
                            of Cheer ... 15 Society, Social Improvement - 4 Strikes .... 39 DEATHS Saviors - - - - - 49
                            Blake, Rhoda - - 23 Sanitary 53, 72, 88, 104, 119, 135, 183 152, 167, Brooks, Lucinda 72
                            Dillon, Judith - - 152 Shakers, History of 79* 121, 137, 153, 188 Dunn, William ... 168
                            Shakerism, The Christ Ideal in 124 95, 108, Evington, Ann E. - 152 Stewart, Ezra J.Letter 97
                            Freeborn, Johanna E.- 88 Silent, When to keep - 141 Jones, Mary Jane - - 72 Shaker, Why am I
                            a 170 Landers, Lydia ... 39 Manluff, Mary ... - 120 Testimony,I. Russell - 29 Newton, Ezra -
                            104 Tenderness - 48 Offord, Emily - 152 Thoughts, Secret - - 54 Pomeroy, Bishop 56 Trust
                            .... 55 Ray, David - - 88 Tribute..... - 91 Rushmore, Henry 120 Tribute .... 135 Rankin,
                            Kate - 198 Truth..... - 136 Tyson, Malinda ... - 136 Thoughts - - - - 139 Van Houten,
                            Catherine 56 Temper, Good - 168 Vance, John B. - - - 72</p></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
As we failed to receive the forecasts for
October, we are at a sad loss to determine
what had better be done. To be without
Word and Works is quite like being without
Faith and Works. Men may live, partially,
without either, but we should advise them to
get Word and Works, so soon as they can,
and lay a good foundation upon which to
build a system of Faith and Works. Word
and Works Pub. Co., 2201 Locust St., St.
Louis, Mo.
The Journal of Hygeid-Thekapy and AntiVaccination, for Sept. Oct. and Nov. in one
Magazine contains the Proceedings of the
Indiana State Centennial Phrenological Convention, that was held at Kokoino, Ind. Aug.
22, 24, 1896. All will want to read Prof. Schell
hous' Letter, as he writes in the interest of
"peace on earth." And then they will not fail
to read the Address of Prof. B. F. Pratt, which
is full of good things for the benefit of human,
ity and for the glory of God. This Magazine
of three numbers is quite liberally illustrated,
and contains a harvest of precious treasures,
from the pens of both men and women who
know whereof they speak. Published by Dr.
T. V. Gifford & Co., Kokomo, Ind.
Madeline Yale Wynne, the author of the
remarkable story "The Little Room" in Harper's Magazine, which was so popular a year
or so ago, writes a pleasing short story for the
November Symposium. "A Glance without
Words" in the same magazine, is a literary
vignette that is handled with considerable art.
"Cedar Boughs." Under the above title a
book of poems has been issued by the Mount
Lebanon Shakers. It is the first volume of
the kind ever published by the community
and it reveals to the literary world, what it
may not have know before, that there is much
poetical genius in and about the Lebanon
hills. Many of the poems are "works of art,"
or rather shall we say the inspiration of true
poetical genius, and "Mount Lebanon Cedar
Boughs" will, we believe, take a high rank
among the poems of recent years. The publishers are the Peter Paul Book Co. of Buffalo.
Price of book $1.00. From "The Cha'ham
Courier." Nov. 1895.
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF  THE
 CHURCH,
OE
"United   Society   of   Believers,"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price, 50 cis.
LARGE   SIZE
BAGSTER'S   BIBLE.
MINION   TYPE.
Size, when open, 13ki by 9}2 inches.

BEST    TEACHERS'    HELPS.
13   COLORED   MAPS.
Sent FREE and Carriage Paid
FOR
Only 10 New Subscriptions
ro
SABBATH   READING
 so
A pair of very Bwitifal Colored Piatarss seat Free to each
New Subscriber. Or SABBATH KEADISTG for a year and
the Bible for $2.
Sabbath Reading is having a phenomenal success among Sunday-school Teachers, Christian Endeavorers, Ep worth Leaguers; Mission Workers and Chiistians
generally. It is evangelical, interdenominational, non political.     Send at once for
Free Outfit of Sample Copies, etc.
Address SABBATH   BEADING,
150 Nassau Street, New York.
N. B. When you see this Bible you will
say that no such value was ever offered on
same terms before. It is bound in strong
leather covers, which are limp and lap
over edges generally known as Divinity
Circuit.
POPULAR SCIENCE
Nature, Invention,
Archaeology, Electricity
 Chemistry, Mineralogy,
Health, Hygiene, Medicine
Formerly  Boston  Journal of Chemistry
ENLARGED and IMPROVED.
This popular monthly contain.-, a large n linber of Short, Easy. Practical, Interesting and
Popular, Scientific articles, that can be Appreciated and Enjoyed by any intelligent rea er,
even though he knew little or nothing-of Science. It is intended to interest those who think
Profusely illustrated and Free
from Technicalities
Entirely Different from and much superior to
other papers  with a similar name.
Monthly,   $1.75 per year.    Newsdealers,   15   eta.
Largest Circulation of any
Scientific Paper in the 'World.
Conducted  by BENJ. LILLARD.
108 Pulton St., New York
4g=Mention this paper for a sample copy
MILLENNIAL
NEWS
HEALTH
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
WEEKLY
THE
MONTHLY
OUTLOOK
Published every Saturday.
13 Astor Place                    New York
The Outlook will be in 1897, as it has
been during each of its twenty-seven years
a history of Our Own Times. In its various editorial departments The Outlook
gives a compact review of the world's progress; it follows with care all the important philanthropic and industrial movements of the day; has a complete department of religious sews; devotes much
space to the interests of the home; reviews
current literature; furnishes cheerful table-talk about men and things; and, in
short, aims to give fresh information,
original observation and reasonable entertainment.
Beginning  with the  fifty-fifth volume,
the  paper  will assume the regular magazine size, which will add greatly to its convenience and attractiveness.    The Outlook is published every Saturdayfiftytwo issues a year.    The first issue in each
month is an illustrated Magazine Number,
containing about twice as many as the ordinary issues,   together with a large number of pictures.    The price of The Outlook is three dollars a year in advance, or
less than a cent a day.
Send for a specimen copy and illustrated prospectus to The Outlook, 13
Astor Place, New York City.
THE  ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all their
property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley, 1719 Franklin Ave, St. Louis, Mo.
Svea Co-operative Association,
Laurel Hill, Walton Co.,
West Florida.
Cost of Membership :One hundred
dollars, cash or installments of $2.00
per month. Each member gets the use
of a 10 acre farm, 2 acres planted in
grapes, house with 3 rooms. Write
for particulars.
Largest circulation of any scientific paper In tho
world.     Splendidly illustrated.    No intelligence
man should ho without;  it Weekly, $3.00 a
year; $1.50 six months. Address, MUNN & Co.,
Publishers, 368 Broadway, New York City                                 
For information and free Handbook write to
MUNN & CO., 361 Broadway, New York.
Oldest bureau for securing patents in A m mr ca.
Every patent taken out by us is brought befora
the public by a notice given free of charge in the
A cream  of  tartar   baking   powder.
Highest of ail in leavening strength.
Latest    United   States   Government
Food report.
Royal Baking Powder Co., Mew York.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>