<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0212" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><date value="18721201" TEIform="date">December 1872</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">89-96</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="89" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">fHE SHAKER. " I WILL SHAKE ALL NATIONS, AND THE DESIRE OP ALL NATIONS SHALL COME; AND I WILL PILL
                        THIS HOUSE WITH GLORY, SAITH THE LORD.' Published Monthly, by and under the direction of the Mt.
                        Lebanon Bishopric. Vol. II. G. A. Lomas, Editor. SHAKERS, ALBANY CO., N. Y., DECEMBER, 1872. No.
                        12. Fifty Cents pkk Annum.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian self-denial" TEIform="index"/>Christian Self-Denial</head><p TEIform="p">"Except a man deny himself."—(of what ?) Christ. " Brave Conquerors! for so yon are, who
                            battle with your own affections, and the whole army of the world's desires." Shakspeare.
                            Human nature hates restriction; it can see no propriety in limiting a pleasant indulgence ;
                            it worries, frets, scolds and galls under the failure of full satisfaction. We know there is
                            such a thing as satiety; we can eat and drink until food in its very best form becomes
                            loathsome—we can indulge all the senses to the exhaustion of nature-—yet nature, in this
                            exhausted condition, pines at its limits, and does not thank God for the boundary. In a
                            country whose laws extend to its subjects the largest liberties—a country, in which "Young
                            America" is trained from the cradle to think that obedience to parental authority is of
                            infantile length only, and then to feel, that to do as he pleases is his inalienable
                            right—'tis here, that self-denial is at a discount, and self-gratification at a premium,
                            more than elsewhere. 'Tis here, that true liberty is misconstrued, and the silver years, if
                            they are reached, are left to teach, that " he alone is free whom the truth makes free," and
                            that the teachings of truth are strongly flavored, with " touch not, taste not, handle not."
                            He is not free who does as he pleases (unless he pleases to do rightly), but the worst of
                            slaves, to the worst of tryants—the passions. Jesus taught, and practiced self-denial, and
                            for this, was very unpopular with the world. His ideas were accepted and practically carried
                            out by an unpopular few; while he was given the choice of relinquishing his doctrines, or of
                            dangling from a three-cornered edifice until life should ebb away. And we opine, that were
                            the millions of professedly Christian people, compelled to practice what they profess—real
                            Christianity—they would soon renounce all claim to the title! Were there not educated
                            adepts, dealing out explanations of what scriptural selfdenial does not mean, in a manner
                            that permits the self-adulation and gratifications of their auditors, there would soon be
                            only as many Christians in name, as in practice ; while the present popularity of the name
                            would then become the synonym of eontempt ! With a large respect for religious sincerity, we
                            cannot hold from saying, that humanity are so prone to indulgence, that they have
                            transformed genuine Christianity into a requirement much better adapted to their desires,
                            and most assuredly without the sanction of its author. The grand truth will one day be
                            discovered, that the terms "Self-denial" and "Selfgratification" are antipodes, and not
                            synonyms. We are constrained to ask of popular Christians : Where is your self-denial and
                            cross ? Wherein is your life, other than carnal men and women choose to have it ? Does not
                            popular Christianity suit the masses exactly, and is it not very diverse from the life of
                            Jesus, whose Christianity, though unpopular, was eminently genuine and practical ? We ask
                            for no needless excoriations ; we plead for none of the excruciatingpractices of wild
                            fanatics, who would lacerate the body for the good of the soul, and mistakenly find
                            themselves the same ; but we do plead for that Christian selfdenial, practiced by Jesus, and
                            taught to his disciples, with the injunction, " Follow me!" Our investigations and
                            conscience will not permit us to make the terms " Selfdeny " and " Self-gratify " identical.
                            We admit, our perverted senses would have had Jesus remarked: "Unless a man gratify himself,
                            in every conceivable manner,, he cannot be my disciple;" but to the horror of our sensual
                            appetites, they are to. be denied and crucified, or we cannot attain to a fellowship with
                            Christ! Let us be assured, that the "redeeming blood of Christ/" will ultimately appear to
                            all as ths: "practical life of Jesus; and that the one will never cleanse us from our
                            iniquities until we adopt the other. As professing Christians, let us be practical ones ; if
                            Jesus is our example, let us live as he lived—let his self-denials be ours. Never let us
                            make the charge, that we cannot live as he did, else we make Jesus most unreasonable in
                            saying: " Let him deny himself, take up his cross and follow me." And let us here admonish
                            the Pastors of the large variety of churches, to preach Christ, unbiassed by any creed of
                            human invention; preach Christ, as Jesus lived; and forget not to remind your flocks, that
                            the virginal celibacy of Jesus; the " alLthings-in-common" principle that he urged; the
                            non-resistant element in which he lived, and keeping himself " unspotted from the world,"
                            cost him just as much, and no more self-denial, than is required of us who profess his
                            discipleship, and hopefully expect to share in his heaven the fruits of Self-denial. Let
                            each one practically learn our Saviour's name, taught in the school of Christ—Self-denial.
                            *.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peter, the Christ" TEIform="index"/>Peter, The Christ</head><byline TEIform="byline">by <persName reg="Myrick, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. Myrick</byline><p TEIform="p">"Search the Scriptures," " For in them ye think ye have eternal life, and they are they which
                            testify of me; and ye will not come to me, that ye may have life. Eull well ye reject the
                            (present) commandments of God, that ye may keep your own traditions." This exhortation of
                            Jesus, to " search the Scriptures," was to renew their faith in the prophecies which
                            testified of his mission. He did not say go back into a semi-barbaric age, when just
                            revengewas tolerated, making the "new commandment" of universal love "of none effect by your
                            old traditions;" but to those inspirational truths by which "ye think ye have eternal life;"
                            and I am now declaring them unto you. The first and greatest is supreme love to God, and
                            second,, fraternal love to man. On these two hang all the law and the prophets. Read John
                            5£h,. 17th, and remainder of the chapter, wherein is recorded the sublimest idea of his;
                            life—the Fatherhood of God:. He said, " I am the Son of God." And again, Our Father
                            declaring; others to be sons of God as really as himself—claiming also to-be the son of man-
                            as well as they. "Whosoever speaketh a word against theson of man,, it shall be forgiven
                            him;, but whosoever speaketh against the holy ghost," or anointing, which constitutes a
                            child of God, "it shall not be forgiven him." Thus admitting equality with other " sons of
                            men," and recognizing the divine relationship, as they become. " sons of God." He asked them
                            (his disciples,) " But whom say ye, that I am ?"' And Simon Peter an\ swered and said, "
                            thou art the Christ,,the son <pb n="90" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 9O THE SHA.KER. of the living God."
                            Omitting the interlude of blessing and confirmation, we have the direct response of Jesus:
                            "I say also unto thee, that thou art, (i.e. so are you) Peter," and upon this rock—" this
                            primary principle of Fatherhood in Deity, and Sonship of humanity in Christ"—will I build my
                            church; and the gates of hell (the false systems of theology, with their Adamic practices,
                            war, triune God, and vicarious atonements) shall not prevail against it. By a slight change
                            in punctuation, is not the analogy in the context more complete? and does it not give a
                            better rendering of the meaning Jesus intended to convey ? The common error that Peter,
                            signifying rock, should be the foundation of an everlasting church—who at most could be but
                            an active agent—is fraught with grave consequences, when solomnized by a creed, and draped
                            about with kindred, damaging phraseologies. Supposing Jesus had said, thou art Thomas, and
                            upon this twig (the scripture name of Thomas) will I build, etc. ? Reason fails to support
                            the long accepted belief, that the declaration to Peter bore any relation to him, or the
                            significance of his name. But to the parental and endearing relationship, existing between
                            the infinite and finite souls, this was the rock, the basis and eternal principle on which
                            to build. And it was this revelation to Peter, which Jesus hastened to bless and confirm.
                            "And I say also vmto thee," "That thou art," Christ, in good degree, And " blessed art thon,
                            Simon," Brother— "Son of the living God," the Father. O Father make them one with me, Even
                            as I am one with thee; We have one master, the Christ sph-it, An heirship such as each shall
                            merit. This declaration of Jesus, that Peter was " Christ, the son of the living God," which
                            also applies to all who became one with him, by obeying Christ as he did, does not preclude
                            the second distinctive advent of Christ in a representative personage—" like unto the Son of
                            Man"—the Daughter of Man—Ann, "the Christ"—the Daughter of the living God." And this is the
                            second appearing of Christ, in glory, supplanting that which was in part. " Beloved, now are
                            we Sons and Daughters of God." Christs, Saviours, " a great multitude, which no man could
                            number of all nations, and kindreds, and people, and tongues, clothed in white robes, and
                            palms of victory in their hands." " Singing salvation to our (dual) God. Blessings, and
                            glory, and wisdom, and thanksgiving, and honour, and power, and might, be unto [and from]
                            our God forever and ever." " Search the Scriptures," which testify unto us such glorious
                            truths, and we will come unto them " that we may live."</p></div2><div2 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To day" TEIform="index"/>To day
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"To Day:"—This is the name of a Health (?) Journal, by Dio Lewis. It is quite interestingly
                            arranged for the general reader. But it is so far from being a radical Health Reformer, we
                            doubt its necessity. Let it go deeper than aught else, or let it suspend. *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Impending evil" TEIform="index"/>The Impending Evil</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">"The wise man (or people) seeth the evil afar off, and hideth himself." In these United
                            States, there is in process of formation a Church-and-State party. It is already larger than
                            " a man's hand," and combines together the master minds of various sects ; being composed of
                            all those who confound religion and theology, and spiritualism and religion—the old country
                            originated donominations, the Catholics, Episcopalians, the dissenting Methodists, Baptists,
                            Lutherans, Calvinists, including the Russian or Greek Church, etc., who are, at the present
                            time, Church-and-State establishments in the Christian War Governments of Europe. Can any
                            rational person have a doubt that what these theological bodies do in England, France,
                            Sweden, Denmark, Belgium, Russia, Canada, and the South American States, today, they will do
                            in the United States as soon as it can be effected ? or that the practical rule of a
                            Church-and-State Government will be the same here as there ? "Is thy servant a dog?" asked
                            Haziel of the Prophet Elisha, when he informed him of what he would do to Israel; and the
                            blindness of Haziel, respecting his own character, touching religious persecution, appeared
                            to be common to human beings. Some of the most conscientious and religiously sincere, but
                            theologically erroneous, persons I meet, believe that none but theologically correct men
                            (according to their standard) ought to be legislators. These think the race has progressed
                            beyond religious persecution, and that they will not again " do this thing." To them, the
                            fire and faggot, the rack and pulley, are things of the past, and could not be reproduced.
                            The believer in war, when possessed of political power, (human nature being unchanged) will
                            always " think that in killing heretics, he is doing God good service." How often have peace
                            people thought that Christian wars were ended. But Christian war, and Christian religious
                            persecution will only die drowning in the blood of the martyrs, which war Christians have
                            shed, locked in each other's arms. Theological errors (which are the seeds of religious
                            persecution, such as) First, That the Douay Bible, King James's Bible, or any one of the
                            Dissenting Bibles, is the "Word of God." Second, That the priesthood are infallible
                            interpreters of the Bibles. Third, That some men, as Adam, Noah, Abram, Moses, and seventy
                            of the Elders of Israel, " saw God," the Supreme Being and conversed with him " face to
                            face." Fourth, That the will of Deity creates and makes a thing right or wrong ; so that the
                            invasion, robbery, and spoliation of whole nations, or those of Canaan, by Joshua, attended
                            by the infliction of rape and murder, was doing God great service. These dogmas, and their
                            practical illustration in the Bible history, have been the basis of similar treatment by
                            Christian demons, like the Crusaders, the Duke of Alva, Cortes, Pizarro, Cromwell, the Duke
                            of Marlborough, and the New England Puritans, when they killed heathen Indians and pious
                            Roger Williams, or when they hung peaceable Quakers, and burnt (as a witch) a spiritual
                            medium on Boston Common. Nearer home. The above are good enough illustrations of what
                            theologically mistaken, religious souls will do, when they have the civil power in their
                            hands, through a union of Church-and-State. But, when we find a contemporary of Mother Ann
                            Lee—her John Baptist, the Angel-representative of Spiritualism, as she was of religion—the
                            learned and gentle seer of the North, Emanuel Swedenborg, holding the above named dogmas as
                            premises, and carried logically to the same conclusion of "thinking" that the killing of
                            heretics was a Christian duty ; and affirming that the most innocent and lamblike of all the
                            sects which had come up in Babylon—Christendom—and the very people out of whom Shakerism
                            arose, " ought to be put to death," we stand aghast! confounded ! and confirmed in the fact,
                            that theological errors produce religious persecution, as an acorn produces an oak tree; and
                            that no theology should ever be permitted into the now simple and pure American
                            Constitution. I quote from the " Debatable Land," by my old friend and former associate, R.
                            D. Owen, pp. 231,2. "Premise: Jehovah himself descended, and assnnied humanity." " Speaking
                            of those 'who are called in the world Socinians, and some of them Arians,' he (Swedenborg)
                            says : • The lot of both is * * * that they are let down into hell among those who deny God.
                            These are meant by those who blaspheme the Holy Ghost, who will not be forgiven either in
                            this world, or in that which is to come.' " Even worse than this is the cruel spirit,
                            aggravated by the assumption of false pre- mises, in which he speaks of those whom he ought
                            to have commended and hailed as spiritual brethren. We have it under his own hand, as
                            divinely revealed to him, that the Quaker worship is so execrable and abominable, that, if
                            Christians but knew its true character, ' they would expel Quakers from Society, and permit
                            them to live only among beasts.' And this—think of it—from one who deemed himself the penman
                            of God ! the recipient and inditer of truth unmixed with error. " In Swedenborg's Diary,
                            under date Oct. 29, 1748, he says: ' The secret worship of the Quakers, sedulously concealed
                            from the world, was made manifest. It is a worship so wicked, execrable, and abominable,
                            that, were it known to Christians, they would expel Quakers from Society, and permit them to
                            live only among beasts. They have a vile communion of wives, etc' Again, Oct. 28, 1748: '
                            They are indomitably obstinate in their aversion to having their thoughts and doings made
                            public. They strove with me and the spirits who desired (but in vain) to know their
                            secrets.'—(See Emanuel Swedenborg, his Life and Writings, by William White, London, 1867,
                            vol. 1. pp. 386, 387). <pb n="91" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SH-A.KLER. 91 "The poison of intolerance, in
                            its most malignant type, still works among a bigoted portion of Swedenborg's followers. The
                            (London) Intellectual Repository is the accredited organ of orthodox Svvedenborgianism. Its
                            editor (sixteen years since, however), after stating his opinion, that ' spirits, even the
                            highest angels, have nothing to tell us in relation to doctrine and life, but what is
                            revealed in the word,' goes on to say: ' We therefore conclude that it is not only
                            dangerous, but impious, to seek to have communion with spirits, especially in regard to any
                            thing of doctrine and life.' But he does not stop here. He tells us that there is good
                            reason for the command, ' so often repeated to the children of Israel, to put those to death
                            who had familiar spirits, and who were necromancers,' or, as in the Hebrew text, ' asked
                            inquiries of the dead.' "—Intellectual Repository, vol. for 1855, pp. 400, 461. "Anything
                            worse than this, we may search the records of modern theology in vain to find." Let all
                            theologies be vigorously excluded from the only free government on earth, "and forever
                            confine its functions to secular education, and the internal rights and duties of" its
                            citizens.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Devotion and love, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>Devotion and Love.—No. 1</head><byline TEIform="byline">BT <persName reg="Pelham, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. PELHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">If thou hast wholly given and devoted thy life, thy all, and thyself to God, what is it to
                            thee whether thou be in this part of space or that, here, or there, or two hundred miles
                            hence, if so be thou art in obedience to God ? If God be thy only treasure, and to do his
                            will thy meat and drink, surely thou wilt be content wherever thou shalt be placed ; the
                            gift of God not being confined to places, persons nor things, but is always found where duty
                            calls. By how much thou art attached to places and creatures, by so much thou lackest of
                            being wholly devoted to God. " Let the words of my mouth and the meditations of my heart be
                            acceptable in thy sight, 0 Lord my redeemer," said David. 0 how watchful and prayerful must
                            I constantly be, to keep this holy, heavenly frame of mind, here expressed by the devout
                            Psalmist. I must speak no word, indulge no train of thoughts, act from no motives, but such
                            as I believe will be acceptable to the Lord. How constantly must I watch ! How fervently
                            must I pray! 0 how closely must I scrutinize and sift each thought, word and action, if all
                            I think and do and say shall be done to the acceptance and glory of God. When thou shalt
                            steadfastly reject thyself and be wholly resigned to do the will of God, thou shalt hear the
                            divine voice within thee saying, " this is my beloved son, in whom I am well pleased." It is
                            written that " obedience is better than sacrifice," but obedience and sacrifice both are
                            better still. We are often exhorted to labor for the quickening power of God, and it is
                            certain that every soul needs it. But who has a distinct idea what it is ? Oh give me a "
                            quickened," tender, sensitive conscience. Let my moral sensibilities be deeply enlivened,
                            that I may sense even the distant approach of an evil thought, and shut up every avenue of
                            my soul against it. This is the quickening power of God which will effectually shield the
                            soul from the least stain of pollution. We often talk of " traveling " in the gospel; we say
                            we are determined to "go on" to " persevere " and " go ahead ;" but we should remember, and
                            never forget, that whosoever travels, is continually leaving something behind. It is
                            impossible that we should become " new creatures" any further or faster than, putting off
                            the old, we get new ideas, new motives, new objects of affection, and new everything. Paul's
                            " new and living way," only means " a new way of living;" devoting our lives to God and not
                            to self. Unless we can perceive in ourselves that we are loosing our relish for mere earthly
                            things, and increasing in the love of those which are spiritual, heavenly and eternal, we
                            may be assured that we are not traveling, not ripening for eternity. If we do not die, and
                            die continually to that which is sensual and earthly, we shall neyer rise to that which is
                            spiritual and heavenly. "I protest," saith Paul, " I die daily." No matter how much gift,
                            power and spirit of God others may possess, we shall not be able to apprehend it in them,
                            nor receive it from them, unless we have a measure of the same. " No man can come to me,"
                            said Jesus, " except the Father draw him." Grace must answer to grace. We cannot receive the
                            Divine Nature by imputation, but by impartation—not by proxy, but in our own souls. He is
                            unacquainted with the love of God and true devotion, who feels to boast of his devotedness,
                            and is expecting some outward reward for his secret devotions. How groveling and selfish
                            would he be thought who professed ardently to love a friend, and often visiting him and
                            holding sweet converse, should be found secretly expecting, or openly demanding, money as a
                            reward of his time and pains ! Sad.—Between the 27th October and 5th November, the home of
                            The Shaker was visited by two disastrous fires. One at Second Family—the large barn with all
                            of its contents—loss, at least, $11,000. The other at South Family, in which the loss was
                            even greater. Three barns, wagon house, with accompanying sheds, with all their contents
                            were swept away. Our dairies are well nigh ruined. We should rather have recorded these
                            fires as accidents—but are constrained to write incendiarism ! The object was robbery in the
                            other families—this was attempted at each fire—but proved a failure. We live in hopes of the
                            arrest of the parties—and until then— and afterward—will pray: " God have mercy on their
                            souls ! "</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No surrender" TEIform="index"/>"No Surrender."</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName"/>WATSON ANDREWS</byline><p TEIform="p">" The following lines were suggested to me by the noble leader in November number of The
                            Shakejj." This war-cry through the nations rings, -And wakes the sleeping spheres; And Hope,
                            replumes her drooping wings, And points to coining years. There's strength within these
                            magic words— There's vigor in their sound, As backward roll the opposing hordes, And clear
                            the doubtful ground. "On, up and on!" bright legions shout, Yours is the victory; And Hope's
                            glad eye beholds the rout, While echo answers—"Victory." What though the ebbing tides
                            disclose The fossils of the deep! What though it seems in vain, that those Bright saints
                            their vigils keep! The laws that lead the ebbing tide, Bring the returning wave; Growth and
                            decay, here, side by side, Their proper oflice have. The seed cannot be quickened, more,
                            Except it first decay; And Cities, Xations, o'er and o'er, Arise, then pass away. But
                            principles do not decay; And virtue never dies; When all things else have passed away They
                            reascend the skies. They reascend, but not alone— Their votaries go too, And sing: " Thy
                            will, oh God be done!" In songs forever new.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fashion" TEIform="index"/>Fashion</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, F. W." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We copy below with great pleasure from the Albany Evening Times—our most interesting
                            local—that which should be preserved in letters of gold. It is from the facile pen of "Will
                            Wimble," or F. W. White, whose future we will watch with brilliant anxiety. <cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Albany evening times" TEIform="index"/></bibl><quote TEIform="quote">" Strange, invisible power! A mythical queen, that has more followers than
                                    Christianity, and whose mandates are obeyed more blindly and willingly than those of
                                    the most august potentate; whose reign is perpetual, whose tastes are capricious and
                                    whose whims are preposterous L Whence she comes or where she abides, no human being
                                    can tell, but her will is communicated to mankind by some inscrutable instinct, and
                                    with a marvelous submission her subjects follow and yield to her wildest fancies.
                                    The rich and poor, high and low, intelligent and dull, saint and sinner, are slaves
                                    to her desires; the wealthy and independent are the quickest to fawn upon her, and
                                    no matter how tyrannical her reign, they glory the more in their idol, and are her
                                    most eager votaries. Should man in his greatness rise to overthrow her mandates, or
                                    refuse allegiance to her laws, Queen Fashion's premier, Society, frowns upon him and
                                    he is cast into the disgraceful abyss of old fogy ism and eccentricity. "The notion
                                    is nearly everywhere prevalent that whatever is fashionable is right; it would have
                                    few objections made to it if the reverse were as true, that whatever is right should
                                    be fashionable. If such were the case, not so many, as now do, would leave unpaid
                                    the tradesman and the state, to worship long and lovingly at the shrine of
                                fashion."</quote></cit></p></div2><pb n="92" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Theological wrangling" TEIform="index"/>Theological Wrangling</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WILLIAM H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">The combative spirit is common to mankind. Whether, as the phrenologists tell us, there is an
                            original faculty in human nature inclining men to fight, which, by an excess of growth,
                            overbalances the other faculties; or there is some other cause for it, the fact is evident
                            that a disposition to contend with each other has ever been prevalent among human beings.
                            Some seem to quarrel from a mere fondness for strife ; others, however, seek some pretext to
                            justify themselves for whatever contests they engage in. This is especially true of
                            theological combatants. These are almost universally found in " the sacred orders;" they
                            have been set apart for the defence of the truth, and, of course, they must discharge their
                            sacred functions. They have high authority for their line of conduct;—"Earnestly contend for
                            the faith once delivered to the saints," is the injunction of holy writ, and nothing more is
                            needed to fire their souls with sacred ardor for God's cause. Woe, then, to the unfortunate
                            heretic who ventures to hurl a dart, however feebly, against the truth as they understand
                            it! The zealot for God's holy cause, allows nothing to stand in the way of his divine rage.
                            He smites-his foes on the righthand and on the left. " Athanasius contra mundum" is
                            conspicuous on the banner which he unfurls to the breeze, and he bids defiance to every
                            adversary. But, unfortunately for the peace of society, some Arius is usually found to
                            accept the challenge; and then begins the wordy strife, which ends, if not in blood, as in
                            ancient times, yet in embittered feelings in those who engage in the controversy, and
                            hostility more or less marked between those who take sides with either combatant. But,
                            thanks to the diffusion of better views respecting human duties and obligations, the rancor
                            once existing among theological disputants is greatly softened. It is true there are parties
                            still that look upon each other with suspicion, fearful lest something terrible may ensue by
                            the prevalence of one or another set of opinions; yet one cannot fail to see that there is
                            in the present age a greater inclination than formerly existed, to discover what good thing
                            there may be in this or that feody of religious people. Let this continue, aed. the best
                            consequences may be expected. For where there is a disposition to praise whatever good may
                            be found, instead of looking after some heretical dogma, each body of people will be emulous
                            of the good, and more ready to .-abandon their senseless, wordy contests about mere
                            speculative views. And this, in fact, is ** the faith once delivered to the saints." It was
                            the faith of Jesus, who proclaimed the reign of Divine Love, and who referred his
                            adversaries to the good he had done as a proof that the doctrines he taught were of divine
                            origin. It was the faith of the Apostles, who .labored incessantly to form a church,
                            distinguished by the love its member: should bear to each other, and by the blameless life
                            they lived, so as to become an acceptable offering to their Divine Head. It will be found by
                            those who carefully look at ;he matter, that Paul, theologian as he was, aimed to bring all
                            the converts of Christianity ;o a unity in the life of Christ, and not to form a mere set of
                            Theological Institutes; though unfortunately, contentious minds have since his day made his
                            writings a mere football on the arena of theological strife. There have always been those
                            who have insisted that their peculiar dogmas shall be accepted by others, because to
                            themselves these opinions seem of so much importance. And that is the ultimatum of their
                            gospel. They do not seem willing to present with the strongest array of arguments they can
                            command, what seems to them to be truth, and ;hen let it rest to be accepted or rejected by
                            others according to their own judgment. They want others to admit the superiority of their
                            views, and, as a matter of course, of their judgment. Hence, they are ready to attack all
                            opinions opposite to theirs, though these may have been as carefully formed as their own.
                            There certainly can be no objections to efforts for the discovery of every truth in God's
                            universe, and for the promulgation of the same; but why insist that we have the truth if we
                            cannot prove it ? And if we can prove what we present, there need be no fear but it will be
                            ultimately accepted by all, though the discoverer's name should be buried in perpetual
                            oblivion. The life of Christ proves itself divine to all who accept it and walk in it, and
                            there is no controversy respecting it among all such. It is the " shining light that shines
                            more and more unto the perfect day." Love, kindness, gentleness, fidelity to duty, and
                            peaceableness of conduct produce no strife. Those only who are destitute of these, but
                            possess the opposite qualities, arc the originators and promoters of the contentions that
                            curse the world.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Day dawns" TEIform="index"/>"The Day Dawns."</head><p TEIform="p">Editor Shaker : If you think the enclosed worthy a place in The Shaker, as evidence that "
                            the leaven which the woman (Ann) hid" is working-, please insert. Such an article conlil not
                            have found a place in the London Quarterly a very few years since. Let us thank God and take
                            courage—"The day dawns." Yours, John Whitkley. THE FEMININE ELEMENT IN THE DEITY. The London
                            Quarter!)/, in discussing the feminine element in our conception of God, says: "To
                            Protestants the worship of the Virgin is a superstition, graceful and beautiful in manjr of
                            its aspects, no doubt, but, like all other superstitions, liable to run into extravagance,
                            and to ally itself with fancies socially injurious and absurd. We are, therefore, discreet
                            and prudent in not allowing this element to creep into our habits of religious worship.
                            Nevertheless, we have something to learn from it; it indicates a want, an instinct which we
                            have too long disregarded—the want of affectionateness, tenderness, and love in our con-
                            ceptions of the Deity in His relations to us, and our relations to Him. The reason why our
                            services are so cold, so dry, so formal, so fruitless of any sweet and genial results in
                            actual life, is perhaps owing to our inaptitude or slowness to conceive of the feminine
                            element in the character of our Creator, and to a notion that piety ought always to be
                            manly, as we call it, and never womanly. If, however, any Protestant, believing in the
                            superiority of tiis faith, contemplates the conversion of the Roman Catholics, he may be
                            sure that he will make little or no progress (especially among women), until the defect of
                            his cold system is cured, and his want supplied; until by him and his Church the Supreme
                            comes to be regarded tenderly as well as reverently, with the affections as well as the
                            intellect, familiarly as well as awfully, as a father that pitieth his children, as a
                            shepherd that taketh the lambs in his arms. If from conceptions of dignity and respect, of
                            power, awe, and majesty associated (and fitly associated) with God, a certain order of minds
                            find it hard to supplement any softer or more commonly human element, they will find that
                            whatever the effect may be as regards their personal religion, they will have very small
                            influence indeed over the hearts of their fellow-men; they may teach philosophy, but they
                            will not enkindle piety. They will find that what they cannot add, humanity in general will
                            add, because it instinctively must, and that if men are forbidden by philosophy to
                            incorporate pity and soft tenderness into their ideas of Supreme Deity, they will fall back
                            upon some other deity associated with the Supreme, less wise and powerful, perhaps, but more
                            gentle and kind. Can we love the same being whom we honor, reverence, worship, and obey ? We
                            answer, Yes ! provided we have presented to us the loving and lovable qualities of his
                            character. Many clever people, however, seem practically to answer, No, because from some
                            cause or other they fail to appreciate the sweetness as well as the light of the divine
                            nature. But poor humanity refuses to be balked in its affections, and hence the worship of
                            Notre Dame, instead of Notre Dieu."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Woman's visitation" TEIform="index"/>Woman's Visitation</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>ALOXZO G. HOLLISTER</byline><p TEIform="p">Poor, oppressed, feeble woman, who has hitherto been considered mostly as an appendage to
                            man, useful or ornamental—a convenient piece of household furniture, having no more rights
                            than a born slave, is at last visited ; and in the face of custom, prejudice, man-made laws,
                            and the accumulated wrongs of sixty centuries, is liberated from her degraded vassalage, and
                            enabled to assume her proper station beside the most exalted virtue—a virtue which only one
                            man had before her attained, and which was deemed so far above human capacity, that men
                            ascribed it to Divine Power and ceased striving to reach it. Does not this event mark an era
                            in human progress more significant and full of promise than any that has preceded it ? What
                            more potent cause of human degradation and misery could exist, than for man to be bound by
                            inexorable law to woman, and woman at the same time denied her proper rights, trodden under
                            foot, and evermore despoiled of purity and innocence, which alone give beauty and
                            elasticity, with the sweetest graces to the <pb n="93" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 93 mind, and
                            wings to those aspirations which lift the soul heavenward ? What, but the enmity of the
                            serpent working in this channel ? God said, " I will put enmity between thee and the woman,
                            and between thy seed and her seed." The serpent's turn was first; and as long as man and
                            woman loved to have it so, and mutually cherished that serpentine nature, depicted in
                            ancient lore thus: "I find more bitter than death, woman, whose heart is as snares and nets,
                            and her hands as bands," no remedy could be applied. In such case, though every unjust
                            statute on the books had been erased, the cause that produced them, operating in the channel
                            of "desire" or lust, would still tyrannize over, and "accuse" those who should be, as
                            brethren and as sisters. The private torture of domestic tyranny, through the operation of
                            disorderly passions, is a far more grievous fountain of bitterness than all the laws of the
                            statute books and public opinion added, as millions of sufferers can testify. But after
                            having suffered enough from that enmity, and eaten sufficient fruit from that deadly root to
                            desire escape from it at any cost, even to the loss of all things, God mer- cifully sends
                            down a power to fulfill the pledge given in this promise: " It shall crush thy head"—this
                            was in Christ's first appearing ; " and thou shalt lie in wait for her heel," —at the second
                            appearing. (Douay translation). Expositors generally concede that Jesus Christ was the
                            woman's seed who was to crush the serpent's head; but having only a glimmer of the true
                            light, under the vail of antichrist, they do not appear to understand how it was
                            accomplished, nor that the same work must be effected in every soul that would participate
                            in its benefit. His testimony, which was the exposition of his practice, we have in these
                            words: " If a man come unto me and hate not his father, mother, wife, children, brethren and
                            sisters, yea, and his own life also, he cannot be my disciple." Never man spake like this
                            before, and no wonder they were astonished at his doctrine, for even to this day, but a few
                            of mankind have been able to receive, or even to comprehend its true meaning. That is to
                            come. As his was a mission of peace and good will to all men, he could not mean we should
                            hate persons, but those selfish ties of flesh and blood which arise from these
                            relationships, and that worldly self-pleasing life which produces and sustains them. We have
                            no account that Jesus ever taught hatred to anything else, and this shows us where and what
                            the serpent's seed is. The serpent of perverted generation, as well as natural reproduction,
                            received a deadly wound from the life and testimony of Jesus and his immediate followers,
                            who, by their perfect obedience to the new creating word, received a power which returned
                            the serpent's enmity upon his own head. But after the fall of the Primitive Church, by its
                            connection with the generative order through the unredeemed woman, the artful doctors and
                            creed mongers of antichrist's kingdom, contrived to heal the wound, and preserve the serpeni
                            to " lie in wait" for the woman's heel. What further of the serpent treader is recorded in
                            the Prophet Micah ? "Arise and ;hrash, 0 daughter of Zion; for I will make thy horn iron,
                            and thy hoofs brass; and thou shalt beat in pieces many people, and I will consecrate their
                            gain unto the Lord, and their substance unto the Lord of the whole earth," jy sundering the
                            selfish ties and crucifying ;he lusts of natural generation—the serpent's seed—and devoting
                            their substance to a sacred md united interest, spiritual and temporal. Here a daughter is
                            represented as co-operating in the same work that was appointed for the son, to whom it was
                            given to " rule all nations with a rod of iron, and to dash them in pieces like a potter's
                            vessel." How did they obtain this power ? By perfect obedience. As it is now the woman's
                            day, with the man, to hate the serpent and his seed in all their alluring, deceitful arts,
                            to cut loose from their snares and bands, and root all their ties frorh her soul; " all the
                            morning stars sing together, and the sons of God shout for joy," while the work progresses.
                            For " now has come to us salvation and strength, the kingdom of our God and the power of his
                            Christ." We have both Father and Mother abiding with us; and spiritual sisters, and
                            brethren, and children are our relation ; and these are the " Vir- gins that rejoice in the
                            dance, both young and old together." Our Eden is restored, and if our trials are more severe
                            than those of the first Eden, our knowledge is greater, and so is the prize for which we
                            wrestle; and with such faithful parents for exemplars, every honest, upright soul that
                            cleaves to them must surely win.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian spirit" TEIform="index"/>Christian Spirit</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Dibble, Chauncy" TEIform="persName"/>CHAUNCY DIBBLE</byline><p TEIform="p">Being in Saratoga, I was accosted by one who thought that the very chaste life the Shakers
                            live, renders them too docile, unspirited, unfit for social life or its enterprises. We
                            disprove this fact, by enjoying the largest amount of innocent socialism of an}' class on
                            the earth. We believe it to be a Christian enterprise, to cultivate love, peace, economy and
                            industiy, untinged by lust, wars, extravagance or laziness. We are professedly
                            nonresistants—this was a specialty in the character of the author of Christianity, and will
                            be in his humble followers—but is not copied by those popularly called Christians. If the
                            indulgence of the lustful propensities is a necessary stimulus to active life, such cannot
                            be Christian life; and we abjure the enterprises that spring from such a source. Thousands
                            of instances daily occur, that are specimens of the motor of animal, generative life; and
                            while these stain the pages of civilized journalism, we will be content, in being called
                            spiritless by the world, if we can only be brimfull of the living spirit of Christ.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Called</head><p TEIform="p">(Since our laxt Issue)</p><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Patten, Joseph" TEIform="index"/>Joseph Patten
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Patten, Joseph" TEIform="persName">Joseph Patten</persName>, Octogenarian, WestPittsfleld,
                                Mass.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blanchard, Hannah" TEIform="index"/>Hannah Blanchard
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Blanchard, Hannah" TEIform="persName">Hannah Blanchard</persName>, aged 85, Harvard,
                            Mass.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fowle, Robert" TEIform="index"/>Robt. Fowle
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Fowle, Robt." TEIform="persName">Robt. Fowle</persName>, aged 73, Canterbury, N. H.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Work and win" TEIform="index"/>Work and Win</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL ORCUTT</byline><p TEIform="p">However difficult the obstacles may appear to the novice in the self-denying way, remember,
                            that if you commence the work with earnestness of purpose, your efforts will be crowned with
                            success. A wavering, doubting mind never did, and never will accomplish anything worth
                            naming. There is nothing like a fixed, firm, steady aim in the gospel cause, that will
                            ensure victory. The true crosshearer, by vigorous, persevering effort, wins crowns of bright
                            glory. It has been truly said, that no excellence is gained without earnest labor. How did
                            our blessed Saviour overcome, and win that bright crown ? And how did our ever blessed
                            Mother gain that spotless robe which she wears ? By resolute perseverance and patient toil.
                            Oh, how worthy of imitation ! Now, what has been done can be done again; and it is only
                            those who work, that win. Therefore in our passage to heaven over life's rough sea, should
                            billows arise to impede our progress, let us remember that constant, earnest labor will
                            conquer all things. Be not discouraged at slow progress. Work on, discarding vices one by
                            one, and " adding to your faith, virtues." Work patiently—Work and Win.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth courts investigation" TEIform="index"/>Truth Courts Investigation</head><p TEIform="p">Nothing tends more to the improvement of the principles of light and truth in the mind of
                            man, than a free, candid, and unprejudiced inquiry, and a willingness to examine into the
                            truth of any tenets or practices which are at variance with his natural inclinations and
                            prepossessions. Prejudice operates upon the mind like jaundice upon the eye, which pre-
                            vents it from seeing objects except through a medium discolored by its own infirmity, and
                            therefore it cannot form any just or correct ideas of what it does actually see. It is to be
                            lamented that popular excitement is often raised to the highest pitch by selfish, designing
                            persons, who, like puppet-showmen, keep themselves artfully concealed. Public good is
                            generally made the plea to obtain the gratification of private ambition or malice ; and
                            whatever may be the ostensible object of the instigators, whether it be of a religious,
                            political, or other nature, the medium of excitement is the same—the passions are developed
                            and prejudice created, the effects of which are in proportion to the estimated importance of
                            the object held up to view. Of all the objects of popular clamor, none are more calculated
                            to make an impression upon the mind of man, than the subject of religion. This has been used
                            as a cloak for persecution in all ages. The public mind is agitated by designing and
                            interested men against some person, principle or system of religion, which stands in the way
                            of their ambitious plans. Such was the excitement raised by Demetrius and his interested
                            coadjutors against the apostle Paul among the Ephesians, who were persuaded to believe, that
                            through the preaching of Paul, their <pb n="94" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. religion was in
                            danger, and "that the temple of the great goddess Diana would be despised and her
                            magnificence destroyed;" while the real danger apprehended was the loss of the lucrative
                            craft of the prime mover of the tumult. In all ages, those religious persons and sects,
                            however few or small, who, regardless of popular opinion, have presumed to think and act for
                            themselves, and to advocate and practice virtue according to their own unbiassed judgment,
                            have always been the objects of popular odium. And persecution against such has always been
                            excited in .proportion to the contrast of their principles with the popular feelings and
                            opinions, and the selfdenial which those principles required against the inbred propensities
                            of human nature; because such principles are viewed as obstacles in the way of the
                            interested designs of aspiring ambition. The only efficacious remedy against the influence
                            of such contaminating excitements, is calm and candid consideration, a sincere and impartial
                            inquiry after light and truth, and a dispassionate examination of every principle presented
                            to the mind that requires important action. The action will then proceed from deliberate
                            judgment, and not from the impulse of passion. In tracing the history of the human race, we
                            rarely find a heinous crime committed under the influence of calm consideration; but
                            generally, if not always, under the excitement of some pernicious and baneful passion, and
                            from some corrupt principle, which has been designedly instilled into the mind conformable
                            to those passions. All evil speaking, all slanders, all defamation and detraction, proceed
                            from these sources. No "wars, no tyranny, nor persecution, could ever be supported by any
                            other principle. If ever the civil and religious liberties of this nation are overthrown, it
                            will be done through the prevalence of these causes. When strenuous and increasing efforts
                            are made to gain a religious ascendancy, and to obtain the passage of laws in favor of the
                            opinions and views of popular sects who lay claims to orthodoxy, and when such laws are
                            enacted to favor such schemes, and to operate against unpopular sects, then let the lovers
                            of national liberty beware lest the consummation of these designs and exertions shall
                            finally terminate in the baneful and dreaded combination of the civil and ecclesiastical
                            powers to sway the destinies of our country. If this should once be accomplished, then comes
                            an end, a final end to all the liberties and privileges, both civil and religious, which
                            have hitherto been the distinguished portion of this highly favored nation. The utility of
                            every principle and system must be tested by its nature and effects. We therefore request
                            the reader to examine, candidly and without prejudice, the tenets of our Society, and see if
                            he can discover anything in the principles of its system incompatible with purity, justice,
                            and charity—anything inconsistent with the social and spiritual happiness, or anything which
                            is not compatible with the free agency of man, or with the civil anc religious rights
                            bestowed upon us by our beneficent Creator, and secured to us by the ree institutions of our
                            country. All must be aware that obedience to Shaker mnciples requires great self-denial
                            against ;he natural propensities of man. But surely, if we believe the testimony of our
                            Saviour, (Luke xiv. 33.) this can be no proof that ;hey are not the principles of genuine
                            Christianity ; and whether they are approved or disapproved, or whether they are agreeable
                            or disagreeable to the feelings of human nature, 10 one can have any reasonable ground of
                            complaint, nor cause of opposition, since all are at their own option to embrace them or
                            not. The faith and principles of our Society aave been tested more than eighty years in this
                            land. Originating from means apparently ;he most contemptible and inadequate, yet
                            nevertheless, means destined to stem all the opposition of nature's passions, to confront
                            the pride and ambition of the world, and the persecutions of the bigoted votaries of popular
                            religions, they have increased and grown, and been gradually unfolded and extended, and have
                            been received by many, until they have stablished a people in the united order of harmony,
                            peace, and social happiness, which continues to excite the increasing attention and wonder
                            of mankind. If individuals who have belonged, to these Societies have violated their
                            religious faith and principles, and refused to reform, they have been obliged, from the
                            nature and operations of the principles, to depart, according to the declaration of our
                            Saviour. Every branch in me that beareth fruit, my Father purgeth it, that it may bear more
                            fruit; but every branch in me that beareth not fruit, my Father taketh it away. (John, xv.
                            1, 2.) No violation of virtuous principles being tolerated among us, unfaithful members must
                            of necessity lose their union and relation to the Body, and go out from us, thereby showing
                            they are not of us. But it must be obvious to all, that persons coming into the Society must
                            necessarily have a time of probation, in order to prove their faith and integrity, before
                            their sincerity can be tested, and their ultimate union as faithful members be established.
                            Hence, during this probationary trial, it cannot reasonably be expected that every one who
                            may reside in this community, though they may assume the garb and adopt the language common
                            to its members, will be faithful representatives thereof. It is by the well known and
                            established principles of the Society, that every individual, professed member is to be
                            judged. Therefore, whatever may be their profession, language, or garb, if they violate the
                            sacred principles aforesaid, they are not in true union, nor proper representatives of the
                            Community—and by this rule all men may know them.—Brief Exposition.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Personal experience and testimony of Aaron Wood" TEIform="index"/>Personal Experiences and
                            Testimony of Aaron Wood</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wood, Aaron" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">I early embraced the everlasting gospel of Christ's second appearing, which was revealed
                            through our beloved Mother, Ann Lee, and those faithful witnesses of God who came with her
                            from England. As I was intimately ' acquainted with these beloved witnesses, I feel it a
                            duty I owe to God, to my own soul, and to the cause of truth, to make an honest declaration
                            concerning my connection and acquaintance with them, and my knowledge of their character and
                            ministration. In doing this, I shall relate a little of my own experience before I became
                            acquainted with them. When I was about twenty years of age, I was convicted of my lost
                            state, and felt great concern for the salvation of my soul. I was sensible that I was daily
                            increasing in sin against God, and I saw no way to escape his righteous judgment. I fled to
                            the holy scriptures ; but I found these condemned me. They testified that, " He that
                            committeth sin is of the Devil." I cried to God as well as I was able ; but found no
                            relief—my trouble of mind daily increased. I attended the meetings of various denominations
                            of professed Christians ; but could find none that I believed really walked with God,
                            according to the precepts and example of Christ. Thus my tribulation and condemnation
                            increased for about the space of five years, until my life became such a burden to me, that
                            I was tempted to put an end to my existence, in order to stop my career of sin. But thanks
                            be to God, that he at length opened a way for my releasement. About this time, I heard of a
                            strange people who were persecuted and imprisoned in Albany, for their religion. I went from
                            Sheiburn, Massachusetts, were I then lived, to see them, and was soon convinced that they
                            lived and reigned with Christ on earth. They spake the word of God to me, which was indeed
                            "quick and powerful." They taught me to confess all my sins to God before his witnesses, and
                            to take up a daily cross against all sin and all manner of uncleanness, and to live a just,
                            holy and pure life before God and all men. I had so much faith and confidence in them, that
                            I was ready and willing to confess my sins, which I did faithfully, and brought them out,
                            one by one, as I had committed them. And the blessed gift of repentance which I felt,
                            cleansed and healed my wounded soul, and released me from the fear of death and the torments
                            of hell. And I can testify of a truth, that in obedience to the faith which I then received,
                            I am saved from the commission of all sin. In my first visit, I did not see Mother Ann. She
                            had been previously moved from Albany to Poughkeepsie, and imprisoned in that town. This was
                            in August. In the fall I went to see the Elders again, and staid with them one night in the
                            prison. After Mother and the Elders were released from prison, I went to see them at
                            Watervliet; and from this time I was with them the most of my time. I journeyed with them
                            from place to place ; and was with them in nearly all the places where they visited. I have
                            suffered much persecution and affliction with them ; and I thank God that I was counted
                            worthy to suffer with them. I have been beaten and wounded by wicked, persecuting mobs, till
                            the ground was besmeared with my blood. At one time <pb n="95" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SH-A-KEFt. 95 I
                            was knocked down with a club, and was taken up and carried into the house for dead. But
                            these things were light in comparison with what Mother and the Elders suffered by the hands
                            of lawless ruffians. I am confident that nothing short of the power of God, could have
                            preserved their lives through such severe suffering as I have witnessed. I was with them at
                            the time Mother was so shamefully and cruelly abused by that outrageous and horrid mob,
                            which began at George Darrow's, in New Lebanon, on the morning of the 2d of September, 1783,
                            and which continued until dark; the bare recital of which is enough to make humanity
                            shudder, and bring everlasting disgrace upon the inhuman actors in it. Shortly after this, I
                            went with Mother and the Elders from New Lebanon to Watervliet; I continued to live there
                            with them for more than a 3'ear ; and was daily conversant with them, dwelt in the same
                            house and eat at the same table. I was there when Elder William Lee deceased, July 21st,
                            1784, and remained there till after Mother Ann's decease, on the 8th of September following.
                            Notwithstanding the evil reports that have been circulated abroad against Mother Ann, and
                            the base charges of intemperance and lewdness, I can truly say, that in all my ac-
                            quaintance with her, from first to last, I never discovered in her the least symptom of
                            intemperance or lewdness, nor any kind of evil whatever. I always considered her to be the
                            most godly person my eyes ever beheld. She truly loved and feared God, and taught the same
                            to others. Her charity to lost souls was boundless ; and her severity against sin was like a
                            flaming fire. No wonder the world hated her; for she was not of the world. Hence they hate
                            her, and say all manner of evil against her falsely. In doing this, they bring the greatest
                            possible evidence in her favor. And now I say unto you that utter false accusations : ye are
                            the children of a persecuting generation. " Fill ye up then the measure of your fathers ;
                            that upon you may come all the righteous blood shed upon the earth, from the blood of
                            righteous Abel," down to the suffering witnesses of God whom ye have persecuted and
                        abused.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eulogium" TEIform="index"/>Eulogium</head><p TEIform="p">Sister Lucy Mclntosh. who, by natural death! left this, for the second phase of life, at the
                            mature age of ninty-one years, was one of the very Jew remaining, whose identity with the
                            society dates with its earliest history. Her steadfast, devoted, and unselfish life, gave
                            potency to her wise precepts; she preached by example. Important positions of care and trust
                            have been honoured by her integrity, intelligence and fidelity. To those who knew her, she
                            needed no other eulogy than her whole life. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M., E." TEIform="persName"/>E. M.</byline></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker communism" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Communism</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The revision of " Shaker Communism" was completed in London ; printed there ; has arrived;
                            and we think it, excepting " The Compendium," the best work for the times issued by our
                            Order. We recommend the same, enlarged, improved, and full of the spirit that should imbue
                            the Churches. Amen. We will send post paid for Fifty Cents.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ho! second adventists!" TEIform="index"/>Ho! Second Adventists!</head><p TEIform="p">In the Second Advent excitement of 1843, there was a peculiar feature manifested by many of
                            its participants. Miller, with many thousands of disciples, firmly believed in the personal
                            appearing of Jesus at that time; all the figures of Sacred Writ, with barely one exception,
                            were supposed to point to the year of 1843. So sincere and zealous were the believers, that
                            in preparation to meet the Lord, they progressed " from faith unto faith," in an exceeding
                            personal purity. Hundreds, if not thousands, were convicted of the impropriety of the works
                            of the flesh—of their non-fellowship with Christ—and long ere "the tenth day of the seventh
                            month" arrived, these might have been found living as brothers and sisters in households
                            that had previously known them only as husbands and ivives. They perceived that neither
                            reproduction nor the relations for the same, belonged to the realms to which they aspired,
                            and cheerfully relinquished the same. Disappointed that Jesus did not appear, many concluded
                            that the Second Advent had already occurred, or that the same would be manifested in a
                            spiritual manner. They sought a refuge, and many found this in Shaker Societies, whose
                            members were believers in the truth that Christ had appeared " the second time, without sin
                            unto salvation," in one, "like unto the Son of Man"—the daughter of man—and having been led,
                            by the Christ angels, to the practice of such personal purity, like unto the Shakers, they
                            were evidently prepared for the Christ Baptism which they found, and were satisfied with in
                            Shaker homes and life. "Now," said Miller, "if there is a possibility of mistake in these
                            calculations—and I do not see that it is possible—then is there but one possible solution
                            left, and this conclusively points to the year of 1873 ! " The near approach of "the end" of
                            all calculations, brings to the minds of Second Adventists the same noticeable peculiarity
                            of sentiment, and we hope, of life, that was such a prominent feature in 1843. None needs to
                            be a very critical observer, to notice in all the literature of these sincere lookers for
                            Jesus, a marked similarity between their sentiments, and Shaker life. Before me are the last
                            two issues of The World's Crisis; and for purity of sentiment, we challenge the heavens.
                            Where such sentiment abounds, there are hopes that such testimony finds a response in active
                            life. In testimony against all fleshty corruptions of the mind and body, I present an
                            extract from The Advent Christian Times, which will forcibly remind many of testimony in a
                            Shaker meeting: " Here the body is to be blameless and presented so, unto the coming of
                            Christ. Here is an explanation of the question, 'am I holy?* Is my body blameless? Are there
                            foes within ? When temptation comes, is there a response to it in my nature? Am I contin-
                            ually struggling to keep down my passions, lest they gain the victory over my love for Jesus
                            ? If so, then those passions are unholy and need something more than conquering. They need
                            eradicating. The flesh needs cleansing in order for the body to be blameless. The spiritual
                            emotions may be all right, but the fleshly emotions are all wrong. In this case the body is
                            not holy, and I think we all believe the body is a very essential part of the man. Xow then,
                            am I holy? What shall we say to this inquiry ? Is it yes, or no ? Let it be candidly
                            considered and answered, even if 1 we find the response to be in the negative. "A
                            deliverance from this condition, so that a person's carnal desires in the flesh are dead,
                            and the whole impulse of the bods' is spiritual, is the point under consideration. Can the
                            body be controlled by the Spirit of God so that its emotions are not carnal but spiritual? A
                            man 'finds a law in his members war.ring against the law of his mind,' and the question is,
                            Can he be delivered from this condition ? " This is as important a question as the one, ' am
                            I holy,' for if a person fully realizes that notwithstanding his love to God and his
                            service, there yet remains the 'sin in the flesh,' it is very important to know whether it
                            must always remain there during mortality, or whether it can be rooted out now." Such are
                            the proper Christian convictions, and these will bring Second Adventists we hope, into the
                            necessary tribulation, by which they will be led " to wash their robes in the life of the
                            Lamb," by confessing their sins, and repenting of the same, by a thorough leaving off of all
                            fleshly transactions. Then will they be led to the advanced faith, made manifest in the
                            Crisis. "Further, for a platform of Christian fellowship, true love will adopt one as broad
                            as that laid down by our Saviour. On a certain occasion, being told that his mother and
                            brethren desired to speak with him, he improved the occasion by stretching forth his hand
                            toward his disciples saying, ' Behold my mother and my brethren ! For whosoever shall do the
                            will of my Father which is in heaven, the same is my brother, and sister, and mother.' "
                            Brother, eister, how does your life compare with your profession? If yon say you are abiding
                            in Christ, to be consistent, yon ought ' also to walk evon as he walked.' " We would that
                            Christ make an appearance in 1873, or before that time; and we doubt not, but " those who
                            look for Christ" in their lives, " to them Christ will appear." We conclude with this
                            assertion and prophecy: Jesus was crucified, his body buried; he ascended into the spiritual
                            world; and no doubt has often visited the earth since. That which now so elevates the
                            anticipations of Second Adventists, is the coming of the Christ Spirit that anointed Jesus,
                            and will anoint many others. When they are fully assured of their disappointment that Jesus
                            will not appear; that their bodies will never rise ; that the resurrection is spiritual, not
                            carnal, we are ready now, as in 1843, to bless them with a refuge, filled with consolation,
                            and present them to Christ, for whom they have looked ; towards whom their testimonies have
                            pointed, and for whose reception, we hope, they have endeavored to keep their bodies in all
                            purity. Then will they sing with us : "Are we fitted, and prepared Tabernacles of the Lord ?
                            Have we found the hidden pearl—Christ—the true Messiah ? Look not for him at the tomb, For
                            the Living he's among ; There he'll meet you, there he'll come, and sit the Purifier." *</p></div2><div2 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Equal distribution of wealth" TEIform="index"/>Equal distribution of wealth
                        </head><p TEIform="p">We have received "The Equal Distribution of Wealth," being an Address of the Editor of
                            Binghamton Times, N. Y. Its reasoning is good, but it puts so far off the accomplishment of
                            its subject, that all may well dispair of the Millenium by the means proposed. So long as
                            mankind have husbands, wives, children, they will never yield the point of private <pb n="96" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> possessions—but cherish these to an extent equal to the possibility of
                            attainment. Let there be an " Equal Distribution" j made to-day, and one year from to-day it
                            would be far worse than yesterday. Jesus began his work by the denial of those selfish
                            relations that will forever make the kingdom of heaven impossible, while actively engaged
                            in. " Follow Me, is the true rule." *</p></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's universal praise" TEIform="index"/>GOD'S UNIVERSAL PRAISE</head><p TEIform="p">North, Mt. L. 1 Sing nn to the Lord a new song— Chant ye His praises sweet— Let earth the joy
                            fnl strain prolong, With harmony replete. 2 Let the starry heavens rejoice; Let earth
                            her tribute bring; The sea shall lift its mighty voice, And all the isles shall sing. Again at tnne the heartfelt song, And bless His holy Name. Salvation Green fields in
                            gladness shall abound, And yield a rich increase; While forests doth to Him belong,
                            Let shall with joy resound— The every voice proclaim, anthems of sweet peace.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editor's appeal" TEIform="index"/>The Editor's Appeal</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">To our Patrons and Friends :—With this issue of The Shaker, we complete Vol. Second. We have
                            again presented ninetysix pages of information of our life, faith and testimony, for the
                            small sum of Fifty Cents ! The actual cost has been much more. We have not presented a life
                            and testimony that meet the " popular idea " of what should be the religious theology ; but
                            rather, have dealt in truths that were unpalatable to the masses, yet known to be truths,
                            nevertheless. By this conscientious course—the dissemination of truth—regardless of whether
                            it pleases or displeases—it is almost a miracle, that we have been as successful in meeting
                            our expenses. We do not believe there is a more radically religious monthly in the world j
                            —radical, so far as going down to the fbundaj tion of human woes and loss, illustrating
                            their cause, effect and remedy, and aiming at the elevation of the whole human race. We have
                            not attempted to attain unto a financial eminence; but rather, have from the first, been
                            humbly content to meet our expenses, while doing the greatest possible good in the least
                            possible space, at the lowest possible price. While we can feel, that the pulse of so
                            large-a part of humanity is with us, sufficiently to aid us with the small pittance asked
                            for The Shaker, we mean to live to uphold the standard of Christian Religion, as lived by
                            Jesus, unbiassed and unmixed with human follies and fleshly lusts. We are very grateful,
                            dear friends, for your kindly recognition of the strife in which we are engaged—to live
                            here, as all expect they must live herafter j and though our little Shaker may not com-
                            pletely effect the desired end—the salvation of innumerable souls from a further commission
                            of sin—it will be an educator for the life that is to come. There are thousands who do not
                            feel able nor willing to receive the saying: "Be a Shaker!" but whose admiration is
                            challenged by the knowledge that there are some who can receive the saying " for the kingdom
                            of heaven's sake; " and such pay a tribute to virtue, when they realize that our principles
                            are " the salt of ttiis poor earth." From such, and from all who love virtue, purity and
                            goodness—from all who are interested in our standing uprightly for Christ's sake, and
                            preaching the true gospel in our every-day life—from such we look for aid in sustaining The
                            Shaker, by sending to us of your substance, according to your ability, and love " For tlic
                            cause, that lacks assistance— For the wrongs that need resistance— For the bright hopes in
                            the distance, And the good that all may do." Again thanking you for past favors, we beg for
                            the continuance of the same—for the renewal of the large number of subscriptions that expire
                            with this issue. We promise to render in exchange, an increasing amount of true religious
                            literature and song; to enhance the value of our medium by a greater variety of subjects;
                            and generally, to devote our whole soul's effort for the best good of humanity. We should
                            not feel it dishonorable to discontinue for the present; but replies from every part of the
                            Union, from all classes of individuals, give this question an emphatic negative. We shall,
                            under this encouragement, " run well for another season ; " and we hope to receive that
                            tangible sympathy, without which our efforts for humanity, but not our love, must fail. We
                            appeal, then, to all: Subscribe for The Shaker. Lend the Lord a half-dollar, and after many
                            days it will return to you, in value, a thousand fold. And may you fare well in our peace,
                            love and blessing, until we meet on Canaan's happy shore ; and there, with one Lord, and one
                            life like unto his, " we shall know of the doctrine," and part no more forever. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Any one desirous of circulating a few copies of The Shaker..." TEIform="index"/>Any one desirous of circulating a few copies of The Shaker...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Any one desirous of circulating a few copies of Thk Shakes, may obtain a select parcel, on
                            application to this office. </p><p TEIform="p"> Bound copies of Thk Shaker, Vols. 1 and 2 together, will be sent, post paid, for two dollars
                            and fifty cents. Bound separately, each, one dollar and seventy-live cents. </p><p TEIform="p"> We purposed an "Extra" with present number, but our dreadful fires have denied us the
                            opportunity of preparing it. Should our December issue be late, we beg the patience of our
                            readers. </p><p TEIform="p"> To News Dealers, Booksellers and Stationers.—We want you to act as agents for THE SHAKES. On
                            application, we will make to you the most reasonable terms. Send us your address, and try
                            the sale of Thk Most Radicai.lt Religious Monthly in the world—The Shaker ! </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Special notice" TEIform="index"/>Special notice
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> With the beginning of next volume of The Shaker the management changes. The present editor
                            retires to the position of Publisher ; and the present, able head of the Novitiate Orders of
                            Shakers—Elder F. W. Evans— becomes its Editor, and to whom all subscriptions SHOULD BE
                            ADDRESSED. This is a consummation long and devoutly icishedfor. Let the subscriptions be
                            sent to him "fast and numerous." </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publications" TEIform="index"/>PUBLICATIONS.</head><p TEIform="p">Christ's First and Second Appearing Dnnlavy's Manifesto Millennial Church ----Compendium of
                            Shakerism Three Discourses on United Interests Shaker Communism—Evans Shakerism, the
                            Possibility of the Race Tracts free, where postage is paid. #1 25 1 25 1 00 0 50 0 50 0 50 0
                            10</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Members of society" TEIform="index"/>MEMBERS OF SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p">Appointed to answer Correspondents, among whom are the Board of Editors. Elder F. W. Evans.
                            Mt. Lebanon. Columbia Co., N. Y. " Galen Richmond, Shakers, N. Y. " Calvin G. Reed. Sonyea,
                            Livingston Co., N. Y. " Simon Mabee, West Pittsfield, Mass. " H. S. Kellogg, Thompsonville,
                            Conn., Shakers. " Albert Battles, Tyringliam, Berkshire Co., Mass. " Win, Leonard. Ayer,
                            Mass.. Shakers. " Jonas Nutting, Shirley Village, Middlesex Co., Mass. " B. H. Smith, Shaker
                            Village, Merrimack Co., N. H. " Henry Cummings, Enfield, Grafton Co.. N. H. " John B. Vance.
                            Alfred, Shakers, York Co., Me. " Nehemiah Trull, West Gloucester, Cumberland Co., Me.,
                            Shakers. " Chas. Clapp, Union Village, Warren Co., O., Shakers. " Ezra Sherman, Preston,
                            Hamilton Co., Ohio, Shakers. " Stephen Ball, Dayton, Shakers, Ohio. " Jacob Kulp. Pleasant
                            Hill, Mercer Co., Ky. " J. R. Eades, South Union, Logan Co., Ky. " J. S. Prescott,
                            Cleveland, Ohio, Shakers.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>