<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm1402" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">23</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">14</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">02</biblScope><date value="18840201" TEIform="date">[month] [year]</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">25-48]</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="14" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="02" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
FEBRUARY.
THE
MANIFESTO
Published by the United Societies,
CANTERBURY,   N. H.
"Blessed are those that hear the word of God and keep it'
SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H.
1884.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
A D VER T1S KM b. N TS.
the
 non
WUw
more agents,   canvassers   and   club
raisers wanted to represent and read
ATTENTION!
FAEMERS and GARDENERS.
THE "SWIFT-SURE5
BONE PHOSPHATE.
Girls' National Reformer,
an illustrated Temperance, Literary, and Agricultural journal, devoted to reformation in education,
society and government.
Circulation guaranteed to exceed SOO,ttOO in
twelve months.
The only Temperance paper in Texas.
The Gtkls' National Rbfokmeb is the outgrowth
of the Girls' Own Paper and the National Reformer,
and is made up and hand omely illustrated by new
artists and supplied with additional writers, thus
making it altogether the most superb periodical of
the kind issued. It appears now as a 64-column
quarto, pasted and cut, rendering it easily accessible to the readers. Each number is accompanied by
a four-page Musical Supplement (filled with choice
vocal and instrumental music) given as a special
premium to sub^ribers.
Valuable premiums to club raisers; liberal paying
commissions to agents.
The Girls' National Reformer, admirably covers its chosen field, and no one interested in Temperance, Literature, Agriculture and Art (either
pictorial or decorative) ca1.: afford to miss its monthly visits. Price $1.00 per annum, in advance.
All regular ministers, Temperance organizations and
Granges where the paper is kept on file in the lodge
room, will receive a copy for one year at JTifty
Oul'N per ami am.
JOSEPHINE GULMORE, Publisher,
65 Travis Street, Houston, Texas.
This excellent, most excellent FERTILIZER
is giving the very best promises of the increase
of AGRICULTURAL & HORTICULTURAL products. Tested in various manners and compared with
many other fertilizers, it is proving itself the best.
 THE BEST.
The Shaker Manifesto has testimonials at
hand declarative of the best merits of the above
fertiliser. The Corn crops have been more than
doubled by its use. The same of Wheat, Oats, Barley and Rye. Garden Fruits, Strawberries, Raspberries and Currants have been monstrous where
the Fertilizer has been used.   Address
M. L. SHOEMAKER. & 00..
(LIMITED.)
PHILADELPHIA, PA.
Vick's Floral Guide.More it is again,
brighter and better than ever; the cover
alone, with its delicate tinted background and
its dish of gracefully arranged flowers, would
entitle it to a permanent place in every home.
The book contains three beautiful colored
plates, is full of illustrations, printed on the
best of paper, and is filled with just such information as is required by. the gardener, the
farmer, those growing plants, and every one
needing seeds or plants. The price, only ten
cents, can be deducted from the first order
sent for goods All parties any way interested in this subject should send at once to
James Vick, Rochester, N. Y., for the Floral Guide
Ueuds Everything SOLID AS
JiOCIVlHard as Adamant!
Firm as Granite I! Strongest,
Toughest, and Most Elastic Glue
on Earth!   A Samsonian,Giant
inStrength among all otherGluea
and Cements! Absolutely Unbreakable  and  Inseparable!
No Heating!No Preparation
Always Ready AlwaysLiquid!
Glues China* Glass, Wood,
Leather Belting-, Crockery, Billiard C ue Tips and Cloth, Marble.
Metals, Patches on Leather and
Rubber Shoes, Bric-a-brac, Book
Backs,   Stone,   Furniture, Bicycle
Rubber Tires, Ornaments of Every
kind, Jewelry, Smokers' Pipes and
Cigar Holders, Card Board in Scrap
Books, and .Everything else with
Everlasting Inseparable Tenacity!
i Manufacturers of Gummed La" icls.Textil Fabrics, Fine Carriages,
_'ianos, Artificial Flowers, Imitation
Stained Glass and Straw CJoods.CabiI net Makers, &c, supplied by Gallon
) or Barrel.   2Oc. Bottle (Brush and
Tin Cover); by mail postpaid. 10 cts.
-fnthsizehottie. extra. Mailed only by manufacturers
JOMRA&CO^
- AgentsWanted Everywhere. Sold by Druggists,
,cers, Stationers, Hardware andGe::err. Stores
ADVICE   TO   MOTHKRg.
Are you disturbed at night and broken of your rest
by a sick child suffering and crying with pain of cutting teeth? If so send at once and get a bottle of
Mrs. Winslow's Soothing Stbup fob Children
Teething. Its \ alue is incalculable. It will relieve
the poor little sufferer immediately Depend upon it
mothers, there is no mistake about it. It cures dysentery and diarrhoea, regulates the stomach and
bowels, cures wind colic, softens the gums, reduces
inflammation, and gives tone and energy to the whole
system. Mrs. Winslow's Soothing Syrup fob
Children Teething is pleasant to the taste, and is
the prescription of one of the oldest and best female
physicians and nurses in the United States, and is
for sale by all druggists throughout the world. Price
35 cents a bottle!
<pb n="25" id="p3"/>
CO NTENTS.
Page.
Unsatisfied Desires,          -          -         -        25
Government of Christ's Kingdom,   -         -   27
Visionary Dream,      .          ....        28
The Christian Warfare, '                -          -   29
Thanksgiving,             ...."
Progress and Order,     -          -          -          -   30
Pioneers of Western Reserve,   -          -        31
Christian Contentment,           -          -          -   33
Letter from Sally Ceeley,          -          -         "
Religion,     -          -          -          -          -          -   34
Soul of Life,   -          .."..."
Alfred, Maine,    -          -          -          -          -   35
Biblical,   - - - - - -        37
Trust,
Duty,
The Future Life,
Letter Box,
|   The Covered Bridge,
Notes,
Education, No. 4,
Slander,
The Rocking Chair,
MusicSun of Righteousness,
Books & Papers,   Kind Words,
Deaths,
Page.
-    38
-    30
41
-    41
42.
-    43
45
47
-    48
Vol. XIV.
 FEBRUARY,   1884.
No. 2.--><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unsatisfied desires" TEIform="index"/> UNSATISFIED DESIRES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/> ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE.</byline><p TEIform="p"> As far as our knowledge extends, there has never been a time in the history of the American
                            Nation, when there was greater prosperity in different departments pertaining to its
                            material wealth, or its educational advancement, than the present. Science continues to
                            reveal new modes of agriculture and machines are invented to meet the growing, expanding
                            ideas which are requisite to carry the new methods into practical operation, which with the
                            combined skill and energetic labor of the tillers of the soil, the land is made to yield a
                            rich and bounteous supply of cereals, fruits and vegetables, for home consumption, and to
                            contribute in considerable degree to the demands of foreign markets. Ships, heavily laden
                            with all kinds of merchandise go out upon the seas, to bear to other lands the products of
                            our own and in r?turn, bring from other ports to our shores fruits and fabrics from soils,
                            and climates, in distant lands. Many of these staunch vessels arc unable to cope with the
                            fierce winds, and go down beneath the billowy waves which rise mountain high, and are seen
                            no more. Still, others continue to plough the great deep, and press their way, and pass from
                            port to port. Fires and floods, devastate the lands, and yearly consume a large amount of
                            the nation's wealth, as 1888 has proved in a marked degree ; but as an off-set, the
                            population is increased by emigration from other countries, and large tracts of land
                            hitherto untilled, are brought under the plow and worked by those who emigrate to America
                            from <pb n="26" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 26 THE MANIFESTO. isles beyond the seas, to find a home and take
                            shelter under her national flag. Why repeat these facts so often told, and so apparent to
                            all, that they who run may read and easily understand ? Our reason for so doing, is to show
                            that with all the accumulated material wealth and financial prosperity, there still exists a
                            restless unsatisfied condition of mind and feeling, in all ranks of society ; which go to
                            prove that there are soul wants and needs, that earthly material things can never supply.
                            Hence we find in all ranks of society, an anxious expectancy, looking for some new thing to
                            transpire that will bring change and fill an aching void in the chambers of the soul, and
                            feed the immortal part. Pulpit orations from the clergy, it matters not how eloquent they
                            may be, or how pleasantly their words may fall upon the ears of the hearersfail to touch
                            their hearts. The Bible has been used as a text-book by many thousands of professed
                            ministers of the gospel, for along period of time, until nearly every verse has been
                            repeated over, and over again and turned, and twisted, and explained, until it has become as
                            sounding brass and tinkling cymbals : for priests and people, by lack cf true charity, or
                            practical love to God and to their neighbor, under the guidance of Christian faith, fail of
                            ministering or receiving even a spark of living inspiration from the Source of divine light.
                            Thousands at the present time, are looking and waiting for some sudden revulsion in the
                            spiritual elements, that shall bring about a better state of things and are hopeful and
                            joyful in the anticipation. Others fear lest a sacrifice of some of their dearest earthly
                            idols may be called for, if coining events which they feel are rapidly drawing near, and are
                            casting their shadows before, actually transpire. As a general rule, the majority of those
                            who profess to want something better than what they now possess, do not want to give an
                            equivalent to obtain it. Like one class of the ancient Jews, who were looking for the long
                            promised Messiah; they expected a prince in pomp and regal splendor to come and establish a
                            throne and kingdom, and sway the scepter of power, and strengthen the then existing
                            hierarchy, and upbuild the aristocracy of that day. They were greatly disappointed ; so much
                            so, that only a few were prepared to receive the Anointed Nazarene, the medium of the Christ
                            Spirit, who came to them in an unostentatious manner, and they did not recognize him, nor
                            understand his mission. Thus it is, and will be with the major part of those who at the
                            present time are hungering for soul food; they desire it, but are not willing to sell all,
                            or even a part of their worldly gains to obtain it. The selfish, ease-loving,
                            pleasure-seeking multitude, cries, "give, give ! but do not take from us our earthly
                            treasures that we love so dearly ! " Jesus, without doubt, was educated with the Essenes of
                            his time, who were numerous in Palestine and Syria, and were practically progressed and
                            virtuous. Philo said of them, " They do not sacrifice animals ; do not hoard up riches for
                            themselves ; yet they regard themselves the richest of mankind ; because contentment of mind
                            is riches. No war implements are found among them ; neither slaves nor slave owners; they
                            hold that virtue and freedom belong together." Their trinity is, "Loveof God, love of virtue
                            and love of mankind. " <pb n="27" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 27 Their Order was not founded
                            upon natural descent, but upon virtue and integrity of character. They required new converts
                            who joined them, to sell their private possessions and divide with their poorer brethren;
                            thus mutually share the burdens of life, and serve one another in love. They enjoined upon
                            all the necessity of meekness and lowliness of spirit, and purity of heart and mind. They
                            commended celibacy which enables a man or woman to abstain from connubial intercourse for
                            the kingdom of heaven's sake ; but acknowledged that all could not receive, or enter into
                            that state, only as was given them thus to do. Gensburg said; "It can hardly be doubted that
                            the Savior himself belonged to this holy brotherhood, that existed during a period of two
                            hundred years before Christ. At the advent of the Messiah, the Jews were divided into three
                            parties ; Pharisees, Saddueees and Essenes. Jesus often reproved the former, but not the
                            latter. " May we not reasonably gather the idea from ancient history, that Jesus brought
                            many doctrines which he taught from the schools of the Essenes, which was the fruit of
                            preceding generations, instead of all those beautiful lessons which he gave, coming directly
                            to him, as a new revelation ? And that the quickening Spirit that descended upon and abode
                            with him vivified and intensified those heaven-born principles, and enabled him to carry
                            them forward to greater perfection ? If those in our own time who are waiting for what they
                            call the millennial day, would prepare themselves for the event as did the ancient Essenes
                            Avho were looking for the Messiah : How long would they have to wait before the Comforter,
                            the true Witness, who now stands at the door knocking, would find entrance and sup with them
                            and break the bread of life with them ? Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Government of Christ's Kingdom,- a theocracy" TEIform="index"/> The Government of Christ's
                            Kingdom, a Theocracy.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/> ABRAHAJC PERKINS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> It should be thoroughly understood that the Government of the Kiagdom of Heaven is neither a
                            Monarchy nor a Democracy ; yet, we find in its nature the elements of both forms prefigured.
                            It is a Theocracy. In its administration, it partakes so much of a Monarchical form as to
                            establish a central power, a throne or tribunal for final decision on all questionable
                            matters ; and so much of the Democratic form as to embody tli3 voice of the people to sus'am
                            it and make its acts legitimate. It is not all throne nor all the voice of the people ;
                            either of which would produce absolutism and monopoly, and furnish a direct fruitful support
                            to self, the arch enemy of the Kingdom. Monarchy fosters and builds up an Aristocracy ; it
                            creates in society castes of high and low, from which condition, neither merit nor demerit
                            removes the stamp of honcr or degradation. In its extreme, it becomes despotic and most
                            unjust. Democracy tends to the leveling of humanity to a common plane. ; and when carried to
                            an extreme, would ignore the respect and dignity justly due to office and that legitimate
                            authority necessary for the power and strength of society. In a Theocratic Government, the
                            lessons as taught by Jesus for the maintenance of order and harmony gave officers and <pb n="28" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 28 THE MANIFESTO. endowed them with power to bind or loose on Earth,
                            even as bound or loosed in Heaven. The Apostles also commanded subjection to Principalities
                            and Powers ; all of which, both in Church and State, should be received as admonitions and
                            lessons of instruction, sufficient to fit man for the duties of life in all things
                            pertaining to human interest and the development and progress of the human mind. No
                            institution or body formed for religious, social or political purposes, neither for any
                            other relation or economy of life can possibly exist without order, the first law of Heaven.
                            For the protection of any organization, the body must be properly officered, having a
                            tribunal whose decision must be final ; otherwise, institutions and societies breed
                            contempt, become confused, divided, disorganized, wrecked, lose their power and fall to
                            pieces, not unfrequently bringing in their destruction mutiny and rebellion, which conclude
                            their history. Because of system for business, for existence and growth, it does necessarily
                            follow, that in society there must be high and low, rich and poor, master and servant. The
                            principle that reduces to equality of condition regulates that feature and gives to the
                            supervisor and menial, priest and layman equal honor; and each in their turn may be called
                            to the same position or vocation in a Theocratic as in a Republican form of Government.
                            Enfiekl, N. 11.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The thing can be said of fresh, cool water..." TEIform="index"/>
                            The thing can be said of fresh, cool water...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> The thing can be said of fresh, cool water, when needed by the system it is most grateful to
                            the sense ; when not needed it offers no temptation. So much cannot be said of beverages
                            that intoxicate.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Fanny B." TEIform="persName"/>Fanny B. Johnson.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Visionary dream" TEIform="index"/> A VISIONARY DREAM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>ALONZO G. IIOLLISTEK.</byline><p TEIform="p"> For the manifesto. Anna Cogswell was born in Pittsfield Mass, in 17G1. In her written
                            testimony given March 1827, she relates as follows ; Sometime in Feb. 1780, being in great
                            trouble of mind, I dreamed I was with a large company of people and a man came and told us
                            that Christ had come to judgment, which greatly shocked my feelings, as I feared I was a
                            false professor and should have no part in his kingdom. He told us we must all walk in
                            procession to a certain place, where we would find a tree in full bloom. Each one must pick
                            a flower from the tree, and those who gathered a flower containing seed, it would be a sign
                            to them that they had the grace of God in their souls. We were placed to walk in order, the
                            men two by two on the right, and the women in the same order on the left. While on the way I
                            trembled with fear, and the woman at my side asked what made me feel such trouble. I told
                            her I was afraid I should be found a false professor. She said she felt no concern for
                            herself on that account. I turned to look at her and perceived she was an adulteress, though
                            I never saw her before. We picked each a ilowcr and returned. The man who sent us, met us at
                            the door, and told us to lay our flowers on a table, and let them be examined. The woman who
                            walked with me laid down hers, which was fairer than mine, and I laid mine by its side. Some
                            seed fell from my flower and consumed hers in a moment. I was so overjoyed at the result
                            that I awoke, and for a season felt very happy. <pb n="29" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 29
                            Having heard of Mother Ann Lee and the Elders, I went in company with others to visit them,
                            while they were in prison at Albany. After entering, we stopped in a narrow passage on the
                            lower floor. Elder James Whittaker came down stairs, and the moment I saw him I knew he was
                            the man I saw in my "dream. He looked at me and said '' Young woman, honor God in Heaven, "
                            and immediately conducted us up stairs, where Mother and the Elders were. He soon began to
                            speak of the coming of Christ to judgment, of the manner of his coming, and how we were to
                            be judged. In conversation with Mother afterward, I related my dream to her. Do you call
                            that a dream? said she, it was a vision of God. The woman you saw walking by your side,
                            represented false professors, who profess to be espoused to Christ and yet have other
                            lovers, and their confidence is in the flesh. But this seed of the gospel will consume it.
                            She then called Elder James and said Anna has been telling roe a pretty visiontell it to
                            brother James. Accordingly I related it to him. Do you call that a dream? said he. Yea, I
                            said, because I was asleep. He answered, it was a vision of God, and a great gift to you.
                            Anna Cogswell became a Savior, in saving herself. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian warfare" TEIform="index"/> THE CHRISTIAN WARFARE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Marion" TEIform="persName"/> MAIUON JOHNSON. </byline><p TEIform="p">Not as a bannered Host With plume and steel in martial rank arrayed; With all the pomp and
                            glitter and the boast Of holiday parade : Nor yet as armies come, When hastening to the
                            conflict and the strife, With deadly panoply of war's dread doom, And fearful passions rife
                            : But in the calm retreat, Secluded from the turmoil and the glare ; They turn the spirit's
                            sword within, to meet The foe in ambush there. Bearing a daily cress Against the dearest
                            idols of the soul; Turningfrom wealth and worldlyfame as dross They press toward the goal,
                            Seeking the aid of heaven In earnest fervent prayer, with purpose true ; Beyond the joys of
                            earth, to them is given, Eternal Life in lieu. Canterbury, JV. II. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thanksgiving" TEIform="index"/> THANKSGIVING.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Keniston, Marinda M." TEIform="persName"/> MARINDA M. KENISTON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> How many hearts witli joy will greet This Nation's cherished festal day; How many loving
                            friends will meet In happy homes to praise and pray. May each, may all, that blessing share
                            Which crowns the day with rnern'ries bright; May love outweigh the din of care, And darkness
                            be dispelled by light. O Earth! what treasure dost thou hold That vies in worth with
                            Christian love? The richest mines of purest gold One half the blessing ne'er can prove. The
                            love that dwells in kindred minds Safe linked in friendship's golden chain, Through all the
                            lights and shades of time Unchanged forever will remain. May all who've gathered here to-day
                            Within these ancient hallowed walls, Whore oft our Fathers met to pray And pledge themselves
                            to give up all, Renew again their lives to God, While angels list to catch the sound, And in
                            the " Book of Life " record That loyal souls still here arc found. O may each soul uplifted
                            be, To feel a tender Mother's care, Thanksgiving anthems full and free, Be wafted on the
                            morning air. May all who pra}-, and all who wait Upon the Lord, to do his will, An
                            inspiration new partake, And through all changes trust Him still. It is the lot of some to
                            sow, While others reap the golden grain, And many here may never know The fruits of all
                            their love and pain. <pb n="30" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 30 THE MANIFESTO. Blest be the hands that toil
                            with care, The hearts that live, mid hopes and fears; Not all unheeded arc their prayers,
                            However dark the day appears. While those upon whose furrowed brow Are seen the telling
                            lines of cave Give thanks, their lives are spafed till now That children may their blessing
                            share; (iive thanks, that when life's strife is o'er, The shoals of time are safely past,
                            Awaiting them on yonder shore Are those whose friendship pure will last. Thrice blessed
                            souls! whose patient toil With trusting hearts and willing hands Planted with gospel seed
                            this soil, A goodly heritage to stand. E'en now we feel their presence near, These faithful
                            waiting ones to bless, And welcome tidings soon to bear, " Receive thy crown of
                            righteousness. " Let those before whose vision lies Yet longer service to be given, Rejoice,
                            that they ma}' win the prize, And be the perfect flowers of Heaven. If loyal they are ever
                            found, And to their Maker freely give The first ripe fruits that e'er abound Where virgin
                            principles are lived. So let all hearts give thanks and praise Who've joined the lovely
                            Virgin throng! Thanksgiving fill the matin lays, And be the theme of evening song. For who
                            like us can truly sing The song of freedom ever grand ? Who better offerings can bring
                            Throughout our Nation's cherished land? As days and weeks glide swiftly on, Each bringing
                            duties to be done, We'll chant a never-ending song And hold the bond that makes us one.
                            Through all the varying scenes we meet, Vicissitudes which mark life's way, Unchanging in
                            our hearts shall beat The love we feel renewed to-day. Enfield, X. II.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progress and order" TEIform="index"/> PROGRESS AND ORDER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., O." TEIform="persName"/>o. p.</byline><p TEIform="p"> LiTEItATURE and mathematics may be greatly unfolded, yet A, B, C, will ever remain at the
                            root of one, and One, Two, Three, at the root of the other. So we may be assured, that in
                            all branches of human progress, initial principles will ever be recognized. The progress
                            made by the Jews from heathenism, was due to a measure of obedience to Hygienic and Moral
                            Law. This statement is self-evident from the fact, that all human manifestations refer
                            themselves to morals and hygiene. Science and Art, may be greatly unfolded, yet essentially,
                            no real human elevation may occur. Such was the* case with the Egyptians ; they represented
                            ancient heathen civilizations ; and such is the case exactly with modern civilization. The
                            Pyramids are evidences of human vassalage, and of its consequent immoralities. The
                            proverbial diseases of Egypt, attest violations of the Law of health. Modern civilization
                            swarms with diseases, they attest its identity with the heathen civilizations of the past,
                            as does also, the degradation of the wealth producers of Chris-tendom. Hygienic and Moral
                            LaAV, and their fulfillment; will ever remain the fundamentals of human elevation. There is
                            a wide difference betwee'n the light of ideas, and the light of life. A person may see and
                            acknowledge the fitness of things, and in his life be practically dark. A scientific fact
                            can be presented, and all is right. A hygienic law applied to heathen habits, and the result
                            is otherwise. From this cause, there is much confusion appending to the matter of progress.
                            However, we may assure ourselves, that if a people in their conduct ignore Hygienic Law,
                            there can be no real human elevation. With regard to the location of an increase of living
                            testimony. Shall it be at the center, or at the extremities? " The wind bloweth where it
                            listeth. " "Limit not the Holy one of Israel." " Hurt not the Oil nor the Wine"the <pb n="31" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 31 love of truth, and the inspiration thereof. An
                            organized body is not obliged to accept any increase of testimony : but if any member, or a
                            family manifests an increase of hygienic, or moral conduct, they ought not to be crushed
                            down, nor retarded by the inertia of the body. The question has been asked, Shall an
                            increase begin at the center, or at the extremities? Let us look around for emblematic
                            illustrations. The rocks can instruct, the sunbeam enlighten and the plants of the earth
                            give us knowledge. There is that wide spreading tree ; we inquire of it; how is it that thou
                            hast acquired such dimensions, and yielded such beneficent results? giving us food, tuel,
                            and shelter. The tree replies, I am an assemblage of individuals ; every bud I bear, is a
                            tree in embryo. Our united labors during past years give the results you have stated. But
                            what of progress? Well, I am a fruit bearing tree ; I was but one bud when I was planted; I
                            grew and produced a number of buds, these again did likewise, and finally, I attained the
                            size you see. Strictly speaking, I am a community; composed of many members working
                            harmoniously together. My progress, growth and strength, have been at, and from my
                            extremities. When thou wast a single bud, didst thou bloom and bear fruit? I did not; the
                            united labors of a great many buds were necessary before I matured and could do that. How
                            didst thou behave under such an innovation as blooming all over into white flowers ? 1
                            continued to grow, supported the increase, and left the growth and fruit buds to their
                            respective duties. I have indeed manifested a degree of diversity in Unity, but there is a
                            tree by the river, which yields twelve kinds of fruits, and its leavesdivine ideas are for
                            the healing of human ills. It manifests a greater diversity than I do, it being a higher
                            organism. Human Society is like me, an assemblage of individuals, and is truly an organism ;
                            and if of the highest type, twelve manner of fruits may be forth coming. Low organisms do
                            not admit of much diversity. It is the province of my roots and trunk to support the buds,
                            and it is their threefold office, to strengthen the trunk, bloom and bear fruit. Unity of
                            action is Order ; growth and fruit is Progress. Order will become stoneh'ed, if not fully
                            compatible with Progress. Progress cannot be established, unless compatible with Order.
                            Where Order is stonefied, an increase will be out of unity. My conditions of growth, are
                            light, warmth, moisture, air. The conditions of the tree by the river of life, are divine
                            light, love, and an atmosphere which invigorates and gladdens all divine forms. Its every
                            bud, is a divine human spirit, accessible to Progress, and ever tending to Order. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pioneers of the western reserve" TEIform="index"/> PIONEERS OF THE WESTERN RESERVE.</head><p TEIform="p"> Notes referring to the Shakers of North Union, Ohio, as published by Harvey Rice in a work
                            entitled, Pioneers of the Western Reserve. Some explanatory remarks are added by J. S.
                            Prescott, a member of the Society of North Union. "In 1822 a religious community known as
                            Shakers was organized in Cuyahoga County, under the supervision of Ralph Russell, a devout
                            man of that faith. He was aided in this work by the Elders of Union Village, Warren County,
                            Ohio. They purchased a tract of wild land in the township of Warrensville, cleared the
                            central part of it, erected a small village of log cabins, and gave it the name of "North
                            Union." Here they tilled the soil, <pb n="32" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 32 THE MANIFESTO. grew in numbers,
                            erected mills, established factories, a school-house, and a church, and for many years
                            flourished, but of late have rapidly declined in numbers and in wealth) and in fact have
                            become but a remnant of what they were in their prosperous days. Yet there are other
                            communities of the same faith that still flourish in different parts of the United States.
                            It must be admitted that the Shakers have become a power in the land, and arc justly
                            regarded as an honest and industrious people. In their mode of worship they introduce a
                            shaking,* shuffling dance, keeping step to the music of a monotonous song or chant, and for
                            this reason are generally called "Shakers "f by outsiders; yet they prefer to call
                            themselves " Believers, J because they believe in the divinity of Ann Lee, and in living a
                            life of pure celibacy. j| In other respects their creed is substantially orthodox, Ralph
                            Russell, who led in organizing the community at North Union, was not only sincere in his
                            faith, but a man of tact and enterprise. He was born at Windsor, Conn. Aug. 3, 1789, and
                            received a good common school education. He loved books, and soon acquired a fund of general
                            information. In" fluenced by a desire to go "West," he settled in Warrensville in 1812.
                            Accidentally, or rather providentially, as he thought, he soon came in contact with two
                            eminent Shakers of Union Village, who convinced him of the truth as it is in Ann Lee. He
                            then commenced to indoctrinate his neighbors in the principles of the new faith, and soon
                            acquired a goodly number of adherents. Thus encouraged, he organized a community of Shakers
                            at Warrensville. " Ralph, " as the brother-hood called him, was a man of imposing presence,
                            tall, grace* Shaking was introduced by the first founders, by the operations of the Spirit.
                            Dancing was introduced as an act of divine worship. See Jeremiah, xxxi. f The term Shakers
                            was given to the people in derision. JThey call themselves "Believei's in Christ's Second
                            Appearing," not in the divinity of Ann Lee, but in the divinity of Christ. Christ is a
                            "Spirit," and can come in a woman, as well as in a man. || They believe in living a life of
                            virgin celibacy, because Christ lived that life, and he was our example. See Matthew, Mark,
                            Luke, and John, on this subject. ful, and winning in his manners, and persuasive in his
                            logic. He was not only one of the first founders of the community in Warrensville, but its
                            principal leader until 1826, when, owing to some disturbing elements of doctrine and rule he
                            withdrew from the community, and settled on a farm in Solon, where he died Dec. 23, 186G, at
                            the age of seventy eight years. He was superseded by the Elders from Union Village. The
                            number of Leaders and Elders who have from time to time succeeded Russell are somewhat
                            numerous. Though subordinate to higher ecclesiastical authorities, this class of officials
                            share a degree of independence and power which renders their position one of great influence
                            as well as honor. Among the number, there are several individuals who have an interesting
                            record. This is true of James S. Prescott, one of the founders of the community at North
                            Union. Though advanced in age, he is still active and faithful in the discharge of his
                            duties. He comes from a good family, being akin to the late William H. Prescott, the
                            renowned historian. He was born Jan. 26, 1803, at Lancaster, Mass. His mother was a pious
                            lady, who instructed him at an early age in the lessons of Christianity. He received a good
                            academical education, and commenced his career in life as a teacher in a missionary school,
                            consisting of some fifty Indian youth, at Oneida, N. Y. In 182G he came to Cleveland, where
                            he found employment as a mason, a trade he had partially learned while in his boyhood. In
                            the course of a few months he left Cleveland and engaged in a job of mason work for the
                            Shakers at Warrensville, North Union. Here he became interested in their religious views,
                            adopted their creed, ^[received their faith, and united with them, and still remains with
                            them. He is a man who lives a pure life, and is highly esteemed by the brother-hood and by
                            all who know him. He is an intelligent, modest, and truly amiable iran. He has The average
                            daily attendance was about forty, including both sexes, taught on the Lancasterian plan. IT
                            The Shakers have no creed, except what is contained in the life of Christ, or, in the four
                            Evangelists, Matthew, Mark, Luke and John. <pb n="33" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 38 recently
                            written a History of North Union, * which is highly interesting in its details, and which
                            should be published in book form. He was never married; yet h^ worships his ideal of a
                            woman, and thinks her divine, f Ann Lee was born of humble parentage at Manchester, England,
                            about the year 1786. Her early education had been neglected ; yet nature had endowed her
                            with unusual mental powers and with a spirit of religious enthusiasm. She married young, was
                            the mother of four children, all of whom died in infancy. She deplored her bereavement with
                            a grief which was inconsolable. This induced reflection as to a remedy for human ills, and
                            led her to advocate celibacy, and to become a dreamer in matters of religious faith. She
                            commenced preaching strange doctrines in the streets of her native town. The populace
                            gathered in crowds to hear her, and in such numbers as to impede public travel. * The
                            history of North Union was written expressly, for the " Western Reserve Historical Society,"
                            by request, and published in the Cleveland Herald. By the Hon. John Babb, Judge of the
                            Police Court. t The term Divine cannot with propriety be attached to any human being,
                            abstractly, Jesus made the discrimination between the human and the divine, when he said, "
                            Thou art Peter, i. c. the human, and upon this Rock, i. e. Revelation or divine, will I
                            build my church and the gates of hell shall not prevail against it." Matthew xvi; 18. and
                            "that Rock is Christ, " the divine Revelation compared to a solid substance because it
                            endureth forever. 1 Cor. 10., 4. It prevailed against the human, but not against the Rock,
                            it stands good yet, i. e. Revelation. Ann Lee, made the same discrimination when she said, "
                            You ought to have your faith grounded in the power of God," or power of his Christ, "for
                            that abidt.th forever. But if your faith is only in persons, and they should fail, you are
                            liable to come ivnder loss." Millennial Church, p. 337. We admit that a woman living a
                            divine life makes her appear beautiful, and so it dees a man, but neither of them are
                            objects of worship, because they are human, the creature, and not the Creator.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian contentment" TEIform="index"/> CHRISTIAN CONTENTMENT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gillespie, Fannie" TEIform="persName"/> FANNIE GILLEHI'LK.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Paul gives us a good lesson on this subject in 1 Tim. vi., 6. " Godliness with contentment
                            is great gain. " We think he referred to those who when trying to be content, still were
                            restless, wishing to be more than God in his wisdom intended or made them to be. We are too
                            prone to move along desiring most, that which affords selfish pleasure, rather than
                            spiritual growth. Christian graces are developed by adherence to Christian principles ;
                            contentment is found, by daily bearing the Christian cross against discontent, impatience
                            with ourselves, and dissatisfaction with our lot in life. Discontent leads the mind " into
                            temptation and a snare, and into many foolish and hurtful lusts, which drown men in
                            destruction and perdition." Let us use every talent we may possess as a divine gift and thus
                            return to our Master his own with usury. The root of Content is found in the recognition of
                            God's love, his mercy, his truth, and a trust in his promises which are sure to the upright
                            and faithful. " He giveth power to the faint, and to them that have no might He increaseth
                            strength." No child at our table needs his daily bread, more than every child of God needs
                            the Christian grace of true Contentment. Canterbury, N. IT.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Sister Marcia; In the September number of the Manifesto..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Dear Sister Marcia; In the September number of the Manifesto...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Shaker Village" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Village, N. II.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Sister Marcia ;In the September number of the Manifesto I found an article entitled
                            "The Voice of Age" which agreed so perfectly with my ideas of faith and gospel principle,
                            that I wish to make mention of it to you, with my sincere thanks. Every sentence seems
                            written as with a pen of fire never to be obliterated, and should be so deeply impressed in
                            the heart of every church member, that a slothful selfish spirit can find no place in their
                            abode. <pb n="34" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 34 THE MANIFESTO. I have thought it unwise to measure health
                            and strength by age, if one should retain their youthful vigor at eighty years of age : why
                            not enjoy the precious blessing of moving in active labor and not fearing any sad results
                            therefrom? Longevity is becoming more universal with the people of our country, and is it
                            not because the laws of life are more carefully regarded? I also endorse your sentiments
                            concerning a want of energy to work for the things of the spirit as we advance in years, for
                            unless we watch and pray we are liable to become dimsighted and lose a portion of our
                            well-earned treasure, this would bring discouragement to others and a burden to the leaders
                            of the flock, whom we should delight to aid and bless in every act of our lives by our
                            faithful exertions and love in the cause of God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ceeley, Sally" TEIform="persName"/> Sally Ceeley.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion" TEIform="index"/> RELIGION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ervin, Anna" TEIform="persName"/> ANNA ERVIN.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Religion is noc ours, until we live by it, in thought, word, and deed, when it goes with us
                            into every place and sits uppermost on every occasion, also forms and governs our hopes and
                            fears our cares, and pleasures. The truly religious person is ever watchful and guarded in
                            spirit; and by a purity of behavior is fearless. Keligion is the name of all that is good,
                            the Angel of Mercy, given to the dwellers of this transient life. It expands and beautifies
                            the affections of the soul. It strengthens the bands of unity. It is the guide of youth in
                            the path of duty, and should be the chosen companion of the inexperienced youth, that its
                            light may illumine their pathway through this life. It is my faith in practical religion
                            that makes my declining years serene with the light that shines from heaven, and a sure
                            refuge is found in Him who watches even the sparrow when it falls. In this faith this
                            consolation is found, that life here is the vestibule of another, bright with immortal hope.
                            En field, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There is no accuser equal in severity..." TEIform="index"/>There is no accuser equal in severity...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> There is no accuser equal in severity of self-examination. Exercise it often. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., M. E." TEIform="persName"/>M.E.IT.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soul of life" TEIform="index"/> SOUL OF LIFE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/> MAKTHA J. ANDERSON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> With thy abiding presence, Lord, And with T\\y mantle of encircling love Enfold us as the
                            light envelops earth. O Sun of life ! O Fount of blessings new! Shine on us still, and still
                            pour out Thy good. As morning mists roll up before the day That floods the earth with light
                            ineffable; So in the glory of Thy countenance, May every shadow that bedims our way Retreat;
                            may every care be turned to joy, And every duty wear fair pleasure's smile; May the tongue
                            of murmuring be dumb, And the full rich spirit of thanksgiving Pour forth in songs of
                            eestasj- and praise! As flowers expand, in beauteous robes arrayed , As blades of grass
                            spring up from earth's dark sod, So may Thy lifeinherent in the soul Bring forth the types
                            of things imperishable. We yearn for higher thoughts, for holier wings That lift above
                            materiality, And bring our souls in rapport with the Infinite Soul of Life that permeates
                            all worlds. Removed from passion's storm and hate of men, From envy, jealous}', and bitter
                            words That pierce like scorpion fangs or poignant spear, Destroying human happiness and
                            peace We would enjoy communion sweet with Thee. One hour, O Lord ! is better far than years
                            Spent in the realm of sensuous delight; One quaff from the celestial fount of truth, Would
                            satisfy the immortal longing, More than perpetual draughts from pleasure's spring; Who dips
                            life's cup therein, shall find The bitterness of Marah's waters there. Ah! who would taste
                            of sweets elysian, Must find the main-spring of their joy in Thee, Relax their hold on
                            sublunary things, Nor deem what earth calls honor worth the strife. Her wealth takes wings,
                            her knowledge flies Before the soul Who opes with glad surprise Her vision to the glories of
                            Thy truth. 0 how my spirit mounts! intensified By the upwelling fullness of the love 1 feel
                            expanding in my soul to Thee. Take all, all that this boastful world can give, But unto Thee
                            forever I would live; Thy love supplants the transient loves of earth, The banquet of Thy
                            peace all want supplies, And in the covert of Thy boundless grace, My soul would find
                            indwelling life for aye. Mi. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Those who quit their proper character to..." TEIform="index"/>Those who quit their proper character to...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Those who quit their proper character to assume what does not belong to them, are, for the
                            greater part, ignorant both of the character they leave and that they assume.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Burke" TEIform="persName"/> Burke. </byline></div2><pb n="35" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="figure" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, Alfred, Maine
                        </head><p TEIform="p"/></div2><pb n="36" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><pb n="37" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Biblical No. 1" TEIform="index"/> BIBLICAL. NO. 1,</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/> BT H. C. BLINN.</byline><p TEIform="p">The Bible is certainly a wonderful book. It is now the book of the Christians, sacred to that
                            order while all other publications may be denominated profane. Its impartial history of
                            God's people from the time that Abraham left Babylon to the prophecy of Malachi, embracing-
                            a period of some 3,600 years, is a work over which hundreds and thousands never become
                            weary, while its exhortations, admonitions and promises have served, no doubt, to make a
                            large per centage of those who have carefully read it, better men and women than they would
                            have been without it. Theodore Parker says of this sacred book, "This collection of books
                            has taken such a hold on the world as no other. The literature of Greece, which goes up like
                            incense from that land of temples and heroic deeds, has not half the influence of this book
                            from a nation alike despised in ancient and modern times. It is read of a Sabbath in all the
                            ten thousand pulpits of our land. In all the temples of Christendom is its voice lifted up,
                            week by week. The sun never sets on its gleaming page. It goes equally to the cottage of the
                            plain man and the palace of the King. It is woven into the literature of the scholar, and
                            colors the talk of the street. " This sacred book of the protestant order of Christians so
                            far as it has preserved an account, of the manifestation of God's work among men, free from
                            the errors of translators and revisers, may with all propriety be designated the scriptures
                            of truth. It is said to contain the best record that has been preserved of the creative work
                            of God and has also furnished us with the historical account and religious experience of the
                            Hebrew nation. Prom its great antiquity and the reverential regard in which the book is
                            held, no other publication, under present circumstances, can take its place. It can be no
                            argument against the book, that it admits of war and slavery and many other things which the
                            present state of society condemns. It is the history of an infant age, of a barbarous age,
                            when to a great extent, Might was Right. In this respect it may bear a close relation to all
                            ancient history. Babylon was filled with its deeds of barbarism and religious
                            licentiousness. Carthage with its savage deity was a city of horror. Greece with its
                            mythology and corrupting religious influences was not, certainly, in advance of the Jews.
                            Cassell speaking of the writings of Moses, says, " Such a code of laws as is embodied in
                            this portion of Sacred Writ, is nowhere to be found in the jurisprudence of any other nation
                            under heaven. Never had laws their basis in such profound wisdom, never were they as
                            benevolent in their character, and never so salutary in their influence. " A testimony like
                            this, in favor of a work that was written some three thousand years, in the past, should
                            enlist the careful attention of every reader. While a diligent study of the Bible may reveal
                            to us conditions not in harmony with oiir views of righteousness, it may at the same time
                            afford us many useful lessons, for the journey of life. No one thinks of throwing away all
                            his books and papers because two or more chapters in each may not agree with his
                            understanding of religious and scientific knowledge. He would dwell upon that which appeals
                            to the better qualities of the mind, and allow the other to fade away. So read the Bible. It
                            is readily admitted that the New Testament or Covenant was written by a very different class
                            of men, and that the inspiration of the work was as much beyond that of the old Testament,
                            as the mission of Jesus Christ was in advance of the Mosaic law. This holds us directly,
                            pleasantly and intelligently in correspondence with its doctrine of God's love to man. It
                            foreshadows a dispensation of glad tidings, of peace and of brotherly love to which we as
                            yet remain strangers. Unlike the old Testament dispensation the testimony of Jesus dwells
                            upon the spiritual education of the mother and children as well as of the father. It gives
                            us the outline of the life of Jesus, who walked with God very differently from either Enoch
                            or Noah. A careful study of this part of the Bible and a discipline of the mind to its best
                            instruction would transform men and women into mes- <pb n="38" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 38 THE MANIFESTO.
                            sengers of love, into angels of God, and this world into a Paradise of peace. Many persons
                            have the idea that the Bible is a verbal inspiration from God and hence every word and every
                            letter is mysteriously correct, and those who could not accept this chimerical view have
                            been denounced as unbelievers in the Bible, as schismatics and as heretics. Although the
                            Bible may give a very vivid account of the manifestation of God among men, and of the
                            visitation of the Holy Spirit, yet it is as true that the Scriptures are only historical and
                            do not contain that Spirit" The Word of God is quick and powerful, sharper than any
                            two-edged sword, and a discerner of the thoughts and intents of the heart. " But the book or
                            Bible can never hold any such place. That part of the Scriptures which comprises the Law and
                            the Prophets was held as a sacred book by the Jews, as is the whole Bible by the Protestants
                            of to-day,the only guide. It was examined with great diligence jo ascertain whether Jesus
                            was a true descendant from the house of David or whether he was an impostor. Jesus took the
                            opportunity on several occasions to rebuke this narrow, bigoted idea, by saying to them, "
                            Ye search the scriptures for in them ye think ye have eternal life !! and then as much as to
                            say to them,how very stupid! If you read the scriptures correctly you would readily see that
                            " they testified of me." Paul was no less emphatic and denominates the word on Sinai the
                            ministration of death, engraven on stones, for " the letter killeth, " but that his brethren
                            were the declared epistles of Jesus Christ, written not with ink, but with the spirit of the
                            living God. To denominate the Bible the "Word of God " and the only rule by which man should
                            walk originated among an arbitrary sectarian class of religionists to prevent others from
                            accepting the ever present revelation of God. The two great Christian denominations, the
                            Catholics and Protestants have each a translation of the Bible, which they are pleased to
                            denominate the only, true Word of God, while they look iipon each other as antichristians,
                            and upon the Bible not of their own order as a false and spurious translation. It was by
                            this sectarian work that the most inconsistent ideas relative to the goodness of God have
                            been established, creeds been formed and an arbitrary worship formulated. It is quite
                            certain that if the Scriptures were all consumed, the Word of God would ever remain the
                            same, and that those who are led by the spirit of God would be denominated the sons and
                            daughters of God. Canterbury, N. II.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="poem" TEIform="index"/> TRUST.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>Mary Whitcher</byline><p TEIform="p"> The wing of an angel May shade for a time, At which thou wonld'st neither Complain nor
                            repine, Well knowing the spirit Of God lieth near, And thou hast no reason For doubt or for
                            fear. How gracious to trust Though thy sky seems o'ercast, The heavens remain Through the
                            tempest and blast; Even so all thy good Shall securely remain Through every tempest, Through
                            sorrow and pain. Canterbury, iV. //. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Duty" TEIform="index"/> DUTY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kaime, Joanna J." TEIform="persName"/> .JOANNA ,T. KAIMK. </byline><p TEIform="p">" Stern daughter of the voice of God! O Duty ! if that name thou love Who art a light to
                            guide, a rod, To check the erring, and reprove; Thou who art victory and law When empty
                            terrors overawe, Give unto me made lowly wise, The spirit of self-sacrifice. " To
                            conscientiously regard my highest conception of truth ; by rendering obedience thereto as a
                            line, or path of duty regardless of the issue, was a lesson early impressed upon my
                            understanding with few rose-colored tints to gild the setting of the pearl to my then ideal,
                            MARY WHITCHKB. <pb n="39" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 39 rather than practical view of life.
                            As I advanced in years however, the benefit derived from giving heed to this injunction has
                            been of inestimable value, and I venture to assert that as persons are guided by this
                            inflexible rule or law, they will accomplish a corresponding amount of work in that field of
                            labor wherein their energies are directed. Indeed little good would have been achieved had
                            not this stern and unyielding principle incited to action the world's great benefactors. Had
                            the human triumphed at the cross when Jesus was called to meet its ignominy, who can say the
                            tide of progress would not have rolled backward (if that were possible) until another
                            instrument was found able for the sacrifice ? Had Ann Lee when called to her noble mission
                            halted to "confer with flesh and blood" where would her name and honor be to-day but with
                            the multitude who have been "weighed and found wanting" because unwilling to be as " clay in
                            the hands of the Potter"unwilling to forego earthly appetites and inclinations in deference
                            to a higher law, and this as clearly revealed to their understanding as to the honest
                            earnest seeker after righteousness.Where rests the responsibility today that so many are
                            found in our Communities singularly blest with a knowledge surpassing the wisdom of this
                            world and yet indifferent tc the sacred trust committed to their charge, while the earnest
                            few, who are lost to personal considerations are working with more than human energy for the
                            wholesome growth upon which rests the maintenance and perpetuity of our virgin Order. All of
                            us who have placed our names as supporters of our Covenantal relation have thereby pledged
                            loyalty to the vital principles which constitute us a living church. We are bound by all
                            that is high and holy in our profession to walk circumspectly and unselfishly with an eye
                            single to the glory of that being who has called us out of " nature's darkness " or a
                            generative life into his " marvelous light" or the work of regeneration. " All that defiles
                            or makes a lie " should be consumed by honest confession and genuine repentance. Let us as
                            Brethren and Sisters of one household awake to a deeper sense of our spiritual duties, to
                            our God, to each other, and to the whole human family, believing that we shall all find
                            sooner or later, " The path of duty is the only path of safety." Canterhury, JV</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Future life" TEIform="index"/> HER FUTURE LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/> F. W. EVANS. </byline><p TEIform="p">We must not believe in two places only hereafter, heaven and hell. It is not likely that all
                            are to go either into perfect joy or unmitigated sorrow. This is a very crude and irrational
                            notion, founded on the literal interpretation of some phrases of Scripture which our prosaic
                            theologians have not had imagination enough to understand. God has made this world
                            infinitely diversified with every degree of beinga longscale of musical gradations. Is God's
                            law in this world a law of variety, and is his law in the other world a law of monotony? Has
                            he a million different conditions for his creatures here, and only two there ? Believe it
                            not! The other world is, no doubt as full of variety as this. It has an outward nature; as
                            rich in air, earth, water, light, fire, <pb n="40" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 40 THE MANIFESTO. plants,
                            vegetables, as this, our old familiar world ; only more graceful, more lovely, more various,
                            more sublime, more tender. So, long ago, Milton wrote : " What if earth Be but the shadow of
                            heaven, and things therein Each to the other like, more than below is thought? " The old
                            theory was based on the parable of the Sheep and the Goats. It was nferred that there are
                            only two classes in the other world, saints and sinners ; only two places, heaven and hell.
                            But while each parable teaches some one special truth, all truth is not put into each
                            parable. The particular truth taught by the " sheep and goats" is, that those who have heard
                            of Jesusthe Gentiles, or* heathenwill be judged according to their fidelity to the law in
                            their hearts, which is a law of universal love. The essential difference between men is that
                            they are selfish or unselfish. This parable declares that all generous, unselfish people are
                            essentially Christians, whether they ever heard of Christ or not. But Jesus says explicitly,
                            and without a parable, that there arc many different conditions in the other world, as in
                            this. The law of degrees prevails there as here. If we expect all to go into one place when
                            we go into the other world I think we shall be mistaken. There is a special place for every
                            one to be born there, as there is here. Every child born into this world comes into a home
                            of its own ; has its own father and mother, brothers and sisters, its own nation, country,
                            town, language ; he is born in the country or city, among the mountains or by the sea, into
                            the home of a farmer, a mechanic, a minister. One little child is born in Spain, one in
                            India, one in I^ew England. Each of us, as we pass into the other wrorld, will go into a
                            particular home there, suited tous, and which we are suited for. It is said of Judas that
                            "he went to his place," the place that suited him, the place where he belonged, the place
                            where it was best for him to go. So the Apostle Paul went to his place which suited him, the
                            place where it was best for him to go. All this is not only scripturalr but reasonable ; so
                            reasonable that Jesus seems to think it almost unnecessary to tell us of it. "In my Father's
                            house are many mansions ; if it were not so, I would have told you. " We are also told that
                            while a good deal of what we learn in this life will pass away, much will remain. "We know
                            in part, and we prophecy" (that is, teach) "in part; but when that which is perfect is come,
                            then that which is in part will be done away." But there are three great elements of
                            spiritual life which remain : faith, hope, and love. The faith which abides 'n not any
                            particular creed or belief; but it is that confidence in God, that trust in universal law,
                            in the order of the universe, in a pervading, providing intelligence, in a blessed fatherly
                            love, which is at the root of all intellectual activity, all intellectual progress. This
                            faith is the " substance of things hoped for, the evidence of things not seen." It is the
                            spring of all thought, reaching out from the known to the unknown. We go into the other
                            world believing there is there plenty to know, that the laws of nature are infinite and
                            inexhaustible; and that this faith is to abide in usproves that the other world is like this
                            world in its inexhaustible opportunities for knowledge. There, as here, there will be
                            infinite variety, boundless adap- <pb n="41" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 41 tations, facts of
                            observation for the senses, beauty for the imagination, problems to be studied, deeper
                            mysteries of science. There will be something corresponding to sunlight, to stars and moon,
                            to ocean and mountain, to forest and meadow, to summer and winter. This little world has not
                            exhausted the creative power of God. We here see but the border of his works, and listen to
                            but a faint whisper concerning him. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence
                        </head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My Dear Young Friends; Feeling desirous that you may find..." TEIform="index"/>
                                My Dear Young Friends; Feeling desirous that you may find...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Shaker Village" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Village, N. H.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> My Dear Young Friends ;Feeling desirous that you may find a permanent increase in faith
                                and good works, we thought, perhaps, an expression of our interest in you all, through
                                the medium of the Letter Box, might he a source of encouragement. We are pleased with
                                the degree of earnestness manifested in desiring to become true Christians by those whom
                                we best know, in our own church and trust that all of the class addressed in our homes,
                                from Maine to Kentucky are at heart seeking to do just right. But do not rest satisfied
                                or yield the strife, until you wear the clear impress of virgin souls, until by
                                obedience to godly principles, you become beautified and adorned with the graces of
                                simplicity, truth and purity, knowing no will of your own, but subject in all things,
                                that no temptation of a worldly nature may have power to allure your minds from the
                                blessing of all blessingspurity of spirit. Keep near to the fountains of life, and they
                                will overflow to nourish you. Walk in the vale of humility, with a spirit of warfare
                                against all haughtiness and vanity, that you may "grow in favor" with God and his
                                people. JSfow is the most acceptable time of life to make strong the foundation of a
                                Christian character. See to it that you do not build upon the sand. You are blest with
                                faithful guides before you, who have eyes of discernment, able to see your needs better
                                than you can discover them yourselves; be obedient to their counsels which we believe
                                will always accord with your inward convictions, if you seek to know your duty.
                                Gentleness of manners is a beautiful quality in the character of young personsnot
                                superficial manners, put on and taken off according to your associations ; but
                                cultivated from motives of principle. Persons that are truly humble are always mild in
                                their ways ; not given to idle conversation and loose habits, but reverential to
                                superiors, to sacred places and subjects. This reverence grows from real love of
                                virtuous principles ; unless you cultivate this in your daily life you cannot bring
                                forth its fruits. Herewith accept our best love for the principle, and as we all
                                increase in the beautiful gifts of the spirit, the interest will daily accumulate until
                                the bond will fortify us against the strongest elements of the world. Be truthful,
                                simple, obedient, gentle, kind and enduring, these virtues will adorn you above rubies,
                                pearls or diamonds. Your Sister and Friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Martin, E." TEIform="persName"/> E. Martin. </byline></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Covered bridge" TEIform="index"/> THE COVERED BRIDGE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barker, David" TEIform="persName"/> BY DAVID BARKER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Tell the fainting soul and the weary form There's a world of the purest bliss, That is
                            linked as the soul and form are linked, By a Covered Bridge with this. Yet to reach that
                            realm on the other shore We must pass through a transient gloom, And must walk unseen,
                            unhelped and alone, Through that Covered Bridgethe tomb. But we all pass over on equal
                            terms, For the universal toll Is the outer garb which the hand of God Has flung around the
                            soul. Though the eye is dim and the Bridge is dark, And the river it spans is wide, Yet
                            faith points through to a shining mount That looms on the other side. To enable our feet in
                            the next day's march To climb up that golden ridge, We must all lie down for one night's
                            rest, Inside of the Covered Bridge.Selected. </p></div2><pb n="42" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes" TEIform="index"/>NOTES
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> THE MANIFESTO. FEBRUARY, 18S4L. In the cultivation of the religious element no
                            sacrifice should be loo great. No obstacle should be too large to be removed by the faithful
                            teacher in Christ. It is a work that exercises not only a salutary influence upon us while
                            on our pilgrimage through this life but also gives us, at the same time, an assurance,
                            according to the promise of the holy Spirit, of life eternal and a dwelling place among the
                            redeemed. That we are called, as Believers, through the love and mercy of our God, to live
                            '"soberly, righteously and godly in this present world" is quite well understood. It was the
                            apostle's admonition to the primitive Christians as an essential rule for their spiritual
                            protection. If in this day, however, greater privileges have been vouchsafed to us, than
                            were shared by those of a former age, then it most assuredly becomes to manifest an
                            exceeding righteousn... s and be the honorable representations of the life of Christ. Our
                            treasures should be of the heavens rather than of the earth, lest moth and rust should
                            consume them or that thieves should break through and steal. Called in the name of disciples
                            away from the world, from its sins and its sorrows as well as from its enchanting pleasures,
                            our lives are now to be remoulded by the life of Christ. Old things are to be done away and
                            all things are to become new. Instead of a life of neglect where the laws of God are
                            carelessly passed by as of but little worth, we have the warning which should never grow
                            valueless ;To live soberly and righteously. To be temperate in all things must be the rule
                            so that we may willingly and cheerfully reap the reward of that which we have sown in our
                            own or in another's pathway. If we should bear in remembrance that all of the duties which
                            pertain to our temporal, as well as to our spiritual interests should be tested by our
                            highest conception of right, we might, possibly, by carefulness in speech and in manners, by
                            our eating and drinking as well as by the general tenor of our lives, induce others by these
                            good works to accept the testimony of truth and at the same time be made able to glorify our
                            Father in heaven. As we are privileged, even while in this life, to grow in the Knowledge of
                            the Lord, we shall also be formed anew as living souls. The character that was wrought out
                            while we dwelt in Egypt, although it may have been the best that a land so dark and selfish
                            could afford, w ould most assuredly need some radical changes before it could pleasantly
                            harmonize with the spirit of a consecrated Community where every life should be devoted to
                            God and to his people. Chosen as we are, from among the children of this world, to stand as
                            the witnesses of the voice of Truth, our duty must be apparent. "Say not ye, There are yet
                            four months and then cometh harvest? Behold, Lift up your eyes and look on the fields ; for
                            they are white already to harvest." This was a valuable, practical lesson. Jesus would have
                            his disciples understand, in all clearness, that they were God's spiritual reapers, and it
                            was their divine mission to harvest souls from the elements of <pb n="43" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. the world and gather them into His heavenly Kingdom. The disciples had not been
                            called to become specially interested in either wheat or barley fields but called rather as
                            teachers of righteousness and to invite souls to repentance ; to amend their own lives by a
                            discipline to the cross, to live soberly, righteously and godly, and then as carefully and
                            as faithfully assist others who might be led to accept the same holy calling. Our gospel
                            work, as Believers, runs parallel with that of the disciples ; to publish the good news and
                            glad tidings of a free and full salvation, and to give as liberally as we have received. If
                            we shall become negligent of this sacred duty it would be a sad departure from the original,
                            foundation principles upon which the Church of the Second Appearing of Christ was
                        founded.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good and strong words from the pen of Justin D. Fulton..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Good and strong words from the pen of Justin D. Fulton...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Good and strong words from the pen of Justin D. Fulton are found in his article of " What
                            shall the outcome be?" " For Christian men to be inactive is to betray God. They cannot
                            withdraw from labor without lowering the standard of piety, without making a trace with
                            Belial and surrendering to evil. Faithful Christian men believe in the aggressiveness of
                            truth. They fight to win. Cold hearted and lukewarm Christians clamor for piety, but they
                            will not denounce sin. " It is very fortunate that witnesses for the truth are still able to
                            bear a testimony before the w^orld, which shall encourage the spirit of righteousness and
                            peace. To hate iniquity, is a warfare in which a Christian can engage with a good
                            conscience, </p></div2><div2 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Education, No. 4" TEIform="index"/> EDUCATION, No. 4.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reed, Calvin G." TEIform="persName"/> CALTIN a. KKBD.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Who can peruse the sickening, and heartrending history of the Jewish wars, which put an end
                            to their existence as a nation ; and of the scattering of them, as with a whirlwind, to the
                            four qxiarters of the earth, and not feel a sorrowful regret for their consummate folly ? Or
                            what does the dark age of the Christian era present, but the incontestable evidence, that
                            ignorance is the greatest curse that can rest upon a people ? England manifested her folly
                            in her treatment of her American colonies, and the dissenter from her Episcopal Church.
                            These in turn exhibited their ignorance by persecuting those who differed from them, and in
                            their mad career in the Salem Witchcraft. The French gave evidence of their arrogance in
                            their Atheistic, bloody reign of terror, and their cruel persecution of the Huguenots. Spain
                            demonstrated her cold-blooded inhumanity and fool hearted tyranny in the foul blot of her
                            red handed curdling courts of the Inquisition. And so it runs : the more uncivilized,
                            ignorant, and barbarous a people are, the more inconsistent, cruel and servile they become.
                            England sought to enforce taxation without representation. This produced eight years of
                            sanguinary conflict and heathenish barbarity, and the loss of thirteen of her American
                            Colonies. The belief in the divine authority of kings, had a stronghold on the ignorant
                            masses of America ; and even the moi*e intelligent, revolted at the idea of precipitating
                            Avhat they considered treason. This feeling delayed the Declaration of Independence, and
                            lengthened the period of the Revolutionary struggle, according 43 <pb n="44" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 44
                            THE MANIFESTO. to Gen. Francis Marion, at least two years. This noble, humane officer,
                            called the " Washington of the South," charged all this to the ignorance of the Southern
                            States ; and that this ignorance prevailed, for the want of Free Schools, which would have
                            cost them less than the expenses of the war. Said Marion; "Oh! knowledge, is wanting,
                            knowledge is wanting ! Israel of old. you know, was destroyed for lack of knowledge ; and
                            all nations, all individuals, have come to naught from this cause." " Happiness signifies
                            nothing, if it be not known, and properly valued. Satan we are told, was once an angel of
                            light, but from want of duly considering his glorious state, he rebelled and lost all. And
                            how many hundreds of Carolinians have we not known, whose fathers left them all the means of
                            happiness, elegant estates, and, in short, every t blessing that the most luxurious could
                            desire! Yet they could not rest until by drinking and gambling they had tooled away their
                            fortunes, and rendered themselves the veriest beggars and blackguards on earth." " Why was
                            all this, but for lack of knowledge ? Had those silly ones known the evils of poverty, what
                            a vile thing it was to wear a dirty shirt, a long beard, or a ragged coat; to go without a
                            dinner or to sponge it from growling relations ; or to be run over in the streets, by the
                            sons of those who were once their father's overseers ; Had those poor boobies, in the days
                            of their prosperity, known these things as they now do, would they have squandered the
                            precious means of independence, and have brought themselves to all this shame and sorrow?
                            Never, never, never !" " And so it is, most exactly with nations. If those that are free and
                            happy, did but know their blessings, do you think they would exchange them for slavery ? If
                            the Carthaginians, for example, in the days of their freedom and self-government, when they
                            obeyed no laws but of their own making ; paid no taxes but for their own benefit; and, free
                            as air, pursued their own interests as they liked ; I say, if that once happy and glorious
                            people had known their blessings, would they have sacrificed them all, by their accursed
                            factions, to the Romans, to be ruled, they and their children, with a rod of iron, to be
                            burdened like beasts, and crucified like malefactors ? Surely they would not. " " Well, now
                            to bring this home to ourselves. We fought for self government; and God hath pleased to give
                            us one better calculated perhaps to protect our right, to foster our virtues, to call forth
                            our energies, and to advance our condition nearer to perfection and happiness, than any
                            government that was ever framed under the sun. But what signifies even this government
                            divine as it is, if it be not known and prized as it deserves? And this can best be done by
                            establishing Free Schools. " Notwithstanding all the efforts that such noble, valiant men as
                            Marion put forth in defense of the cause of education, pointing out its benefits, and
                            contrasting it with the disastrous influence of ignorance ; Yet the South clung to their
                            folly, their idols of slavery, and of caste, till they produced the lamentable results of
                            the late Civil War, which spread devastation in all their Mates, and caused the slaughter
                            and death of a million men, the flower and strength of the nation ; the expenditure of
                            billions <pb n="45" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 45 of money, and a like amount of waste of
                            valuable capital, in industries and homes and improvements, and wasted opportunities,
                            besides the breeding of moral pestilence and ruined character, in the lives of those who
                            entered into the conflict. At the close of the Revolutionary War, and the acknowledged
                            independence of the Colonies, had it not been for the influence of the Crisis and Common
                            Sense, coupled with the judgment and keen foresight of such men as Washington, Franklin and
                            those of their class, instead of a democratic government, with the power in the hands and
                            keeping of the people, we should now be under the dominion of a monarchial rule with all its
                            concomitant evils. But thanks be to the honored father of our country. He would not be a
                            king, holding a scepter and wearing a crown. He had learned to detest tyranny, having with a
                            suffering people deeply felt the fangs of its bitterness. With noble heroism, he set a
                            worthy example to all future generations, that sovereignty is the inheritance of the people.
                            For this, poets and orators have vied in speaking his praise. Proud Byron did him reverence
                            in his song: " Where may the wearied eye repose, When gazing on the great, Where neither
                            guilty glory glows, Nor despicable State? Yesonethe firstthe lastthe best, The Cincinnatus
                            of the West, Whom envy dared not hate Bequeathed the name of Washington, To make men blush
                            there was but one. " But why seek afar off to find the bitter apples of ignorance, when they
                            lay so plentifully on our own domain ? Can any thoughtful mind dwell complacently on the
                            results of a century's experience of our own development, and not feel a pang of regret that
                            the frosts of ignorance, and the blights of indifference, have produced such waste and
                            decimation among us as a people? We started with a warmth of zeal which promised a fruition
                            of glory and brilliant success. Noble principles formed the foundation of our institution.
                            We were a century in advance of the religious world. Inventive skill produced some of the
                            most beneficial utilitarian implements, among which are the circular saw, the planing, and
                            the matching machine. All that we needed to make us a successful, a prosperous, and a
                            representative people ; true examples to mankind, was wise, aud intelligent foresight to
                            encourage and foster the industrial skill of the people, by establishing abroad, an
                            educational system, which would cover all the requisitions needed in every department of
                            life, including the physical, mental, and the psychical development of a rational being. We
                            glory in the spirit, perseverance, and results of our founders, and well we may. But what
                            are we doing to sustain their honor, or to achieve one for ourselves? Is not our glory and
                            power gradually passing from us ? And for what cause? Is it any other than our ignorance?
                            Are we not supinely waiting for God to help us when it is oar duty to help ourselves ? Are
                            we not giving our strength to laying up treasure upon earth, instead of seeking fiist the
                            kingdom of heaven and its righteousness, and so are becoming dail) more and more liable of
                            losing both ? Would it not be wise in us as a people, to consider crefully, prayerfully, and
                            wisely, what we ought to have done that we have left undone, and what we have left undone
                            that we ought to have done ? <pb n="46" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 46 THE MANIFESTO. What is it to be wise ?
                            " Tis but to know how little can be known, To see all others faults, and feel our own. "
                            Like causes produce like effects. The tree is judged by its fruits. What are we developing,
                            that will prove for us, to be the grand anticipation of a century's future growth of noble,
                            vanguard principles, as did our parents of a century ago ? Certainly they cannot be begotten
                            of ignorance and indolence. We have made it our aim to be semimonastic, by alienating
                            ourselves from the human family by a life of seclusion, which has to a great degree deprived
                            us feeling the pulsating life of mankind, and thus have been left to float around the center
                            of our isolation. Jesus Christ and Mother Ann did very differently from this. They felt that
                            they had a mission that the people needed ; so they went from house to house, and from place
                            to place, dispensing their treasures of sacred wealth and wisdom, and many heard them gladly
                            and thanked God that they had lived to see that day ; but the foolish, the ignorant scoffed
                            and persecuted. Nevertheless, their principles prevailed. Mount Lebanon, JV. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Slander" TEIform="index"/>Slander</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hillsgrove, Elmira" TEIform="persName"/> ELMIBA HILLSGKOVE.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The slanderer's tongue, 0, who can tame? What antidote, will any name? What shall we do for
                            eyes, that sec, And ears, that hear so readily, The thoughtless words, so heedless spoken,
                            The unkind look, or adverse token, By hours and days, mature in strength, Till, Slander, is
                            their name, at length. Whatever ill is on the wing, And willingly suspicions bring To add
                            fresli fuel to the flame? Pray, how can we such passion shame? When looking at our own
                            misdeeds, Reflecting on our spirit needs, So much we see to do at home, We find no time to
                            cast a stone. If Ave, henceforth, would seek to find The good, so often left behind, We
                            might, by magnifying this, Rebuke whatever is amiss. There is a power, ruling all, The just,
                            the unjust, great and small; And we as finite beings, fail, When from the judgment seat we
                            hail. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In the rocking chair" TEIform="index"/> WRITTEN FOR THE MANIFESTO. IN THE ROCKING CHAIR.</head><p TEIform="p"> I sit, and I rock in the old easy chair, My heart full of longing, my head full of care, So
                            sorely depressing, So keenly distressing, I try to rock hope out of brooding despair. I
                            fancy I see a black cloud overhead; A blank lonely silence reign9, as with the dead; Oh
                            hours so dreary! Oh spirit so weary Look out from beneath the deep shadows of dread!, Faint
                            not in thy weakness, thou tried heart of mine Nor murmur, tho' dark days of tempest be
                            thine; Thy trials and crosses, Thy burdens and losses, Are only the chastenings of God's
                            love divine. Rise not in defiance, but bow at His throne, And say, " Ah my Father Thy will
                            be mine own, " And then in His blessing Thou'lt find sweet redressing, And joy, that the
                            depth of His mercy be known. I know, my young heart, that thou canst not see Why it is that
                            that sad Angel visiteth thee. Why 'tis that she chides thee, Yet trusting confides thee, And
                            I rock as I wait for an answer to thee. It is this; that a lesson both needful, severe, She
                            has brought for thy keeping, in love, not in fear, Wheresoever thou goest, Whatsoever tho a
                            so west, The same thou shalt reap when the harvest is here. Oh sink thou not down 'neath
                            this chiding so sweet, It is for thy repentance; go, lay at His feet, The gifts in thy
                            keeping, The fruits of thy reaping, The golden bound sheaves as an offering meet. Then awake
                            to the music of Hope, Oh my heart, Stand not back in thy doubting, but render thy part, The
                            Love-angel lingers, Her fairy-like fingers Sweep over the strings f her beautiful harp. And
                            so I have rocked off" my sorrow and care, Have rocked a sweet hope out of bitter despair, In
                            lieu of cold sadness, A heart full of gladness, Thank God for my peace in the old rocking
                            chair.</p></div2><pb n="47" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sun of righteousness" TEIform="index"/> SUN OF RIGHTEOUSNESS.</head><p TEIform="p"> Groveland, N. Y. Canterbury, N. H. In the Spiritual Sky there is beam - ing A Sun that will
                            never go down; O'er the hill-tops its light is streaming, Be - vealing the E - ternal
                            Throne. E'en the arches of Heaven are shin - ing, And the path of the pilgrim is bright; All
                            dark clouds have a silver lin - ing From the orbit of truth and right. </p></div2><pb n="48" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books
                        </head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/> Phrenological Journal
                                and Science of Health. </head><p TEIform="p">January. Contents: Distinguished Visitors ; Lord Coleridge; Matthew Arnold and Henry
                                Irving; The Oriental Type of Character, Illustrated; China, Illustrated; Observations on
                                Amativeness; The Stormy Petrel; Mental Treatment of Disease; The Heart; Notes in Science
                                and Agriculture; etc., etc. Fowler &amp; Wells, Pub., 753 Broadway, N. Y. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Surveyor-Boy and President" TEIform="index"/> Surveyor-Boy and President</head><p TEIform="p"> Young People's Life of Geoiwk Washington; By William M. Thayer. Elzevir edition, 466
                                pages, Brevier type, leaded. With illustrations. Extra cloth, 50 cents; half Russia,
                                red^dges, 65 cents. No other name has received such universal homage as that of
                                Washington. Edward Everett spoke but the verdict of the world when he pronounced
                                Washington, "of all the men that ever lived, the greatest of good men, and the best of
                                great men." Frederick the Great, whose own name ranks with those of Alexander, Csesar,
                                and Napoleon, declared his deeds to be " the most brilliant of any in the annals of
                                military achievement." Whether as schoolboy, surveyor-boy, Indian fighter, member of
                                Congress, Commander-in-Chief, or President, his life was full of striking incident, and
                                ever an example to thrill and inspire any youth whose heart pulsates with the free and
                                vigorous blood of the Anglo-Saxon race. Mr. Thayer, the author of the present work, just
                                published, has proved by his world-famous lives of Lincoln, " From Pioneer Home to the
                                White House." and of Garfield, " From Log Cabin to the White House," a writer whose pen
                                is wondoi'fully suited to its theme. II" writes with an enthusiasm worthy of his
                                subject; with vividl}1 drawn pictures of the times and scenes through which Washington
                                passed, quoting the language of his friends and contemporaries, and crowding the pages
                                with appropriate illustrative anecdotes, he makes the times and the characters seem
                                present realities to the reader. His book will at once be aecepted as one of the best of
                                the lives of Washington, not for young people only, but for older folks as well. It is
                                not sold by dealers, but only direct by the publisher, who will send a 100-page
                                descriptive catalogue of his attractive and famously cheap publicatious free on request.
                                John B. Alden, publisher, 18 Vesey St., New York.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/> Herald of Health.</head><p TEIform="p"> Jan. Contents: A lecture on Light; Sanitary Science; The Church and Health Reform; The
                                W"ater Cure in Europe; Salutisland; Education of Children; How to preserve the Eyesight;
                                Sawing Wood for Exercise; Beer; Studies in Hygiene for Women. M. L. Holbrook, M. D. Pub.
                                13 &amp; 15 Laight St., N. Y. $1.00 a year.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/> Hall's Journal of Health.</head><p TEIform="p"> Dec. Contents : An Age; Care of the Eyes; Croup; Teething; How to Cleanse the Waste
                                Pipes; The Sick Room j The Evils of Hot Bread; Milk as Food; Variety in the Daily Food;
                                A Neglected Disinfectant; Choose Health or Sickness; Food Adulterations. E. II. Gibbs,
                                M. D. Editor. No. 21 Clinton Place, 8th St., N. Y. $1.00 a year.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/> Kind Words for the Year 1883.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We desire to send you and all interested in the editing..." TEIform="index"/>
                                We desire to send you and all interested in the editing...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Ohio, Whitewater, February 1883" TEIform="index"/> Whitewater, Ohio, Feb. 1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> We desire to send to you and all interested in the editing and publishing our monthly,
                                so full of rich treasures, our kind love and thanks, praying that it will enlighten and
                                bless many souls with the truth, which alone can free the soul from sin.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ball, Stephen, W." TEIform="persName"/> Stephen W. Ball.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The April Manifesto is very good and interesting..." TEIform="index"/>
                                The April Manifesto is very good and interesting...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Enfield, April 1883" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, N. H. Apr. 1883. </dateline><p TEIform="p">The April Manifesto is very good and interesting. I pity those who would not like to read
                                it.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Caroline" TEIform="persName"/>Caroline Whitcher. </byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I think the Manifesto is improving..." TEIform="index"/>
                                I think the Manifesto is improving...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, April 1883" TEIform="index"/> Mt. Lebanon, Apr. 1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> I think the Manifesto is improving. Hope it may live and grow.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stewart, Amos" TEIform="persName"/> Amos Stewart.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One of our greatest comforts is the monthly reception of..." TEIform="index"/>
                                One of our greatest comforts is the monthly reception of...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Maine, West Gloucester, December 1883" TEIform="index"/> West Gloucester, Me. Dec.
                                1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> One of our greatest comforts is the monthly reception of the Manifesto which always
                                comes laden with a feast of good things. We are glad to add our two mites to sustain our
                                only periodical, and that growing every year more interesting and indispensable. Elder, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sawyer, Otis" TEIform="persName"/>Otis Sawyer.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths
                        </head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Taylor, Polly" TEIform="index"/> Polly Taylor,</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 18, 1883, at north family, Union Village, Ohio. Age, 78 yrs. Has been a member of
                                the Society for sixty years and was a very faithful sister in the discharge of all her
                                duties, both spiritual and temporal.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., O. C." TEIform="persName"/> O. C. H,</byline></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kidney, Daniel L." TEIform="index"/> Daniel L. Kidney,</head><p TEIform="p"> Dec. 17, 1883, at North Union, Ohio. Age, 64 yrs. 10 mo. and 25 days.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Swint, Joseph" TEIform="index"/> Joseph Swint,</head><p TEIform="p"> Dec. 24, 1883. at Hancock, Mass. Age, 65 yrs.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall, Betsey M." TEIform="index"/> Betsey M. Hall,</head><p TEIform="p">Jan. 12, at Harvard, Mass. Age 68 yrs. and 3 mo. Our kind and loved sister has bid
                                farewell to friends in the terrestrial, to join those of the celestial. To those who
                                knew her best she needed no other eulogy than her whole devoted life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M., E." TEIform="persName"/>E. M.</byline></div3></div2><pb n="49" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><!-- 
AD VERTISEMEiXTS
 cibbd.
An old physician, retired from practice, having
had placed in his hands by an East India missionary
the formula of a simple vegetable remedy lor the
speedy and permanent cure of Consumption, Bronchitis, Catarrh, Asthma and all throat and Lung Affections, also a positive and radical cure lor Nervous Debility and all Nervous Complaints, after having tested its wonderful curative powers in thousands of cases, has felt it his duty to make it known
to his suffering fellows. Actuated by tins motive
and a desire to relieve human suffering. I will si'iid
free of charge, to all who desire it, this recipe, in
Gorman, French or English, with full directions for
preparing and using. Sent by mail by addressing
with stamp, naruina1 this paper, W. A. Notks, 149
Power's Block, Rochester, if.  Y.
Vick's Floral Guide.
For 1884 is an Elegant Book of 150 Pages, 3 Colored Plates of Flowers and Vegetables, and more
than 1000 Illustrations of the choicest Flowers,
Plants and Vegetables, and Directions for growing.
It is handsome enough for the Center Table or a
Holiday Present, Send on your name and Post Office address, with 10 cents, and 1 will send you a
copy, postage paid. This is not a quarter of its cost.
It is printed in both English and German. If you
afterwards order seeds deduct the 10 cts.
"Viek's Sels are tlie Bt*st in tli World!
The Floral Guide will tell how to get and grow
them.
Vick's Flower and Vegetable Garden, 175 Pages,
6 colored Plates, 500 Engravings. For 50 cents in
paper covers; $1.00 in elegant cloth. In German or
English.
Vick's Illustrated  Monthly Magazine- - -32 Pages,
a Colored Plate in every number and many line Engravings. Price $1.25 a year; Five Copies for $5.00.
Specimen ISmmbejs sent for 10 cents; 3 trial copies
for 25 centJAMES VICK.
Rochester, N. Y.
MEDAL   MACHINES.
HEW IQ2X STATE AGEICULOTSAL WOSZS
a 11 it anna e t sri iiiirin ifimniaB mi sii hi
1st Premiums at all Competitive Trials.
Railway, Chain and lever Hor Power*, Tlir".<*li*i\i ami Clranera, Th riM'rs
& Shakers, Clover Hullers, feed Cutters,  Wheel   Horse   Rakes,   Horse
Pitchforks,    Mhing-le       ITIathiiies,
Straw   Preserving- Rve   Threshers,   Portable   Steam-itg-ines,
Ciller   and    W'ine  .Mills    and
Presses,     Dog-    and    Pony
Powers,     JDisc      Harrows
ASpring-rTooth Harrows.
WHEELER & MELICK Co.,
ALBAXY, BT. Y.
Send stamp for Circular and report of Centennial
trial.
The Eev. J. E. Searles, of New York, is
one of the most widely-known and highly
esteemed of Methodist ministers.
Mr. Searles says: " I am imprcs ed that it is a duty
I owe to tlioxo afflicted with Kheumatism or Neural,
gia, to nay that a remedy has been discovered that ia
indce I a marvelous success. My Fon was greatly
afflicted with Rheumatism, and suffered so severely
that, at times, he was obliged to liave morphine injected into his arm to get relief. While in this condition he discovered a remedy v, Inch effected immediate relief, nd a permanent cure. Ho has since i urniahedittomanv others with the same result. I have
also furnished it to a number of peivons sufferii:;^
with Rheumatism, and the result has been immediate
relief, and a permanent cure. Ainoug-o.heri:, I jraveit
to Kev. Wm. P. Corbit, pastor of the George St. M. R
Church, New Haven,Conn.,who was suffering-greatly
with t':ii terrible disease. I will give you his own
words as written to my son,'wishing-him to publish
the fact for the benefit of others suffering with the
same disease."
What Mr. Corbit Says;
" New Haven, Ju^y 24. 1882.
"Mr. Searles: Dear Sir:I wish to gay for the benefit of all who are Buffering- with Inflammatory Rheumatism, that your medicine is infallible. I suffered
for two month;; the most excruciating-torture ; lost
35 pounds of flesh, and was not out of my hou1 e for
a month ; I heo.;: I of your remedy, and was almost
instantly relieved by it. If there i-* a specific for diseases of auy kind, yours most certainly is for Inflammatory Rheumatism in its severest form.
" Yours iin t re ipeel fu I ty,    Wm. 1\ Corbit,
1' Pastor George St. M. E. Church, New Haven, Conn."
Such is Athlophokos1a thorough and
efficient c;;re for the worst cases of Rheumatism and Neuralgia.
If you cannot get Athlophobos of your drug-gist,
we w!;l send it express paid, on receipt cf regular
priceone dollar per bottle. We prefer that you buy
it from your druggist, but if he hasn't it, do not be
persuaded to try something- else, but order at once
from us as directed.
ATHLOPHOROS CO., 112 TOIL ST., NEW YORK.
TO AIL  AHIIOIHD   WITH
HERNIA or RUPTURE.
Prof. J. C. Wakd, continues the manufacture and
application of his TRUSS at No. 43 High  st. near
Hudson Avenue in Albany, N. Y. and a<* to its merits would refer to any of the leading- Physicians.
Respectfully jours,
JOHN C. WARD.
Good Fay for Agents. $1OO to &3OO per
mo., made selling our fine Books <fe Bibles. Write to J. C. IVIoCurdy & Co., Phiia.  Pa.
 "P A 'PTTT? m&y be found on file at Geo.
 rillJCiXl p Lll & C'   X
 &y be found on file at Geo.
 p. Lowell & Co'n Xewspapei
Advertising Bureau (10 Spruce St.). where advertising
contracts may be made for it IN NEW YORK.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
A U VER T1SEM l'L\ VS.
BRAIN AND NERVE FOOD.
VITALIZED PHOS-PHITE.
Composed of the Nerve-giving Principles of Uie Or-Brrtln       J  Wheat-Germ.
IT RESTORES THE ENERGY LOST BY NERVOUSNESS OR INDIGESTION; RELIEVES LASSITUDE ERRATIC PAINS AND NEURALGIA ; REFRESHES THE NERVES TRIED BY WORRY,
EXCITEMENT OR EXCESSIVE BRAIN FATIGUE; STRENGTHENS A FAILING MEMORY, AND
GIVES RENEWED VIGOR IN ALL DISEASES OF NERVOUS EXHAUSTION OR DEBILITY. IT
IS THE ONLY PBEVEJFMVE OF CONSUMPTION.
IT GIVES VITALITY TO THE INSUFFICIENT BODILY OR MENTAL GROWTH OF CHILDREN PREVENTS FRETFULNESS, AND GIVES QUIET, REST AND SLEEP. IT GIVES A BETTER
DISPOSITION TO INFANTS AND CHILDREN, AS IT PROMOTES GOOD HEALTH TO BRAIN
AND BODY.   Physicians have pracrH*ed dOO.OOO p?ckug-N.
F. CROSBY Co., 664= and 666 Sixtli Av., IV. Y.
For sale by druggists or by mail, $1 in P. O. Order, Stamps or bill.
NO  CURE!   NO  PAY!
Dr. Lwnsn's Cough Mm
is warranted to cure COUGHS, COLDS, HOARSENESS, SORE THROAT,
and all diseases of the   Throat and Lungs.
We do not claim to euro consumption when thoroughly seated, but we do claim that'thousanda of lives
might be saved every year by the timely use   of Dr. Lawrence's Cough Balsam.
Many people imagine they hive cons .mprioii, when in reality they only have a bad cold, which can
easily be cured by proper care ami ilie right kind of medicine. We could fill columns with testimonials, but
do not believe in I hat way of advertising, our idea is to let everybody that is afflicted with a cough try
for themselves, and if not perfectly satis fled, return the empty bottle to the dealer of whom it was bought
and receive their money back.
' Price for Trial Size, 25 Cts. Family Size, $1.00 per Bottle.
lS*m<'iB!lM', Wo  Cure,  jjfo  Pay.
No Cube, No Pay! Dr. Lawrence's Cough Balsam, when once used, takes the place of all others.
OPE DEAF.
Peek's Patent Tubular Cushioned Ear Drums cure Deafness in all stages. Recommended
by scientific men of Enrol)*' and .\nn-rici1. Wr.ii- lov illustrated descriptive book and testimonials from
doctors, judges, ministers and prominent men ; nil \v< men w ho hiivo Ih'cii enif i, and who take pleasure
in recommend in a then). Tiny ;nv unse.i n vlnii- i.i use. comfortable to wear, find make a permanent
cure.   Addri'ss.WEST & CO., 7 Murray St., New-York, Agents for Souih and West.
McShane Bell Foundry
Manufacture1 tlioo celebrated  B^lls
and    Chssnes    fov    diurciies
XowiM-Cloeks, &;.. Ac.   Prices
and catalogues sent f'-eo.   Address
II. MflShane at Co.. Baltimore, iMd.
Hut This Out
& Return to us with TEH
CTS. & you'll get by mail
A GOLDEN BOXOFCOODS
ythat will bring you in MORE MONrY, In One Month,
than anything else in America. AbsoluteOertainty.
Need no capital. M. Y oung,173 Greenwich St.N. York
Our Special "FAEM and GARDEN"
Offer ! An unequalled opportunity to secure
the "Farm and Garden" for one j ear. Absolutely FJKEE, and a supply of Choicest
GAltUEN SEKJ>S at a trifling cost. We
Rend the "Farm and Garden" (the nionthlj
Farmers' paper) one year FREE with each
Trial Package "F" oiOorr's Iowa SeedsWe make the otler to imlucu you to try our Seeds,
rand to introduce them into thousands of new homes this season. We want every Jt armer ami Gardener to give
them a fair, honest trial. Package "F" contains one packet each, Cuban Queen Watermelon, J\ew Favorite Tomato, Exeelsior Cabbage, Lone Orange Carrot, Boston Market Celery, fcrreen i rmKed Lettuce,
Mammoth Hed Onion, Sugar Parsnip, Lone Scarlet Jiadish, Boston Market Cucumber, ^"W/e-^P Turnip, Bay View Melon ; also Superb Pansy (which alone sellsfor 0c) Usual pnee of these heeds >s$1.80: BA.
add the price of the "Farm and Garden," 50c, makinfi S2.30, and see what we give for ONLY 9Uti
<&.BZ.f\t\ IM PAQU DDCIUIIIIMfi <r the bl:st Vegetables grown from our Seeds. Competition open
Sar^ularHnd direoMons sent only with each package. Order^t^nciTa" takeldvan'tage of the greMesToffer eVer made,
ttorr'a Iowa Seed Dlanual sent with each order.   Send your address, with SOc. in cash or stamps, and receive the Seeds
<pb n="" id="p"/> --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>