<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1203" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><date value="18820301" TEIform="date">March 1882</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">49- 72</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--                     <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p>VOL. XII. MARCH. NO. 3. MANIFESTO PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. CANTERBURY, N. H. Blessed are they that hear the
                        word of God and keep it." Shaker Village, N. H. 1882. SHAKER</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
--><pb n="49" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What Shakerism teaches" TEIform="index"/>WHAT SHAKERISM TEACHES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p"> Shakerism is the Nazareth of Christendom. One hundred years ago the Christ Spirit, through
                            Ann Lee, broke the seven seals with which the Little Book, written on the inside, the
                            outside, on the backside, was sealed. The unlearned could not read this book, because they
                            knew neither Greek nor Hebrew. Neither could the learned, because it was sealed. In the old
                            heaven and old earth, there was not a man who could either open the book, or endure to look
                            upon it, so as to read even what was written upon the outside thereof. It took a Christ
                            woman to break the seals and begin to read its contents. What new theology did she read? If
                            there are to be a new earth and new heaven in place of the State and Church that have
                            hitherto ru?ed in the affairs of men, the first principles—foundations—of both the old and
                            new should be clearly understood. Is it any marvel that the rulers in the old earth and
                            heavens, Church and State, are not able to bear even a look into those principles that
                            underlie the new order in Church and State, which will supplant the old? It is like the
                            change in life relations at Pentecost, or as paganism passed away before what was called
                            Christianity in the Roman Empire. All existing forms of Christianity, whether Catholic,
                            Greek, or Protestant, are, in their essence, Church and State organizations. Collectively
                            they are the Church in the Wilderness state—1260 years. This Church in the Wilderness claims
                            authority, in the name of God, as against the right of private judgment in matters of faith
                            and conscience. It assumes to regulate the human understanding. The subordinate Protestant
                            sects—little images—protest against this claim to authority and infallibility on the part of
                            the Greek and Catholic churches, while they, each in its sphere, exercise the same power as
                            those churches, so far as they can control the State. They send heretics to prison in this
                            world, and to <pb n="50" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 50 SHAKER MANIFESTO. an eternal hell in the next. It
                            asserts that belief is a product of the will, not a result of evidence ; that salvation is a
                            reward of belief, not the result of ceasing to do evil; while damnation, eternal hell, is
                            the punishment for not believing some theological mystery that the teachers thereof don't
                            profess to comprehend. It asserts that war is a Christian element ; the Church and State in
                            one nation may properly wage Christian warfare with the Church and State of another nation,
                            thus making hell upon earth. The Church, from the Catholic hierarchy to its least image,
                            claims the right to use State laws and State power to restrain heretics, to support an
                            inquisition. At present, in America, it seeks to inflict pecuniary loss, and to ostracize
                            heretics from good society. This is only the beginning. The Church teaches, also, that there
                            is no probation beyond the grave, no progression, at death eternal happiness, perfect and
                            complete, or eternal hell fire, excruciating, helpless, hopeless, endless physical pain, and
                            horrible mental agony. Finally, it teaches that the old earth and heavens, which are to be
                            destroyed at the Day of Judgment, are the material earth and heavens. They will be burned
                            with material fire, and all the physical bodies of past time will be reorganized. After
                            being judged out of some big books, the righteous, sheep, will inherit the earth again,
                            rejuvenated by fire. The wicked, goats, will go into a material lake of fire and brimstone
                            everlastingly. Amen. What are the claims and principles of the new order in earth and
                            heaven? 1. God is dual—Father and Mother. 2. Christ is not Jesus, but a Spirit that may be
                            in each human soul as really, practically, as it wras in Jesus. 3. No man or woman is a
                            sinner until he or she willfully commit sin, nor any longer than the sin is persisted in.
                            Total depravity does not exist. 4. Repentance goes with existence, and the mercy of God
                            endureth forever in all worlds. 5. There are many heavens and hells. Those in the heavens
                            and hells of one dispensation or degree may be gathered into the heavens of the succeeding
                            dispensation or degree, as scholars may leave the ignorance, errors, and faults of one
                            class, or school, by going up. 6. The Church, Christianity, when first seen was pure and
                            holy, like a woman clothed with the sun, standing upon the moon, a::d crowned with twelve
                            stars. When she formed improper connections, she was called hard names. The Shaker Church
                            has the moon under her feet—lets it alone, and desires that all other sects and peoples of
                            earth shall let it alone, and leave us a pure secular government that takes cognizance of no
                            theological sin. I propose to pile up evidence, add line to line, precept to precept,
                            confirmation to demonstration, until such men as Ingersoll are conquered ; and if it cannot
                            be effected in any other way, to be so good and do so much good that if they believe not my
                            words, they will yet believe for the works' sake, in a word, to overcome what I think evil
                            in them by what they think good in me Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Care" TEIform="index"/>CARE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline><p TEIform="p">Take care of Jife,— Why should we not If life is worth the giving; The gift should Never be
                            forgot, But we take care of living. Canterbury,N. H., </p></div2><pb n="51" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian experience: patience vining" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN EXPERIENCE: PATIENCE VINING</head><p TEIform="p">Friend Editor ;—I am one of the few left of the eighteenth century. I have enjoyed the
                            privilege of reading the Manifesto from its first number, and it has been a great pleasure
                            to me. I now wish to add to it my mite by writing a short autobiography, including my
                            experience as one of the witnesses for Truth and Righteousness. It may do a little good to
                            some inquiring minds, to know that there are many that they have never heard from, who have
                            lived for many years in the Society, and still feel thankful for their privilege, and for
                            the protection of God particularly when age brings infirmities, that cannot be avoided. It
                            is good to have kind friends ever near to smooth the roughness of the way. I was born in
                            Lyden, Mass. Nov. 9, 1799. My father's name was John R. Vining, and my mother's, Rachel
                            Field. There had been more or less acquaintance in the family with the Society of Shakers
                            for many years. My mother, at one time, related to me a vision that she received previous to
                            becoming a member of the Society. "I saw a man standing in the center of the room. Again, I
                            saw the same person standing in the highway. Hiss peculiar manner and appearance led me to
                            invite him into the house. I now Sfav that he Avas a member of the Society of Shakers, and
                            that his name was Benjamin S. Youngs." Four years after this my parents, one brother, three
                            sisters and the writer moved to the Society at Mt. Lebanon. It has now been but a few years
                            since my parents passed from this life, a brother and two sisters have also gone before me.
                            One sister still remains on the shores of time. My mother, at the time that I was two years
                            of age made a visit to the Society at Enfield, Conn, and from this date my practical
                            experience may be said to begin. When six years of age I urged my mother very strongly to
                            let me go and live with the sisters, which request was fhWly granted. My experience of
                            seventy six years includes many more blessings than I am able to recount. From the early
                            date of six years I have been made the recipient of God's love, and the life of the Believer
                            has been beautiful to me. My blessings have been abundant, and my days happier than those of
                            Lords or Kings. When I was young I often saw brethren and sisters under the control of
                            spirit influence, and was in a quandary for a long time wondering how a spirit could move a
                            body without the will of the one moved. I made it a subject of prayer. One day while alone
                            and in deep thought on this subject, I felt the manifestation of the spirit of God on my
                            body and knew what it was. This proved satisfactory. I had received a spiritual baptism, and
                            was never troubled any more about it. I have often read,—"There is no respect of persons
                            with God." Had there been I might never have been called into his fold of love, for as a
                            child I was very rude. I will now close with this poem. The King may have his throne, And
                            the miser his gold ; The monarch his palace And the princess her home. I covet none of
                            theirs For I've a gospel call, And a kind loving mother That is better than them all. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="52" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant season" TEIform="index"/>A PLEASANT SEASON</head><p TEIform="p">Alfred, Me., Jan. 1882. Dear Editor, Manifesto ;—Our late Christmas Festival, which for good
                            reasons was postponed to the evening of the 26, was one of the most social entertainments,
                            of the kind, we ever enjoyed. ' The following Christmas song was one of the contributions.
                            It was good for us all to be there, to witness the sparkling brightness, and overflowing
                            enjoyment of all the little folks, and even the "children of larger growth," as they looked
                            upon the three evergreen trees, with their expansive limbs heavily laden with a great
                            variety of fruits, pretty and useful tokens of sweet remembrances. Some original and many
                            select pieces were admirably spoken. All fitted to the occasion and tending to awaken an
                            strengthen the bond of Christian love and fellowship, and unite the hearts of all as one
                            from the oldest, 81 to the youngest 7 years of age. Our very special, liberal and loving
                            friends, the Goodalls of Sanford, and the Ushers of Bar Mills, which includes, M. U. Osgood.
                            all of whom are always doing good, contributed many beautiful, nice as well as sweet things,
                            which each recipient gratefully received.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christmas song for 1881" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTMAS SONG FOR 1881</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sawyer, Otis" TEIform="persName"/>OTIS SAWYER</byline><p TEIform="p"> Down through the ages comes a voice,— Israel's Shepred teaching; That then, as now and now,
                            as then, That love's the truest preaching. By this, said Christ, shall all men know Who are
                            my true Disciples ; 'Tis by their fruit, nor high, nor low The Thorn ne'er yieldeth Apples.
                            The Angel with the Keed he bears, To measure human greatness; Declines the selfish soul, who
                            wears These marks of human weakness. Whose hearts bear malice, spite and hate Towards a
                            fellow brother, Nor on his tablet this be found; "0 love ye one another." When Mother, Oh!
                            most precious name, Begun her holy mission; Her gentle love diffused abroad,— Inspired a
                            heavenly vision. The Angels caught the sweet refrain, And forth to man they hasted; Good
                            news, glad tidings, from our God,— Heaven and earth are wedded. Come, woman in your strength
                            arise, For your Eedeemer cometh ; Fill ev'ry space from earth to skies With songs of love
                            that charmeth. Let echo and re-echo roll From valley, over mountain; The tender love of God
                            is known By this new, open'd fountain. The Mother-hood of God's revealed, 0 blessed
                            revelation; The mystery so long concealed, The healing for the nations. The comforter to
                            earth has come With healing wings, to bless, And this the name whereby she's called, "The
                            Lord our Righteousness."* The New Creation's now begun, The Parentage complete; Sons of God,
                            and Morning Stars, Make harmony replete. So we this day will celebrate,— Renew the Sacred
                            Story; "Peace on earth, good will to man," And unto God give glory. We'll bless our
                            consecrated home With blessing that's perpetual; Bless the aged and the youth, And call this
                            place Emmanuel. Those other Sheep not of this fold, Are ours with special blessing; Whose
                            loving hearts and lib'ral hands, Are blest, ten fold, in giving. Alfred, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inspiration like the love of God is an active principle in the mind" TEIform="index"/>Inspiration like the love of God is an active principle in the mind
                        </head><p TEIform="p">See Jer. xxxiii, 16. Inspiration like the love of God is an active principle in the mind. In
                            the innocence and with the simplicity of childhood, confide in thy Heavenly Father's
                        care.</p></div2><pb n="53" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Job bishop" TEIform="index"/>JOB BISHOP</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">BT Although it has been the pleasure of the Societies of Canterbury and Enfield to write upon
                            their records many valuable names of the pioneers of their gospel work, yet none occupy a
                            more endearing place in their memories than that of Father Job Bishop. He was born in New
                            Lebanon, N. Y. Sep. 29, 1760. His early years were spent with his parents, and so soon as
                            his age permitted, he assisted his father in his work on the farm. In 1779 he became quite
                            interested in a religious revival of which he writes, I entered fully into the spirit of the
                            work, and received great light. I was often blessed with the presence of the spirit of God,
                            and believed that the gospel of Christ required a daily cross against sin. Although zealous
                            prayers and religious exercises often had the effect to produce spiritual sensations, yet
                            they were not permanent and left me a subject to temptations. I was encouraged by the
                            revival to look forward with hope for a manifestation of the light of God, and fully
                            believed that the second coming of Christ was near at hand. Elder Joseph Meacham who was one
                            of the principle leaders in the revival warned us to take heed, that we might not oppose the
                            work of God, as it was revealed to us. He believed that in this work, a virgin life would be
                            required, but as he saw no way to protect the people in it, he thought it was not prudent to
                            preach the doctrine. The spirit of this revival continued through the summer, and then
                            gradually declined leaving its subjects in great tribulation. They had renounced the creeds
                            and ceremonies of the chinches, but their meetings though still continued had lost their
                            power. The speakers recently so active now sat in silence with bowed heads. Those who rose
                            to speak of to pray lost the power of utterance and were obliged to resume their seats in
                            silence. We passed the winter exhorting each other to faithfulness, while we anxiously
                            waited for the accomplishment of the prophetic spirit of the revival. The work came. In the
                            spring of 1780 we learned of a people near the city of Albany, N. Y. who were reported to
                            have received a singular kind of religion, and that they possessed a large degree of divine
                            light and spiritual power. Many went out to see them, and returned fully persuaded that they
                            were the true witnesses of God. The interest increased and I felt a great desire to satisfy
                            myself concerning these strangers and their religion. Early in June, in company with several
                            others, I made them a visit. We arrived on Saturday evening and remained till Monday. We
                            found them all kind and social. Elder James Whittaker explained to me the doctrine which
                            they taught; reasoned from the scriptures and manifested great knowledge of the spirit and
                            light of the gospel of Christ. We attended their meetings. The singing was inspiring, the
                            speaking powerful and heart searching. The wisdom of their instructions, the purity of their
                            doctrine, and the Christ like simplicity or their deportment, all reminded me of the
                            apostolic faith. I returned home in a state of mind hardly to be described. A deep
                            impression had been made upon my feelings, <pb n="54" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 54 SHAKER MANIFESTO. and a
                            new scene had been opened to my view. I saw that the work was of God and my salvation
                            depended upon it. The cross that was before me was an evidence of the spirit of the
                            testimony. On the one hand the prospects of the world were nattering to my mind. I was in
                            the prime of life, and in the vigor of health. My reputation was fair, and my hopes not
                            unpromising. On the other hand religion had been my pursuit. The revival had raised my
                            hopes, and directed my faith to a greater and more glorious work. I subsequently made
                            another visit and was received with kindness. I confessed my sins to God, and with a fixed
                            resolution accepted the cross of Christ. I was now taught to rectify every wrong that I had
                            committed, to forsake all sin and to take up a daily cross. I also became more intimately
                            acquainted with Mother Ann Lee and the Elders who were with her, and am a witness of the
                            purity of life which they constantly maintained. The doctrine they taught was strictly
                            conformable to the precepts and example of Jesus Christ. By obeying their precepts I
                            experienced the truth of their testimony. I was blessed with heavenly visions and felt my
                            faith established on a sure foundation. I visited Mother Ann and the Elders many times at
                            Watervliet, Harvard, Ashfield, Hancock and New Lebanon, and have most freely associated with
                            all the leading members of the Society. To my great satisfaction, I have seen that the
                            principles which were first taught by Mother Ann have been faithfully kept by her
                            successors. "The three witnesses* who came from * Mother Ann Lee, Father William Lee and
                            Father James Whittaker. England had all prophesied of a gathering of the Church into order.
                            A successor to Father James, however, had not been appointed at the time of his deaJh,
                            although Joseph Meacham had been named as an assistant in this great work. The prophecy
                            concerning him had a corresponding bearing upon several others among whom we find Elders
                            Calvin Harlow and David Meacham. "As no preponderating excellence appeared where so much
                            native talent and intellectual power were the endowment of each, combined apparently with
                            equal religious zeal and spiritual attainment, it seemed impossible for aught save Divide
                            Wisdom to decide the election. No eye but that which is single to the glory of God might
                            look in upon that praying band, who were seeking to learn whom God had chosen to lead his
                            people to the promised inheritance where all should share alike the blessings of a bounteous
                            Providence, so great was the power manifested in the heavenly influence, so eloquent its
                            utterances, so encouraging its promises that a beholder might well say as each declared the.
                            message given, 'Surely the Lord hath chosen this' yet no such power was vouchsafed to the
                            burdened spirit of the chosen one as he meekly listened to the divinely inspired eloquence
                            of his fellow laborers. When all the candidates had ceased, still waiting for a decisive
                            manifestation, the voice of a youth, Elder Job Bishop, was heard, calm and decided,
                            declaring with a power which left not the shadow of a doubt on the mind of any present, that
                            the silent listener, Joseph Meacham, was the anointed of God to lead his people." Father Job
                            always regarded this as a revelation from God. An out growth from their united prayers while
                            in that <pb n="55" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 55 sacred conference in the church at New
                            Lebanon. Immediately after this prophetic announcement, Elder John Hocknell kneeled in
                            prayer before the assembly, giving utterance to this expression only, "Blessed be God."
                            Overshadowed with the divine presence these reverent and prayerful children of God fell upon
                            their knees and the floor was wet with their tears. Giving his soul so unreservedly to a
                            life of holiness, Father Job was made the happy recipient of the life of Christ and enjoyed
                            a measure of that inspiration which Jesus said should follow those who believed in him.
                            Although a thorough disciplinarian and a man of practical, sound judgment, yet through the
                            illumination of the spirit he saw the visionary forms of many who had passed on to the land
                            beyond. He would relate with much pleasure the spirit welcome that he and those with him, in
                            the ministry, received while on a visit to the society at Harvard, Mass. No less than four
                            of the first Elders manifested themselves so fully that Father Job was pleased to denominate
                            it the most remarkable vision of God that he had ever received. (TO BE CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth" TEIform="index"/>TRUTH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Martin, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName"/>ELIZABETH MARTIN</byline><p TEIform="p"> Truth fits to truth! An attribute of Him who reigns As King o'er all the powers that are ;
                            What vital strength, what majesty It is revealing everywhere ! Truth fits to truth ! Already
                            hewn by law of God— No need of plane, nor square, nor line, It ever is the same, its mould
                            Attests its origin divine. i Truth fits to truth! No circumstance can change its face, No
                            creed or system gave it birth; It was, and is, and is to come,— A part of God, diffused
                            through earth. Truth fits to truth ! The more its virtue we employ, The nearer Heaven's gate
                            we rise; The more it enters all our joy, We grow more just, more good, more wise. Truth fits
                            to truth! Then let us build our character On solid truth's foundation stone ; And as our
                            edifice we rear, Let every act be truth alone. Thus shall it stand Thro' Summer's smile, and
                            Winter's frown, Thro' whatsoe'er may test and try; No power can tear the structure down, If
                            truth its pillars underlie. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ancestral tradition" TEIform="index"/>ANCESTRAL TRADITION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p"> Mortal beings, whatever powers of mind, or talents they may possess, cannot change one truth
                            ; for Truth is coexistent with Deity. Tradition and education have moulded our thoughts, and
                            shaped our ideas, and many things which we conscientiously think we believe, are only
                            shadows from pictures painted upon our memories in early life, or monographed by historians
                            and the priesthood in later years, by iteration, which have taken such strong holds upon our
                            minds that the impress is hard to remove, and the echo to die away. But thorough
                            investigation on our part, often convinces us that many of those ideas are only tra- '
                            ditionally ours, inherited, and have not come to us by close reasoning, nor earned by labor.
                            Hence the necessity of great charity for the views and opinions of others, who think and
                            reason differ- <pb n="56" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. ently from us ; and in all cases "to
                            be kindly affectioned one towards another." If the advancement of truth be our aim, then all
                            can work harmoniously together. Many times a small differance in phraseology may give a
                            false impression of the idea sought to be conveyed, when if a different word, or phrase,
                            were substituted, such as ourselves would have employed to express the same idea, it would
                            be clearer to us at least, while others might have taken the idea as first propounded, as
                            the clearest. Calm reasoning in such cases is much better and wiser, than sensorious
                            criticism. In this is manifest the wisdom and "patience of saints." It is our privilege to
                            take lessons from the wise and unwise, the progressed and unprcgressed. Let all have a place
                            to work according to their several gifts and attainments, "one after this manner, another
                            after that," according to the measure of grace through the gift of God to them and the
                            ministration and effectual working of His power by the spirit of Christ. Childhood and youth
                            are preliminary to full manhood ; and the anterior stages of existence are a necessity to
                            the posterior. Development and growth marks and moves everything. As we read and understand
                            the law given through Moses to the ancient Jews, by the light of the present Christian
                            dispensation, and the curtains formed of rites and ceremonies are drawn aside, we see its
                            weaknesses and defects in a large degree ; but Jesus said, it was not his mission to destroy
                            the law ; he came to fulfill it. The law in its most potent form was far from being a full
                            Savior ; it was only adapted to the immature condition of its subjects in that epoch, given
                            as a safeguard for the time being, and a delineator, pointing to something higher and more
                            perfect in the future. That it was defective and weak in many points, no one can deny; that
                            it also contained much truth we will not undertake to dispute. The Israelites, unto whom
                            that code of laws was given, were a rebellious, hard hearted, warring and licentious people.
                            It dealt with them as they would accept, or reject. If the light of the present age shines
                            brighter and clearer than in the past, let us learn wisdom and seek to divide the true from
                            the false. Cast that which is unworthy to be retained, back into the great sea of human
                            passions ; and let all that is true, still live. The progressive spirit of the ages will
                            roll onward the great car freighted with the ripest and best fruits of the centuries gone by
                            ; and let us say, as did Jesus, that it is not our purpose to destroy or annul any truth of
                            the Law or Gospel; but pray and work to the end, that every jot and tittle may be fulfilled,
                            and glorified. One writer recently said; "We cannot down with the Old Testament and claim
                            that it is obsolete, for it contains truths that will outlive the centuries ! Truth can
                            never die. Hence we see the Old and New Testaments, bound together between two lids, lying
                            on our tables and in our Churches ; while they contain errors, there is truth enough in both
                            to bear them up, and commend them to the better feelings of all," Truth is a unit, it is
                            indestructible ! and, whether physical, intellectual, moral, or spiritual, pertaining to
                            body or soul, belongs in the final issue, to a perfected dispensation, and forms a part of
                            one great whole. 56 <pb n="57" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 57 The Ark, which was the
                            repository of the archives of the ancient Jews,, and contained their covenants, and also the
                            Mercy Seat, overshadowed by the wings of the Cherubim which was a beautiful type of the dual
                            Christ Spirit, a representative picture that is still pleasant to look upon after the lapse
                            of ages, was very sacred to them, and-was guarded with care, while it was borne upon the
                            shoulders of the Levites, the highest order of priests. The growth of the ages has been
                            slow, but sure. Stepping stones have been laid from time to time, and pioneers in the march
                            of truth have ventured to go forth as vanguards and occupy a little higher, and still higher
                            ground, while they kept in sight of the main body. The path of progression is an up hill
                            grade and difficult to travel; its possibility has been tried, and successfully proved by
                            many who have climbed its rugged steeps, and have come off conquerors. The first Christian
                            Church had its defects and also had its days of prosperity. While it maintained its
                            integrity by firmly adhering to fundamental principles, it was invulnerable against the
                            powers of darkness and spiritual death ; but when anti-Christ came and knocked at the doors
                            of the sanctuary, and sought admittance that there might be an alliance formed between them,
                            then, disintegration began to take place, and the power of the holy people was scatterd.
                            Shall we learn, and be warned by the past to look well to the present, and to hold fast our
                            veracity, while we press on to know and understand the future, and prepare to meet whatever
                            may betide, whether weal or woe, prosperity or adversity? If forewarned, we may be
                            forearmed; and thus be able to stand where others have fallen ; and then we shall be debtors
                            to the wise and unwise. Mt. Lebanon N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nothing lost" TEIform="index"/>NOTHING LOST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER</byline><p TEIform="p"> Waste not thy time— That moment spent In idleness and play, Might benefit some needy one In
                            this, and future day. With good intent, From heart sincere, Deep answers back to deep, And
                            no good deed is ever lost Though long the silent sleep. Our thoughts have voices— And will
                            tell On many a heart and mind, The feeling, greatest gift of all The senses of mankind.
                            Cty., N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sherman, Ezra" TEIform="index"/>EZRA SHERMAN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Schroyer, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Thomas Schroyer</byline><p TEIform="p">We have received a copy of "The Harrison News," in which we find a notice of the death of our
                            Brother at White Water, Ohio, published by his friend, ANOTHER PIONEEE C3-OISTE_ "Death has
                            again visited our Community, and claimed for its victim one of our most honored and
                            respected citizens,—Ezra Sherman. None knew him but to love him. During the three months of
                            his sickness, we visited him a number of times. On our first visit he seemed delighted that
                            we called. He said, Thomas, I am glad you came to see me : I wanted to see you and talk with
                            you. I may get well, but I think not. I am old and willing to go. ***** Don't pay any
                            attention to creeds, but live right. Do right, and when you are called to enter the great
                            hereafter, you will have nothing to regret. For several days preceding his death he had a
                            presentiment that he should die at nine o'clock, A. M., the same hour that he was born, and
                            sure enough, on Sunday morning, as the hour hand reached the hour of nine, his spirit took
                            its flight."</p></div2><pb n="58" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good will to all" TEIform="index"/>GOOD WILL TO ALL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. HAMPTON</byline><p TEIform="p"> The goodness of God leadeth on to repentance ; Forgiveness, the need of confession sincere;
                            Man's weakness, a plea for entire dependence On God's tender mercies while traveling here.
                            Contrition and sorrow become the Believer, For sin and short coming, and hardness of heart;
                            And who of such gift is the happy receiver Can truly be said to possess the "good part." I
                            know that the true consecration of spirit Which we are commanded in deed to possess, Is
                            genuine Love and good will to inherit, And ev'ry good saint and vile sinner to bless. To
                            soften each feeling of coldness and hardness In tender conpassion, to friend and to foe; Of
                            all to be anxious and watchful, regardless Of what they are doing or going to do. The old
                            roots of bitterness, malice and slander, 0 let us dig up, and consume in the fire Of patient
                            forgiveness, and charity tender, If nearer to Heaven and Christ we aspire. Cease, once and
                            forever, from all evil speaking, And learn the new language, to speak well of all; The good
                            and the union of all to be seeking, For this is in earnest the trumpet's loud call. Why
                            should we continue to injure each other O God! shall the sword never cease to devour? O are
                            we not ready, dear Sister and Brother, Of Peaceful at-one-ment, to hail the glad hour? Sweet
                            union, is Heaven on earth to believers It strengthens the wav'ring, and comforts the strong;
                            Ev'n here in this life, from all grief it delivers, And fits us for joys of Eternity long.
                            Union Village, Ohio. O how blessed is the union of God's children just and pure ; Bright and
                            shining are the mansions, which our Father does ensure, Ever blessed, ever holy, shall our
                            work and calling be : Free from evil, clean and lovely, in the spirit we'll agree.</p></div2><pb n="59" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes from the life experiences of Mother Ann Lee" TEIform="index"/>NOTES FROM THE LIFE
                            EXPERIENCES OF MOTHER ANN LEE</head><p TEIform="p">Great pains were taken by Mother and the Elders, to teach and instruct the Believers in the
                            care and management of temporal things. They were often taught to be industrious ; to put
                            their hands at work and their hearts to God ; to be neat and cleanly and to observe good
                            economy. They should be prudent and saving and let nothing be lost or wasted through
                            carelessness or neglect ; to avoid equally coveteousness and prodigality; to be kind and
                            charitable to the poor and to keep clear of debt. These things wTere strictly enjoined upon
                            the Believers, from time to time, as matters of special importance, in order to secure a
                            spiritual blessing. It was always held as a doctrine of truth, and abundantly proved by
                            experience, that those who were unfaithful in temporal things, could not find the blessing
                            and protection of God in their spiritual work. It was essentially necessary in order to
                            inherit the true riches that they should make a faithful and wise improvement of every
                            talent and all their time. In addressing the sisters, Mother Ann said, Are you willing to be
                            the daughters of Zii'n ; to be searched like Jerusalem with candles, and confess and forsake
                            your sins, to put away all wrong, and be the children of God ? Regard your privilege. Go and
                            keep the way of God and not return to your former sins, for the labors of the people of God
                            must not be lost. They will be a savor of life unto life, or of death unto death. Mother Ann
                            on passing an apple tree that was filled with blossoms, called the attention of those who
                            were with her and said,—How beautiful this tree is now ! By and by the fruit appears ; but
                            some of it will fall off quite soon ; while some will hold on for a longer time, till they
                            are fully half grown and some will get ripe. So it is with souls who set out in the way of
                            God. Many will set out very fair, and soon fall away; some will continue longer and then
                            fall off, while others will go through to the Kingdom. The gifts and calling of God are
                            given to souls in nature's darkness ; not because they have repented, but the gifts are
                            intended to lead souls to repentance. Some one asked, What is repentance ? and were
                            answered, To&gt; cease from committing sin, is the only repentance that God accepts, and
                            this no one can do except by an honest and faithful confession of all sin to the chosen
                            witnesses of Christ. The severe persecutions and cruel abuses which Mother Ann suffered in
                            consequence of her faith and testimony, were occasionally related to the Believers. They are
                            striking evidences not only of the inveterate hatred and malice of a lost world against
                            every increasing manifestation of divine light, but also of Mother's unexampled confidence
                            and resolution in maintaining her testimony. Mother and the Elders abounded greatly in
                            visions, prophecies and revelations. Many who received the testimony were also blessed with
                            the same gifts. They were given to strengthen, confirm and establish the faith which the
                            people had received.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inspiration is the breath of the Almighty; whoever catches this breath of life is stimulated to deeds of Holiness and Love" TEIform="index"/>Inspiration is the breath of the Almighty; whoever catches this breath of life is stimulated to deeds of Holiness and Love
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Inspiration is the breath of the Almighty; whoever catches this breath of life is stimulated
                            to deeds of Holiness and Love.</p></div2><pb n="60" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obedience" TEIform="index"/>OBEDIENCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Theobald, Arthur" TEIform="persName"/>ARTHUR THEOBALD</byline><p TEIform="p"> "Behold! to obey is better than sacrifice." I. Sam. xv, 22. Never has anything been more
                            fully verified than this statement. The Jews, as long as they were obedient to the law, grew
                            and flourished; but as soon as they threw it aside, they were plunged into wars, which
                            resulted either in poverty or slavery. The Jews' however are not the only people upon whom
                            this severity has been inflicted; the Romans in their disobedience to the laws of nature and
                            of humanity experienced a fall which has become proverbial. So with every nation, whose
                            ambition, driving it madly on in disobedience, finally plunges itself into difficulties from
                            which there is no extrication. All history is replete with corresponding examples. So also
                            in the spiritual sphere, although the penalty may be delayed, it is, nevertheless, sure to
                            be measured to the delinquent, in its fullness. The stings of conscience may quicken a soul
                            to confession and repentance, by which some atonement can be made, and forgiveness obtained;
                            while, on the other hand, obedience to established law would prevent, in all cases, the
                            sufferings which always follow disobedience. The result of obedience is peace and
                            prosperity, and an unalloyed enjoyment. A difference of development must have a
                            corresponding difference of conception. It is not possible for the child or youth to
                            understand, fully, the meaning of the term obedience, and therefore, are not under the
                            obligation that belong to age and judgment. It could not be expected that a short privilege
                            in the Shaker or true Christian life would enable one to discern duty in this direction, as
                            clearly as those, who by their experience, and therefore more mature judgment, are
                            capacitated for that obligation. Every one has a part to act in life and that faithfully
                            performed, brings its reward. Even the children find happiness in obedience, and as the
                            understanding matures, the necessity of more strictness forces itself in, which if heeded,
                            will result in a blessing. There are two forms of obedience—one voluntary, willing and
                            cheerful, the other a kind of forced obedience, which is shown in the half way manner in
                            which it is yielded. This latter kind, in fact, is not true obedience. It seems closely
                            conjoined to disobedience and is of a low type, underhanded and mean; while obedience,
                            willingly and cheerfully rendered is a virtue to be desired and obtained. This is
                            accomplished by bringing all selfish desires into subjection to the "higher law." It
                            requires the crucifixion of self-will, the slaying of false judgment, and in fact, the
                            burning of ail selfishness in the fire of gospel testimony. It is an obedience that knows
                            only the straight and narrow path of self-denial. To those who walk therein, the blessing is
                            vouchsafed. It is the path in which is found the living soul: and as it demands a childlike
                            subjection as rendered by our Exemplar, we must expect to find those only who having
                            accepted its searching light, are still striving for greater perfection. Unabated by trials,
                            they have an ardor, more determined than ever to gain the proffered treasure; thus attesting
                            that although there are struggles in the way, there are joys also, which more than
                            counter-balance the sorrows. It is the earnest workers who are in an enviable condition,
                            whose happy faces and cheerful voices give strength and encouragement to many a weary
                            toiler;— whose lives shine with a never dimming lustre as an example to all who would
                            behold. This condition is surely the indication of that happiness which the world cannot
                            know. It is ever increasing, filling their spirits with love as they hold out to us the joys
                            of the gospel of obedience and leave an inheritance for us to beautify and enjoy. We who are
                            young should not be unmindful of our duty; should ever strive to gain those virtues which
                            they possessed, by a careful daily life in obedience. It seems befitting that at the
                            beginning of the New Year we should pledge ourselves to greater obedience hoping to have the
                            union of all who are young. In this we shall feel assured that we share the truth of the
                            prophets word:—"Behold! to obey is better than sacrifice." Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><pb n="61" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Time flies" TEIform="index"/>TIME FLIES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL ORCUTT</byline><p TEIform="p"> Young persons seldom think much of old age, but when old age comes, they are surprised that
                            they did not think of it more. "Rejoice, O youth, and walk in the ways of your hearts, and
                            in the sight of your eyes ; but know that for all these things, God will bring you into
                            judgment." "What is your life? It is even a vapor that appeareth for a little while, and
                            then vanisheth away." Time flies ; and ere you are aware, golden opportunities may fly too.
                            God has given you ability, employ it for His glory. You may not have ten talents nor even
                            five, but you have at least one talent, and that one talent, rightly used, will produce good
                            results. Every moment spent for God yields unalloyed happiness. While your day lasts work.
                            Garner the durable riches, as you would garner a supply of luxuries. Moments are more
                            valuable now, than years that are gone. "Seconds and minutes are the gold dust of time,
                            which are often wasted. Take care of your gold dust." If any portion of time can be called
                            yours, it is the present. Past opportunities will not return. "You cannot catch the moments
                            that no longer tarry, they are gone forevermore." Too much time has already been lost. Lose
                            no more. What is time, but the brief hour for preparing for eternity? This may be your last
                            hour. Prepare. "Work in my vineyard," is the Master's command. Living to God is every day
                            work. Begin now. lie will not forget your service. He offers riches lasting as eternity.
                            Eternal life is the gift of God; accept it while it is piofFered. There's danger in delay.
                            Living in sin hardens the heart. Break from evil habits now. The more convenient season will
                            never come. Tomorrow may be too late. "You know not what shall be on the morrow," God
                            commands, obey now. Now, for it is the accepted time. "Harden not your hearts." Tltfcy are
                            hard enough already. Life is uncertain. "Thousands of lives are extinguished as a candle is
                            suddenly blown out." The thought of death has brought many to a decision. The voice of God
                            is the voice of authority. He has a right to speak to you ; obey now. Defer not later.
                            Should you repent tomorrow, yet it would be a sin to remain impenitent to-day. You cannot
                            afford to put off until tomorrow, that which should be done now. Every day leaves a day more
                            to repent of, and a day less to repent in. A day will not last always ; a day is only a day.
                            Time flies. Well improve it and you are saved, misimprove it and you are lost. Enfield,
                            Conjf,.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beauty of Zion" TEIform="index"/>BEAUTY OF ZION</head><p TEIform="p">See Zion fair city, in beauty arise, Her children in heavenly harmony join, While thousands
                            their order behold with surprise And truly confess that her Laws are divine. No nation, or
                            people that dwell on the earth Can boast the bright joys of this lovely abode; 0 bless'd
                            emanation from mansions of mirth, Such harmony, union and peace are of God. Harvard,
                        Mass.</p></div2><pb n="62" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker manifesto" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER MANIFESTO</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">MARCH, 1B83. Change of Office of Publication. The "Shaker Manifesto" for the presem will be
                            published at Shaker Village, N. H. All business matters connected with the financial
                            department of the paper will be directed to the,— Publisher of Manifesto, Shaker Village,
                            Mer. Co., N. H. All other communications may be addressed, Editor of Manifesto, Shaker
                            Village, Mer. Co., N. H. One Copy per. year, Postage paid, .60 " " six months, " " .35
                            Enclose a two cent stamp for a specimen copy. To avoid mistakes, those who send money,
                            should write the name of their Post Office, County and State. KCO One inch, one insertion "
                            " three " " " six " " " twelve" " column ----- ---- $ 1.00 each .75 " .65 " .50 ----- 6.00
                            Larger spaces, rates in same proportion.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In loving kindness" TEIform="index"/>IN LOVING KINDNESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Before and above all religious Societies the Shakers should be the most earnest advocates of
                            that discipline which incites in them the spirit of the life of Christ. The civilized world
                            of today is well filled with a form of moralizing which savors very strongly of an order
                            corresponding to that of those beautiful sepulchres to which Jesus so aptly referred. Among
                            many the daily practical life of the Christian is becoming more or less obscured by the term
                            of non essentials. If a man is able to reconcile his mind to the belief that his habits and
                            practices are in accordance with a well regulated religious society, and all are made for
                            the honor and glory of God, then his fortress stands upon a pretty firm foundation.
                            Believers may not, however, be able in their communistic order, to accept the liberty of the
                            radical or of the indifferent minds of other churches, as ours must be a united brotherhood
                            and sisterhood in every temporal and spiritual dutySt. Paul's lesson to the Brethren in the
                            church of Corinth was most excellent and charitable. He found that the members were not
                            equally developed in understanding, and yet they were no less his brethren in Christ. He
                            advised those who had a knowledge of some of the non-essentials to exercise a care lest "by
                            any means this liberty of yours become a stumbling block to those who are weak." Then like a
                            father in the Church, the good apostle makes this avowal in regard to the eating of meat
                            which had been sacrificed to idols. If the eating of this meat maketh my brother to stumble,
                            I will eat no more flesh forevermore. One of our religious exchanges pubishes this fact;
                            "The attendance upon church prayer meetings are mostly women, and the rest chiefly middle
                            aged or old men." As a matter of course the writer should know whereof he speaks. Possibly
                            something more attractive than a 62 ADVERTISERS. TERMS. <pb n="63" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 63 prayer meeting calls the attention, of the absent class, another way. Shall we
                            not, as Believers, find in this a lesson which will admonish us to more carefulness ? We
                            certainly need not fear to learn a good lesson, as taught by the experience of those not of
                            our faith. We also have prayer meetings. Are they so organized that all wish to be present?
                            Shall we not make them fruitful seasons of spiritual love and life, in which, every member
                            of the household shall hold a privileged place ? The spirit of prayer must of necessity grow
                            with a body of Christians as they grow in the spirit of righteousness. The explanation which
                            Mother Ann gave to prayer is the embodiment of all that helps to lead the soul home to God.
                            "Every breath," said she, "is continual prayer to God." It may take the form of a petition
                            for protection, for guidance or for determined resolutions. Whatever it may be, let us give
                            it as a free will offering to the cause of right and truth. A society of ladies in
                            Washington, D. C. have organized themselves into a society under the name of "Guardian
                            Angels." May the beautiful spirit of our Lord so inspire them with an abundance of his
                            loving and saving grace, that they may be able to direct the wayward into the paths of
                            righteousness and peace.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Once on a time Br. R. P. sent by express, two fancy chickens..." TEIform="index"/>Once on a time Br. R. P. sent by express, two fancy chickens...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Once on a time Br. R. P. sent by express, two fancy chickens, to a Brother in a distant
                            Society as a present. The brother not understanding it to be a free gift, wrote to Br.R. of
                            the beautiful fowls he had received but that he could not find any bill. Can't you, said Br.
                            R. really, I am very much surprised as I thought I sent you two bills.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="St. Kitts, British West Indies" TEIform="index"/>St. Kitts, British West Indies</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="McNish, J." TEIform="persName"/>J. McNish</byline><p TEIform="p"> St. Kitts, British West Indies November, 28, 1881. 5 Elder F. W. Evans, Mt. Lebanon, N.
                                Y. Bear Friends: Your postal card, and the three pamphlets also, with your letter came
                                safe to hand. I will hear by mail due here on 2.12, if my family received them at
                                Bothwell. We have had three weeks rough seas and a half gale blowing so that I have not
                                heard from our friends in Nevis, except one visit from a member of the meeting, just
                                before your valued papers came ; but I told him to call at the post office at
                                Charleston, as soon as the mail was in, as I knew there would be some matter for them
                                from Mt. Lebanon. Thou wilt please accept my heartfelt thanks for thy prompt answer to
                                my request. Thou knowest how very weak words are to express deep feeling. I was much
                                pleased that it was in thy heart to write to me. I did not expect more than the
                                pamphlets. I can assure thee I enjoyed thy lecture very much. Some matters are new to me
                                and require to be well considered. The life of Mother Ann touches one and calls out our
                                sympathies. I believe if our Lord was to come to earth this day, hj would be crucified
                                again by the rigidly righteous. I am free to tell thee, they are being read by quite a
                                number of people, and are passed from one to another as soon as read. It may be bread
                                cast on the waters. Thinking men here who know the rottenness of these islands, say and
                                feel the end cannot be far off. It was in my mind to speak with thee regarding what T.
                                L. Harris says about Ann Lee, in the book "The Two in One," but will not enter upon that
                                subject. I never heard even a hint as to the Duality of God, or that God was male and
                                female—two in one—until I read it in Harris. To me these are new truth's, and some of
                                them can only be comprehended as the Spirit gives me light. One thing is plain enough;
                                let me live the life marked out, and by and by, that will bring confirmation. In the
                                meantime, life is a hard fight, and it is hard to get along without in some way hurting
                                your neighbor. I may tell thee frankly, the world is made up <pb n="64" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 64
                                SHAKER MANIFESTO. of two classes—those who eat and those who are eaten; if you don't eat
                                yoii will be eaten. Quakerism was, and is said to be, Primitive Christianity revived.
                                Since getting a glimpse of your system, I begin to think it was and is, Primitive
                                Christianity revived, wanting the principal idea. Community of goods, or all things in
                                common, "Robert D. Owen tried it at Lanark, on the Clyde, but it was a sham and a show ;
                                it was tried near to my home in Bothwell Parish, but broke up with loss. Land is
                                required. If the present state of matters is to continue, we will see the next great
                                movement in Britain to be the land question. The land belongs to the government for the
                                benefit of the whole people. The mass of the present owners got it when Might was Right,
                                and under conditions that have long passed away; but Right is coming to the front, and
                                Might must go down. Had I got over to Nevis, I could have sent thee a fair account of
                                how matters really stand, their number, character, and all particulars. I dare not
                                judge, but we cannot shut our eyes to the state of matters around us. And I am much
                                afraid few people in these islands are willing to sacrifice the animal nature in
                                themselves. Climate, nay all around them is against it. One reason for the loss of shame
                                (women don't know what modesty means) is, children in the country run naked up till four
                                or five years of age. Little girls have generally a cover of cotton ; boys up till able
                                to work a little have only a shirt, or trowsers in rags. I am speaking of the children
                                of the estate hands, or laborers. I have no doubt from what I have heard, that the
                                majority of children here know more of what lust and bestiality means than one-half of
                                your people put together. It may be the result of slavery. No one works here if they can
                                get along without it; and as no fire is required, and no bed clothes, little does them.
                                A cane cut from the nearest cane-piece is quite sufficient for a day's provision, with a
                                little bread. Indolence is so grafted into the nature of the people that to expect a
                                fair day's work out of them is quite out of the question. Mark, I do not blame them. I
                                have done hard work in factory life at home ; I have tried to work here, just to prove
                                the matter to my own satisfaction. A white man cannot work in these islands, and I do
                                not blame the colored people for doing just as little as they can. Just as in slavery
                                times the hands are crowded into gangs. Young boys and girls pulling weeds and gathering
                                stones, get about eight cents a day; women sixteen cents, and men from one to two
                                shillings. All are paid by the piece. Dig so many holes for one shilling; if you are
                                willing you may do two tasks. So with all the rest. , No laborer on these islands can
                                get apiece of land to buy, or even to rent; if they do get a bit up the mountains, after
                                they have brought it in from bush it is taken from them, so that few of them have a
                                little bit The owners know that half an acre will make the laborer and his family
                                independent for life ; for that half arcre will produce far more yams and sweet potatoes
                                than will keep them, and from the overplus they can get salt fish, which is about all
                                they get or require; or, now and again if they can kill a monkey, it makes a feast. At
                                home I was a vegetarian, here I can't be. Unless an American schooner comes in we never
                                see cabbage or any other vegetable. I had fully intended writing out an account of a
                                trip I made on the first of this month to the little Dutch island of St. Eustacia, known
                                as Statia, not that for one mo" ment I could expect to take up thy time in reading
                                anything I could write, but thinking it is the only means in my power to prove that I
                                feel grateful for thy kindness. I can assure thee the card brought a sort of peaceful
                                feeling, or sphere, with it. I trust thou knowest something of this, as I have been
                                sneered at for holding such an idea. The American steamer will not be here before
                                tomorrow, but the post office closes the mails shortly, so I must close by simply
                                saying, I feel much at thy kindness, and will try to deserve it. Thy obliged friend,</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whatever is really useful is virtuous, though it does not at first seem so" TEIform="index"/>Whatever is really useful is virtuous, though it does not at first seem so
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cicero" TEIform="persName"/>Cicero</byline><p TEIform="p">Whatever is really useful is virtuous, though it does not at first seem so.—</p></div3><pb n="65" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lowell, Mass. Dec. 27, 1881" TEIform="index"/>Lowell, Mass. Dec. 27, 1881</head><p TEIform="p"> Lowell, Mass. Dec. 27, 1881 Elder F. W. Evans, Dear Sir ;— This is to inform you of my
                                whereabouts and that I have not forgotten you. I have had my land surveyed and expect to
                                sell in a few days. Dear Sir, I will, herein, ask you a few questions, if you please. In
                                the first place, if I come to live with you, I must quit all female society, moral or
                                immoral, and associate with men only. Next, I must stop the use of Tobacco. Next, must
                                live' that sober, industrious and retired life that I see among your people. Also drop
                                all my Music, of which I have over $500, worth, and I am called a good Musician, a
                                talent very much respected by the common people. Also, I must drop the Lecture Roll and
                                attend strictly to the industrial duties of your Society, notwithstanding I have a cash
                                income, sufficient to support me through life, without work. Under these circumstances,
                                do you think it advisable for me to come and sacrifice all these so called blessings ? I
                                presume I have all the natural instincts of the natural man. Will your sort of life
                                become so unnatural and monotonous as to destroy all the beauties of this life ? I trust
                                you will condescend to answer the above in your clear, honest way, and by so doing, not
                                only oblige me, but prepare me better to know just what I am to meet, if I come with
                                you. On sabbath, the 18th inst, I preached in Grand Army Hall, in this city, to a very
                                large audience. Subject; Why stand ye idle. Last Sabbath, I spoke in Well's Hall, this
                                city, before the Reform Club, of some 2000. Subject; Why do young men learn to drink ?
                                To night, I am to speak in the Congregational Church, this city. Subject; Where is my
                                Mother ? On Sabbath next, in the Well's Hall again. Subject; Prisons, Prisoners, and the
                                great cause of crime. Again, will you be so kind as to enlighten me on the above
                                subjects ? I don't want to come to you to bring discord among you nor to lead you in a
                                new field. If I come, I want to do you good and make you happy, if possible. Sir, I look
                                upon you as the great head of the Order, and to yoix I appeal for light on the subject.
                                Your letter shall be strictly confidential. I still see those great golden Letters,
                                Lebanon. What does it mean ? Please give my undivided Love to all your Family,
                                especially to the good Brothers and Sisters with whom I spoke. Please answer and oblige
                                your well wishing friend.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, Jan. 3, 1882" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, Jan. 3, 1882</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline><p TEIform="p"> Mt. Lebanon, Jan. 3, 1882 Esteemed Friend ;—Your letter of Dec. 27, came duly to hand. I
                                have not before had time to answer it. It is an unique letter. You have formed a
                                singular character, have had a strange history. The habit of moving has become second
                                nature. Starting when you like and going where you please; perfectly independent, you
                                refute Pope's axiom; "God never formed an independent man." How is it that a man, of
                                your general intelligence, asks so Stupid a question (excuse the word, it is plain
                                Saxon) as your first one ? "Must quit all female society, moral and immoral, and
                                associate only with men ! !" Is that what you have learned, the conclusion you have come
                                to, after visiting so many Shaker Societies and assaying to unite with several of them ?
                                I am afraid of you ! ! Do you recognize no relation of the sexes but the animal? Are men
                                and <pb n="66" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 66 SHAKER MANIFESTO. women always to be animals, the Lords of
                                animal nature ? If men and women are immortal in their existence, what will be the mode
                                and functions of that existence, is a matter of some interest to rational thinking
                                people. "The Old Adam and New Adam." "The Old Man and New Man." "That which is natural
                                first, afterwards, that which is spiritual." Do these terms represent ideas? To me, they
                                do. "Dying daily, under a daily cross," "Crucifying the Old man, with his affections and
                                Lusts," is reality to a true Shaker. The Resurrection means a Spiritual Order, with a
                                Spiritual relation of the Sexes. New Heavens and New Earth. I was under the impression,
                                after about 50 years experience, that I had found a relation of a pure, heavenly
                                quality, not to one woman only, but to an hundred fold, as compared with what the
                                World's order affords. Am I mistaken? Do I "associate with men only?" If what you write
                                indicates your actual knowledge of Shakerism, you had better conclude that you know
                                nothing, yet, as you ought to know, respecting our Order. "Eye hath not seen, nor ear
                                heard" the things God has prepared for his people, in this Resurrection ralation in the
                                union of the Sexes, "in the Lord." Oneidaism turned the Grace of God into
                                licentiousness, but it did not destroy the Grace of God. Shakers may make shipwreck of
                                faith, as drunkards may make shipwreck of temperance, as the thief makes shipwreck of
                                honesty. That destroyeth not true Shaker faith, true temperance, nor true honesty.
                                "Stopping the use of Tobacco ;" Is that such a dreadful thing ? A Temperance Lecturer,
                                who goes about exhorting those who are ready to perish for want of strong drink, and
                                with the social poverty and spiritual destitution of a system of false science, false
                                religion and false Spiritualism, beginning by robbing human beings of the land, to which
                                they have the same inalienable rights that they have to life itself; himself using
                                tobacco ! ! I should suppose your words would choke you before they reached the ears of
                                your fellow sensualists. Alcoholic preparations, Opium, Tobacco, even Licentiousness,
                                are but substitutes for a substance that God has for his people. They inherit substance,
                                having no need of miserable, Devil substitutes. They are satisfied with God's goodness,
                                physically, morally, affectionately, spiritually. The Souls of the. Priests of the
                                Resurrection Order, are "satiated with fatness." Even in the Natural Order, there are
                                those who live intellectual Celibates, Platonists, like Andrew Jackson and Mary, who
                                claim to have lived, for many years, in Platonic Love, as brother and sister but that
                                does not constitute them Shakers. They are intermediate between the two Orders,
                                Generative and Resurrection. From that class, Male and Female, when we have a true
                                Republic, I looktto have all the Governmental Offices filled, leaving the married people
                                at home to care for each other. "Music to be sacrificed too;" I thought Shakers were
                                among the most musical of people. For worshiping God with music and dancing, they have
                                been persecuted by Antichristian sects. Perhaps you refer to Instrumental Music. That is
                                only a matter of time, of wisdom. Many Societies have it; some not. If you have $500
                                worth of Music, sell it, "Drop the Lecture business." I should suppose it would be a
                                blessed <pb n="67" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 67 thing to do that, for a goodly
                                season. Paul did it, and all whom we have ever gathered, of Preachers, Lecturers,
                                Exhorters, Reformers, have done it, until they have passed through the river of
                                Judgment; the 'river of repentance, and become New creatures. I did it. Let all such
                                first take the beam out of their own eyes, before they preach to, or attempt to rebuke
                                others, lest they become castaways. What good of your "Cash income ;" is it not the
                                price of blood? What shall it profit a man, if he gain the whole world ; property wife,
                                honors &amp; if thereby he lose his soul? When he enters the Spirit World, whose
                                shall these things be? Without faith, you cannot please God, but will continue to please
                                yourself. You must be the judge. Except a man forsake all he hath, can he be a Shaker?
                                If living in possession of all those blessings, you are satisfied, what more do you
                                want? Let well enough alone. Do not come here to be looking back to, and murmuring for,
                                the good things of Egypt. While you have them, enjoy them. If you love them, more than
                                you "love me," hold on to them, but know that sooner, or later, the end will come. You
                                might anticipate that end ; might flee from the wrath to come, the wrath of your own
                                soul against those things that will make its misery when death says, Come ! Should you
                                desire still to come here, you may come as a probationary member. Thus doing, you run no
                                risk of losing anything you possess. You may gain that which will be of more value to
                                you than all the wisdom of this world, or all the gold of Ophir. If there be a work for
                                you to do as an individual, first, and then a work for others, I know of no law against
                                Love, nor against doing good. The whole world is to be redeemed. The harvests are ripe
                                unto the sickle. We have prayed the Lord of the Harvest to send more laborers into the
                                Field. If you are one of them, remember that whoso runneth a race, must observe the Laws
                                of the Race Course, or he will not be successful. Now you run when no organization has
                                sent you. You preach willingly, willfully, and have your reward ; a scattering Gospel.
                                In much Love, your friend,</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit world" TEIform="index"/>THE SPIRIT WORLD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Nye, Joseph W." TEIform="persName"/>JOSEPH W. NYE</byline><p TEIform="p"> The spirit world is not afar, As taught in ancient song and story; Alone beyond the farthest
                            star, Lies not the realm of bliss and glory. Around us here and everywhere Though not
                            discerned by mortal vision, Are "angels ever bright and fair," Celestial scenes and fields
                            elysian. They have not gone—those we call dead, And laid away with grief and weeping; As
                            softly by their mounds we tread, We say, "Not dead but sweetly sleeping." Nor yet asleep !
                            awake, they move Among us none the less, and ever Are drawing us by cords of love, Which
                            death no power hath to sever. Veiled by the flesh, we do not see The glory all around us
                            beaming! The veil will drop, the shadows flee Before the light forever streaming! Then will
                            all souls, from earthly thrall Released, forevermore be singing, And God at last be "all in
                            all," His love and peace to all hearts bringing. O, triumph grand of truth and love! Then
                            Faith beholds its full fruition, When all the earth and heaven above Will see fulfilled the
                            Saviour's mission ! Lynn, Mass,</p></div2><pb n="68" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sherman, Ezra" TEIform="index"/>Ezra Sherman</head><p TEIform="p">, at White Water Village, Ohio, Jan. 22. Age, 76 yrs. and 4 mo. (See page 57.)</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Deere, Elizabeth" TEIform="index"/>Elizabeth Deere</head><p TEIform="p">, at North Union, Ohio, Jan. 26. Age, 79 yrs., 9 mo. &amp; 25 days.</p></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>Juvenile</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Words, words, words!" TEIform="index"/>WORDS, WORDS, WORDS!</head><p TEIform="p">Much innocent gratification may be derived from getting a friend to read over the
                                following, and holding the dictionary on him,— so says the Argonaut,—and then devotes a
                                whole column to those who make merry over obscure sentences and illimitable words. We
                                begin midway in the story,—"These peremptory tripartite brethren arrived at Greenwich,
                                wishing to aggrandize themselves by indulging in exemplary relaxation, indicatory of
                                implacable detestation of integral tergiversation and exotic intrigue. They fraternized
                                with a phrenological har. lequin who was a connoisseur in mezzotint and falconry. This
                                piquant person was heaping contumely and scathing raillery on an amateur in jugular
                                recitative, who held that the Pharoahs of Asia were conversant with his theory that
                                morphine and quinine were exorcists of bronchitis. ******* Meanwhile an unctuous
                                orthoepist applied a homeopathic restorative to the retina of an objugatory spaniel. The
                                best speller stands at the head of the class.—Here is the name of a German orga.
                                nization. "The Winterthurerhandwerksburschenvorwartsgrupp. A small Welsh village is
                                named, Llanfairpwllgyllgogerpwllllandypilwgogo. Here is a passage from Mr. William
                                Crookes :—Dinitroaniline, chloroxynapthalic acid, which may be used for coloring wool an
                                intense red, and nitrophenylenediamine of chromatic brilliancy. An attractive volume is
                                entitled "Ontipericatametanaparbengedamphicribrationes." Argonaut</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hens" TEIform="index"/>Hens</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C." TEIform="persName"/>C.</byline><p TEIform="p">Hens lay eggs and keep them warm. The hen will have some chickens and when they get old
                                enough to go out the mother hen will take them out to walk in the fields and catch some
                                grasshoppers to eat. Then they go and dig in the dirt and get some bugs and worms to
                                eat. This is all I will say about hens now. </p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fable: the father and his sons" TEIform="index"/>FABLE: The Father and his Sons</head><p TEIform="p"> A father had a family of sons who were perpetually quarreling among themselves. When he
                                failed to heal their disputes by his exhortations, he determined to give them a
                                practical illustration of the evils of disunion and for this purpose he one day told
                                them to bring him a bundle of sticks. When they had done so, he placed the faggot into
                                the hands of each of them in succession, and ordered them to break it in pieces. They
                                each tried with all their strength, and were not able to do it. He then took the sticks
                                separately, one by one, and again put them into their hands, on which they broke them
                                easily. He then addressed them : My sons, if you are of one mind, and unite to assist
                                each other, you will be as this faggot, uninjured by all the attempts of your enemies ;
                                but if you are divided among yourselves, you will be broken as easily as these
                                sticks.—JEsop.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reed, Amy" TEIform="persName"/>Amy Reed</byline><p TEIform="p">Mount Lebanon, N. Y. My Dear Young Friend;—Your effort to comfort and cheer those whom
                                you esteem as parents, I much admire, and return many thanks for the lines addressed to
                                me. I am glad to witness any young person consecrating her life and strength to noble
                                purposes. I would encourage every resolve, knowing that an upright Christian life,
                                freely rewards the heart thus dedicated; not only in that land beyond the river, but
                                here in our present home, surrounded by loving friends whose affections prove truer than
                                any worldly ties. I am happy to know that yours is ODIE.A.I'HS. <pb n="69" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/>
                                SHAKER MANIFESTO. 69 the portion of the highly favored among earth's daughters. You have
                                a Christian home where the highest opportunities for developing the spirit are given.
                                Cherish, prize and use the means placed within your power, and your life will prove no
                                blank, hut victory over every opposing element, will bequeath you laurels worth wearing.
                                Remember, my young friend, the foundation of your strength lies in the blessing you draw
                                from those veteran friends of whom you have spoken with so much reverence ; and your
                                strict adherance to the principles which have made them glorious. I think of so many to
                                whom I would love to breath sentiments of affection ! I cannot individualize, but trust
                                you will be willing to express my love to all as you may have opportunity. I have much
                                to be thankful for, when I on" ly stop to count over my blessings, and the darkest night
                                always opens to the morning of a new day. Now to my dear sister C.—I would wish every
                                blessing, while I trust by a good, virtuous life here, to meet in one spirit in the
                                hereafter. In these wishes I remain your friend and sister, </p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, N. H. Jan. 1882" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, N. H. Jan. 1882</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Harry" TEIform="persName"/>Harry</byline><p TEIform="p"> Shaker Village, N. H. Jan. 1882 Dear Mother, Mary Ann C ;—I send my love to you. I am
                                pleased with those cards yoii sent me. When I am not in school I carry some wood to the
                                Cottage, where sister Mary and sister Marcia live. Sunday, I learn a Bible text to speak
                                in prayer meeting. Every Wednesday evening at 5 o'clock, the children have a singing
                                school. I learn a good deal and I like to go to school every day. Last summer I watched
                                the Honey Bees to see that the swarms did not fly away. Please give my love to sister
                                Tamar. Thank her kindly for my pretty card. My love to you, my mother. Good bye. From
                                your little boy. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="None preaches better than the ant, and she says nothing" TEIform="index"/>None preaches better than the ant, and she says nothing
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Franklin" TEIform="persName"/>Franklin</byline><p TEIform="p">None preaches better than the ant, and she says nothing.—.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>House-hold</head><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oatmeal in the household" TEIform="index"/>Oatmeal in the Household</head><p TEIform="p"> . In Great Britian children of all ranks are raised on an oatmeal diet alone, because it
                                causes them to grow strong and healthful, and not better food can possibly be found for
                                them. It is also quite as desirable for the student as the laborer, and for the delicate
                                lady as for the hard-working sister ; indeed, all classes would be greatly benefited by
                                its use, and dyspepsia, with all its manifold annoyances, can be kept at a safe
                                distance. Oatmeal is more substantial food, it is equal to beef or mutton, giving as
                                much or more mental vigor, while its great desideratum consists of one's not becoming
                                weary of it, for it is as welcome for breakfast or tea as is wheat or Graham bread. It
                                can be eaten with syrup and butter, as hasty pudding, or with cream and sugar, like
                                rice. It is especially good for young mothers upon whose nervous forces too great a
                                demand has been made, when they lose the equilibrium of the system and become depressed
                                and dispirited. Oatmeal requires to be cooked slowly, and the water should be boiling
                                hot when it is stirred in.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mustard plasters" TEIform="index"/>Mustard Plasters</head><p TEIform="p">.—By using syrup or molasses for mustard plasters, they will keep soft and flexible, arid
                                not dry up, and become ' hard, as when mixed with water. A thin paper or fine cloth
                                should come between the plaster and the skin. The strength of the plaster may be varied
                                by the addition of more or less flour.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jellies" TEIform="index"/>Jellies</head><p TEIform="p">, jams, etc., can be preserved perfectly from mold by cutting a piece of letterpaper just
                                the size of the top of the tumbler containing it, dipping in brandy or alcohol and
                                pressing it down close upon the jelly, the tumbler then closed securely Math a paper
                                gummed or pasted around the top.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For toothache" TEIform="index"/>For toothache</head><p TEIform="p"> caused by a cold, use a woolen cloth of several thicknesses wet with vinegar and put
                                over a hot brick or stone, with something thrown over the head to keep in all the
                            steam,</p></div3></div2><pb n="70" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Banner of light" TEIform="index"/>BANNER OF LIGHT</head><p TEIform="p">Enlarged from Eight to';Twelve Pages. BANNEROFllGHT; THE OLDEST AND LARGEST JOURNAL IN
                                THE WORLD DEVOTED^TO THE spiritual philosophy. I»»U13J&gt; WEEKLY At So, 9
                                Montgomery Place, Boston, Mass, COLBY &amp; RICH, Puitlialievw anil Proprietors.
                                Isaac'B. Rich.....Business Manager, IjItthbr Colby.....Editor, John W. Day.....Assistant
                                Editor, Aided by a large corps of able writers. THE BANNER is a first class "Family
                                Newspaper of twelve pages—containing sixty columns of INTERESTING AND INSTRUCTfYE
                                READING—CinbraCing A. LITERARY DEPARTMENT, REPORTS OF SPIRITUAL LECTURES, ORIGINAL
                                ESSAYS—Upon Spiritual, Philosophical and Scientific Subjects, EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT,
                                SPIRIT-MESSAGE DEPARTMENT, and CONTRIBUTIONS by the most talented writers in the_world,
                                etc., etc. TERMS OF SUBSCRIPTION, IN ADVANCE: DPer Year......... $3.00 Six
                                Months........1.5O Three Months.......75 Postage Free, In remitting by mail, a Post
                                Office Money-Order on Boston, or a Draft on a Bank or Banking- House in Boston of New
                                York City, payable to the order of Colby &amp; Rich, is preferable to Bank Notes.
                                Our patrons can remit us the fractional part of a dollar 4 inpostage stamps—one*'and
                                twos preferred. Advertisements published at twenty cents per line for the first, and
                                fifteen cents per line for each subsequent insertion. Subscrip ions discontinued at the
                                expiration of the time paid for. t£g*Specimen copies sent free. c oTb 7^~rTc h Publish
                                and keep for sale at Wholesale and Retail a complete assortment of Spiritual,
                                Progressive, Reformatory, and Miscellaneous Books. Among the authors are Andrew Jackson
                                Davis, Hon. Robert Dale Owen, Dr. James M. Peebles, Henry C. Wright, Giles B. Stebbins,
                                D. D. Home, T. R. Hazard, William Denton, Rev. M. B. Craven, Judge J. W. Edmonds Prof.
                                S. B. Brittan, Allen Putnam,Epes Sargent, W. F. Evans, Kersey Graves, A. B. Child, P. B.
                                Randolph, Warren S. Barlow, J. O. Barret, Mrs. Emma Hardinge Britten, Miss. Lizzie
                                Doten, Mrs. Maria. M. King-, etc. Any Book published in England or America, not out of
                                print, will be sent by mall or express. WCataloguesof Books l?ul&gt;lislvecL and for
                                Saleby Colby «fc H/ioli sent free. The following are among the contents of the February
                                number of The Homiletic Monthly : Sermonic :—The Transfiguration—a Communion Sermon, by
                                Charles Gerok, D. D , translated from the German ; Opposition to the Truth, by John
                                Hall, D. D. Christ's Statements as to the Fact and Eternity of Future Punishment—a
                                Discourse to Young Men, by S. V. Leech, D. D.; Parental Kesponsibility, by W. F. V.
                                Bartlett, D. D. What is your Age? by Rev. W. H. Luckenbach; Is Giving a Help or
                                Hindrance? by Justin D. Fulton^ D. D.; God the Chief Object of Search, by B. M. Palmer,
                                D. D. ; The Perfectness of the Character of Jesus, by T. H. Skinner, D. D.; Young Men's
                                Service: An Important Question Answered, by Edward P. Ingersoll, D. D.; Vicious Bondage,
                                by Herrick Johnson, D. D.. Beside the above this number contains a Lecture to Students,
                                by Spurgeon ; Homiletic Studies in the Book of Hebrews, by Rev. D.C Hughes ; Thoughts on
                                Suggestive Themes, by C. S. Robinson, D. D. ; Themes from Revivalists of Yesterday and
                                Today, by Rev. G. W. Hervey; The Power of Persuasive Speech, by Prof. E. P. Thwing. Then
                                there are a number of articles under Sermonic Criticism, Preachers Exchanging Views, and
                                Living Issues for Pulpit Treatment. A United Effort Against Polygamy is a note-worthy
                                appeal to the Clergy to assist in arousing public opinion against the crime of Polygamy.
                                The present number of this Monthly will prove of more than usual interest to all
                                students of the Bible. Price, single number, 25 cents; per. year, $2.50. I. K. Funk
                                &amp; Co., 10 &amp; 12 Dey St., New York. RIP ~VJ±N WINKLE. This, perhaps the
                                most famous, as it is one of the most charming sketches which American literature has
                                produced, gives the title to a very beautiful and remarkably cheap little volume just
                                issued by the Useful Knowledge Publishing Co., New York. The volume comprises all the
                                most interesting articles usually included in "The Sketch Book" of Washington Irving. It
                                contains 240 pages beautiful type, excellent paper, press work and extra cloth binding,
                                and is sold for only 20 cents, or by mail, 25 cents ! This is the second volume
                                published under the programme of the Literary "Rebellion." It certainly surpasses both
                                in quality and cheapness any of the famous books of the Literary "Revolution" The
                                reading public certainly appreciate the work of Mr. Alden, whose skill and energy will
                                be recognized in this new enterprise. The Company announce as in press, uniform with Rip
                                Van Winkle, Green's Large History of the English People, in 5 volumes, $1.50, Carlyle's
                                French Revolution, 2 vols, 70 cents, Creasy's Fifteen Decisive Battles, 35 cents and
                                Schiller's History of the Thirty Years War, 35 cents. These same four famous histories
                                are also to be issued all in one 'volume, "model octavo," for the amazingly low price of
                                $1.25. Specimen pages and catalogue will be sent on receipt of postal card by the
                                publishers, the Useful Knowledge Publishing Company, 162 William Street, New York.</p></div3></div2><pb n="71" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Select</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Human heartlessness" TEIform="index"/>HUMAN HEArRTLESSNESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dike, V." TEIform="persName"/>V. Dike</byline><p TEIform="p">Alas ! the heartlessness of which human nature is capable. Some in gluttony and
                                drunkenness are endeavoring to still the voice of a reproving conscience, are striving
                                by brutalizing their nature, to obliterate the memory of past crimes; or worse still,
                                are laboring to produce that fiendishness of spirit which actually delights in dwelling
                                upon the revolting scenes of former iniquities. Having enlisted soul and body in the
                                service of Satan, they attempt to silence the whisperings of God in the soul, so that
                                they may sin henceforth unrebuked. The rich and the gay, in lordly palaces or in gaily
                                decorated saloons, are eating and drinking, are revelling and rioting, while the world's
                                unfortunates are pining away in cellars and garrets, unknown, unrelieved, unpitied. The
                                piteous wail of anguish, deep-drawn sigh which only hopeless poverty can heave, the tear
                                of grief which in midnight solitude scalds the pallid cheek, how often are they unheeded
                                ! In homes of heartless wealth and in halls of gayety and frivolity the feast and the
                                dance go on, while near by in lonely agony heart-strings are breaking, penury's dark
                                night is deepening, anguish is crushing its helpless victims. Man's forgetfulness of man
                                seems incomprehensible. The proximity of joy and sorrow, of wealth and poverty, of hope
                                and despair, how inexplicable ! The wail of unrelieved suffering and the songs of joyous
                                festivity are wafted heavenward on the same breeze. The shouts of drunken revelry and
                                the prayer of penitence ascend side by side. Thus everywhere, joy and feasting above,
                                wretchedness and starvation beneath; the one piteously petitioning for relief, the other
                                stoically indifferent to human suffering,- </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Useless studies for girls" TEIform="index"/>USELESS STUDIES FOR GIRLS</head><p TEIform="p">The other day a young girl of our acquaintance, who is pursuing a selected course of
                                study in one of the collegiate institutions of the city, was examining the printed
                                curriculum with reference to deciding what study she should take up next term. While
                                consulting about the matter she read over the long list of text-books on science,
                                language, literature and mathematics, when suddenly she exclaimed, "I'll tell you what I
                                would like to study— I would like to study medicine. I don't mean that I want to be a
                                physician and practise, but to know what to do at home if anybody is sick or anything
                                happens. I am sure that it would be more useful to me than"—and she turned to the
                                prescribed course of study— "than spherical trigonometry and navigation? But we can't
                                run for a doctor every time anybody sneezes or coughs, and I would like to know what to
                                do for any one who is a little sick " Here is a matter concerning which young women need
                                some simple but careful instruction. But who gives them any? As daughters in the family,
                                they can repeat the dates of the Grecian and Roman wars, work out aa intricate problem
                                in algebra, and give the technical names of all the bones in the body; but if the baby
                                brother left in their charge burns his hand or is seized with croup, how many of them
                                know the best thing to do while waiting for the doctor? And when, as wives and mothers,
                                the duties of life increase, how many of them have any practical knowledge which will
                                help them to meet calmly and intelligently the every-day experience of accidents and
                                illness which are inevitable in every family?—Harper's Bazar.</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In years gone by it so happened that John Lyon and his sister Lucy..." TEIform="index"/>In years gone by it so happened that John Lyon and his sister Lucy...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> In years gone by it so happened that John Lyon and his sister Lucy, in company with
                                others, made a visit to the society at N. Before the day of their arrival Br. JohnF.
                                asked the Elder if the family had not better be notified that a lion and lioness were to
                                pass through the village that day. Indeed not, said the Elder, I am surprised that you
                                should suggest such a thing,—to turn the attention of all the family to see two wild
                                animals. Well, said Br. John, I thought it might interest the family as it will only be
                                Elder John Lyon and his sister Lucy Lyon from the state of N. H.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The flitting of thoughts is like the dancing of sunbeams" TEIform="index"/>The flitting of thoughts is like the dancing of sunbeams
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The flitting of thoughts is like the dancing of sunbeams.</p></div3></div2><pb n="72" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fold of Christ" TEIform="index"/>FOLD OF CHRIST</head><p TEIform="p">Canterbury, N. H. Shelter'd in the fold of Christ, Blessed is thy portion to be fashioned by
                            his life, For thy sacred ' mission. Count no sacrifices great, Call no act unworthy Which
                            the spirit bids thee make. For a claim so holy.</p></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sweet is the peace..." TEIform="index"/>Sweet is the peace...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C Hampton</byline><p TEIform="p"> Union VILLAGE, Ohio. Sweet is the peace of the spirit resigned,—Giving to good every power
                            of the mind; Will and affection surrender to God, Moving in charity, at home and abroad. In
                            this love all is serene, Angel contentment, Love's brightest sheen Beams in the calm sky of
                            the pure; Those who the yoke of Christ will endure.</p></div2><pb id="p29" TEIform="pb"/><!-- 
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>