<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0112" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><date value="18711201" TEIform="date">December 1871</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">89-96</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="89" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">" I WILL SHAKE ALL NATIONS, AND THE DESIRE OP ALL NATIONS SHALL COME ; AND I WILL FILL THIS HOUSE
                        WITH GLORY, SAITH THE LORD." Published Monthly, by, and under the direction of the Mt. Lebanon
                        Bishopric, Vol. I. SHAKERS, ALBANY CO., N. Y., DECEMBER, 1871. No. 12.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love and fire" TEIform="index"/>Love and Fire</head><p TEIform="p">Religious revivals are the resultant of the love of God toward humanity. Love is fire, in its
                            ultimate incarnated. "God is love ;" and this makes God a consuming fire through jealousy. "
                            I am a jealous God," hating idolatry and adultery above all things, and always operating to
                            destroy the idols as Abraham destroyed the images of gods and goddesses, which his father
                            made his living by creating. Christendom is "full of idols;" consequently, when the
                            righteous in a city pray to God, as Lot did in Sodom, they are praying for the destruction
                            of that city, unless timely repentance—a turning from idolatry—averts it. As Jefferson
                            affirms, all great cities are ike caucers of the nation ; being produced by false organic
                            laws, permitting the monopoly of life elements, and destroying the taste of the people for
                            rural pursuits—agriculture in its various branches—it is merely a matter of time when such a
                            city as London will be destroyed, and by what agency. We may hope that it will be through
                            the soil of England being returned to its owners, the people; and that the soil will allure
                            the people from London, leaving it, like Babylon, to "the owls and bitterns ;" for the
                            prophecy of desolation upon that city is as applicable to all cities as it was to Babylon.
                            The fact that a certain city is destroyed, does not prove that its wickedness exceeded
                            "above all other cities," but that it was more ripe, and that the love of God was towards it
                            in an especial manner; and that as it has perished, so likewise will all other cities
                            perish, unless their inhabitants repent. Under the law of " the co-relation of forces,'' the
                            love of God may be transformed into material fire, sweeping away, as in a moment, the
                            accumulated labors of many generations, who had not wrought in God sufficient to preserve "
                            their works." Not that there was no good—no religion— nor yet that there was no natural fire
                            to begin the conflagration at Chicago. In Rev. 9:23, " Moses and Aaron went into the
                            tabernacle of the congregation, and came out and blessed the people, and the glory of the
                            Lord appeared unto all the people, and there came a fire out from before the Lord and
                            consumed upon the altar the burnt offering and the fat, which when all the people saw, they
                            shouted and fell on their faces." In this case, there was no physical fire as a nucleus; but
                            when "Nadab and Abhiu, the sons of Aaron, took either of them his censer and put fire
                            therein, and put incense thereon, and thus offered strange fire before the Lord—" natural
                            fire"—which he commanded them not, " there went out fire from the Lord, and devoured them,
                            and they died before the Lord." They lacked faith as spiritualists. How far, and to what
                            extent, do the modern priesthood offer strange fire, when they offer their gifts—sparks of
                            their own kindling—eloquent prayers, and learned essays—fires of ambition, impelled by the
                            love of self—in place of the true spiritual gifts of the primitive church ? Will they not,
                            one of these days, originate a conflagration that will burn up them and their works ? In 1st
                            Kings, 18:34, Elijah said to the prophets of Baal, "Call ye on the name of your gods, and I
                            will call upon the Lord; and the god that answereth by fire, let him be God; and all the
                            people answered and said : it is well spoken." " They, the priests of Baal, took the bullock
                            which was given to them, and dressed it, and called on the name of Baal from morning till
                            noon, saying, 0 Baal, hear us ! But there was no voice, nor any that answered; and Elijah
                            mocked them, saying : Cry aloud ; for he is a god; either he is talking, or he is pursuing,
                            or he is on a journey, or peradventure he sleepeth, and must be awaked. And they cried
                            aloud, and cut themselves with knives as was their manner, till the blood gushed out, but
                            with no avail. When it came Elijah's turn, they filled four barrels with water three several
                            times, and poured it upon the burnt sacrifice and the wood, and the fire of the Lord fell,
                            and not only consumed the burnt sacrifice, but, as in Chicago, it burnt " the wood, and the
                            stones, and the dust, and licked up the water that was in the trench." And the people said :
                            " The Lord, he is the God; the Lord, he is the God;" and the unspiritual prophets were
                            themselves destroyed. This descent of fire frequently occurred during the his- tory of the
                            Jewish nation. This fire would not injure the righteous any more than water would injure
                            fish. "Who amongst us," Isaiah inquired, " will dwell with the devouring fire ? Who shall
                            dwell with everlasting burnings? The Lord descended upon Mount Sinai in fire, and the people
                            were afraid because of the fire, and said: Let us not see this great fire any more." In
                            Numbers, 35, after the earth had swallowed up the houses and all the men that pertained unto
                            Cova, with their goods, " there came out fire from the Lord and consumed the two hundred and
                            fifty men that offered incense." But, of all the prophets of Israel, none exceeded Elijah as
                            a medium of spiritual power over the material elements. 2 Kings i: The king sent a captain
                            and fifty men, to bring Elijah down from the top of a hill on which he sat. Approaching, the
                            captain said (mockingly), " Thou man of God, the king hath said come down;" and Elijah
                            answered: If I be a man of God, then let fire come down from heaven, and consume thee and
                            thy fifty; and there came down fire from heaven, and consumed him and his fifty. And when a
                            second captain and fifty was sent, being a little afraid, he said: "0 man of God, thus hath
                            the king said: ' Come down quickly.' " Again the prophet called for fire to consume them,
                            and the fire of God came down from heaven and consumed him and his fifty. And the captain of
                            the third fifty was sent, and went up, and, like the Egyptians, being thoroughly converted
                            to a belief in Spiritualism, fell on his knees before Elijah, and besought him, and said to
                            him, "0 man of God, I pray thee let my life, and the life of these fifty, thy servants, be
                            precious in thy sight. Behold there came fire down from heaven and burnt up the two captains
                            of the former fifties, with their fifties, therefore let my life be precious in thy sight."
                            This humble and candid confession showed that the fire of the Lord was going back from
                            whence it came, towards the interior of things. It had burnt up unbelief in the <pb n="90" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 9O THE S H .A. K E H . captain's soul, and become again a spiritual fire of
                            faith and zeal towards God. The angel of the Lord said unto Elijah, " Go down with him." The
                            fire had reached the soul of the king also; and " Elijah said to him : Thou hast sent
                            messages to inquire of Baal-Zebub, the god of Ekron ; therefore thou shalt not come down off
                            that ted on which thou art gone up, but shalt surely die. So the king died, and Elijah was
                            not injured. And Elijah went up by a whirlwind into heaven," from whence the fire came. It
                            was not his body that went up, but his soul and spirit that had already ascended into the
                            heaven—the paradise of the Jews. Thus did Elijah subdue military power by Spiritualism,
                            according to the true design of the Mosaic dispensation, where the war power was transferred
                            from the physical to the lower sphere of the spiritual world. It is on this wise that war
                            will be abolished, and the millenium inaugurated, in which the nations shall cease to learn
                            and practice it any more. In that epoch, the male and female will be equally represented in
                            the earthly government, which will become the image of the government of the universe. War
                            Raised One Step Higher. The Christ Spirit, with which Jesus was baptized, converted and
                            convicted him first from the Jewish plan of war — the application of physical force — by
                            means of which, he. cleansed the temple of the commercial people who were trading and
                            trafficking under a cloak of religion, calling them " thieves and robbers," who were
                            desecrating the house of prayer. This was one step upwards. " The zeal of the Lord's house
                            had eaten him up." Further travail prepared him for another step; so that when a village of
                            the Samaritans refused to receive him and his disciples, because his face was set as though
                            he would go to Jerusalem, with whose inhabitants they held no social communion, James and
                            John said: "Lord, wilt thou command fire to come down from heaven, and consume them, even as
                            Elias did?" Jesus turned and rebuked them, and said : " Ye know not what manner of spirit ye
                            are of," in respect to the spirit and practice of war. Ye are good Jews, after the pattern
                            of Elijah; but are not yet converted to Christianity, which will save you from destroying
                            your enemies even by spiritual agencies, and even when they arc heretics, and have refused
                            to receive and entertain the Son of Man, havinoturned their backs upon the kingdom of
                            heaven, which had come nigh unto them. "For the Son of Man has not come to destroy men's
                            lives, but to save them, both body and soul, provided they will obey the truth." This
                            obedience will never be secured, except through a baptism of fire and love, which shall
                            create, as at pentecost, a genuine spiritualistic, religious revival.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker iconoclasm" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Iconoclasm</head><p TEIform="p">While millions are seeking their heavens in the indulgences of perverted passions, »e are
                            called to work ours out by severe chastisement of our affections for sinful lusts—by rigid
                            self-denial to all that engenders worldly ambition or selfish aggrandizement. After
                            thousands of years' activity in the habitual practices of war, marriage, private property;
                            of carnal desires, and the gratification of those desires by our ancestors; we are commanded
                            to turnback the tide of nature, and build the foundations of a new structure, that
                            condescends not to the use of a single material, good nor bad, that constitutes the bulwarks
                            of the old order of life! Who, then, wonders at our persecution ? Who is surprised at the
                            few who bear the ordeal and comply with the command ? Or who wonders at the worldly cry of
                            the failure of Shakerism, and the desires that it should fail, while it is making such
                            devastation with worldly institutions? It has already proved itself a successful re-
                            generator; and what has been done by it, can with it be accomplished again. *</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True wealth" TEIform="index"/>True Wealth</head><p TEIform="p">Be my mind a sacred treasury, Stored with gems and diamonds blight, Where no dross shall ever
                            gather, That would dim their lustrous light. Garnered there the wealth of knowledge, Truth
                            and Wisdom's golden sheaves, Kichest fruits and fragrant flowers, Not alone life's fading
                            leaves. Walls of sapphire form the chambers, By eternal Goodness made, I will fill this
                            heavenly structure With the sunsnine. not the shade. I will hang it round with pictures,
                            That shall give me joy to see, Not the imagery of demons, That would haunt and follow me.
                            Like the ghosts in ancient story, Protean forms of passions base, Sordid loves, and gross
                            desires— These the temple would deface. Innocence and pure affection, Deeds in consecration
                            wrought, Holy thoughts and aspirations, To this temple shall be brought. Germs of good my
                            soul shall cherish, Spurn the false and jyrize the true, Look beyond the things that
                            perish., Where bright glories rise to view. Brighter now appears the prospect, And the angel
                            life is mine ; Growth and progress are eternal, In the spheres of truth divine.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha" TEIform="persName"/>Martha Andebson, Mt. L.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian equality" TEIform="index"/>Christian Equality</head><p TEIform="p">" Ye are all brethren.'' There is nothing in the teaching of Jesus Christ more apparent than
                            the thorough and absolute change he purposed to effect in the lives of all those who should
                            become his disciples. This change had reference not only to the individual character of
                            each, but also to the relations they were to sustain toward each other as a community of
                            believers. He taught not only humility, in contradistinction to pride and vanity;
                            gentleness, in opposition to an overbearing spirit; faith and patience, as arrayed against
                            distrust and heart-consuming anxiety ; love to God and the neighbor instead of hatred; but a
                            change in the fundamental condition of Society. In it there was to be neither noble nor
                            plebeian, rich nor poor, bond nor free, as they had hitherto existed in all human societies,
                            not excepting that established by Moses. Not only were these distinctions to lind no place
                            in the community of his followers, but even the titles, which were wont to foster the pride
                            of those installed into any office among men, were to be discarded. " Be ye not called
                            Rabbi, or Teacher, for one is your Teacher; call no man your Father upon earth, for one is
                            your Father." There is but one simple relation to be sustained among all the disciples of
                            Christ, that of brethren, the children of one common, divine parentage. This teaching is
                            thoroughly radical, and aims to eradicate a disposition that has had a controlling inlluence
                            upon mankind for ages upon ages—that of exalting one's self at the expense of others. It is
                            not surprising that it has pro duced so little effect comparatively in the world, nor is it
                            a cause of discouragement to one who has studied the Divine method of working, that this
                            doctrine was so soon abandoned by many of the professed teachers of Christ's religion ; that
                            the head of one of the divisions into which the church was split should be stjied Papa,
                            Pope, or Feather; that the chief of another division should be called Patriarch, or Chief
                            Father; and that the teachers of other divisions should assume or accept the title of
                            Doctor, which is simply another term for Rabbi. The Infinite has an eternity in which to
                            accomplish his plans. Nothing else was to be expected, when the professed disciples of
                            Christ discarded his teachings in this respect, but that they should seek to justify their
                            conduct; nor is it a matter of wonder that those who disallow his authority altogether
                            should style him fanatic, because of his extreme doctrines. Chateaubriand, the celebrated
                            defender of '• the Church " against the infidels o f his day, conscious that Jesus had
                            uttered some radical sayings respecting equality, says : " The Christian religion estab-
                            lishes the doctrine of moral equality, the only kind which can be preached without
                            overthrowing the world." That is, to give his own explanation, Christian priests can remind
                            the great ones of earth that they are made of no nobler dust than the plebeian,- which truth
                            the priests of ancient Paganism did not dare to utter in the ears of a Nero or a Tiberias.
                            This wonderful gain, then, has been made by Christianity over Paganism ! To preach more than
                            this would be to overthrow the world ! But Christian equality, whenever practiced, does
                            overthrow the world, and that is the very design of it. It banishes at once and forever all
                            those distinctions created and fostered by human pride, whether of ruler and subject,
                            nobleman and vassal, or clergy and laity. It discards not only the secular titles, as they
                            are called, of Emperor, King, Duke, etc., but ecclesiastical as well—Sovereign Pontiff", My
                            Lord the Archbishop, or Bishop, being as open to Christ's reprehension as any other title.
                            It puts an end to that selfish abuse of God's gifts, by which a few appropriate to
                            themselves that which belongs to the many. It diffuses an abundance of everything needful
                            among all without distinction. It establishes not merely what the French writer styled "
                            moral equality," which still leaves the haughtiness of the haughty undisturbed; allows every
                            distinction in Society which human pride has <pb n="91" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 91 devised,
                            together with every -display in dress, equipage and residence that tends to keep up those
                            distinctions, but also actual equality, bringing the proud down to the position they should
                            occupy, and raising the degraded to a condition in which they may enjoy God's greatest
                            blessings. It makes short work %itk everything that enkindles wars or engenders strife of
                            any kind, removing all the causes that lead to them. It strikes a deadly blow at all
                            pleasure, passions and lusts, whose tendency is to weaken and destroy the physical, intel-
                            lectual and spiritual man, and to introduce into the world of God's creation whatever causes
                            hatred, divisions, and moral disturbances. It not only brings society upon a level, but
                            gives to the individual subject of it perpetual quiet of soul. " If makes the rough paths of
                            peevish nature even, And opens in each breast a little heaven." Christian equalitjr,
                            therefore, tends to overthrow both the great world that exists in the form of human tyranny
                            and slavery, of inequality in wealth and privileges everywhere prevalent, and the world of
                            pride, ignorance, passion, lust, envy and hatred, and every ignoble thing that exists in the
                            individual breast. In overthrowing these, however, it does not leave society in a state of
                            chaos, nor the individual to float rudderless over the dark ocean. Gradually it brings order
                            out of confusion, dispels the darkness of the mental horizon, brings in the dawn with its
                            resplendent colors, and ultimately diffuses everywhere the heart-cheering and invigorating
                            light of the perfect day. When the former heaven and earth have passed away, the Sons of God
                            chant the anthem that celebrates the creation of the new; they sing of peace and love, of
                            order, equality, and perpetual unanimity. Their melody inspires and fills the souls of all
                            who constitute the family of heaven.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life in God" TEIform="index"/>Life in God</head><p TEIform="p">The First Great Cause has deeply implanted in human souls the laws of righteousness, for the
                            government of his children in their conduct towards each other; and in the revelation of His
                            Divine will, these laws in the mind are confirmed. The Saviour said: "Whatsoever ye would
                            that men should do unto you, do ye even so unto them." His whole life was a dedication to
                            the laws of love and divine justice. In the laws of life, there is a fitness, an ap-
                            propriateness in human action; we will call this fitness Justice. Human beings feel that
                            they are entitled to be treated justly in all the transactions of life. Every one feels that
                            he or she has an inherent right to the bounties of a kind Providence, and cannot feel
                            satisfied when any of these rights are withheld or denied. Integrity in man will
                            scrupulously allow all these rights to a fellow being ; not only allow, but bestow kind acts
                            to aid his fellow man. In the wide domain of commerce, the man of integrity will make known
                            the quality, age and condition of his produce, and regard in weight and measurement the same
                            honest}7'. Every citizen should feel safety in person, character and property; uncertainty
                            in these destroys our happiness. Each man should feel a concern for the life, character and
                            property of his fellow man, not only to guard against casualties, but to render, in sickness
                            or affliction, a kind and willing assistance. Common prudence should teach that we are all
                            human beings, and, as such, may need the same kind attention; and that the human heart, full
                            and running over, will be ready and desirous, under these generous impulses, to render back
                            the measure more than full. The gifted and fortunate should voluntarily be guardians for
                            their less-gifted and unfortunate fellow beings, and, in kindness, counsel tfaem, show them,
                            entreat them; for they lack understanding of the conditions, proprieties, duties and dangers
                            of life. Suffering mortality is beseeching, and must not be turned away empty. 0. for the
                            compassion of the Christ spirit! To the young man or woman in nature, whose life is to begin
                            as the future father or mother, these inquiries should arise: Do I start with integrity in
                            every purpose and design in this highest, earthly prerogative, to do the will of my heavenly
                            parents, in perpetuating my likeness and representative in time ? Or, am I looking forward
                            to scenes of voluptuousness, irrespective of my call, obligations, or consequences ? Do I
                            consider that life and death are set before me, and that I am accountable for the use of my
                            endowments and for the consequent good or evil that may arise in my connection, through
                            time, and for ages to come ? In the matrimonial union you have pledged yourselves to verity
                            and integrity without reserve; and in keeping this solemn declaration in accordance with the
                            laws of nature, depends your future fruitfulness and blessing. In the family relation must
                            be instituted good government; faithful obedience for the child, and religious, rational
                            instruction for youth, all conducted in the spirit of the true Christian. A sacred
                            veneration for God and His divine attribute, Truth, should be deeply planted in the juvenile
                            mind. In the family mansion is laid the foundation of future government of state and nation
                            ; may it be laid on the basis of truth and obedience to law and order, for God works through
                            these principles for the salvation of nations. Let us examine the inmost recesses of
                            thought, for in the laboratory of the mind are manufactured the intentions, designs and
                            consummations of human existence.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Redmon, William" TEIform="persName"/>Wm. Redmon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Are the shakers ascetics?" TEIform="index"/>Are the Shakers Ascetics?</head><p TEIform="p">In all ages, mankind have felt the desire to appease an offended Deity ; for men have erred
                            since the early days of earth's history, and consequently felt the sting of remorse and
                            unhappiness, the natural result of violating God's laws. And as most men will relent and
                            forgive an injury, when approached humbly and sorrowfully by the offending party, so men, in
                            their short-sighted conception of the Eternal, have thought to propitiate Him, and regain
                            their own peace of mind, by vows and sacrifices, or the observance of an ascetic life.
                            Others, again, stimulated, doubtless, by a pious longing after holiness and purity, proposed
                            to subdue the inherent inclination to evil, and the inordinate desires of their minds, by
                            seclusion, fasting, the recitation of long prayers, bodily torments, and the abjuration of
                            every comfort or innocent pleasure! They are called Ascetics —persons who, secluded from the
                            world, live a rigid and austere life, and employ their time mostly in devotions and
                            mortifications. Are the Shakers Ascetics ? This epithet is not uncommonly applied. Let us
                            look at their everyday life, and thereby see whether the name " Ascetics " property belongs
                            to them. Do they live secluded from the world? Decidedly they do, in a certain sense. They
                            claim to live in retirement from the world, in a life of self-discipline and preparation for
                            a future state. There are no high, cloister walls around their buildings, and no dark courts
                            lead to their dwellings ; but God's bright sunlight is invited everywhere, to cheer with its
                            rays, this simple and unassuming people. The visitor or traveler will not find the
                            forbidding words, No admittance," written on any of their gates or doors, but meets with a
                            kind and hearty welcome, with an invitation to examine and judge for himself; while hardly a
                            day passes by in which hundreds of strangers do not come through their farms and villages.
                            The hermits of old retired from the world, and buried themselves in the inaccessible
                            wilderness, and many a weary and sad heart now, will retire behind the gloomy walls of a
                            cloister. They were and are Ascetics. Are Shakers? They retire from the wrorld so far as not
                            to take part in political movements, which certainly tend to abstract the mind from higher
                            and purer pursuits ; nor in the usual pleasures of the world —the principles that make the
                            world (see John ii. 15, 16)—considering them as not consistent with a life devoted to
                            spiritual progress. They have separated from the principles of the world, but do not live in
                            seclusion; they shun the evils of the world, and all which leads to worldliness, but do not
                            shun its children, in whose souls are the images of God ; they come in contact with those
                            who are of the world, but live not according to the demands of the world—are they,
                            therefore, Ascetics ? Is their life rigid and austere ? It may appear so to the egotist or
                            the devotee of pleasure, but not to the philosopher or Christian. The ancient axiom, " The
                            fewer wants, the more happiness," is still true. All the riches in the world will never
                            suffice to supply the wants of a depraved appetite, for every sensual gratifi- cation
                            excites a desire for new indulgences of a more refined kind, and in proportion to their
                            fulfilment, the passion demands those that are more extensive and luxurious. "Shakers," or "
                            Believers," enjoy the products of nature, with which they are amply supplied, and use all
                            the comforts and conveniences which the fruits of their industry permit. They live not in
                            luxury, but in comfort; not in extravagance, but in sufficiency. And is their manual labor
                            hardship ? Labor is pleasure, if performed moderately, and for a good purpose; it has a
                            salutary effect upon body and mind, and no one among them is required to work beyond his
                            capabilities. An evidence that their daily life is far from being austere, is afforded by
                            their records of mortality, which prove a greater longevity among the Shakers than any other
                            class of people. True piety will not show a solemn, Puritanic <pb n="92" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER. countenance, but will enjoy a hearty laugh, a mirthful and agreeable conversation.
                            And let any visitor call at a Shaker village, and he will not meet many faces of a
                            forbidding or downcast aspect, but the peace within will show itself in the serene and happy
                            countenances of those who have devoted their lives to purity and soul-development, and who
                            feel that they are at peace with God, and beloved by their companions. Do Shakers employ
                            their time mostly in devotions and mortifications ? Their devotional formalities occupy a
                            very small portion of the day, for labor is prayer, and useful occupation more acceptable in
                            the sight of heaven than the recital of long and meaningless prayers. But they most
                            emphatically claim that their lives are spent in mortification, not of the body, but of the
                            carnal will. " Know thyself," was written, as the essence of wisdom, on the portals of the
                            temple of Ephesus; and " Know thyself," and "Conquer thyself," is written now on the
                            standard of Believers. To subdue themselves, and even eradicate that which "the still small
                            voice" condemns, and to restore the soul to its native purity, as a fi-t emblem of its
                            Maker—to replace in their minds the spiritual instead of the sensual, is their aim and daily
                            labor. Can such an end be reached without a struggle ? without mortification ? God alone
                            knows the fierce combat that has raged in many a soul aspiring after holiness; and often He
                            alone has seen the silent tears, and heard the suppressed sobs of many a weary traveler
                            towards His kingdom of eternal rest; and He alone knows the agony whieh the demand, "Conquer
                            thyself," often extorts. And were it not for His help, who would succeed ? But success is
                            certain. His help, and the observance of the eternal truths established in the Church of
                            Christ's Second Appearing, will enable every soul to conquer the enemy within, and then the
                            state of happiness will commence, and the soul will find heaven on earth. Then the words of
                            Christ will be fulfilled ; " Every one that hath forsaken houses, or brethren, or sisters,
                            or father, or mother, or wife, or children, or lands for my name's sake, shall receive a
                            hundred fold, and shall inherit ever- lasting life," and peace, comfort and bliss will dwell
                            in abundance in the soul, which will then receive a forshadowing of the eternal, heavenly
                            joys. There cannot be victory without a combat, nor holiness without struggles and
                            mortifications of the carnal mind. Ascetics mortify the body; Shakers mortify the
                            principalities of evil. But let Shakers be called Ascetics, or fanatics, or a deluded
                            people—it will not alter the truth. There is only one way to salvation, and every soul, at
                            some period of its existence, either in this world or in the world to come, will
                            havetoenterit—the way that Jesus taught in the words : " Forsake all, and follow me." God
                            speed the day when the light from above will shine on repentant and sorrowstricken souls ;
                            when His angels will point out to an anxious and burdened multitude the true and only way of
                            salvation from evil: Confessing and forsaking sin, and living alife of purity, humility, and
                            unselfishness !</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wager, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. Wager. Union Village, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Knell of the dying year" TEIform="index"/>The Knell of the Dying Year</head><p TEIform="p">Hark ! what is that low, murihrtHng sound, That faintly falls upon the ear? So distant, yet
                            it jars the ground,— Hush ! 'tis the knell of the dying year. ; All nature seems to hear the
                            toll, The tempests pause in their wild career, E'er they have reached their destined goal,
                            And list to the knell of the dying year. The stately trees of the forest bend To catch the
                            sound, and, appalled with fear, A murmuring dirge in their sorrow lend, To bewail the knell
                            of the dying year. The stars look down from the murky sky, Through a veil of clouds their
                            sad faces appear, And the moon, enmantled with mists on high, Seems to weep the knell of the
                            dying year. And wilt thon not join in the solemn scene O, man ! while thy death toll
                            approaches near? And would'st thon listen with downcast mien, To the sorrow ful knell of the
                            dying year ? " Let thy footsteps tread pure virtue's way, And thou shalt never shed a tear
                            "— A voice to my spirit seems to say— " As thou nearest the knell of the dying year.'1</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, William" TEIform="persName"/>WILLIAM CALVER</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Charity" TEIform="index"/>Charity</head><p TEIform="p">Charity has been defined to be a principle which leads us to make use of the best means to
                            bring about the best results. St. Paul said that " charity rejoicethin the truth." All the
                            Christian virtues and graces, which adorn the character of the good, harmonize; they never
                            are antagc-nistical. If " charity rejoiceth in the truth," it also rejoices in justice and
                            righteousness, as well as in mercy and kindness; and as all these harmonize, the greatest
                            charity to any soul is to hold it to strict justice, and not to indulge it in any wrong,
                            because, " he that doeth wrong shall suffer for the wrong he doeth," Indulgence, instead of
                            being charity, is injustice and wrong to the very individual to whom it is extended, and in
                            a social point of view, indulgence to one is injustice to the whole community. This
                            individual indulgence being intrinsically unjust, it can never promote harmony, peace, nor
                            righteousness in any society where it exists. Indulgence is exceedingly prone to assume the
                            name and garb of charity, and, under this false color, often deceives and has sometimes
                            ruined very good men. The oft-repeated maxim, that " it is better to err on the part of
                            charity, than do otherwise," is losing its effect, and, with some, has become entirely
                            obsolete, and not without good reasons. To make this subject plain to the understanding, we
                            will give some brief illustrations: We remember to have read of a millionaire in France who,
                            out of charity, undertook to support all the poor in a large district, and by his profuse
                            liberality ultimately spent his immense fortune. Although his funds were exhausted, he still
                            felt it his duty to support all the poor within his reach, indiscriminately, and, finding no
                            other resource, he took to highway robbery ! In this he was for a time very successful.
                            Several heavy robberies were committed in the neighborhood, but no one for a moment
                            mistrusted the good philanthropist. At length he waylaid a priest, who was carrying a large
                            sum collected to build a cathedral, and he murdered the priest and got the money ! All these
                            sums were freely appropriated to feed his poor. This good philanthropist was at length
                            caught in the very act of robbery, to the'surprise of everybody. He was brought to trial,
                            pronounced guilty, and condemned to be hung I When the judge pronounced his sentence, he
                            only replied, " Alas ! who will take care of my poor!" Thus, we see that erring on the part
                            of charity proted the utter ruin and destruction of this man, and it will of every
                            individual family, or whole community, who persist, perseveringly to err on the part of this
                            kind of charity, at the expense of justice, righteousness, and without regard to £ne moral
                            character of its objects. Thus, we see one great theme seemed to hare taken possession of
                            this man's mind, so as to overshadow all idea of justice, and even to conceal the horrid
                            crime of murder! Has there not been something like this transacted among Believers, only
                            difFering in degree, but not in nature ? Have there not been some unprincipled, dishonest
                            creatures indulged, andsuffered to trample on and outrage the feelings and faith of all the
                            more faithful part of community, under the plausible pretext of extending charity to the
                            poor? Thus, the innocent and worthy members of community are imposed upon, and robbed of
                            their just rights, and their confidence and better feelings crushed, murdered, for the sake
                            of indulging some lazy, shiftless, self-willed unworthy individuals; all done by erring on
                            the part of charity, when great injustice is done to all parties. To illustrate this subject
                            further, we will make an extract from the Westminster Review: " Victor Hugo, of France,
                            tells us of a very philanthropic bishop, who spent all his wealth and revenue on the
                            poor—gave up his palace to be iised as a hospital, and lived in a small cottage. He had no
                            furniture but of the plainest kind ; nothing that indicated wealth, except a set of massive
                            silver plate, which, as an heirloom, had descended to him by legacy. This he would display
                            on his table when he had guests. On a certain occasion, a desperate convict, who had served
                            several terms in the penitentiary, amounting to nineteen years, called on the good bishop,
                            soon after he had served the last term. " The convict made S clean breast, and introduced
                            himself in his true colors, as an outcast, and spumed by mankind. To his astonishment, the
                            good bishop did not appear shocked, but looked upon him with kindness. The convict repeated
                            the terrible factT and, in proof, showed the passport given him on leaving the prison. The
                            good bishop still smiled on him, and invited him to partake of food and lodging. Supper
                            being prepared, and the silver plate paraded on the table in honor of the guest, they sat
                            down and ate together. The convict eyed the silver plate and two massive silver
                            candlesticks. The bishop was all goodness and loving-kindness toward the stranger—the
                            convict carefully watched where the servant put the silver plate, and was finally conducted
                            to bed by the good bishop. " In the dead of night the convict awakes, and makes his way to
                            the place of deposit and grasps the plate—all but the candlesticks, which he could not
                            readily find, goes back to his chamber, and escapes through the window. The next day he was
                            arrested by the police, and brought back to the good bishop, with his 9*2 <pb n="93" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHA.KKR. 98 stolen plate, and the bishop, in the deep charity of his soul, told the
                            policeman that the said convict was his friend, and that he had given the plate to him ! The
                            zealous policeman, mortified at his mistake, immediately withdrew. The bishop turned to the
                            convict, and quietly presented him with the silver candlesticks, which the robber had
                            omitted to take with the plate, an I, laying his hand on the man's arm, said : ' My brother,
                            you belong no more to evil, but to good. It is your soul that I now purchase of you; I
                            withdraw it from the spirit of perdition and give it to God !' The convict departed with his
                            booty, and that very day committed another robbery!" Says the Review : " The prominent
                            feature is an unbounded benevolence, before which every other consideration, even justice,
                            as well as prudence, gives way. This is particularly displayed in the last scene in which he
                            appears before us, when, in order to extricate the robber from the hands of the police, he
                            dismissed the latter with a falsehood, thus sacrificing truth itself to the benevolent
                            purpose of accomplishing the convict's conversion, and saving him from his just deserts.
                            Would it not be better for spiritual teachers to feed and stimulate the minds of their
                            flocks with a desire for spiritual improvement, and a spirit of obedience, instead of
                            encouraging, by undue and perilous indulgence, that which is at once a cause and symptom of
                            mental degeneration ?" We will now make the application, and close the subject. Have we not
                            seen something like this in the course of our experience ? How many there are who, if they
                            have not stolen directly, have unjustly spent the " silver plate," and, after all, have been
                            presented with the " silver candlesticks," too ! And how many of these unjustly-treated ones
                            have ever reformed, and their " souls thereby redeemed and purchased to God ?" Have we not
                            failed as utterly as did the good bishop ? And hava we not, by thus giving away our "
                            candlesticks," let our candles go with them, and thus gradually been left in darkness ?
                            Consequently, are there not some among us who will have to exclaim, in the language of the
                            foolish virgins to their more honored, faithful brethren and sisters l " Alas! give us of
                            your oil, for our lamps are gone out ?" so that they are left in the dark, and are scarcely
                            able to " discern between the righteous and the wicked, between him that serveth God, and
                            him that serveth Him not ?" When charity, the greatest of three distinguished virtues, is
                            made tributary to crime, and subservient to vice, then it is that we have arrived at a point
                            beyond which charity ceases to be a virtue. The same may be said of true Christian
                            forgiveness, for they are inseparabty connected, and we cannot be in the exercise of one
                            without being in possession of the other. The true ground of Christian charity and for-
                            giveness is always on conditions ; thus, " if thy brother trespass against thee, rebuke him;
                            and if he repent, forgive him." Here is the foundation of true charity and forgiveness, but
                            be sure that his repentance is genuine, and not feigned. A brother is not a reprobate. If
                            his repentance is genuine, he wrill be willing to suffer the just penalty due to his
                            transgressions, and not to complain of the innocent because they withhold their sympathy.
                            How was it with Jesus, our Elder Brother, when speaking of the baptism of sufferings through
                            which he must pass, in order to find his redemption from that fallen nature which he took
                            upon him, and when Peter began to sympathise with him, and said, " this shall never be unto
                            thee, Lord ?" Why, Jesus rebuked that false spirit of sympathy in Peter, and said s "Get
                            behind me, Satan ! for thou savorest not of the things that be of God, but of men." How was
                            it with Mother Ann, our first-born Elder Sister, when she was suffering the just penalty due
                            a fallen nature ? Did she complain of the innocent for their want of sympathy ? Never! She
                            sought rather to hide herself, " lest some should pity her with a pity which God did not."
                            Let us go and do likewise, and then sympathy will flow spon- taneously. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>Jas. S. Prescott</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Last night of Jesus on Earth" TEIform="index"/>The Last Night of Jesus on Earth.</head><p TEIform="p">Beautiful for situation; As Jerusalem of old, Is the Lord's new habitation, Where His truth
                            and power unfold. Built of His eternal treasure, Is the City from above ; Vainly would our
                            spirits measure Half its glory, peace and love. We. whose hearts and homes are lighted With
                            the radiance of His face, Know that bloom will reach the blighted, As the sun the darken'd
                            place. Here, among the hills and mountains, Revelations v?e can gain ; Drink from spiritual
                            fountains, Ne'er to thirst for earth again. Here the future is unfolded: From the shadows of
                            the past, From wild chaos, God has moulded Beauties that will live and last; And His power
                            is not diminished, Greater wonders He will do, Ere His work on earth is finished, And all
                            things are made anew. Hope, with joyous, starry pinion, Speeds into the coming day ; Love
                            goes back, through time's dominion, On the pilgrim's rugged way— Love goes back to him who
                            sorrowed O'er the wicked and perverse, Back to him who toil'd and suffered, To destroy the
                            Eden curse. Love, like Mary, bows and listens When the multitudes are taught; In her eyes
                            emotion glistens When the miracles are wrought. What, to her, is learning's station, With
                            its pompous iron sway ? Better far the soul's salvation, Spoken of in simple way. Parables,
                            from nature taken, Illustrate the law divine, And the honest soul awaken To the truths that
                            round it shine. Still the world will kill the lowly ; For it loveth but its own, Hearts that
                            would be pure and holy Still the press must tread alone. Jcsns gave his life for others ;
                            None could minister to him, Though he fain would make them brothers, Yet their spirit-life
                            was dim ; All they knew he had imparted, Streams their source cannot supply ; They were
                            faithless and faint-hearted, When the darkened hour drew nigh. When the last sad meal was
                            ended, And the solemn hymn was o'er, They the mountain slope ascended With a grief unknown
                            before. All their love to Mm had centered ; They had known him as a man ; But theirTjearts
                            had never entered Into God's deep, holy plan. When his grief he cvnild not smother, Pressed
                            on him with heavy weight; They were striving with each other, Who among tttem should be
                            great. They were children, and he led them } Their affections round him grew : Carefully he
                            taught, and fed them In the life and spirit new. Oft he gathered them together, To baptize
                            their souls in flame— They, like lonely, desert heathen, Knew not whence the spirit came.
                            Theirs was fervent, human feelingTender sympathy and love ; God was to his soul revealing
                            Elements they knew not of. Every human creed must perish ; Fairest flowers will fade and
                            part; And the closest ties We cherish Break and wreck the trusting heart/ Let this lesson
                            ever waken Strength within the struggling soul: Principles are never shaken j God has kept
                            them tf us and Whole. They will grovt and brighten, ever, 'Neat.h the Angels' chastening rod
                            ; They will form our home forever— " Stones ¦' approv'd and blest of God. O my spirit, thou
                            art lifted With a burst of holy song ; And thy inmost sight is gifted With a vision, sought
                            for long. What, to thee, is earthly trial ? O, behold the heavenly state ! In the clouds of
                            self-denial, Toil, and for fruition waft, Numbered not with ariy nation, Israel, here shall
                            dwell alone ; But his glory and salvation Shall throughout the earth be known !</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="De Vere, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>Cecelia De Vere</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">Dear Editor :—The following, from the American Phrenological Journal, is so excellent and
                            true to life, that I call your attention to it for the benefit of your readers. I have
                            thought that judging any by their features was an unsafe and unjust criterion ; but am now
                            satisfled that our spiritual beings become transformed into the likeness of those virtues
                            for which we have admiration, or reflect the vices we endorse and practice. C. Djisisle.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mind builds its own house" TEIform="index"/>THE MIND BUILDS ITS OWN HOUSE</head><p TEIform="p">" A sensual disposition deforms "the handsomest features. A cold, selfish heart shrivels and
                            distorts the best looks. A mean, groveling spirit takes all noble character out of the
                            countenance. A cherished hatred transforms the most beautiful lineament into an image of
                            ugliness. " It is impossible to preserve good looks,with a brood of bad passions feeding on
                            the blood, a set of low loves trampling through the heart, and a selfish, disdainful spirit
                            enthroned in the will. " Badness and beauty will no more keep company than poison will
                            consort with health. The experiment of putting them together has been tried for thousands of
                            years, with one unvarying result. The laws of spirit work with unfailing effect, making sin
                            punish itself. Every bad passion turns tell-tale, and publishes its disgraceful story in the
                            features of those who have given themselves up to every sort of wickedness. This may not be
                            all, but this transforming a face once full of hope and innocence, into deformity, is
                            terrible. " There is no sculpture like the mind. The man who thinks, reads, meditates
                            aright, has intelligence in his features, stamped on his brow, and gleaming in his eye.
                            There is nothing that so refines and ennobles face and mien as the constant presence of
                            great thoughts, a high determination, a virtuous principle, an unquenchable enthusiasm. But
                            more powerful still than any of these, as a bcautifier of the person, is the overmastering
                            purpose and pervading disposition of impartial kindness in <pb n="94" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 94: THE S H
                            A. K E the heart, a universal benevolence, and desire to make others happy. The soul that is
                            full of pure and generous affections, fashions the features into its own angelic likeness,
                            as the rose, by inherent impulse, grows in grace and blossoms into a lovliness which art
                            cannot equal."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Resurrection of the dead" TEIform="index"/>Resurrection of the Bead</head><p TEIform="p">The following literal translation of, and observations upon, the XV Chap, of St. Paul's First
                            Epistle to the Corinthians, v. 35 to 52, are presented in the hope that they may ren- der
                            this difficult passage more intelligible to the ordinary reader than it is at present.
                            Several reasons combine to make this portion of scripture hard to be understood. The trans-
                            lators of the New Testament did not understand St. Paul's meaning; and, even if they had, it
                            would require, for the reader to understand the words, an amount of spiritual intel- ligence
                            which few possess. But the persons to whom St. Paul was writing, though in some respects
                            enlightened, were not sufficiently advanced to comprehend his meaning: therefore, St. Paul
                            had to give a portion of his own light to them in the best manner he could. This has,
                            naturally, produced a mingling of spiritual truth and figures which must be \ery con- fusing
                            to the unenlightened reader. We must bear in mind that the early apostles' great difficulty
                            was to give the Gentiles a real belief in a future existence. Lastly, the apostle himself,
                            though far superior in spiritual light to most of his contemporaries, and though his
                            spiritual perceptions were much opened, had not himself the full light, which was reserved
                            for the future. In the first part of the chapter the apostle labors to convince the
                            Corinthians that there is a resurrection from sin in this life, and a life after the death
                            of the body. He uses the appearance of Jesus to himself and others, as a means of
                            enlightening their darkened minds. But, that the real meaning refers to spiritual life, is
                            evident from the expression, ' ye are yet in your sins.' Then he explains, that not only is
                            there a spiritual life while on this earth, but a life hereafter. If there were not a future
                            life, why run hourly risk of misery in this ? he asks : UTEBAL TRANSLATIN. Y.. 35. '• But
                            some one will say : ' How are the dead raised ? and with what body do. they come ? 36. O.
                            Ssenseless! that which thou sowest will not produce, except it die.*' EXPLANATIONS. Some one
                            will ask the question : •¦ What kind of bodies have the dead?" Paul answers: 'As the husk of
                            the seed dies, and another body springs from the life principle in the seed.' lie continues
                            : " We do not sow (he fruit, but grain of various kinds, and 37. '' And as to that which
                            thou sowest, thou sowest not the body that is about to be, but the bare kernel, as it may
                            happen, of wheat or of some of the other kinds (of grain)." 38. '¦ And God will give it a
                            body as he willed, and kinds of fruit, to each (kind) of the seeds its own body." 39. " All
                            flesh (is) not the same llesh ; but (there is) one tlesh of men, another flesh of beasts,
                            another of fishes, another of birds." 40. " And (there are) bodies heavenly, and bodies
                            earthly ; but the glory of the heavenly (is) one, and the glory of the earthly another." 41.
                            '• The glory of the sun (is) one. and the glory of the moon one, and the glory of the stars
                            one; for star differs from star in glory. God gives the several He continues to enforce the
                            same idea by another simple illustration, varying kinds of animals. Now he carries the idea
                            farther : There are heavenly bodies as well as earthly, and the glory of the heavenly
                            differs from the glory of the earthly. Illustration of the foregoing, the difference be-
                            tween the heavenly bodies. 42. " And thus (is) the reITe comes to the subject snrrection of
                            the dead ; of wliich the foregoing is (the man) is sown in corillustrative: The resur-
                            ruptiou, is raised in inrection of the dead is just corruption; the same ; the man is 43. "
                            Is sown in dishonor, sown in corruption, but is rai'ssd in glory; is tlie legitimate fruit
                            oi' that .sown in weakness, is man is an incorruptible raised in power; spirit. 44. " Is
                            sown a soul body, Thy man is sown, posis raised a spiritual sessed of a soul, but rebody :
                            there is a soul generated or raised ; liis body and there is a spirit is evolved and be-
                            spiritual body. comes his actual body: for the soul has a form or body and Ihe spirit has a
                            form or body. ' I'snchiIcon ' means ' soul,' as an adjective, and cannot, in reason, be
                            contorted into any thing else; ' phnsikon' is physical or natural. 45. "And thus it is writ-
                            The lirst Adam had a ten: The first man a soul, existing, indeed, Adam was produced inbut
                            capable of giving life to a living soul ; the last to no other; the last Adam man Adam into
                            a lifeis a spirit able to give life giving spirit. to others .¦ i. e., the first is
                            retreating from Deity, the latter is advancing toward Deity. 46. "But not first (is) the The
                            soul is first generspiritual, but the soul atcd. the spirit is subse(prineiple); afterwards,
                            quently ev lved. the spiritual. 47. " The lirst man (is) of the earth, earthy ; the second
                            man (is) the Lord from heaven. 48. " Like the earthy (are) the earthy; and like the heavenly
                            (are) also the heavenly. 49. "And as we bore the likeness of the earthy, we shall bear the
                            likeness of the heavenly. 50. " This I say, brethren, To prevent the possibilithat flesh and
                            blood are ty of mistake, he says that not able to share the our physical bodies will kingdom
                            of God. nor not rise. does corruption share incorruption. 51. "Behold, I declare tinThe
                            spirit of this proto you a mystery: All phecy is now fulfilled ; no of us shall not die. but
                            doubt the.ehange that the we shall all be changed: Apostle speaks of has 51. " In a moment,
                            in the been experienced by them winking of an eye, in in the spirit land ; and the last
                            trumpet "[for it many dead are now being shall sound], both the raised within the sound dead
                            shall be raised inof the last trumpet; but corruptible and we shall like all the early
                            Chrisbe changed." tians he expected the change too soon, and manifestly expected that both
                            the" change of the living, or spiritually enlightened, and the raising of the dead, in sin,
                            would be much more rapid than it is in reality. He has doubtless found by this time that
                            nothing is gained without effort. Note.—Words inclosed thus ( ) are omitted in the Greek.
                            Words inclosed thus [ ] are bracketed in the Greek,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stroud, Thomas I." TEIform="persName"/>Thomas I. Stroud, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Were Moses and Jesus free agents?" TEIform="index"/>Were Moses and Jesus Free- Agents ?</head><p TEIform="p">Who was Jesus of Nazareth ? What was his mission ? Was it possible that he might have failed
                            in performing his mission ? If he had so failed, would the present race of beings have been
                            hopelessly lost, or would there have been another Medium, Teacher, Christ raised up, by the
                            power of the Holy Spirit, to have done the same important work which he performed for
                            humanity ? I wish that I were a thorough historian, a theologian and something of a
                            logician. Then, if I could bring my wayward pen under the rules of rhetoric, I could solve
                            some knotty questions which now I find much more difficult to answer than to ask. I was
                            taught in early life, by a pious, devoted Baptist mother, that Jesus was one of the Gods
                            incarnated in human form; that he was snugly ensconced in the bosom of the All Father before
                            the worlds were framed, and that he was the only son. That this Loving Father, who saw the
                            end from the beginning, did, from all eternity, predestinate that certain portions of the
                            race should be lost, and that at some time he would send this beloved son to rescue a part
                            from utter destruction, and thus manifest his love and justice as also his great mercy.
                            Eeligious teachers give children some hard nuts to crack when they talk to them about
                            predestination and trinity of three male Gods conjoined in one; and full grown children oc-
                            casionally are puzzled to understand how it is, and often find themselves in a maze from
                            which it is difficult to extricate themselves. I have always thought it the wisest way for
                            me to avoid great mysteries, and as much as possible to keep on a plain, even road, where
                            the fool, for Christ's sake, may travel and not err; keeping a good conscience and using
                            what little common sense was given me. Eeason is God's gift to man, and is given for use. A
                            few years ago an intelligent female friend, whose father was an Episcopal clergyman, said to
                            me : " Oh ! do not try to reason upon the doctrine of the Trinity; that is just the.cause of
                            so many infidels in the world." I said: "Is not God the author of reason; and will He
                            require us to believe anything that will not bear the light of reason ? " She replied, " It
                            is a true doctrine, but too high for finite comprehension." We will leave the Trinity and
                            return to the Sonship. If Jesus was the Christ, the only begotten of the Father, who are
                            they who call upon God as their Heavenly Father ? Children by adoption, are they, or is
                            Jesus the Father upon whom they call ? Hardly that; for they say " grant our petitions for
                            Christ's sake." When we go back upon Bible history, we see that the Great First Cause who
                            framed the universe, gave the dry land and the sea their bounds, and marked out times and
                            seasons and set the wheels in motion, designed that under law and order there should be
                            eternal growth and progress. Never has the infinite mind lost sight of the universe of its
                            own creating, nor left it without a controlling, moral force sufficient to hold it in its
                            course, and keep it from returning to chaos. Mineral, vegetable and animal life have
                            progressed. At particular periods of time, when growth and development called for higher and
                            more progressed teachers, there have been what we might call especial providences. Teachers
                            and rulers have been raised up to meet the needs of the people for the time being. Then
                            prophets would come forth, and, through inspiration, point them to a greater work, a more
                            perfect day in the distant future, when they should have progressed unto it; a light ahead
                            in the ascending upward scale. Moses was providentially raised up to perform a certain work.
                            He was a powerful minister of physical truth to the Jews—precisely what they needed and must
                            have in order to progress. Now, was it possible for Moses to have proved recreant to that
                            people —the Jews ? If so, would there have been another providential teacher or law giver
                            raised up unto that people, or would the chain of progress have been broken and the
                            machinery reversed ? If there could have been another Moses found, there might have been a
                            little delay, but no failure. So we say, blessed is he or she who, being called and
                            appointed to any I <pb n="95" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 95 work, are found faithful. That
                            depends upon their own volition. If Jesus was a divinely inspired teacher, possessing larger
                            powers of receptivity than any that had preceded him; had risen higher in the scale of
                            purity by reason of his own obedience to laws given through Moses, and also on account of
                            the progressed physical and moral condition of his ancestry, and was thus fitted to receive
                            a baptism of the Christ Spirit that would induct him into a higher sphere of spiritual life,
                            he thereby became the High Priest of a new dispensation wherein the law of an eye for an eye
                            should be annulled by substituting love for force, rendering good for evil. Could Jesus have
                            refused the call and offer of the teachership and inductor of the Jews into this higer
                            law—the new dispensation ? If it were possible, and had thus refused to receive the Christ
                            Spirit which was seeking a medium through wrhich to wrork, could or would that same spirit
                            have sought and found another prepared vessel into which the oil through the golden pipes
                            from the bowl or church in the invisible world, have been conveyed to the people, or would
                            the race have been hopelessly lost?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. Doolittle</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Appreciation" TEIform="index"/>Appreciation</head><p TEIform="p">I have been an attentive reader of every number of The Shaker. It certainly has able
                            expounders of our beautiful and soulinvigorating faith, and to this class of writers we need
                            not add more. One after another of the brave veterans of a holy cause —those who might have
                            retired with wellearned laurels, that shed lustre and joy over declining years— have come
                            forth, as to the sound of a trumpet, and with pens that seemed dipped in the fires of truth,
                            and in the light of revelation, are thus proclaiming the pure principles of salva- tion.
                            Noble fathers and mothers ! may God send tlte angels to watch over you, to give light to
                            your dimmed eyes, and strength to your failing hands, that the glorious work of expounding
                            the principles of "heaven on earth" may not fall into less efficient hands ! We read in the
                            July number an expression that strongly unites in sympathy with its editor in making The
                            Shaker " a home educator." I have greatly desired to see this idea advanced, so that those
                            who are children in years, and those who are willing to " become so for the kingdom's sake,"
                            may find the desiderata that will enable them to become wise in spiritual things. Though not
                            a youth, I am still near enough to that condition in life to know of its attendant
                            temptations and dangers. This age needs just such "a home educator" as our little paper, to
                            balance its perversions—to rebuke them—for it is an age that is too fast for the culture of
                            virtuous deeds and eternal life. " Youth is the time to serve the Lord," a period when the
                            song of life should be as fervent as the little bird's, that seems to sing with all its
                            might, and to the utmost expansion of its little bird's harp : " Oh God, I praise thee ever
                            !" It is before the young tree has sufficiently developed, to produce perfect fruits, that
                            it requires the most attention. The careful gardener never neglects to train, prune nor
                            graft, nor to protect the young trees from worms, hurtful insects and the " little foxes
                            that destroy." Great care must be taken in every department of the juvenile age—physically,
                            morally and spiritually. Much pruning is necessary to prepare souls for the scion of faith,
                            in extreme purity of life, and failure to be thus grafted is despair. Oh, the blasting of
                            bright hopes that make up despair ! For the right culture of youth, is required the
                            sacrifices of noble souls unto untiring zeal in their behalf. And it may be encouraging, for
                            all to know, that such there are; and youthful minds, " the buds of promise," who read The
                            Shaker, are not to be neglected.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wheeler, A. M." TEIform="persName"/>A. M. Wheeler, U. V., Ohio</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>JUVENILE DEPARTMENT</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth" TEIform="index"/>Truth</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Children :—In God, our Heavenly Father and Mother, are embodied the living
                                principles of all truth. If you love God, and desire to express your love, live in the
                                element of truth — speak the truth, act the truth. Adopt as the motto of every day's
                                life: " / will speak the truth at all times, and under all circumstances." You will meet
                                with circumstances that will tempt you to stray from this path of duty, and which
                                promise more pleasant inducements. Beware of the tempter, stand firm by }rour motto !
                                The real heroes upon our earth, who have striven in the past, and who are now zealously
                                striving to elevate the race, have ever scorned to speak or act an untruth. Learn to be
                                heroic, and you need never fear any harm when clothed with the armor of truth. God will
                                bless, if you will be truthful. The spirits of love and purity will journey with you
                                daily, and writh pleasure; and your spiritual fathers and mothers will own you and
                                admire you if you resolve to stand upon the ground of truth. Endeavor to rise in love
                                with truth, and then the kingdom of heaven will not be far off—you will be in a
                                condition to enjoy life; or, preparing for death, you will find peace and happiness with
                                Christ, in those mansions, not made with hands, eternal in the heavens.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Beaver, O. M." TEIform="persName"/>O. M. Beaver</byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Formation of character" TEIform="index"/>Formation of Character</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Editor :—Some time in my youthful days, I remember to have read in some author a
                                very interesting description of two distinct characters. One was of a character of
                                firmness and integrity of purpose, who was somewhat cautious on what he resolved or
                                promised; but the resolution once formed or the promise once made, was never to be
                                swerved from or violated, no matter wThat unforseen difficulty might arise in the
                                performance. The other character, though amiable in many respects, was quite forward and
                                incautious with his resolves and promises, and that too with sincere and good
                                intentions. But he was weak and wavering: the least unexpected trouble would disconcert
                                him, and away wrent all his good resolutions and promises! In a word, he was wholly
                                unreliable, and as men became acquainted with him, they set him at naught and dropped
                                him. On the other hand, the first named character, when inquiry was made concerning him,
                                the reply would be : " Well, he is not as ready to enter into promises and engagements
                                as some others, but if you once secure his promise you are just as sure of the
                                performance as you are of his life and ability to perform his engagement. He is a man of
                                integrity and faithfulness; one that may be perfectly relied on." As I read the
                                amplified description of these two characters, I instinctively decided in favor of the
                                man of integrity. After reading, reflection came on, and the question was put home : To
                                which class of these characters do I belong ? Looking back over my life, I had to
                                pronounce judgment against myself; I decidedly belonged to the weak, wravering,
                                unreliable class, which, in my conscience, I despised ! I had been whiffling, shirking
                                and dodging on meeting the least unexpected difficulty. I could not quietly sit down, or
                                go on under the just impeachment of being such a character. It was a crisis, a turning
                                point in my career. I then and there resolved, and covenanted with myself, that I would
                                break up that mean habit of whiffling and changing, and I laid down the following rule
                                for myself: " Whatever I promise or resolve to do, nothing shall ever prevent me from
                                accomplishing but the absolute inability or want o. power, or the discovery that the
                                fulfillment would be morally wrong." From that day I have striven, and not in vain, to
                                live squarely up to this rule, and it has changed my whole character and course of life.
                                Hence, I have come to the conclusion that .every youth or young man can, if he will
                                firmly and with all his heart set about the work, change off a low, mean and degraded
                                character and course of life, for one that is far more excellent and lovely. I mean, I
                                believe he can do this by the aids and means which the Gospel furnishes him. This
                                conclusion is the pith of the matter. I do not expect that the character I have drawn
                                will suit every one ; but I do mean that every one has some defects of character which
                                he may discover by honest and faithful selfexamination, and extirpate by decided efforts
                                made in obedience to gospel principles. This is the work of regeneration. There are no
                                mysterious depths in it; it is the regeneration of your spirit; it is putting off the
                                first coarse husks of character, and putting on those refinements of spirit and
                                consequent refined external accomplishments, which the Gospel alone can give and firmly
                                establish in the character. It is embellishing our character and manners with all those
                                glorious virtues which all good men love and respect, and which will enable us to love
                                and bless mankind. I cannot do better here than to finish with a paragraph from a good,
                                old, enlightened author. "If thou hast any thought of being hereafter a member of that
                                blest society of chosen spirits, of the excellent ones of the earth, of souls framed to
                                love and peace and harmony, thou wilt set thyself in earnest to enrich thy mind with the
                                heavenly graces of meekness, patience, forbearance and benevolence; and in the exercise
                                of these virtues thou wilt find joys inconceivable to the sordid sons of earth; thou
                                wilt endeavor to be to thy fellow creatures, even in this life, a guardian angel and a
                                God."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. P.</byline></div3></div2><pb n="96" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True love" TEIform="index"/>True Love</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leggett, E. T. (words) and Lomas, G. A. (music)" TEIform="persName"/>Words by E. T. Leggett.
                            Music by G. A. Lomas.</byline><p TEIform="p">1 Purer than the skies of even, brighter than the morning sun, Is that angel love from
                            heaven, blending all our hearts in one; Now like rippling waters meeting, murmuring
                            gladness to our ears, Now within our hearts 'tis beating, marches to the brighter spheres.
                            2 Oh, it is a glorious feeling, deep'ning as we heavenward go, Spotless as the sunlight,
                            stealing softly through the felling snow; 'Tis a fount of living waters, with rich blessings
                            running o'er, Where all Zion's sons and daughters, drink of bliss and thirst no more. 3 Love
                            will heal the broken hearted, it will cure the stricken soul; Twill unite whom death lias
                            parted, where no waves of sorrow roll. It will triumph when the mountains, time, at last,
                            shall overthrow, And when silent, all life's fountains, love shall bright, still brighter
                            glow. 4 Like the light of hope that's beaming, o'er the dark clouds rolling high, Love
                            reveals far o'er them gleaming, brighter worlds beyond the sky. Grant, thou Great Almighty
                            Giver, o'er our wild and bleak domain, Love may, like lost Eden's river, make this world to
                            bloom again. 5 'Tis to God and to each other, love unites us heart and hand, And will guide
                            us, sister, brother, homeward to the promised land; While we pray to be forgiven, while we
                            hope for heaven above, May our strife be all for union, and our contest all for love.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker to its readers" TEIform="index"/>The Shaker to its Readers</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The present number of ourself completes the first volume. We have attempted, and have
                            measurably succeeded, in giving correct information of the peculiar people whose nickname we
                            bear. We might animadvert somewhat upon the writings of those who have filled our pages, but
                            prefer to look with a i charitable eye upon those whose theology has j been unable to keep
                            pace with the increase of j the revelations of the Good Spirit. We purpose being a special
                            agent for the enlightenment of the household of Shaker principles, and with it, leaving the
                            dead of the past, j "go on unto perfection." (Heb. 6:1.) We j have traveled far and wide
                            before we are one ! year old. We have had more than seven thouj sands of ourself circulated
                            each month—six j thousands and more reaching actual subscribers j and agents. We purpose,
                            with the aid of every lover of virtue—every friend to the reform of vice and admirer of
                            purity of life, to reach a circulation of ten thousand, the coming year, if possible. We
                            mean to meet our patrons with an improved appearance, on superior paper, and with living and
                            life-giving material of enhancing value, the coming year; we therefore beg to meet our old
                            subscribers— every one—on New Year's Day. Our subscription price is the same; and, while it
                            does not pay the cost, we are no poorer in spirit for all of ourself we have given away. Let
                            each of the Shaker Societies give us a day's labor, or an acre of ground benefit,
                            remembering the reward of giving to the poor. We know we are the advocate, in the missionary
                            line, of principles that are eternal, that wilL not down at the bidding of worldly pride,
                            lust nor selfishness. We mean to live—and by your help, kind readers, we mean to do a great
                            deal of good. Though the following may seem a little irreverent for our pages, may not some
                            of us find therein a valuable hint ?</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Making her fly" TEIform="index"/>Making Her Fly</head><p TEIform="p">Old Aunt Dina was a shouting colored saint of the city of Charleston, who would sing at the
                            top of her voice and cry "Glory!" above all the rest of the congregation. It was common at
                            the missionary prayer meetings of the colored people to take up a collection while singing
                            the hymn, " Fly abroad, thou mighty Gospel!'' In the midst of which Aunt Dina always threw
                            her head back, shut her eyes and sang lustily till the plate passed. The sable collector
                            observed her habit, and one evening stopped when he came to her and said bluntly: " Look
                            aheah, Aunt Dina, you needn't be asinging ' Fly abroad, thou mighty Gospel' if you doesn't
                            give nothing to make her fly !"</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The responsibility of receiving and preparing material for our columns..." TEIform="index"/>The responsibility of receiving and preparing material for our columns...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The responsibility of receiving and preparing material for our columns, as well as directing
                            each individual wrapper, rests upon the Resident Editor. The folding and wrapping, ready for
                            mailing, is the gratuitous offering of Sister Harriet Bullard with her able corps of
                            youthful assistants. This is to be appreciated. Bowing in gratitude for past favors, we
                            invite your immediate renewal of subscriptions that we may continue to " fly abroad " many
                            years to come.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shaker" TEIform="persName"/>The Shaker</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bound copies of the first volume of The Shaker..." TEIform="index"/>Bound copies of the first volume of The Shaker...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Bound copies of the first volume of The Shaker, may be obtained by application to the
                            Resident Editor. Price, Two Dollars; extra binding, Three Dollars. JJjJS^* Any parties
                            sincerely solicitous of a thorough explanation of Shaker views of religion; and who would
                            willingly bear the expenses, in transitu, of a Lecturer, to discourse upon "Religious
                            Communism;" or " Ann Lee and the People called Shakers ; " may communicate with this Office.
                            G. A. Lomas. Shakers, Albany Co., N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publications" TEIform="index"/>PUBLICATIONS</head><p TEIform="p"> Christ's First and Second Appearing Dunlavy's Manifesto Millennial Church..... Compendium of
                            Shakerism Three Discourses on United Interests Tracts free, where postage is paid. m 25 1 25
                            1 00 0 50 0 50 </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker, monthly journal, devoted to the exposition of religion, acording to Shaker theology" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER. MONTHLY JOURNAL, DEVOTED TO THE EXPOSITION OF RELIGION, ACCORDING TO SHAKER
                            THEOLOGY.</head><p TEIform="p"> Fifty Cents, Pek Annum, in Advance. G. A. Lomas, Resident Editor, Shakers, Albany Co., N. Y.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Members of society" TEIform="index"/>MEMBERS OF SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p"> MEMBERS OF SOCIETY J Appointed to answer Correspondents, among whom are the Board of
                            Editors, ElderF. W. Evans, Mt. Lebanon, Columbia Co., N. Y. " Issachar Bates, Shakers. N. Y.
                            " Calvin G. Reed, Mt. Morris, Livingston Co., N. Y. " Simon Mabee, West Pittsfield, Mass. "
                            Stoughton Kellogg, Thompson ville, Conn., Shakers. " Albert Battles, Tyringham, Berkshire
                            Co., Mass. " Win. Leonard, Aver, Mass., Shakers. " John Whiteley, Shirley Village, Middlesex
                            Co., Mass. " Kebemiah Trull, Shaker Village, Merrimack Co., N. H. " Henry Cummings, Enfield,
                            Grafton Co.,N. HT. " John B. Vance, Alfred, Shakers, York Co., Me. " Alonzo Gilman, West
                            Gloucester, Cumberland Co., Me., Shakers. " Chas. Clapp, Union Village, Warren Co., O,,
                            Shakers. " Ezra Sherman, Preston, Hamilton Co., Ohio, Shakers. " Stephen Ball, "Dayton,
                            Shakers, Ohio. " Jacob Kulp, Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co., Ky. " J. R. Eades, South Union,
                            Logan Co., Ky. " J. S. Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio, Shakers.</p><p TEIform="p">Sample Copies of The Shaker sent free to any address upon application at this office.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>