<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0409" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><date value="18740901" TEIform="date">September 1874</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">65-72</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="65" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
                        <p>Vol. IV. No. 9. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. > Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co. N. Y.September, 1874,. *™™.</p>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stomach and conscience" TEIform="index"/>STOMACH AND CONSCIENCE</head><p TEIform="p">Two manners of people exist—the Jacob class and the Esau class. To the first, the blessing of
                            God comes in the sunshine of an inner spirit world, continually ripening them up for a
                            sphere, wherein they will be invisible to the Esau class, and live upon food, that to it,
                            would be as the manna to the Egyptian appetites of the Israelites. To the latter class, the
                            blessing of God comes in the sunshine of Earth, and in the dews and fatness thereof. It is a
                            question between stomach and conscience, as to which class each person shall be- long. " All
                            the labor of man, is for his mouth," and we are made up of the kind of food we put into it.
                            If we eat earthly food, we are earthly men and women. If we eat Angels' food—manna—we become
                            Angelic—spiritual men and women. If stomach — appetite — have the control, and pleasure be
                            sought, in physiological unrighteousness ; money — the representation of labor — is prized
                            as the means of indulgence. Money may be accumulated and held, from a mere insane love of
                            it, without any use to be accomplished by its possession. That is acquisitiveness run mad —
                            sheer covetousness. In such persons, common sense is almost extinct, and every earthly and
                            heavenly comfort is sacrificed for the purpose of economizing expenses. Whereas, money is
                            nothing worth, except for the good that can be derived from its possession, either to the
                            owner thereof, or to some other person. As a nation, it will be generally recognized, that
                            stomach predominates, at this present time, over conscience ; and the love of money over the
                            love of the use it represents. Appetite and looks — lust of the eye and perverted taste —
                            are the controlling influence that determine the kind of medicine and quality of food that
                            men provide, and women cook, and also how they shall cook it. The same rule and principle,
                            or the want of them, govern, first, the men, and next, the women, in relation to dress.
                            Health and comfort, morality and religion, the good of the present generation and the
                            welfare of the future, are sub- ordinated to appetite and looks, to that degree, that he, or
                            she, who stops to enquire of conscience, why do I eat and drink and do, this or that — what
                            the object — the use — the comfort — in this article of food, drink, apparel or medicine, I
                            contemplate buying and preparing for myself and others, is as much outside the social
                            circle, as are the insane. And indeed, they are by appetite-created-mentality, accounted as
                            "Samaritans"—as "having a devil," or as being beside themselves — forming a class, who are
                            forever turning " the world that now is/' upside down. They desecrate the Temples, destroy
                            the gods and change the Ordinances of the Degree, that has accomplished its mission — become
                            old and is ready to perish, and be supplanted by its successors, as a new wave of progress.
                            The same lines of argument — the same turmoil of passion, that the existence of chattel
                            slavery, in America, gave rise to, terminating in a destructive, uncivil war, come into
                            operation in all contentions and struggles between stomach and conscience, that have
                            occurred, and will hereafter occur, in any new degree of progress, in Nations, in Societies,
                            or even individuals. Three classes are created. 1st. The Prophetic class, who receive the
                            inspiration of the coming Degree. These are the Radicals, who proclaim liberty to the
                            captive — whether it be the captive, man and woman, who are bought and sold, like animals ;
                            or souls, captive to some appetite — some lust of the flesh, or mind, that has had its day.
                            2d. The second class are the Moderates, who have been progressed by the Radicals, and
                            repelled by the Conservatives. With this class Wisdom was born. And when it becomes ex-
                            tinct, Wisdom will die with it. They have, like the middle of a stick, a horror of the two
                            ends — of all extremes. 3d. The opposite extreme, or Conservative class, whose stomachs are
                            the Gods they worship, whose intellects are enslaved by their appetites, and who reason only
                            to make the worse appear the better part — to prove that what they want, and will have, is
                            agreeable to their conscience, which is subordinated to, and enslaved by their stomach. It
                            has not been revealed to these Moderates, that if the two ends were cut off there would
                            still be a middle. The stick might be made shorter and shorter, until it represented the
                            simious tribes, but the same order would still exist — there would be the two ends, and a
                            middle, held together by the two ends. Flesh meat is, almost exclusively, the food of the
                            wild Indian, in his primitive state. It is wild animals, which require a large area of
                            country, with sparse population. To change their diet is to change their whole social sys-
                            tem. If they come to feed upon domestic animals, there must be fixed habitations, and a
                            system of agriculture, like the Creek Indians have adopted, and adapted themselves unto. If
                            again they would change their diet, and discontinue the use of domestic animal food, that
                            would involve the introduction of Horticulture, like the people of Vineland. Thus would they
                            approximate the diet of the Israelites in the wilderness. Had Moses lived, would he ever
                            have taken the Children of Israel into the land of Canaan ? Had Jesus lived, would he ever
                            have formed an organization ? In Canaan, they went back, not unto Egyptian diet, with its
                            flesh pots, but to a mixed diet of flesh, vegetables and fruits. But the most holy class
                            among them — the Nazarenes — ate no flesh, drank no wine, and lived lives of celibacy. These
                            were what the whole body of the people had begun to travel toward, and would attain unto,
                            when the Messiah came to change their diet and learn them to eat the most sacred of all food
                            — unleavened bread, made of unbolted flour—the Lord's last supper. These things were written
                            for our admonition, upon whom the ends of the world have begun to come. When the Seventh
                            Trumpet begins to sound, the mystery of God shall be finished. A young man, or woman, who
                            begins life with conservatism, is as an Israelite who began life by desiring to go back into
                            Egypt to get his education. They will not leave the world any better than they found it.
                            Neither will such help to progress any society into which they may enter. The food question
                            is the soul question. A change of dietetics, is a change of the social system, for better,
                            or for worse. Hitherto, all the changes, made by Americans, as a people, have been from bad
                            to worse. To-day, the young are commencing life with a dietary that old people ought to be
                            ashamed to die upon. The stomachs, of the young Americans, have absorbed and digested their
                            physiological consciences. Superfine flour, and poisoned candies, are the two extremes, and
                            there is not much wisdom in the middle. It is exceedingly small, at the waist. There is but
                            one reason why the Females are so small at the middle; and that is, they wish the whole
                            world to know, they are as unfit, as they are determined, never to be Mothers. Jesus went to
                            extremes in his life conduct, to that degree that he was practically unpracticable, in the
                            day he lived in. He formed no Church Organization. David did not build the Temple. Solomon,
                            his successor, used the material David had accumulated to build it with. Peter and the
                            Apostles organized the Jewish Pentecostal Church. Jesus ministered unto them the Christ
                            Spirit, by which it was accomplished. Jesus labored in the wilderness of abstract ideas,
                            occult forces and subtle spiritual principles. These were the material that became
                            incarnated in the external organization of the Primitive Church, that lasted three hundred
                            years, and was then " scattered " — spread — through the whole Roman Empire, where it F. W.
                            EVANS, Editok. <pb n="66" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 66 worked like leaven, until a new organization was
                            effected, after twelve hundred and sixty years of wilderness travel. We are now in the
                            wilderness of a second Degree. The first Degree has done its work, and has been used as
                            leaven, to leaven Christendom. " The sound of its testimony has gone into all the world." We
                            must see to it, that we do not settle down, and become like the " magnetic ships, on the
                            ocean," in an unchangeable condition. The Lord's House — the Temple of the Second Degree —
                            will yet be built by the Solomons and Peters — Saints — unto whom the Spirit is calling —
                            come out of her — Babylon — my people, that ye be not partakers of her Bins of monopoly and
                            sensuality — of stomach against conscience — and that ye receive not of her plagues.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ayer, June 10, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Ayer, June 10th, 1874</head><p TEIform="p">Dearly beloved Elder Frederick, You have probably seen the report of our meetings in Lynn,
                            published in The Banner for June 6th. I also sent a Lynn Record to Bro. Daniel Fraser, and
                            propose to send you, as soon as the papers ordered arrive, a better report in the Lynn
                            Transcript. The meetings were interesting, truly so. And one friend writes me since : "
                            Personally, I shall never forget the visit of the Shakers to Lynn. It was a new era in my
                            life. The time you spent here — from Saturday night to Monday morning — was of great
                            interest and enjoyment to me. I have long wondered if a person could not be religious and
                            devotional, without believing in the terrible dogmas which have been my stumbling-blocks
                            from youth up, and it seems to me that in that particular, the Shakers realize my ideal." A
                            female medium, writing to Sister Catherine, expresses similar sentiments, and goes on to
                            tell what she saw in our last meeting there : " Three doves, with the olive branch, soar-
                            ing around you — which seemed to indicate that you had brought peace — also a shield of
                            silver light which seemed to surround your whole body, like steam, while you were talking,
                            and a sweet spirit-face, that with eyes of beaming rest, seemed to say " Well done! " How I
                            would like to see the face of Mother Ann. How much I have thought of her, since hearing you
                            tell of her." " There was over Elder William's head, while speaking, a silver light that
                            took the form of a sheaf of wheat, and at his feet a flowing stream of what seemed like the
                            morning dew." " On the right arm of Elder Vance, a drooped flag, bearing this inscription :
                            ' The end is Victory,' behind him stood a spirit of ancient times, with a surplice and three
                            bells, the tone of which I ccruld not hear but could feel. During the singing, there was
                            every thing beautiful to be seen, and while you were singing ' God is infinitely able,'
                            etc., I saw a shower of stars falling, and as they fell they became fastened in the form of
                            a chain, by links, till at the end they were made to inclose you all. I could say much more
                            but shall weary you. Will only add, I saw a golden key in the hand of Elder John Whiteley,
                            and a large white mantle was thrown on Brother Horace Taber.'" " All this has some meaning,
                            and in part unknown to me." " I wish I could go and see you all, and learn to be strong in
                            mind. It may never be my pleasure to do so, but I shall ever have a kind loving heart for
                            the Shakers." Two men have been already " to spy out the land," and others are coming. The
                            harvest work truly is great, and the laborers few. But we will not only sing, but believe,
                            that " God is infinitely able to sustain the week and feeble." Won't we? Time is crowding me
                            to a close ; but I want to tell how much we think of and speak of (in loving remembrance)
                            the visit we recently enjoyed with the lovely inmates of the North House. Heaven bless them
                            all, and add to their number of valiant soldiers, who will not flinch in the day of danger
                            and conflict. For truly " The end is victory." Special love from our Order, and believe me
                            ever Yours very truly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitely, John" TEIform="persName"/>Elder John Whitely, Shirley, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Theological treasury" TEIform="index"/>THEOLOGICAL TREASURY</head><p TEIform="p">Salvation. Heavens — happiness, unalloyed, never-ending, is the ultimate of all human
                            aspiration. To be at rest in Jesus, is the hoped for sum total of tenets, inculcated by any
                            and all persuasions. The word Salvation acts upon the mind, as does the word door, when the
                            door opens, admitting us to palatial scenes. Salvavation, too commonly conveys, to the
                            general mind, the erroneous idea, that the punishment for sin,is,in some way, to be avoided;
                            while the continuance of sinful practices may be indefinitely prolonged. To obtain
                            salvation, as we receive rain and sunshine — gratuitously — is the expectation of millions.
                            Contrast the numbers who want to be saved from the consequences of their sins, with those
                            who want to be saved from all sinful indulgences. Contrast the multitudes who are will- ing
                            to bear the cross and share the glory of Angelhood, sometime in the future, with the few who
                            are making, for themselves, Angel characters now, by bearing the Gross, as did Jesus,
                            against all sinful practices — and what do we find ? " Straight is the gate." Going back on
                            the record, they that find Life, are few. We reverently hope for a better record of the
                            future. It is reasonable to suppose, that the oft-expressed desire " to be saved from my
                            sins," would more generally express the truth, if worded, " to be saved IN my sins; " and
                            probably, there is no other instance in all Bible reading, where these two prepositions,
                            express the possible and impossible more truly. If saved at all, it will be away, apart from
                            our sins ; but never in them, nor while loving to practice sin. While the millions express
                            their anxiety for salvation, but few wish their fleshly lusts and worldly ambitions
                            disturbed ; and if salvation means annihilation to the pride of life, and to the general
                            catalogue of lusts, then, the number desiring salvation is reduced to a decimal. Christ came
                            to save people from their sins, by the gospel of self-denial — taste not, touch not, handle
                            not. But the doctrine of salvation by faith alone, " is the ignis fatuus of theology, that
                            never yet has been realized — it is imaginary. It promises a heaven without a cross; and
                            immediate change from a life of fleshly lusts into one of angel purity— a road so easy into
                            eternal felicity, that not one idol needs be burned, nor one base habit nor indul- gence
                            changed, no matter how earthly, sensual or devilish ! Oh, beautiful theory, how many myriads
                            hast thou thrilled with enchanting lays — oh, beautiful spider's web, how many human flies
                            hast thou ensnared to their utter deception ! What the world needs most, is salvation from
                            sin, to-day — self-denial; total abstinence from human lusts. All the theolo- gies extant,
                            have been unable to give proof of salvation, equaling the internal evidences of a humble,
                            true-hearted, travailing soul. And there is hope for the world, that mankind are outgrowing
                            the bondage of popular pulpit dogmas. Strive as may the established theologies of our day,
                            to seal the lips and blind the eyes of living souls, the truth of the present necessity of
                            practical salvation, is working a grand convincing commotion in the hearts of the people.
                            Christians do not sin — they are saved from the necessity of sinning ; and the idea that we
                            are all sinners and must remain so, is the second greatest lie of the devil, the first
                            being" Thou shalt not surely die !" We feel a supreme pity for those whited sepulchres, who
                            preach and pray, year in and out, of their being miserable sinners. Let them take up the
                            cross, of him whom they profess to love ; and so, living will be an every day antagonism to
                            sinful life, and an increasing salvation from the very thoughts of sin. Jesus, born with a
                            sinful nature, just like the rest of humanity, did, by laboring, strug- gling and wrestling
                            with the adversary of all good, progress to a point beyond the power of temptation, and was
                            saved from day to day. He stands to-d-ay an evidence that we too may enjoy the same blissful
                            fruition. Through the same struggles for salvation, must we all pass, or miss the prize. Our
                            pattern — Jesus — became the way, the truth and the life unto all Christians. And when we
                            walk that way, learn that truth and live that life, we shall experience the saving power of
                            his gospel, and not only know that we are saved, but know of the means by which our
                            salvation is accomplished ; and be able to impart the same power to others. It was an
                            ingenious device, of Luther, to have the "just saved by faith alone;" and this is the
                            desideratum of lazy, sin-loving hypocrites, who want to enter heaven without earning their
                            right there; who want Paradise brought to them, without their own exertions. But " faith,
                            without works is dead," and will work " death unto death," not salvation. Let cunning
                            speculators, in theology, continue to blindly lead the blind ; twist the truths of scripture
                            with anti-conscientious legerdemain ; to pamper the appetites of travelers on the broad road
                            ; let them speak as is pleasing and encouraging to carnal understandings, and receive
                            therefor, the applause of the multitude; and then, we make them welcome to their rewards,
                            when God distributes justice.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>Elder G. A. Lomas, Watervliet, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nurseries, Vermont, July 6, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Nurseries, near Winooski, Vt.,) July 6th,
                            1874.</head><p TEIform="p">Elder F. W. Evans, Editor of Shaker AND ShAKERESS. Respected Brother :—After some twen-
                            ty-five years have rolled away, since I had the pleasure of seeing you personally, with
                            other esteemed Brothers and Sisters, at Mt. Lebanon, S HE .A. K'JE R A.ND <pb n="67" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEEE88, 67 N. Y., who have ever held a place in my pleasant thoughts, I direct you
                            this line. Long ago I wrote to you and Bro. Bushnell, then living, and regret I did not
                            receive your answer. The books, you presented me, have been read by intellectual persons.
                            They were last carried to Burlington and left with radical and progressive men and women.
                            They, being spiritualists, like myself, liked them. As a traveling preacher I visited you. I
                            was blessed and enlightened. I have out-traveled the popular religions of the day. I am a
                            Free-Lover, and believe in the proper and scientific rights of generating the human species,
                            in accordance with the Laws of Life, as sacred, pure and virtuous, because natural and in
                            harmony with the reproductive forces of nature. But progressive liberals are advocates also
                            of continency, and, I believe, are truly of the most fastidious of the human race. For my
                            part, I feel akin, to a large extent, with your people, who seem to walk so near to God and
                            his Angels. The ideas of Samuel Hurlbut, of S. Union, Ky., are before me, as expressed in
                            your paper of May. I feel assured I can say Yea, with a heart full of earnestness, to his
                            invitation to 100,000 Shakers wanted—to all he so beautifully says, from No. 1 to the end of
                            No. 8. The community life leads to higher attainments. Truly these should lead to happiness.
                            Now, if radical " Free Lovers" could be accepted, to entertain their sentiments among you,
                            as a people, I doubt not, you would have many accessions to your numbers. I am thinking of
                            offering my lands, at least in part, for Community. Radicals, as we are, we cannot affiliate
                            with the selfishness, the impurity,the craft, the dishonesty, the untruth- fulness—the total
                            falsity of the world. We want a harmonious home, based on the social sciences, wherein we
                            may have a Temple of Freedom, and live simple, or plain, virtuous, intellectual and
                            progressive lives. Why can you not, as Brothers and Sisters, open the door of your community
                            ? Extend the hand of welcome, and bid us come in, to the number of a few hundred, it may
                            be—a Family or Families by ourselves, living out our progressive ideas, in entire harmony
                            with yours, cultivating for each other, mutual and lasting respect; as sacred, without
                            discordance or invasion of human rights—insured from intrusion. Such liberal, tolerant,
                            yielding, to each and all, the sovereign right to elect, or choose, a pure, holy, celibate
                            life; or a virtuous life, based on the principles of social science, with the scientific
                            propagation of the human species, as advocated by the most advanced radicals, in " Woodhull
                            and Claflin's Weekly." Could you all accord with this wise arrange- ment—as I believe it is,
                            and hope you can—I should feel to know the Temple of Harmony could be erected on the Earth.
                            I have ventured my thoughts—cultivating for you and for all you love and cherish, the
                            highest sentiments of respect. My family join me in wishing the Angel world may be all
                            around you. I am ever and faithfully yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shipman, Orrin" TEIform="persName"/>Orrin Shipman</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="July 14, 1874" TEIform="index"/>July 14, 1874</head><p TEIform="p">Orrin Shipman, Esteemed Friend : Your important letter, of the 6th instant, is in my
                            possession. The tone and spirit of it are good. People may disagree in doctrinal matters,
                            yet be one in spirit; or, they may be one in abstract ideas, and be diverse in spirit. "Ye
                            know not what spirit ye are of," was the gentle rebuke of Jesus to his Disciples, who had
                            forsaken all others, to follow him. You refer to a visit at Mt. Lebanon, some twenty-five
                            years ago, and to the favorable impression made upon your mind, by individuals, and by our
                            system. Among so many visitors and incidents, I do not recall that visit. After stating that
                            you are Free Lovers, of the Woodhull &amp; Claflin school, you express a wish to
                            fraternize with us, to the number of a few hundred, at least so far as our outward order —
                            the temporal — goes. I infer, from the fearless, yet friendly tenor of your communication,
                            that you are free-lovers from principle — a love of truth — and not for other supposed
                            additional indulgence attending the practice of your ideas. That, in fact, begging the
                            question that Shakers are right, and free-lovers wrong, per se, it is, with you, more a
                            matter of misunderstanding, than of love for unrighteousness — of confusion of ideas,
                            arising from the admixture of truthful principles that appertain to two distinct orders —
                            two discrete degrees. This causes both your agreement and disagreement with the Shakers. In
                            a word, the Shakers, with their asceticism, have more charity for, and do better understand
                            free-lovers, than do orthodox sectarians, whose actual lives approximate much nearer to
                            free-love sensualists, than they would care to have the world know or think. Is it not an
                            indisputable fact, that the popular idea of marriage, is that of a license, granted, by the
                            respective parents, to the Bride and Bridegroom, for them to live in fornication, without
                            public reproach or private condemnation ? The Church and State authorities sanction this
                            license — make it legal, and churched — and the neighbors silently ac- quiesce. Fruitf
                            ulness in this union in sensuality, is evidence of nature's vitality. The law of nature —
                            copulation for offspring only, being wholly ignored. Shakers regard this as the " agreement
                            with hell, and covenant with death." It is now being annulled by both classes of free-lovers
                            — one class substituting general promiscuity, thus making bad worse. The other class talk of
                            scientific propagation. The shakers discover no practical difference. Both are alike
                            obnoxious to censure, from those in the New Earth and the New Heavens. Two manners of people
                            exist—two discrete degrees of life and progress — a Propagating order and a Resurrection
                            order. To the hosts of embryonic beings, existing in the world that lies between conception,
                            and birth, the varying scenes of time and sense experienced by the army of children who have
                            been born, live, move and have their being in the outer world, are incomprehensible. When,
                            by evolution, these latter have become generative men and women, the scenes of life, in the
                            Resurrection order are, to them, equally incomprehensible. Of it Jesus spake, when He said,
                            " I have meat to eat, that ye know not of," in " that world, and the resurrection from the
                            dead." As a type of resurrected souls, the first — Jesus — was continually teaching others,
                            what He knew they could not then understand. But, in the last day when they would be
                            begotten again, into the kingdom of heaven, and be born again, into the kingdom of God, all
                            things that He had said unto them would come to their remembrance. If I have made my
                            premises plain, so he, who reads, may run, the conclusions will be easily apprehended. Your
                            complaint is, that you cannot affiliate with the selfishness, the craft, the dishonesty, the
                            untruthfulness — the total falsity of the world, as it is. Judging the tree by its fruit —
                            the system by its effects, you condemn it. In that, your class of Free-Lovers and the
                            Shakers agree. You want a harmonious home, based upon science — social science — where you
                            can live simple, plain, intellectual, progressive, virtuous lives. That is just what the
                            individuals, who have built up Shaker societies, wanted, and what they have found, or,
                            rather, achieved. It has been done by forsaking all appertaining to the propagative order —
                            natural relationships, arising from birth, and culminating in marriages; together with
                            selfish property rights and duties, culminating in monopoly of life elements, which generate
                            class distinctions and devastating wars. Woman can never be free until liberated from
                            physical maternity. Hence, as she feels the influences, coming from the Resurrection order —
                            "the Law, going forth from Zion," of the equality of the sexes, possible in the spiritual
                            order only, she fights maternity — she frets and chafes under its burdens and its
                            restricting duties. Then she kills and destroys what the legal lustful free-lover has not
                            destroyed and killed by his brute powers and uribrutal passions. You ask why we cannot open
                            our doors and take you in, as simple free-lovers, who desire scientific propagation, while
                            those, among you, who may prefer, like the Shakers, to live pure, holy, celibate lives, have
                            liberty so to do. An important question, which I desire to answer logically, not intending
                            the least disrespect to the questioner. Suppose a pack of wolves, who live upon mutton,
                            should thus address a flock of sheep : " God and Nature made us wolves and sheep and endowed
                            us with all our faculties, powers, passions and appetites — both communities — the pack and
                            the flock — recognize one common Creator, who is good. Why can we not fraternize and live in
                            love and peace together ? True, we are roving and unhappy, but, it is because we have not,
                            like you, a home, a fold and kind shepherd, who protects and provides. We do not wish to do
                            any thing wrong, or unnatural — any thing we ought not to do. Let us be good and fraternize
                            together. We mean no more harm in eating mutton, than you do in cropping the grass and the
                            flowers of the field. Lay aside your exclusiveness — be liberal — noble. Let us all live in
                            one fold — each party carrying out a line, according to our inherent rights, observing the
                            organic laws of our beings. This will be to the honor of our common Creator, and the mutual
                            happiness of each other." Can the leopard change his spots, or the wolf his tastes ? Will
                            they eat grass, like the ox and lamb ? Or would the pack of wolves refrain, when hungry,
                            from devouring the silly sheep, who had opened the door of their fold and admitted them in?
                            Judge ye, of your own selves, what is reasonable. Can two walk together, except they be
                            agreed? And if the Israelites were so taught the law of separation, that they were not
                            willing to sow divers kinds of seed together, nor, by generation to mix the blood of dif-
                            ferent species of animals, nor their own, by intermarrying with Gentiles, nor even to wear
                            linsey-wolsy garments, how much more should the children of this world, who " marry and are
                            given in marriage, be separated from the children of the Resurrection Order, who, like
                            Jesus, live pure, holy, celibate lives ? Are you not like fish, who are dissatisfied <pb n="68" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 68 SHAKER A.ND with the water, and yet would surely die upon the land ?
                            If those waters have become muddy — land and water mingled — is it not because the law of
                            separation has been violated, and the waters have not obeyed the command : " Hitherto shalt
                            thou come, and no further 1" This creates amphibious creatures, in the earth. And the
                            Revelator saw unclean spirits, like frogs — amphibious — come out of the mouth of the false
                            prophet, and out of the mouth of the beast and of his image." Out of church and state —
                            flesh and spirit — organizationsBabylon means mixture. It is the continued attempt to mingle
                            generation and regeneration together. Such is Christendom. And now, that a Second Christian
                            Church has been in existence for nearly one hundred years, you propose for it to lapse back
                            into Quakerism, from whence it arose. Upon due consideration, do you think the extinction of
                            our order would be a blessing ? A Shaker is one who holds that true marriage has an order of
                            its own — that a New Earth will arise, fulfilling the ideal of the most enlightened,
                            scientific rationalists, like yourselves. In it all earthly good will be gathered, Poverty,
                            War, Prostitution, legal and illegal, and disease will be supplanted by Plenty, Peace,
                            Chastity, Health. The equality of the sexes will be established and secured, and
                            cooperation—not community — become universal. The New Heaven, or Spiritual Order — the
                            Church — will be distinct and entirely separate from the civil government of the Natural
                            Order — the New Earth — and will derive its authority, through Divine Revelation, from the
                            Christ, or Resurrection Heavens. " There will be no more sea," or Church and State
                            governments. Trusting that the kindly tone and spirit of your letter are preserved in this
                            communication, I submit it to the crucible of your rationalistic, spiritualistic,
                            intuitional and revelational powers. May the very spirit of truth possess us increasingly,
                            to the glory of God, and the good of humanity.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Drugs" TEIform="index"/>DRUGS</head><p TEIform="p">Most happy have I just been made, by reading, in the last issue of this monthly, the strong
                            testimony of such eminent physicians as Johnson and Magendie, against the false science of
                            medicine. Having no basis on facts, it can never become a science whereby the cause of
                            diseases can be removed. Alopath and Homopath imply other and new diseases, by means of
                            which the absurd effort of curing the old one is put forth. As well say, two wrongs make one
                            right — that evil spirits may be cast out by Beelzebub. Strictly speaking, disease is the
                            merciful effort, nature puts forth, to remove an enemy from the body. It is a friend, not a
                            foe, to be drugged, or doctored. Snuffis an enemy. Sneeze is a disease. Instead of
                            restraining, or fighting such efforts, we should befriend them. Professor Magendie says: "
                            Nature does a great deal." Yea, in the truest sense, all. We may, and ought to, undo what we
                            have done amiss. If the sick be cold, warm. If too warm, cool — cleanse, inside and out,
                            from all filthiness of flesh — acting, in all respects, with, not against, the wise efforts
                            of nature. Dr. Franklin, in his celebrated almanac, had, among others, this wise saying —
                            God cures — the physician collects the fee." A fine poet expresses the same sentiment thus:
                            " Nature resists the injuries done her, Drugs and doctors get the honor." Thousands, who
                            have not yet, the moral stamina to adopt the great Shaker reform — apply the ax to the root
                            of evil — lust and avarice — will gladly join them in applying it to bad diet, and even more
                            destructive drugging.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, W." TEIform="persName"/>W. Perkins, Irving, 1U-</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Two edged sword" TEIform="index"/>TWO EDGED SWORD</head><p TEIform="p">Judgment shall begin at the house of God. And if its inhabitants scarcely be saved, where
                            shall the sinner and ungodly appear, who are without God and hope of salvation, in the world
                            1 So far as any, who are numbered with the people of God, are slaves to perverted appe-
                            tites — physical sins — either willfully, or through ignorance, will they be under the curse
                            — bondage to sickness and diseases. Staying ourselves upon the Lord, aa his peculiar people,
                            the time has fully come — the trumpet of the second degree of Gospel travel begins to sound,
                            calling us away from all bondage and slavery, to any of the lusts of the flesh and mind. As
                            a body, we must, by devotedness and perseverance, stand, like a rock in the ocean, against
                            the flood of stimulating beverages, whether in the form of drinks or medical tinctures, as
                            dragon's blood, No. 6, or of cordials, that prepare for the use of opium and other poisonous
                            narcotics. These are not incentives to duty, nor do they prepare souls for the true service
                            of God. Is it not a singular hallucination of the mind, that leads professing Christians to
                            seek pleasure in unrighteousness — in the use of things, destructive of perfect health ?
                            When Jesus said, " Except a man forsake all that he hath," did it not include the hankering
                            arising from his adulterated nature — abnormal appetites in food and drink, and drugs and
                            doses ? Nature, as God created it, would preserve every faculty, desire and feeling, of body
                            and mind, in perfect unison with the spirit of God — the Law of use. The result would be
                            order, decorum, in all things, temporal and spiritual, in the new creation. Why should there
                            be physical infirmity as the product of physiological sin, any more than there should be
                            condemnation of soul — remorse of conscience — as the effect of spiritual transgressions ?
                            Nature and God are in harmony, as are science and religion. When there is a testimony
                            against this, or that, as being natural, it is perverted nature; or it is that something,
                            properly pertaining to one order, is intruded into another, and more spiritual order. Let
                            God be true, and truly acknowledged, if it prove every man and woman to be, by some ungodly
                            habit, as a limb out of its joint and socket. God is no respecter of persons, and that which
                            is hygienically wrong will create disease in the saint, as in the sinner — in the Shaker, as
                            in the Presbyterian. As are the penalties for physical and physiological sins, in the one,
                            so are they in the other. Where much is given, much is required. Of all the people in
                            Christendom, you have I known ; therefore will I punish you for your bodily iniquities, even
                            as I would have done for your soul errors. Now, as there begins to be some plainness of
                            speech, in the Shaker and Shakeress, in relation to our own society sins, let us set the
                            world an example of humility, by accepting the reproof of a friend, as better than the kiss
                            of an enemy — until the sins of Zion shall be sought for, by friend and foe, and shall not
                            be found — till the iniquities of foul air, bad cooking, improper food, uncleansed sewers,
                            stopped-up drains, dirty water, mixed drinks, and the eating of physic, instead of food,
                            shall be looked for — and there shall be none. dark Hayden, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. '* Set a mark
                            upon all, who sigh and cry, because of the abominations that are done in J erusalem," was
                            the voice of the Christ Spirit, to the Prophet. Reformers see, intellectually, the errors of
                            the present, and the truths of the future. Prophets see, spiritually, the sina of the saints
                            of the existing church, which the increase of God, will remove. Reformers belong to the
                            earthly order — Prophets, to the spiritual order. In each, there are two classes. One breeds
                            divisions, makes innovations, incites insurrections and creates revolutions. They attempt to
                            correct existing errors, in the interest of their own selfhood, using war as a means. It is
                            the Devil reproving sin — and the Devil opposing, and oppressing the Reformer, and killing
                            the Prophet — one Spirit. When that class of Reformers and Prophets conquer, they are
                            defeated. The other class are in union with what ia. When they speak the word — the coming
                            truth — it cuts both ways — cuts the Reformer, and the righteous, who need to be reformed—
                            the Prophet, and the sinning saints, who will confess and forsake, in the light of the New
                            Degree.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Editor</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obedience" TEIform="index"/>OBEDIENCE</head><p TEIform="p">" For I am a man under authority having soldiers under me, and I say to this man, Go, and he
                            goeth, and to another, Come, and he cometh, and to my servant, Do this, and he doeth it."
                            Matt, viii, 9. " Obedience is the first duty of a soldier" are the opening words of the
                            British Articles of War, a copy of which is put in the hands of every private soldier. War
                            chieftains have ever been alive to the paramount importance of maintaining discipline
                            amongst their followers. Without this nothing but defeat and dishonor could attend the
                            movements of the best appointed army. To secure obedience the severest penalties are
                            attached to the crime of insubordination, and mutiny is mercilessly stamped out. Earl St.
                            Vincent was the most rigid of disciplinarians and, it is said, he infused the spirit of
                            prompt obedience throughout the entire British navy, and thus raised its destructive
                            efficiency to a standard unparalleled amongst other maritime powers. It is, indeed, the
                            tritest truism, that the subjection of one to another is necessary to success in any and
                            every undertaking requiring the association of individuals. This fact is recognized the
                            world over, and to secure order and submission to authority, pains and penalties are called
                            into requisition, experience teaching only too surely that, in the present hellish
                            constitution of society, this is the only way of attaining the end in view. Withdraw the
                            influence of fear, and anarchy would result; for pride, envy, malice and all the evil
                            passions of human nature would conspire to make people rebel against even the best of
                            governments. But in a millennial state of society, all will possess that strength of
                            character and devotion to principle, which will enable them to govern themselves, and submit
                            themselves to be governed. Already there exist individuals on this earth — but alas how few
                            in number—who are thus devoted to principle, and consecrated to Truth ! Under the mild rule
                            of the Gospel an appeal is made to the higher nature of human beings, and love induces that
                            obedience which only fear commands in the world. This is a very simple and a very sure test
                            of Gospel travail. Do love and devotion to principle procure that obedience from me that
                            fear of punishment would in the world ? Just in proportion as they fail to do so, do I fall
                            short of regeneration.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brown, Hewson" TEIform="persName"/>Hewson Brown, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Religious Philosophical Journal of Chicago is winning golden opinions..." TEIform="index"/>The Religious Philosophical Journal of Chicago is winning golden opinions...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The Religious Philosophical Journal of Chicago is winning golden opinions among moralists and
                            the better class of spiritualists, because taking strong ground against the free-lust
                            practices of many professed spiritualists. This is a "judgment day" in the ranks of
                            spiritualism.</p></div2><pb n="69" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: wars" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: WARS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">Why should we marvel that the spirit and element of war have out-lived the centuries of the
                            past and are so rife to-day in all nations whether professedly civilized and Christianized
                            or otherwise, when that spirit has been fostered, encouraged and glorified, by every
                            succeeding generation, since the day that Cain Blew his brother ? And those who have
                            accepted the Bible, as a whole, for the inspired word of God—that it is the Alpha and Omega
                            of the Divine will to men—have taken shelter under the wings of the God of the Jews, when
                            they have marked the pages of history with the blood of martyred heretics. And why should
                            they be deemed culpable when the Hebrew God did justify and encourage war ? It would appear,
                            from historic records, that many times he was General-in-chief of the armies of Israel, and
                            used spiritualistic powers to crush and slay tens of thousands of men and helpless women and
                            children. Should not mortals be commended for striving to be Godlike ? When we come down to
                            the Christian era/we ask, How could the Jews, who were conscientiously tenacious of the Law,
                            and were bound to and oy the traditions of their fathers —their kings and seers—be condemned
                            for persecuting Jesus and his disciples who taught the Gospel? They believed in Moses, and
                            knew tiiat God spake through him, and gave the code of laws and commandments which had
                            sustained and guided their nation through centuries. Of Jesus, they said, "as for this
                            fellow, we know not from whence he is." Moses taught, " an eye for an eye—tooth for tooth."
                            Jesus said, " resist not evil." The Law said, " Love thy neighbor and hate thine enemy."
                            Jesus said not so. Love your enemy—render good for evil. Instead of burning for burning —
                            return blessing for cursing. This Gospel changed conditions radically. Let us hear a few of
                            the declarations of the Lord God of the Jews. (We must confess that the moral sensibilities
                            are shocked, and a cold chill creeps over us when we read the following) : " If I whet my
                            glittering sword, and my hand takes hold on j udgment, I will render vengeance to mine
                            enemies, and reward them that hate me. I will send the teeth of beasts upon them, with the
                            poison of serpents." Again. " The Lord will come with fire and chariots, like a whirlwind to
                            render his anger with fury, and his rebuke with flames of fire. It is the day of the Lord's
                            vengeance. Give them sorrow of heart—thy curse ;—persecute and destroy them in thy anger." "
                            Thus saith the Lord God: Woe to the bloody city ! Heap on wood—kindle the fire— consume the
                            flesh—spice it well, and let the bones be burnt." Was there any thing perpetrated during the
                            "dark ages" more cruel and intolerant in perse- cuting the so-called "Heretics" than the
                            foregoing? Burning at the stake, the sword and gibbet —the rack and dungeon—and even
                            surrendering human beings to wild beasts to be torn in pieces, could all find justification
                            in the Jewish scriptures. Then how shall we find a solution of the matter. Shall we conclude
                            that the old scriptures are annulled—no longer binding upon the subjects of the New
                            Covenant— which teaches love in place of hate—mercy in lieu of vengeance ? Then we ask, Were
                            those laws good and valid, in olden time ? If so, by whom were they given ? If, by the God
                            of the Universe, why subject to change ? In this reasoning age, a Court of inquiry is called
                            and an investigating Committee has already undertaken to find whether, after making all due
                            allowance for mistranslations and interpolations, it be necessary to accept all the seeming
                            absurdities and contradictions of the Scripture Records. Or if it be possible to harmonize
                            the Scriptures with reason and common sense, as well as with the religious sentiments of the
                            age in which we live. It is evident from all of Nature's works (which are but an outward
                            expression of the interior spiritual forces of the unseen world) that it was not the design
                            of the creative Powers to perfect the earth, or its inhabitants, by sudden organic changes
                            and convulsive throes; but by gradual growth from one degree to another, as from infancy to
                            mature manhood. It is but reasonable to conclude that tutelar divinities from time to time
                            have been adapted to the condition of the people, and that as they progressed and were
                            prepared for it, higher intelligences could find access to them. The tutelage depended upon
                            the preparation of those over whom they were sent to preside. It is also very evident, that
                            at times, the prophets of those days were visited and inspired by spirits of a high order,
                            even from the inner heavens ; and they were caused to shadow forth in beautiful pictures,
                            the glories of the coming ages, when their warring God should cease to rule—and their
                            "spears should be converted into pruning hooks, and their swords into plow-shares." War is
                            incompatible with true Christian principles, and never emanated from that God who is Wisdom
                            and Love. It matters not whether religious frenzy, political strife, ambition, revenge, or
                            jealousy be the moving cause, it is demoyiiac, and causes the fires of lust to burn in the
                            souls and bodies of those who engage in it. Let every truth-lover unite in prayerful
                            investigation, and seek for more light—more truth—and let new springs of life open, that we
                            may drink therefrom and be renewed. Let old things, ideas, thoughts and feelings, — be
                            analyzed and shaken, if need be, all that is good and true will remain. The windows of the
                            soul should be open to let in the sunlight of Divine revelation and the inspirational
                            breezes which come from the heavens; and when the angels sound the trumpet for an increase,
                            let all who profess to be rising with Christ in the new life, on the resurrection plane, be
                            ready to advance forward. We must remember that to the increase, in the subjects of Christ's
                            kingdom, there will be no end.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Action" TEIform="index"/>ACTION</head><p TEIform="p">Life and action are manifest in all the vast creation of God's universe. Whether visible, or
                            invisible to the external perception, change is constantly wrought by development, or
                            diminution; even in the sterile rock, or the mosses that grow thereon — action is appar-
                            ent. Look at yon mountain, we may say its aspect to us is the same that it was years ago ;
                            but geologists would undoubtedly tell us of marvelous changes and transformations, that had
                            been wrought by Nature's ceaseless action, both when we wake and when we sleep. As-
                            tronomers tell us of changes in the stellar regions. " They that go down to the sea in
                            ships, that do business in great waters," could tell of the foaming changing waves of the
                            restless ocean, and how those waters teem with life and action. The seasons come and go in
                            regular succession, bringing seed-time and harvest — summer and winter, while forests deepen
                            with the growth of years. The mineral and vegetable kingdoms, and the lower order of animals
                            produce their kind, in harmony with Nature's laws ; all acting in unison with the First
                            Great Cause; but, where do we find man, who was formed to be the noblest — the crowning work
                            of God's creation ? May we count him as the connecting link, a controlling force in the
                            great chain that spans the universe, to unite that which is below him with the Giver and
                            Fructifier of all life? It is true, action marks his course. In Art, Science and Literature,
                            he commands ; but he often sways the sceptre of power unjustly, over those below him in rank
                            and fortune, and thus misdirects, and abuses the talent that is given him for good and noble
                            purposes. If man, as lord of the creation, had kept in rectitude — subject to law and order
                            — and through dependence, had maintained an unbroken union and communion with his Maker, he
                            might have made this earth a terrestrial paradise ; and his connection with all of God's
                            creation would have been harmonious and true. But through selfishness, pride and arrogance,
                            he has wandered far from the position that he was designed to occupy ; and captured, in a
                            net of his own weaving, he has become entangled therein; and is unable to extricate himself.
                            He has become a slave to the lower instincts of his nature. Thus, while in captivity to the
                            law of sin, he exclaims, " 0 wretched man that I am! Who shall deliver me from the body of
                            this death ? " The finer feelings of the soul, are blunted and crushed by the deception of
                            the serpentine nature. Even as a bird becomes a prey in the grasp of its alluring enemy, so
                            does the human heart become a prey to wild, unsubdued, animal propensities. Many suffer the
                            tempter to lead them to sip from the cup of sensuality, till they create depraved appetites,
                            with unabated cravings, which they have not power to resist. Such fall lower and lower,
                            until they are really forced as it were, to drink to the dregs, the cup which the Revelator
                            said, " would be poured out in indignation without mixture." Moral and spiritual death
                            ensues — the soul is held with rigid grasp — the mental faculties are weakened, and the
                            physical body goes down to a premature grave. Do we not see evident marks of death and decay
                            in deformed men and women, with pale emaciated visages stalking broadcast through the land,
                            at the present time ? The image of the heavenly is effaced, and God is not found in their
                            thoughts, nor ways. But, when we look upon the grand picture that Nature spreads out before
                            our vision, ever increasing in order and beauty, typical of the world beyond, we find a
                            sweet and gentle monitor. Whether she speaks in the thunder's <pb n="70" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> TO
                            SHA.KER crash—the vivid lightning's glow— the ocean's roar, or in the rippling stream. — we
                            find, her the same wise teacher. If at times she stands as a stern reprover, it is for the
                            purpose of creating healthy action. Order is the product of obedience — disobedience results
                            in disorder and confusion. Query : Is there no way of returning to the statutes and laws of
                            God and Nature ? no waymarks left to guide the feet of the wandering, to the Father's house
                            ? Truly, if the prodigal sons and daughters, who have traversed the wilderness of sin,
                            really become tired of feeding on husks, and will turn, and by true repentance, which is
                            forsaking, retrace their steps, they will find the highway of holiness, that is cast up for
                            the ransomed of the Lord to walk in; and that there is a refuge for the weary and oppressed,
                            from the rude storm of a sin-blighted world — an ark of safety — a home of joy — a home for
                            body and soul, where all material and spiritual needs are well supplied. The invitation is
                            extended to such, to " Repent and be converted that their sins may be blotted out; " and to
                            prepare for " the times of refreshing, that shall come from the presence of the Lord."
                            Justification must be attained by returning to orderly conditions. Through positive
                            innocence, which conies by trial, souls may be brought into harmonial relations with God and
                            Nature, and join in one universal song of praise and good-will.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna White, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hope" TEIform="index"/>HOPE</head><p TEIform="p">We shall meet beyond the river, Where the harps iEolian chime, There to clasp our hands
                            together, On the other side of time. Tow'ring mounts may here divide us, Storms may threaten
                            fora time ; Storms nor mounts, can there divide us, When we reach that happy clime. In the
                            truth, naught can alarm us ; Toes without and foes within, Ne'er can gain the power to h;trm
                            us, If our hearts are free from sin. Not to live for joy and beauty, Are we called while
                            here in time; But to walk the path of duty, Till we reach the summer clime. Look beyond 1
                            there's light before us, Like a shilling mantle there ; And God's love is with and o'er us ;
                            We are folded in his care. Let a holy purpose guide us— While we stem the stream of time ;
                            And from earth's illusions hide us, Till we reach that sun bright clime. Faith, the gift
                            that God has given, Is to us a beacon star; That will lead our souls to Heaven, From earth's
                            elements afar. When we reach the pearly portal, Songs of joy shall to us come ; And dear
                            friends, long since immortal, Gladly bid us welcome home.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wheeler, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>Maria Wheeler, Union Village, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Invocation" TEIform="index"/>INVOCATION</head><p TEIform="p">Our Heavenly Parents, we bow our hearts in humble acknowledgment of the manifold blessings we
                            have received individually and collectively ! And we ask a continuance of divine favors ;
                            the greatest of which is power to live truly—to be just to our own souls, and to all
                            mankind. More especially do we render thanks that we live in a day and time when the Mother
                            in Deity is revealed, as a co-worker with the Father. We have felt the power of love that
                            emanates from her pure spirit. Now, souls are begotten and brought forth in the New
                            Creation, bearing the image of the Heavenly. With the spiritual vision open, and with
                            quickened understanding they are able to comprehend divine things ; and by putting an end to
                            sinful works, the mystery, which gathers round and clings to false theologies, is finished.
                            Our God, we not only ask a continuance of the light and power, that have been so freely and
                            mercifully dispensed to us, but we ask an increase of the same, to enable us to live still
                            nearer to the truth, that we may honor and glorify our Heavenly Parents, by doing their will
                            on earth as it is done in the spheres of light, by those who have risen with Christ in the
                            true resurrection, and stand upon a sea of glass, singing songs of joyful praises that they
                            have gotten the perfect victory. By Divine assistance, we will renew our vows to endure the
                            chastenings, which increasing light and truth may bring upon us, and place our all upon the
                            altar of self-abnegation counting not the carnal life dear; but nerve ourselves to pass
                            through the furnace, and not flinch, until we are refined from all that is earthly, and
                            reflect the image that is heavenly. Thus, the Zion of God on earth will be a beacon light
                            upon the hill of practical truth, that cannot be hid; but will give light to those who are
                            in darkness, who have sought happiness in the broad road of sinful indulgence, and have
                            never tasted the superior joys of a life consecrated to true principles. We ask a blessing
                            upon all the nations of the earth. Visit the rulers of every land, and teach them justice ;
                            how to render good for evil and blessing for cursing, that wars may cease to the ends of the
                            earth; show them that it is far better for mortals, from the king to the peasant, to humble
                            themselves in mercy than to be humbled in judgment. And especially, O Lord, do we ask, that
                            a merciful visitation of conviction for wrong doing and repentance toward Thee, may rest
                            upon our own nation. O, may the Spirit of Truth find a dwelling place in this land, that has
                            hitherto been blessed above all others. If, in thy wisdom, O Lord, thou hast chosen America
                            to be the home of the oppressed of other nations,—where freedom of conscience can be
                            enjoyed—grant that it may also lead in the van of moral action, and religious truth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Potter, Eleanor" TEIform="persName"/>Eleanor Potter, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-conquest" TEIform="index"/>SELF-CONQUEST</head><p TEIform="p">History declares that those nations who have lived the most luxuriously and voluptuously,
                            after a few successive generations, have degenerated into mental and physical effeminacy,
                            and lost their power to efficiently sway the national sceptre, or for self-government ; for
                            what is true of nations, may be applied, with equal force to individuals, of whom fam-
                            ilies, communities and nations are formed. Every act of unrestrained self-indulgence, lowers
                            the moral tone, — debilitates the vital nervous forces — detracts from mentality— darkens
                            spiritual perceptions, and merges the individual into abnormal conditions of slavish
                            servitude to the low propensity—life. The powers and functions of our being, are for use,
                            not abuse; and the action of the will, should be subservient to the higher moral law, which
                            directs to lofty aims, and genuine purposes, in the exercise of all the faculties ; that
                            happiness, not misery, may follow our deeds. The ten days of pleasure, spent on one of the
                            loveliest isles of the ocean, by Seged, the Prince of Ethiopia, where the beauty and
                            simplicity of nature could not fail to mock his regal grandeur, leaves a moral to the
                            pleasure seeking world, that is worthy of consideration. All that wealth could procure —
                            genius invent, and art produce—the charms of beauty — the gaiety of fashion — the liquid
                            strains of music, mingled with the voice of mirth — the tippling of the social glass, and
                            fullness of feasting, interspersed with the flattery of courtiers, and the pompous array of
                            kingly power and dictation, failed to give satisfaction. At the close of each day's varied
                            scenes, there remained some poignant sting to pierce his heart, and wound his conscience. He
                            proved beyond a doubt that " a man of pleasure is a man of pain." The lowliest of his
                            subjects were happier, in their humble situation, than was Seged in the midst of lavish
                            indulgences. " Vanity of vanities and vexation of spirit," is the sum of human life, when
                            happiness through the gratification of the senses is made the only object of pursuit. "Deny
                            thyself" — taught the sweet souled — self-conquered Nazarene. It was just this beautiful
                            spirit of self-denial, that thwarted the tempter — crushed the hydra-headed monster — lust
                            in every form — subdued gross appetites, leveled vain ambition, stifled avarice, and carried
                            him up into the sublime realities of spiritual life. In his expanded soul-love for humanity,
                            he said, " If I be lifted up, I will draw all men unto me." He would not lower his standard
                            to come to them ; but whither he went, they might go. Through the same self-denial and
                            self-sacrifice, they might ascend into the sphere of divine life and goodness, in which it
                            was his delight to dwell. " The joys of conquest, are the joys of man." The wise of the
                            earth have proved this beyond doubt. Sages, philosophers, and truthloving souls, in all
                            ages, who have turned "with disgust from the follies and evils of a worldly life, and have
                            carried out their exalted ideal of a glorious, perfected life, have given evidence of the
                            superior joys arising therefrom ; even though error was mingled with their religious
                            asceticism. Many carried the idea to the ultra point of belief, that the body was an enemy
                            to the soul. Yet the principle involved, of subjecting the inferior to the superior part of
                            their being, was right; for they who bestow all their care and concern upon the outward, and
                            seek physical enjoyment, regardless of the unfoldment of their higher natures and spiritual
                            powers, are living for a low purpose. Self-conquest, is the price of lasting happiness,— the
                            soul's seal of lasting bliss. True heroism is requisite to accomplish this great work. Not
                            the brute force of base passion, by carnal weapons, but the firm immovable resolve of
                            enthroned Reason and immortal Virtue. " Self-discipline is the soul of the law," said a
                            Buddhist. And we add, It is the very soul of right living. The youth, who has moral courage
                            when ripening into manhood or womanhood, in the flush and vigor of life, to strike out in
                            the narrow path of self-culture and strict discipline in right educational prin- ciples, is
                            on the royal road to unfading glory ; and will achieve greater success than the sons of
                            ambition, who seek conquest through ignoble strife to win the perishable laurels of earthly
                            fame. " He who governs and conquers his own spirit, is mightier than he who taketh a city;"
                            being conscious that they are perfecting a soul work that will create him, or her, in the
                            image of Divinity, that shall command the respect of man, and win the plaudits of angels. If
                            " there was joy in heaven over one sinner that repented," will there not be greater
                            rejoicing over one, who, through self-denial, crucifies the nature whence sin proceeds ; and
                            nobly rises above those elements 1 Beautiful were those words of wisdom and counsel, spoken
                            long ago: " Remember thy Creator in the days of thy youth, while the evil days come not, nor
                            the years draw nigh, when thou shalt say, I have no pleasure in them." Evil will surely
                            follow those who willfully violate the laws of their being; for their deeds will cause them
                            shame, and unless obliterated by confession and repentance, their sun of life will set in
                            darkness ; while gladness cheers and sweetens the cup of life, as the self-conqueror moves
                            on the homeward journey. Like the " sweet influences of the Pleiades" the light of their
                            memory shall be.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Martha J. Anderson, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beautiful example" TEIform="index"/>BEAUTIFUL EXAMPLE</head><p TEIform="p">" When ye are reviled, revile not again," was the teaching of the Divinely Anointed Jesus.
                            How nobly he exemplified the spirit of forgiveness in his own life and character! When his
                            persecutors afflicted him and filled his soul with anguish (as far as they had the power),
                            and made his pathway thorny and difficult to travel, he did not retaliate nor seek to harm
                            them, neither did he feel bitterness of spirit toward his enemies. When he knew that the
                            crucifix awaited him, and the hour drew nigh when his body would thereon be suspended, and
                            his disciples whom he had loved, blessed and comforted, AND <pb n="71" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEEES8.
                            had, through fear of ruthless foes, denied or forsaken him, how beautiful were his soul-
                            breathings, when he said, referring to his persecutors, " Father, forgive them; they know
                            not what they do 1 Was not that a manifestation of love toward his enemies that was not of
                            the world 1 They mocked him—smote and spit upon him—and crowned him with thorns ; but all
                            this did not move him to anger. With faith unwavering to the last he meekly bowed in
                            resignation, and in sweet, deep-toned accents, said, " Father, into thy hands I commend my
                            spirit!" Would that all who profess the Christian name, follow his example ; and strive to
                            be like the pattern—like the first born Christian in regard to the principle of forgiveness.
                            He took hold of Justice with one hand, and of Mercy with the other, and prayed, " Forgive us
                            our debts, as we forgive our debtors." As we forgive men who trespass against us, so will
                            our Heavenly Father and Mother forgive us, when we trespass upon the laws of God. If people
                            would repeat, what is called "the Lord's prayer," understanding]y, and make it effectual by
                            living it, what a change would be wrought in society ! Without a practical application, it
                            is worthless. The S. and S. is a small organ, but large enough to convey messages of truth.
                            And we earnestly desire that it may be a fearless exponent of error, all that is false, and
                            at the same time bear marks of true love, charity and Christian benevolence. May it be like
                            a snow white dove, Winging its way from sea to sea, Bearing the blessed balm of love,
                            Breathing good Will and charity.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Burger, Martha A." TEIform="persName"/>Martha A. Burger, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Motherhood" TEIform="index"/>MOTHERHOOD</head><p TEIform="p">Who is a mother ? She. who strongly holds A little group of ties of kindred blood ; Whose
                            dearest treasures are the hearts she folds, Whose one ambition is their joy, their good. Her
                            deep, deep love, knows not the ebbing wave That wrecks the heart on life's dark treacherous
                            tides; She takes the path that leadeth to the grave, If on it duty, to her loved, abides.
                            Her self-forgetfulness is still the same, Affection prompts her ever helpful hand; From
                            childhood's foible unto manhood's aim She, patient, suffers for that little band. Yet she is
                            only like the brooding bird That spreads her breast against the coming storm, That trembles
                            not, when thunders loud are heard, But, self-reliant, keeps her fledglings warm. From fierce
                            gorilla, down to sightless mole, The female loves and cherishes her charge, Then cannot
                            woman, with immortal soul, That narrow scope of motherhood enlarge? If she have children,
                            they should bind her heart To sympathize with every child on earth ; To make all mothers'
                            care of her's a part, And claim her hand to sow the seeds of worth. But if no little ones
                            around her cling, Then is she free to toil where need is great, To gather orphans 'neath her
                            sheltering wing, And be an angel in the way of fate. Yea, she whose mind may tread a path of
                            stars, Whose aspirations heavenly circuits take, Shall pass, with seraphs, through all bolts
                            and bars, 'Till fettered captives learn their chains to break, And wrongs, that now cry
                            loudly unto God, Will sink in silence, and dissolve in air, When the weak victims that
                            oppression trod, Shall rise to freedom, and develop there. No more will they the crystal
                            goblet fill With crimson serpents to infest the brain ; No more will they the unborn infant
                            kill, Nor blight its life with sin's corroding stain. And draining luxury (death's haughty
                            aid), That slays with famine and with overflow, With false religion shall be lowly laid,
                            Where cold oblivion's misty waters flow. When, mortals feel that God created them, In that
                            grand " image," male and female too, Maternal love shall, like a diadem, Enwrap the soul and
                            give it impulse new.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>Cecelia Devyr, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="False and true" TEIform="index"/>FALSE AND TRUE</head><p TEIform="p">As I lift the curtain of retirement, which screens my mind from the turbulent sea of life, as
                            it generally exists, what do I behold ? A striving, self-serving, world-loving throng.
                            Consequent to the legalized sin, land monopoly, one underlying cause of human distress, and
                            of the unjust bearing of other man-made laws, all classes of society are made sufferers.
                            Those whose circumstances permit, amass great wealth, which their own toil neither creates
                            nor sustains ; and they revel in luxuries deleterious to both body and soul; which cause an
                            idle, artificial life, wherein contentment finds no abode. And, while they seek renown and
                            honor in the eyes of the aristocracy, they are envied by those whose very nerve and sinew
                            provide their support, and whose unremitting but unrecompensed toil secures, to themselves,
                            scarcely the necessities of life; while they are debarred from that degree of mental, social
                            and moral culture, requisite to carry them above the low society and debasing influences
                            engendered by poverty. Thus is labor robbed of its dignity, and it becomes an irksome yoke
                            to those upon whom it falls so heavily. As life is stamped on every feature of the universe,
                            those who do not find employment in simple, useful industries, will resort to illegitimate
                            means. Hence we see those whose abnormal physical appetites, seek gratification in gluttony
                            and other low forms of animal life, with corresponding mental excitements ; for which
                            ball-rooms, theaters, and other places of vain amusements amply provide. Another class,
                            gorge the intellect without reference to use, and without practical application. With such,
                            spirituality is supplanted, leaving little room for the divine inflowings needful to render
                            life acceptable to individuals, or a blessing to humanity. With deep lament we behold the
                            masses worship at Fashion's unhallowed shrine. Many, whose young hearts blossom hopefully in
                            spring-time, which is a prophecy of good fruit in maturer years, are induced to sell all
                            else (save a carnal life) to ape those who monopolize wealth, and degrade honest labor while
                            they seek to exalt idleness, extravagance, and their associate evils, and make them
                            respectable. Rising above this vast multitude, we thank- fully recognize those of sterling
                            integrity, through whom the voice of truth is nobly uttered, relative to the various needed
                            reforms of the day. We ask blessing upon every one whose life is dedicated to humanity's
                            weal, and look with compassion upon sad, weary hearts, whose inner thirstings can never be
                            satisfied with perishing joys; and who seek love in a broader purer sphere, than earthly
                            relationships can afford; and we invite them, with us, to turn from the sorrowful picture.
                            The curtain falls — the scene changes — and what the vision 1 A peaceful, holy seclusion —
                            sweet rest in the truth — a home for the soul. We see a band, in whom the fires of
                            Pentecostal love have been kindled, prompting to a common brother and sister-hood — a united
                            inheritance — an impartial distribution of the blessings of life. One clean spot on earth,
                            teeming with beauty, and smiling with abundant harvest; made fruitful to those by whom labor
                            is exalted and divested of its painful yoke, and brightened by the angel touch of
                            consecration. This is true life, in which all the faculties of being may be brought into the
                            service of God, and still be richly fraught with enjoyment and a healthy condition of
                            physical, social, intellectual and spiritual senses, be enjoyed. Eternal principles are
                            lived by those who have pledged themselves to sell all for the " priceless pearl" ; and a
                            relationship is thus formed which robs death of its sting, and the grave of its victory. And
                            by united efforts a second temple is reared whose doors are open to all true worshipers of
                            the living God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/>Catharine Allen, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="story" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Berries among weeds" TEIform="index"/>BERRIES AMONG WEEDS</head><p TEIform="p">Among the most pleasant of our summer employments, is that of gathering strawberries. Whether
                            we go into the gardens to secure the rich crops raised by our good brethren, or ramble
                            through the fields and meadows in quest of the sweet wild fruit, it matters little: for
                            interest and pleasure are combined with our labor. It was my fortune, one warm day last
                            summer, to discover an old strawberry bed that had been abandoned to weeds, which had grown
                            very rank. I was impressed to make a thorough investigation of the down-trodden patch, and
                            was rewarded with an ample supply of bright red berries; and I also learned a profitable
                            lesson. I was led to reflect that the human mind is like a garden, wherein weeds and fruit
                            grow together; and that, many times, it is difficult to see aught else but weeds; and how
                            apt we are to turn away, and think it is useless to look for any good thing from such
                            sources. I was instructed that it is far better to exercise patience, and to search
                            diligently for good plants and fruit, and to use our best exertions to destroy the noxious
                            weeds, and preserve the good vines or plants. We are all placed in the garden of Eden, to
                            dress and to keep it. The germs of a higher life are committed to us to develop; and, if we
                            are diligent and faithful, we shall make our paradise more beautiful, instead of losing it;
                            and shall draw thither good angels to dwell with us, and instruct us in those things which
                            pertain to eternal life. Inspired by such impressions, I resolved anew never to slacken my
                            hand in cultivating the good soil of the heart, and in striving to uproot every plant which
                            our Heavenly Father and Mother have not planted ; and to carefully guard the good plants,
                            and water them with charity and love, which will be like sweet refreshing dews. Then an
                            abundant harvest will prove the integrity of my life, and be my reward, and my garden will
                            not, through neglect, be like the strawberry bed, bearing many weeds, and a proportionate
                            small quantity of good fruit.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Potter, H. E." TEIform="persName"/>H. E. Potter, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Questions and answers at spiritual meetings, Doctor Samuel Maxwell, speaker and medium" TEIform="index"/>Questions and answers at spiritual meetings, Doctor Samuel Maxwell, speaker and medium
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">QUESTIONS AND ANSWERS AT SPIRITUAL MEETINGS, DOCTOR SAMUEL MAXWELL, SPEAKER AND
                                    MEDIUM A. Christ was a spirit, entirely independent of Jesus; was a spirit a
                                    thousand millions of years old — in existence long before this planet. He took
                                    charge of his medium, Jesus, the man, and manifested His power to the world through
                                    him. Q. Have you ever met that spirit, Christ ? A. I have never met Christ
                                    personally, because He is one of the grand old spirits, who has range of all the
                                    Spiritual worlds in space. His mission is of such a character, that He does but
                                    rarely come Himself to earth at all, or the rudimentary spiritual world, but works
                                    through agents or mediums, in these rudimentary Spirit-lands to carry out His work.
                                    His special work upon this planet is employing in the Spiritual world a vast
                                    combination of agencies to-day, to bring about this spiritualizing of our lives ; to
                                    inject into the external world, so much of the experiences, the beauty and glory of
                                    that other interior life, as can find lodgment and appropriation in the lives of men
                                    upon this earth. Q. Do the followers of Jesus usually meet Him personally? A. Jesus,
                                    that beautiful soul has passed on from the first Spirit-world. They do not ever meet
                                    Him, because all persons, when they escape from the material body, must first come
                                    to this nearest Spiritual belt, or of one which surrounds the planet, but can only
                                    rise through each one, as they are prepared by growth. Q. You frequently allude to
                                    our " eternal Father," will you explain who this is ? A. There is, my friend, a
                                    great want of expression—the Father and Mother, two principles united in oneness.
                                    The divine life is both Father and Mother, balanced precisely throughout infinite
                                    space. Every cubic inch of this Father and Mother life, full of its wisdom, full of
                                    its love, of its power, and with a completeness of consciousness that transcends the
                                    most perfect consciousness that ever has existed in the human soul. This is the "
                                    All-Father," as well as the "All-Mother." To this as it is manifested to our souls
                                    in their inmost depths, we all turn with divinest reverence, for this pure, this
                                    infinite love, the spiritual wisdom, is the fountain from which comes all life, all
                                    consciousness, all being. This to us is the truth.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="B. P. journal" TEIform="index"/>B. P. Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We present to the readers of our Monthly some lines..." TEIform="index"/>We present to the readers of our Monthly some lines...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">We present to the readers of our Monthly some lines that were written by a novitiate sister
                            of the Shaker fraternity at Mt. Lebanon, who soon after was reaped from the earth-life, and
                            gathered to immortal spheres. They have been set to music since her decease.</p></div2><pb n="72" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beautiful valley" TEIform="index"/>BEAUTIFUL VALLEY</head><p TEIform="p">1. l am seeking a beautiful valley, Its pathway I ne'er before knew, And as I am slowly
                            descending, Its beauties unfold to my view; 2. 'Tis true the descent has been painful, With
                            watching, and toil and great care, I've been prosper'd thus far on my journey, And now grow
                            content with my fare; 3. There are pilgrims descending before me, They all have some good
                            thing to say Of humility's beautiful valley, And also of Zion's highway; Away in my old
                            native city, I dream'd of this land far a way, But thought it a desolate region, And dreaded
                            the rough thorny way. I find that each step I have taken, But gives new experience and
                            strength, My courage is strong and unshaken, I'll gain the blest valley at length. For Just
                            through the midst of the lowland, Is a highway of holiness clean, The H-on this path hath
                            not trodden, Nor eye of the vulture e'er seen.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Temperance" TEIform="index"/>TEMPERANCE</head><p TEIform="p">The things of old must pass away, That long o'er man has held the sway, And trampled on his
                            dearest rights, And closed his eyes and dimm'd his lights. Of such is wine, so long
                            renown'd, That laid the patriarch on the ground ; The Lord of Lords that seals their fate,
                            The King of kings that rules in state. Such is the glory of the cup, The high, the low, the
                            rich will sup ; And from the days of Noah down, The laws could only on it frown. All
                            helpless now before its sway, Yet hope inspires a better day, For God hath said tfhe strong
                            must fall, Before the weak, who conquer all. No crowned heads norscepter'd host Will in that
                            day of courage boast; But truth shall guide the actors well, And prayer and praise in
                            accents swell.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brooks, Emmory C." TEIform="persName"/>Emmory C. Brooks, Groveland, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Personal experience" TEIform="index"/>PERSONAL EXPERIENCE</head><p TEIform="p">The writer has lived with the Shakers, sixtyeight years—lived with those who believed under
                            the ministration of Mother Ann, who was the same, in spirit, as Jesus, in his appearing.
                            They gathered into Apostolic order— Community of interest. They carried out the Christ
                            principle to the very letter. They who had wives, lived as they that had none. They who
                            possessed houses and lands, as though they possessed not—for the fashion of the world had
                            passed away. They were a noble people, strong in body and in mind. It was a great blessing
                            to me, that my lot was cast with them, when I was young", away from the evils that are in
                            the world, to learn to wear the Christian yoke, till it became easy and the burden light—to
                            obtain the promised rest, to my soul—in this present time.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Maybee, Simon" TEIform="persName"/>Elder Simon Maybee, Hancock, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Henry Ward Beecher probably gives utterance to more radical ideas than..." TEIform="index"/>Henry Ward Beecher probably gives utterance to more radical ideas than...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Henry Ward Beecher probably gives utterance to more radical ideas than any other orthodox
                            clergyman in the country. In a recent sermon he said: "The gates of Hell have opened into
                            this world through ecclesiastical judicatories, and the greatest cruelties have been
                            practiced by Christian sects, and the world has been presented with a hideous,
                            bloody-mouthed God, that makes men only to drown them. The Church dominion in the world has
                            been simply monstrous; there havebeen no excesses more abominable than those committed un-
                            der Church discipline. The Church has been under the dominion of the Devils." Alluding to
                            his position among the Congregationalists, Mr. Beecher said it was often asked, " Why, as he
                            maintained such liberal views, he did not separate from them t" "I stay here," said he,
                            "because there are men that say Congregationalist ministers shall not stand in the pulpit
                            and say certain things, and I say that they shall!"</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Theological controversy is 'the Gates of Hell'..." TEIform="index"/>Theological controversy is 'the Gates of Hell'...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Theological controversy is " the Gates of Hell." They can be opened only by a spirit of
                            infallibility, that holds belief, of more vital consequence to salvation, than good
                            righteous works. That thinks to do God good service by afflicting human beings, as Calvin
                            did Servetus, because he did not believe that Jesus was the eternal son of God.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sexual promiscuity..." TEIform="index"/>Sexual promiscuity...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">1. Sexual promiscuity — corresponds to savageism ; or the gross, selfish and sensual in human
                            nature. 2. Marriage, for the propagation and education of the race. This institution lies at
                            the foundation of society and civilization in the natural order. 3. Celibacy; alias life in
                            the mental and moral brain-region rather than the cerebellum. Plato, Jesus, Appollonius,
                            Michael Angelo, Sir Isaac Newton, Miss Bremer, Florence Nightingale, John G. Whittier, the
                            Quaker poet, and a whole galaxy of the great and good, lived and live celibate lives. All
                            live thus in the Spirit World of immortality.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/>J. M. Peebles</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sermon to gamblers" TEIform="index"/>A SERMON TO GAMBLERS</head><p TEIform="p">The Rev. Mr. Hammond, revivalist, has been preaching a special sermon to the sporting men of
                            St. Louis. He published an invitation to gamblers and fast men, and in response the church
                            was crowded to its utmost. When no more could get in, about three hundred Christians kindly
                            left in order to make room for the sinners. Probably a like congregation had never before
                            been in a church. In the main, it was orderly, the only serious disturbance being caused by
                            a drunken woman. Mr. Hammond began with an onslaught on tobacco, quoting to great applause
                            this verse : Tobacco is a fljthy weed; It was the devil sowed the seed; It drains the
                            pocket, scents the clothes, And makes a chimney of the nose. Among other things, Mr. Hammond
                            told them the following story of David Mattoon, a Rochester gambler: " He started one night
                            for the theater, and got along beside a low brick church where an Evangelist was preaching.
                            He saw the light, and an invisible hand drew him in. At the close of the meeting Mattoon,
                            the professional sporting man, walked forward. Then and there he knelt down and prayed,' God
                            be merciful to me, a sinner.' He rose from his knees a saved man. He went home. He had
                            $3,000 worth of gambling implements. He burnt them all up. With a mother and sister to
                            support, he said,' What shall I do ?' His hands were delicate and soft as a lady's.
                            Everybody knew he was a gambler. After many fruitless efforts to obtain work—for people were
                            all afraid of him—he hired himself to a grocer at $20 a month. His old friends, and one in
                            particular, tempted him. He stood firm. He said, ' I will never touch a card again.' It was
                            after this that he entered the service of the grocer. He neither drank, smoked, nor chewed.
                            No Christian ought to do either. He became mayor of Oswego and was elected a member of the
                            New York Legislature."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For life we run" TEIform="index"/>FOR LIFE WE RUN</head><p TEIform="p">Behold the straight and narrow way To life eternal leads; To win we run, improve our day, Nor
                            to temptations yield. All base desires we banish hence, True freedom to secure, The word of
                            God is our defense, By which we life insure. The tempter, thus we overcome. The world within
                            subdue, This victory first our Saviour won, His inward foes he slew; Yea his disciples do
                            the same, Still learn his yoke to wear, Endure the cross, despise the shame, Hence his
                            salvation share.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Slack, Dyer" TEIform="persName"/>Dyer Slack, Enfield, Ct.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lebanon shakers" TEIform="index"/>THE LEBANON SHAKERS</head><p TEIform="p">The Troy Press, in writing up a Shaker history, says, in 1779, the people in the vicinity of
                            New Lebanon became greatly interested in the conversation of a Shaker who chanced in that
                            direction. Many were ready to believe his doctrines. Calvin Harlow was appointed by the New
                            Lebanon folks to see the people at Niskayuna, and to bring an account of them. When he
                            returned he confessed himself unqualified to give a proper report, and Joseph Meacham and
                            Amasa Hammond (both Baptist ministers) and Aaron Kibbemade another excursion with him to the
                            Shaker settlement. The four believed that what they saw and heard was the truth of God. A
                            settlement was formed at New Lebanon, and in a short time the converts there were more
                            numerous than the original Believers at Niskayuna.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jesuits" TEIform="index"/>JESUITS</head><p TEIform="p">The Catholic Church is built upon Peter, and Peter built upon Jesus. Therefore that church
                            brought forth an order of Jesuits — men, who imitated Jesus, instead of becoming Christians,
                            as did the man Jesus, by being baptized with the Christ Spirit.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pool, Martha" TEIform="index"/>Martha Pool
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Pool, Martha" TEIform="persName">Martha Pool</persName>, aged 78; at Canaan, N. Y., May 5,
                                1874.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pool, Samuel" TEIform="index"/>Samuel Pool
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Pool, Samuel" TEIform="persName">Samuel Pool</persName>, aged 83; at Hancock, Mass., May 29,
                                1874.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bartlett, Almira" TEIform="index"/>Almira Bartlett
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Bartlett, Almira" TEIform="persName">Almira Bartlett</persName>, aged 32; at W. Gloucester,
                                Me., July 11,1874.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brainard, Daniel" TEIform="index"/>Daniel Brainarp
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Brainard, Daniel" TEIform="persName">Daniel Brainarp</persName>, aged 81; at Watervliet, N.
                                Y., July 15, 1874.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Roberts, Martha" TEIform="index"/>Maetha Roberts
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Roberts, Martha" TEIform="persName">Maetha Roberts</persName>, at South Union, Ky., June 23,
                                1874.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Daniel Fraser has moved from the North Family, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., to Shirley, Mass." TEIform="index"/>Daniel Fraser has moved from the North Family, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., to Shirley, Mass.
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Daniel Fraser has moved from the North Family, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., to Shirley, Mass.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>