<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm1801" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">18</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18880101" TEIform="date">January 1888</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="18" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1">
                    <!--
                    <pb id="p1"/>
                        <p>JANUARY. MANIFESTO. Published by the United Societies, VOL. XVIII. "Blessed are the peace-makers: for they shall be
                        called the children of God."—Matt, v., 9. Canterbury, N. H., 1888. THE</p>
    --><pb id="p2" TEIform="pb"/>
                    <!--
                    <div2 type="none">
                        <p>CONTENTS. The Gospel Testimony, 3 The New Year, -% 5 Fighting Negations, • " Form of Worship, 6 Thoughts of the
                            Absent, 7 Ann Lee, ..... 8 Sabbath Evening, " JL True Story, .... " Elder L. C. Torrey, 9 Louise Guest, ... 10
                            In Memorium, .-..." The Church of God an Earth, 11 Visit to White Water, " Letter,—D. Eraser, .... 13 " W. G.
                            H..... 14 H. N. M. .... 15 Retrospection, 17 It Dosen't Pay to Worry, A Healthy Fruit, ...» This world and the
                            Next, " Editorial,—The New Year, 18 Mastication, 19 Rules for Winter, " Refreshing Drink, ...... 20 Temperance,
                            -" Let in the Sunlight, Letter,—D. Orcutt, 21 Be not Weary, " Acrostic, " Little Men and Women, " Trust in
                            God, 22 God's Promises, .... The New Leaf, ...-" Music,—Bright Vision, 23 Books & Papers, 24 Kind
                            Words, .... » Preparation for Death, " Deaths, -</p>
                    </div2>
--><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Advertisements" TEIform="index"/>[Advertisements]</head><p TEIform="p">[Advertisements deleted.]</p></div2><pb n="1" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. Published by the United Societies, vol. xviii. "Blessed are the
                            peace-makers: for they shall be called the children of God."—Matt, v., 9. Canterbury, N. H.
                            1888.</p></div2><pb n="2" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><pb n="3" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the Elders, William Lee and James Whittaker, no. 22" TEIform="index"/>The Gospel Testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the Elders, William Lee and
                            James Whittaker. No. 22</head><byline TEIform="byline">Published expressly for the several Communities of Believers in IS 16.
                            Re-written by<persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>Henry C. Blinn</byline><p TEIform="p">Journey from Harvard to Petersham. On the 4th of July, 1783, Mother Ann and the
                            Elders left the Believers in Harvard and made a journey to Petersham, Mass. They tarried
                            with the family of David Hammond. Quite a little company of Believers went with them, who
                            had come from different sections of the country. On the third day after their arrival, a
                            body of people, who were returning from a funeral, gathered around the house and in an
                            unpleasant manner seemed determined to enter. It was a very singular proceeding. David
                            Hammond and others who were standing in the halls of the dwelling prevented their ingress.
                            Elder James Whittaker observing their riotous spirit read to them the "Billof Rights," which
                            grants to Christians of every denomination, equal rights and privileges, in the exercise and
                            enjoyment of their religious profession and worship. He then reasoned with them, for some
                            time, and endeavored to show them that such proceedings, were unchristian, unlawful, unmanly
                            and abusive. Others of the Elders also addressed the company and reminded them of the abuse
                            which the Elders had suffered in Petersham at an earlier date. Mother Ann admitted several
                            of the company into the house and pointed out to them a narrow passage in the rear of the
                            chimney, where she said, "They thrust me through that place. It seemed as though they would
                            press the breath from my body. I was never so abused in all my life." Soon after this the
                            company withdrew, but to their dishonor, be it said, they returned near the close of the
                            day, with every indication that they were bent on mischief. Only a few of them were al-
                            lowed to enter the house. Mother Ann and the Elders passed up stairs, into a chamber. The
                            mob next attempted to reach the upper windows of the dwelling but were not successful. Some
                            of the Brethren reproved the mob for their ungodly behavior, but as they seemed to be
                            determined on acts of wickedness, it did little or no good. Stones and sticks were thrown in
                            at the windows, and several persons were more or less injured ; yet in the midst of all the
                                tur<pb n="4" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 4 THE MANIFESTO. moil the Believers began to sing a
                            hymn of praise and prayer. Several were able to testify to their faith in the cross, and
                            that in all boldness. The evil influence, however, predominated among the mob and they
                            became very noisy and abusive. One man by the name of Witt, struck Br. Aaron Wood with a
                            club, so furiously that he fell to the ground, and was unable to move. At that moment some
                            one cried out, '' You have killed him" and Elder James added, "Mark the man that killed Br.
                            Aaron. " Instantly the mob began to disperse, and ran in every direction, clambering over
                            the walls and fences in such confusion that the scene became perfectly ludicrous. The
                            Believers taking advantage of the hasty retreat gave three cheering shouts which made the
                            woods echo with joyThere was no more harm that night, but on the following evening the house
                            was again surrounded by a noisy rabble, who were xnockins, hooting, and yelling like
                            savages. A pistol was discharged in at the window, apparently with a view to frighten the
                            Believers, but the singing and speaking proceeded as though nothing had happened. Night
                            after night these wicked people would gather around the house where the Believers were
                            holding their meet- ings and create a disturbance by their unpleasant noises and rude
                            behavior. This continued most of the time while they remained in Petersham. Mother Ann and
                            the Elders comforted the Brethren and Sisters and counseled them to forget their troubles
                            and to remember their sorrow no more. At one time Elder William Lee discovered three men, as
                            they came across the fields, toward the house, and calling to the Brethren, advised them to
                            take care of their things. "The wicked are coming," said he, "and the wicked will do
                            wickedly." Mother Ann called several of the Believers, and said to them, "Go quickly and see
                            what they wnnt. and just as you deal with them, so Christ will deal with you." These men
                            appeared to have but little sense of the mission upon which they had b-en sent. They came in
                            great zeal and running as fast as they could, shouting and making a great noise. They were
                            strangers to the Believers. Suddenly they turned and ran from the house with utmost speed,
                            and appeared to be very much frightened. The next mission of Mother Ann and the Elders whs
                            to the town of Cheshire where they arrived July, 18 L 783, and called at the home of Joseph
                            Burnett. They remained with this family over the Sabbath and held a public .service. Large
                            numbers came to attend the meeting. All the Elders addressed the assembly, and opened the
                            gospel testimony with great clearness. At the close of the service several persons came to
                            the house and used very abusive language toward the Elders, and especially toward Mother
                            Ann. One of the young sisters remarked, "She is my Mother;" "She is my Mother." This put
                            them to silence and they left the place very much ashamed of their conduct. After holding
                            meetings in Cheshire about one week they went to the town of Richmond.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Behold! another day is gone..." TEIform="index"/> Behold! another day is
                            gone... </head><p TEIform="p">Behold! another day is gone, Look back, my soul and see, If every passing
                            moment's borne A good report of thee.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, A. J." TEIform="persName"/>A.J. Calver</byline></div2><pb n="5" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New year" TEIform="index"/>THE NEW YEAR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Newton, Agnes E." TEIform="persName"/>Agnes E. Newton</byline><p TEIform="p">We've finished the page and turned the leaf To begin another year; We've reviewed
                            the same, balanced account, Our credit and debt made clear. We've written the lines we
                            thought to write With earnest and soulful care; When the New Year dawned with snowy page And
                            our hearts were bowed in prayer. The record is there, never erased, The false nor the true
                            can be ; 'Tis written we know for more than time, It stands for eternity. Yet we find our
                            hearts are striving today With purpose still firm and true ; To profit by truths the past
                            has taught And gladly accept the new. Unchanging the law of perfect growth, The new shall
                            succeed the old; E'en the blighted fields and barren waste Shall verdure and bloom unfold.
                            Then welcome the cross and life of Christ, Creating all things anew; We pray that its light,
                            our souls, may guide And inspire the whole year through. The sorrows or joys the New Year
                            brings, The Christian heart can meet; Where Christ is enthroned, in vain the storms And
                            tempests of life may beat. Ah! hidden with Christ, a safe retreat, His mission and law our
                            guide; The tempter may come but nothing find As we in the Vine abide. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fighting negations" TEIform="index"/>FIGHTING NEGATIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>Oliver C. Hampton</byline><p TEIform="p">Love and not hate is to save us all, if we ever are saved. It is vastly better to
                            cultivate a love and interest for a virtue, than to employ our time in parading before us
                            and hating its opposite. Can't we love Mercy without taking the trouble to bring before our
                            minds, scenes of appalling cruelty as so many 'b men of straw" and hating them ? Can't we
                            love purity without the necessity of taxing our imaginations to remember or perhaps even
                            create images of disgusting sensuality, so that we can hate them and fight them? I should
                            not wonder if we eventually came to find that a godly man—a Christian, is under no necessity
                            to hate anything. What are sinful habits, courses, —propensities, anyhow? They are vio-
                            lated laws. They are ''lines of confusion, and stones of emptiness." Mere negations, to be
                            substituted sooner or later in every case, by love, wisdom, purity, patience, kindness and
                            intelligence. Let us love the good and cultivate it and let what we call the evil die a
                            natural death (if any one thinks it is possessed of vital elements) and let it be relegated
                            to the limbo of everlasting forgetfulness as soon as possible. In our zeal in hating a
                            violation of any of God's good laws we are so very prone to hate the violator, that our
                            hatred is almost sure to consume nearly every bit of our charity. But our blessed Savior and
                            Mother don't allow that on any consideration whatever. It seems to me a reasonable,
                            philosophical and even inspirational suggestion that we should cultivate as much love and as
                            little hatred as possible, aud if guided hereinto by holy and heavenly impulses of wisdom
                            from above which the beloved Apostle assures us is "first pure, then peaceable" we shall
                            climb the great ladder toward perfection with much security and peace. Now for a little
                            experience. When I first set out to be a Shaker the cry was war to the knife against the
                            "world, flesh and devil." I pitched in and fought in 5 <pb n="6" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. those wars for many years. We shook, vociferated, stamped and in every way,
                            demonstrated outwardly what was going on inwardly. We used to sing : "The greatest war
                            beneath the sun Has surely now with us begun, Each soul must fight (?) or surely run And
                            leave the valiant numbers." And also : "When once we've entered the campaign We need not
                            think to fly, Our freedom then we have to gain 'Tis conquer then or die. For if we should
                            the cause desert, Or yield unto the foe, To endless shame we must depart Where all such
                            cowards go." These warring scenes sometimes seemed to have a strange effect upon me. At such
                            times the stronger the belligerent demonstration the fulbr of evil I seemed to become and
                            consequently the farther I felt from the victory. But I was told that it was to be compared
                            with medicine, which in order to do any good, must first rouse up all the latent elements of
                            disease, after which it could and would eliminate them from the system. So 1 let it go, and
                            fought ou. After many years of this military life, I solemnly made a review of my experience
                            aud found myself appallingly poor and destitute of patience, forgiveness, charity and
                            unselfishness. I had experienced but a very small portion of divine love by which my spirit
                            was allured and brought into the wilderness of silence, and spoken comfortably unto. So I
                            felt very poor and disconsolate after twenty years of military life wherein I had never
                            missed a single battle. I now began earnestly to love and cultivate all that was good and
                            wise, high and holy, sweet and unselfish, kind and sympathetic, beautiful and sublime,
                            poetic and harmonious. I have pursued this plan for many years and gained the unspeakable
                            riches of peace and righteousness flowing from a quiet practical self-abnegation. I have
                            gone through terribly exhausting physical labors, fighting for spiritual emancipation. But I
                            have gained more real travel in prayer and peace and tranquility and love to God and
                            practical goodness to man, in one year by my later spiritual regime than in many of the
                            years of my former experience. It may be that all may not be able to receive these sayings
                            of mine. Yet I am not afraid to exhort all to cultivate in thought, word and practice, all
                            that is good, holy and heavenly until such a sweet life is a second nature with them, and
                            forget as fast as possible all that is below this high standard, and I will guarantee all
                            such a swift, happy and successful travel heavenward. Union Village, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Four queries about the shakers, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>Four Queries about
                            the Shakers. No. 1</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, Chancy" TEIform="persName"/>Chancy Dibble</byline><p TEIform="p">Form of Worship. It is supposed by some that we have a variety of monkish forms
                            to which all must submit, but this soon vanishes from the mind of one who learns bow few are
                            the ceremonies with us, one side of necessary duties and industries. Our worship is perhaps
                            the most peculiar part, to which some think we are very much wedded, whereas in reality we
                            have no faith in any form, farther than it is expressive of emotion and reverence to our
                            Divine Parents. The form is of no consequence ; all depends upon the purity and sincerity of
                            6 <pb n="7" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. the worshipers. Whether we sit or stand,
                            kneel, sing, march or dance ; all must proceed from reverence and love, or worship of any
                            kind becomes formal and lifeless. Our leaders were prompted to this form by aspirations
                            after the power of salvation from sin. Every motion had its original signification. The
                            march, that we are ever on the move toward perfection. Our hands are spread, in token that
                            we are needy and anxious to gather from spiritual sources. We shake with indignation against
                            the nature of evil in our own hearts. We dance for our victories over the temptations of
                            life, which so often sink men and women in degradation. The fitness and congeniality of our
                            worship to all ages and dispositions, is appreciated by such as realize the failing of
                            lifeless forms to which fashionable churches hold. The congregation seated in their easy
                            pews, witnessing the performance of some theologian who displays himself, perhaps more than
                            he displays the gospel ; thus one man does the worshiping while the crowd look on. We do not
                            wonder that people educated to old forms, should look with surprise at so wide a deviation
                            as we have made. Dancing upon the Sabbath, according to the blue laws, such should be
                            imprisoned for desecration of the day. Shaking, why what fools to thus manifest our
                            indignation agaiust dirty, sinful habits. But is it not right to act out what we honestly
                            feel? Who in seasons of revival finds fault with the sinner, under conviction, for acting
                            out that to which the spirit impels him ? On the whole, our worship is not merely a
                            curiosity, for there is no position that brings us nearer in harmony with spirits. While our
                            exercises enliven the physical part, the mind is active and receptive, not for tipping
                            tables or material- ization, but for an overcoming power against sin, which reigns in the
                            human heart and in Society. Watervliet, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thoughts  of the  absent and of our  day and time" TEIform="index"/>Thoughts
                            of the absent and of our day and time</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>May Whitcher</byline><p TEIform="p">Tis not for the departed That we are called to weep, Or for the honest hearted
                            Who still their vigils keep. But for an aid in Zion Of equal strength and care Her inmates
                            can rely on And all the needy share. Something must fill this measure A living pool to
                            stand, Or Zion lacks the treasure Required at her hand. Some one must hold her order, Obey
                            her saered truth, Maintain her virgin whiteness, Or who shall know her worth? Where is the
                            burden falling Where are the hands well staid And where the feet established Through living
                            faith obeyed? And can we lose our birthright When called the chosen seed, Or shall we hold
                            our standing Till we are free indeed? The spirit answers in us, We must obey our light, And
                            walk in true uprightness If we maintain the right. No longer point the pathway But place our
                            feet therein, And from the morn till evening Sin not, nor lead to sin, Duties are always
                            with us And those who need our care, And as we give, we're given Increase for all we share.
                            7 <pb n="8" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 'Tis not a fabled story, But those who
                            keep the word, They know and feel the glory And power of their God, To walk above earth's
                            darkness Her groveling and her sin, Above all nature's cravings With spirit pure and clean.
                            Then keep the standard waving The cro s we'll not bring down But every trial braving Till
                            ours, the Conqueror's crown. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ann Lee—the seer" TEIform="index"/>ANN LEE-THE SEER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Elizabeth Oakes" TEIform="persName"/>Elizabeth Oakes Smith</byline><p TEIform="p">Written for The Manifesto. CassancIras have their fervid visions cried; Unheeded
                            Sibyls on the unwilling air Have cast their inspirations in despair. Joan of Arc, her simple
                            flock beside, Wept o'er her country's wrongs, nor dared to hide The Voice that bade her
                            virgin feet repair Where slaughtering men and ruined cities were; And forth she went, truth
                            panoplied, and died. And not the less from out the feons roll The Voice by prophet heard and
                            ancient seer, And chastely o'er Ann Lee's inspired soul, Love, such as angels know, to
                            angels dear, Enshrined the Gospel of the Higher Life, Symboled by Adam ere he sought a wife.
                            Hollywood, N. C.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbath evening" TEIform="index"/>SABBATH EVENING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Caswell, Mary H." TEIform="persName"/>Mary H. Caswell</byline><p TEIform="p">The Sabbath day was ended, The Bible placed aside ; Full many texts I'd gathered
                            From this unerring guide Which rested on my spirit As rays of purest light, Revealing to me
                            clearly My duty in God's sight. Though oft through early childhood, And e'en in wayward
                            youth, I'd read these sacred lessons, And learned to love their truth; Yet, in the recent
                            review Of ancient precepts rare, One 'mong the many others Engrossed my special care. 'Twas
                            uttered by our Savior, Most sweetly, calmly given To his devout disciples To point the way
                            to Heaven ; See Luk*. Except ye be converted And like a child become, Ye can in no wise
                            enter The Kingdom as my own. So positive this statement, I ask who can gain-say This truth
                            divinely spoken A truth that lives to-day? And thus I said 'tis folly, For one to entertain
                            A hope to reign in glory, Without a righteous claim. Henceforth may angels witness, My
                            promise which shall be, To seek the Father's Kingdom, Through blest humility. Canterbury, N.
                            H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True story" TEIform="index"/>A TRUE STORY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Basting, Louis" TEIform="persName"/>Louis Basting</byline><p TEIform="p">Traveling recently through Southern Kentucky we became acquainted with a
                            gentleman whose probity and integrity is well known throughout that section of the country.
                            During the course of a lengthy journey on the cars he related the following incident which
                            we reproduce here for the benefit of readers of The Manifesto. The Society of Believers
                            located at Pleasant Hill, Ky., has for some years past permitted camp meetings to be held on
                            its grounds. As a consequence many called for food and lodging and were entertained
                            according to the ability of the Society. The chief attraction at last year's encampment was
                            a noted evan- gelist. Among those who availed themselves of the Society's hospitality was
                            the aforementioned Rev. S. J. Coming 8 <pb n="9" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. one
                            morning into the office with a swaggering sort of manner, cigar in mouth and spitting
                            tobacco juice on the clean floor he began a general criticism of Believers, their manners,
                            system and theology. An aged gentleman who was visiting a daughter, who was a member of the
                            Society at last ventured to check the speaker's volubility, by asking him what particular
                            point of their theolog/ was objectionable. The answer was' that the celibacy practiced by
                            Believers was anti-Christian and unscriptural. Then his questioner remarked with some warmth
                            : "Do you know what you are talking about? Have you read the New Testament? Was not Jesus a
                            celibate and were not his apostles and disciples celibates? The only question today is, who
                            of us is ' able to bear that saying. Yes, sir, celibacy is the very Cap sheaf of the
                            Christian Religion. And as to manners : look at the inscription over the door—Erected in
                            1839. Now 1 venture to assert, that since that inscription was placed there, no gentleman
                            has ever come into this house smoking a cigar and spitting on the floor." Mr. J. found it
                            best not to continue the conversation on these lines, but others who had witnessed the inci"
                            dent caused it to be related in the papers, and it followed him in his wanderings to
                            Chicago. There he astonished his audience by coming out with a testimony against the use of
                            tobacco. Thus was the Reverend's conversion from tobacco brought about. Ought it to stop
                            there Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. [How nice it would be if others could follow this example of the
                            Eev. S. J. and astonish the people "by coming out with a testimony against the use of
                            tobacco."—Ed.]</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memorium: Elder Lemuel C. Torry" TEIform="index"/>IN MEMORIUM. ELDER
                            LEMUEL C. TORRY</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Doyle, Alfred E." TEIform="persName"/>Alfred E. Doyle</byline><p TEIform="p">Earth to earth and dust to dust For this is Heaven's decree, And nature bows to
                            pay the debt That makes the spirit free. But we who mourn with keen regret The losof father,
                            friend and brother See hut the passing glorj' of tbis world And not the rising of another.
                            Through the valley of the shadow, One by one alone must tread; We call this death, but is it
                            true That ours are with the dead? Faith and Hope both answer nay, Death is but the gate of
                            life, To higher planes and broader fields— Of onward upward strife. Our present loss is
                            future gain, One friend below for one above; It must be so in God's own law, For God Himself
                            is love. We have this hope and can rejoice In the field well fought and won, And with him
                            share his well earned joy To hear the sweet " Well done." But we shall miss him, Ah how
                            sorely, The kindly voice and helping hand; But whispers hope we'll find our own All in a
                            fairer, better land. What shall we say, for words are weak, To these the children of his
                            care? The Lord of Heaven is the orphan's God, Take everything to Him in prayer. For He has
                            promised to kindly temper The wind to the shorn lamb, To bless with-holding or bless in
                            giving The chastening rod or healing balm. Full well we know, how blest the thought, The
                            journey he has trod, Though strewn with thorns led safely on To the Harvest Home of God. A
                            fond farewell, a glad God speed Our father, friend and brother, Not dead but risen, still
                            let us say— From this life to another. This holy faith, Oh glorious hope, To know whate'er
                            befall, Of joy or grief in Heaven or earth God's mercies cover all.</p></div2><pb n="10" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute to the memory of our beloved sister, Louise Guest" TEIform="index"/>A
                            Tribute to the Memory of our Beloved Sister LOUISE GUEST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Settles, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>Mary Settles</byline><p TEIform="p">How soon are we called again to review And witness the scene which we all must
                            pass through, But those who are faithful have nothing to fear When called in that heavenly
                            world to appear. Death takes of all classes the young and the old, The weak and the feeble,
                            the stout and the bold, No one can escape it, but all must resign, When called by the voice
                            of Almighty Divine. Yea, all souls in justice their portion must meet, When called to appear
                            at the great judgment seat; No one can call back the time they've delayed But each must
                            appear in the robe they have made. Then let us my dear loving comrades be wise, Resolved to
                            be winners of that holy prize, Come life, or come death let us stand for the Lord, And die
                            in the cause and defense of his word. For lo! our sweet moments glide swiftly away, And soon
                            we'll be called from this frail house of clay, Then let us prepare with bright angels to
                            dwell, And bid earth's vain glories a lasting farewell. We have the example before us now
                            placed, Of one who has faithfully finished her race, And gone to explore the bright regions
                            above There join with the angels in streams of pure love. She offered to God the first
                            fruits of her life, Renounced this vain world, withiis pleasures and strife Has stood for
                            the gospel and never looked back, But kept her feet placed on the firm solid Rock. She long
                            hath stood with us, through tempest and tide And no vain allurements could draw her aside,
                            She always did speak in support of the truth, And this she has faithfully kept from her
                            youth. And now like a flower she is pluck'd in her prime, And gone to a fairer and happier
                            clime, No more to return to dwell with us again But in the bright regions of glory remain.
                            She now can rejoice from the sorrows of earth, And sing with bright angels in heavenly mirth
                            And raise the sweet notes of thanksgiving and praise That she stood for the cause to the end
                            of her days. And O ! that we all may thus finish our days [raise, That when we are call'd
                            hence, the same notes we may And pour forth our souls in thanksgiving to God That by his
                            kind mercy and power we have stood. O may we all meet in that heavenly land, United together
                            forever to stand; Where no earthly troubles can come to annoy, Our happiness, comfort, and
                            eternal joy. But there in the mansions of bright glory and peace, Our glory will shine with
                            an endless increase; And there we'll rejoice on that bright happy shore, Where sorrows are
                            ended and parting's no more. Pleasant Hill, Ky,</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memorium: sister, Louise Guest" TEIform="index"/>IN MEMORIUM. SISTER,
                            LOUISE GUEST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Settles, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>Mary Settles</byline><p TEIform="p">"Leaves have their time to fall; the stars to set, And flowers to wither at the
                            north wind's breath, But thou Oh Death ! hast for thine own all seasons." When the lovely
                            autumn was waning, and in the quiet night as the silvery rays of the moon shed a soft and
                            starry radiance down on the earth wrapping it in splendor, a pure spirit winged its way to
                            its Maker, returned to the God who gave it. She had no fears of the future. In her youth she
                            gave her all to God, and his work, renounced the siren pleasures that are so attractive to
                            the young, and with a firmness, worthy of a soldier she never looked back, but onward and
                            upward was her motto. Our sister was meek, unobtrusive, quiet in her manners, adorned with
                            the priceless adorning of humility, faithful in the performance of her duties, kind and
                            respectful to the aged. We shall miss her when we meet to worship, as her voice was heard in
                            these sacred halls. We shall miss her in the home circle, in all the walks of life where her
                            usefulness was well known. Her physical body was worn and weary from the inroads of disease,
                            and though a patient sufferer, yet she longed to be free, and to go to the home above, to
                            rejoin nany dear ones who had preceded hr to the home " Over There. " Her good example was
                            before us, and we shall niiss her ^ad!y, but we rejoice that she is not lost, only gone
                            before, and in a few brief years we shall bid adieu to things of time, and lay down the
                            cares of this life and explore the unknown land " Beyond the smiling and the weeping." We
                            to-day come here to offer a tribute of respect to the departed, to drop a tear to her
                            memory, and the loving hands have arrayed iier for the silent tomb. Her young friends have
                            come to do honor to her, and bring their floral tributes, mute offerings to the voiceless
                            one whose hands are meekly folded over her heart and who now is rejoicing that her spirit
                            has put on immortality. We will tenderly lay her away beneath the sod with the sky and the
                            twinkling stars and pale moon, over head, to keep watch over the spot. The birds will sing a
                                <pb n="11" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 11 requiem, and her spirit will go to
                            the land of the immortelles. We who survive are reminded that to pome of us the summons may
                            come ere long, as "we know not the day when the Son of Man cometh." And then I think of one,
                            Who in her prime and beauty died The fair meek blossom that grew up And faded by my side; In
                            the cold moist earth we laid her When the forest cast the leaf, And we wept that one so
                            lovely Should have a life so brief. Yet not unmeet it was That this dear friend of ours, So
                            gentle and so beautiful Should perish with the flowers. Pleasant Hill, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Church of God on Earth" TEIform="index"/>THE CHURCH OF GOD ON EARTH </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Butler, Charles Wm." TEIform="persName"/> Charles Wm. Butler </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> O Church of God on earth ! What strong and holy ties Are thine
                                    by virtue of thy birth And Christian sacrifice ! Hush now the strife of words, Bid
                                    every war-note cease And deeply sound the music chords That sing the Prince of Peace
                                    ! O Church of God on eartli! The?gazing world stands by, She marks the signs of
                                    inner worth And sees the glory nigh! Then speak the truth in love, In faith and
                                    patience wait, If thou wouldst see the whole world move Within the Church's gate ! O
                                    Church of God on earth! Give thou no place to wrong! Prove more and more thy
                                    Heavenly birth And stand sublimely strong1! Build in thy temple high and fair The
                                    unifying throne! That truth divine, undying there, May glorify its own !</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="All Christians will be at home what they would fain appear abroad..." TEIform="index"/> All Christians will be at home what they would fain appear abroad... </head><p TEIform="p">All Christians will be at home what they would fain appear abroad. They should
                            ever be what good people honor and what God can bless.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Baker, A. I." TEIform="persName"/>A. I. Baker</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Visit to White Water Village, and to Union Village, Ohio, in the autumn of 1881, by one who was a shaker boy" TEIform="index"/>A visit to White Water Village, and to Union Village, Ohio, in the
                                Autumn of 1881, by one who was a Shaker Boy.</head><p TEIform="p">Little Rock, Ark. Early on the morning of Sept. 23, 1887, I started with some
                                friends of our family, having made up my mind to see White Water, a Shaker Village, in
                                Hamilton Co., Ohio. We arranged to make the journey by carriage, as I wished to see any
                                familiar spot on the pike from Cincinnati to the Village. There being no railroad nearer
                                than North Bend of the Ohio River, (some seventeen miles from W. W. V.) when I lived
                                there, but since that time a railroad has been finished to Harrison six miles from the
                                Shakers I wished to go the old way, and return by railWe had a delightful ride. Being in
                                the fall of the year, the forests, and fields appeared so beautifully to me, and of
                                course, as all boys think, no State is like their own, so I think no State is like Ohio,
                                especially, Southern Ohio. Every brook, tree, house and even the cattle that I saw
                                seemed like old friends, and more so as I neared the Village of White Water. We partook
                                of a fine dinner with an old gentleman and lady, and their adopted daughter, relations
                                of my iriends who lived on Paddy's Run, a small stream about four miles from the Shaker
                                Village. I talked of the good people to my friends for all in my mind was the Shakers.
                                After spending a few hours with our host and hostess, we continued our journey, arriving
                                about 6, P. M., at another relation of my friends, where we ate su; per, and soon
                                retired for the night. In the morning, I arose quite early for me, and in company with a
                                little boy, after breakfast, ascended a high hill, (there are many south of the Shaker
                                Village,) to take a loving view of my old home, the Shakertown, as the people call it. I
                                viewed all, saw the Centre Family, the large barn, and other ob- jects in the distance.
                                O what thoughts filled me after twenty-three or more years have passed since I saw the
                                old place. How anx<pb n="12" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 12 THE MANIFESTO. ious I was to
                                continue the journey. I never will forget it while memory lasts. I had never seen a
                                Shaker or a person who had lived with them in all that time, and so very few that knew
                                anything about them. At last the time came for the start, and another carriage joined
                                us, of the family who entertained us for the night. As I drove over Dry Fork, a creek
                                running around the Shaker Village, memories came over me; my heart was full, and is as I
                                write this letter. We passed the South Family, the old school-house, the graveyard, and
                                on up to the Office. Here I met Elder Stephen Ball. We stopped and shook hands. I knew
                                him. We hitched our horses, and went into the Office and were met by sister Julia Ann
                                Bear. The company remained about half an hour, leaving me to visit my friends. None of
                                them seemed to know me as I have grown very stout weighing some over two hundred pounds.
                                I took a walk after dinner, to see the old places. There was some change after
                                twenty-three years. Visited Howard's Creek, the woods, fish pond, the grave-yard and
                                here saw many names of those who had fought the fight of faith, and entered into their
                                reward. Among them, Elder Ezra Sherman, John Easterbrooks, Ebenezer Eice, a good soul as
                                ever lived, and Josiah Burnham, for many years the trusty man and deacon of the Village.
                                Many names of the Sisters, bright stars in the army of God, who had finished their
                                labors and entered into rest. Many whom I once knew had now passed away. During my stay
                                I ivas very kindly treated Charles Stirr, a young man, who does the business, gave me
                                much information as to the present state of the Society, and answered all my questions,
                                which I know were many. I found him polite and entertaining. Stephen Ball also came to
                                see me, and I enjoyed all their visits. Elder Henry Bear, my good friend and Elder
                                visited me quite often. He related to me his religious experience; how he became a
                                Shaker; and I shall never forget his kind words. He has, though he did not speak of it,
                                gone through the furnace of affliction, and I love him as a gospel father. Julia Ann
                                Bear, who has charge of the office, was very kind to me and talked freely. Mary Ann
                                Wheeler was also at the office. With Br. Charles Stirr I visited the laundry, the
                                stable, the old nursery, the dwelling house, and the meeting room in the old church;
                                nil, all, so familiar to me. I went up to the North Family and visited Eldress Elizabeth
                                Sharp, whom I knew; also Elder Charles Faraday, who was a dear friend of mine. We used
                                to work together in the seed garden. He looked the same but older. We talked of old
                                times and walked down the road together. I went also to the South Family and saw Eldress
                                Betsy Gass and John Atchison. They all seemed like relations of mine, but those I knew
                                in childhood of course were the dearest to me. I also saw Eldress Amanda Rubush, Lucinda
                                Packer and others of the Center Family. I had quite a visit with Eldress Amanda and
                                found her a pleasant lady, the only one left of a large family. On the Sunday following
                                I attended divide worship, and as they stood in their ranks and sung, how I thought of
                                the time when I had my place among those pure people. Sad thoughts came over me. Some of
                                the songs I had never heard, but one was sung which I have never forgotten. " O come, I
                                will lead you, I'll clothe and feed you, And guide you along, by the confluent stream;
                                Where angels, bright angels, are washing in Jordan, And you shall be free from all
                                sorrow and pain. I never will leave you, nay never forsake you, Though deep tribulations
                                and troubles arise; But I will be with you my faithful, dear children, That you may be
                                able to press for the prize." That was too much, the tears would come in spite of all I
                                could do to prevent them, but I felt better. Of course I missed the large company of
                                former years, I missed the exercise in the stepping, the round dance, the shuffling, and
                                all those beautiful forms of worship I once knew so well and which I think help on the
                                life of a Believer. I say it, though it may seem strange for a church clergyman to
                                express such views; I believe that life comes by earnestness, even to earnest laboring
                                in the dance, shouting, clapping of hands and violent exercises. We read that "the
                                kingdom of Heaven suffereth (or alloweth) violence, and the violent taketh it by force."
                                    <pb n="13" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 13 I believe the songs of Zion
                                will again come to be of the lively nature, and companies of people will seek her
                                protection, and the dance, the shaking and all the glories will return to her people, to
                                help them to bear their testimony against sin, and against the world without fear, as
                                brave soldiers of the cross. The gospel trumpet, I believe, has sounded and is sounding
                                now, andthe_ time is near, when all slip-shod services will disappear from Zion, and her
                                beauty and her glory will again be restored. On Monday morning, I bid farewell to the
                                kind friends and rode to Harrison in a Shaker wagon. Here I took the train for
                                Cincinnati, well pleased with my visit, and it can never be effaced from my memory.
                                While at the Hotel I made up my mind that I would visit Union Village, the largest
                                Society of Shakers in the west, and on Tuesday, following, the 26th of Sept., I took the
                                narrow guacre to Lebanon, arriving there about 6 P. M. Hired a carriage to drive up to
                                the Centre Family, and stopped at the Office, where I met tin.: Ministry, three of them
                                being members of the Society of White Water. During my stay, Elder Oliver Hampton spoke
                                very kindly to me, and gave me some books. Among them I have the "Book of Testimonies,"
                                which I have sent to be bound, as I prize it a treasure. Eldress Louisa Farnham, an old
                                friend of mine, entertained me very kindly, and we held a pleasant conversation. Eldress
                                Louisa is not much changed and is seemingly as smart as she was twenty-five years ago.
                                She is a woman of good sound sense, a gift all of us do not have. Such a gift is far
                                better than great learning. We all love Eldress Louisa Farnham. She was the first
                                Shakeress I ever knew, and my mother also was fond of her. She was kind to all, and I
                                hope she will live long to do a good work for the Societies in the West. I also enjoyed
                                my visit with Elder Oliver, and his words are a goodly treasure in my mind. Eldress
                                Adeline Wells was very kind and pleasant, as were sisters Ann Maria Myers, Susanna
                                Armstrong, Brother Ezra Leggett, the Post Master, Brother Gustave in charge of the
                                office, and Brother Peter Boyd all made my visit very pleasant. I called at the North
                                Family, and as Eldress Louisa sent me up to see my friends, sister Mary Middleton and
                                Matilda Butler, I found them and found that Sister Mary was also glad to see me, and
                                tears came in her eyes when I told her that years ago, I was a Shaker boy, and at that
                                time she so kindly took care of me and my clothes in the Village at White Water. I am
                                assured that tears are no sign of weakness as foolish people sometimes think, for the
                                bravest and best of men, have often shed tears.: Jesus did, and when honest and sincere,
                                the more they touch the heart. I spent some time talking of days gone by, and I almost
                                felt as though I was prophesying when I told them of a time coming, of religious
                                revival. Tn the afternoon I attended the funeral of a sister at the West Family. The
                                services were without ostentation or show, bat solemn. I rode back to the office, and
                                left for Lebanon in a buggy with Eldress Adeline and Sister Susanna. We did some
                                shopping, (or rather I went with them to do some shopping) and felt honored to be seen
                                with my Shaker friends. Bidding the Sisters good bye, I took the train for Cincinnati.
                                My visits will always be remembered as a bright oasis in the desert of this life, and
                                one of the brightest pages in the memory of my soul. I still maintain, if a person is an
                                honest Shaker, he is to me the "Salt of the earth," and a light in the world. Sincerely
                                Yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Berne, Joseph L." TEIform="persName"/>Joseph L. Berne</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York, November 1887" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N.
                                Y., Nov. 1887</head><p TEIform="p">Respected Friend, Prof. G. V:—I learned from a Kansas paper that you are
                                connected with a form of Social Life embracing "Shaker principles minus celibacy." To
                                me, the civilizations of the past and present, are the outcome of a definite Force in
                                humanity. Its products are essentially alike under all conditions. So universally alike,
                                that the exceptions are phenomenal. Nevertheless, these <pb n="14" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 14 THE MANIFESTO. exceptions show, that there is also a force in humanity, which,
                                when in oper- ation, will bring forth a form of social life which will be communal—g'ods
                                in common. A few years ago 1 made an analysis of the Force which creates the^e
                                civilizations. I found that said Force, is composed of two atoms—a woman and a man.
                                Th:ir leading and creative force, is an affinity to form family relationships. The Motto
                                of which is, "Me and Mine." The reverse of yours. This Force, is of the animal in man
                                and woman—all animals marry as they do. The civilizations alluded to rule by force, as
                                the beasts of the fields do. All nations are true to their origin, and represent
                                themselves emblematically as wild beasts ; one is a bear, another a lion,&amp;c.
                                Nations are but aggregations of distinct families. They never coalesce, and the richer
                                the family, the more distinct it is, and the more intense the emotion '"Me, and Mine."
                                Were the Genus Homo, in possession of but one set of emotions, as all other animals are,
                                we could have no conception of having goods in common. The fact that so many aspire to
                                communal life, is evidence that there is in humanity a higher order of emotions, than
                                those which refer themselves to animal life in man and woman. Should you be so blest as
                                to be able to call forth the God-element in your friends, and quicken into life its emo-
                                tions, then you will have a divine form of social life. Its external manifestation will
                                be goods in common, and its motto yours "The happiness of each, the first object of
                                all." Should yourself and friends decline to ignore these animal emotional forces; then
                                you will be content to refer yourselves to the aforesaid civilizations. And be assured,
                                that all your efforts to manifest communal life, will be but " As the snow-flake on the
                                river, A moment white, then melts forever." We are not alone ; the sentiment of living a
                                life to the total exclusion of all propagative emotions, is prevailing. I am truly your
                                friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Fraser</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Portland, Maine, October 1887" TEIform="index"/>Portland, Me., Oct. 1887</head><p TEIform="p">Mr. Editor :—Although I am not a Shaker, yet from what little I have gleaned
                                from reading I have great respect for the Shaker view in their interpretations of the
                                teachings of Jesus Christ. Particularly so since the doctrines of the Socialists as
                                opposed to giant monoplies, have become rife in the land, has the words of Jesus in the
                                light of Shaker interpretation looked reasonable to me But my object in this writing was
                                to give a little account of my experience at a religious meeting, one of the
                                "evangelical" kind, with their monopolized interpretation of Scripture. How long will
                                Jesus endure the use of his name as sanction to dogmas having no Scriptural foundation
                                whatever. But the meeting—I felt a desire to attend the Sunday morning prayer meeting of
                                the Young Men's Christian Association at their rooms by the announced subject, " A word
                                to moral young men." Having had my idea of about what the drift would be—upon at-
                                tendance I was not only not disappointed but more lully confirmed in my opposition to
                                such teachings which while denouncing "morality," indirectly encourages crime. The
                                nineteenth of Matthew 16—20, formed the basis for the topic of this meeting at which the
                                first half hour was spent in prayers offered in the name of him who uttered these words.
                                And then stopping where they did without including the 21st and 22nd verses, and putting
                                in the mouth of Jesus a meaning which he did not utter or intend to teach, I felt to
                                ask, how long will Jesus thus be mis<pb n="15" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 15
                                represented, made to teach what he did not? And I felt to pi ay, that those who were
                                trying to inculcate their false teachings upon others might have their eyes opened to
                                the truth. Why did they not read and explain the 21st and 22nd verses, which were
                                omitted and which contained not only practical morality but pointed the way to a real
                                following of him who spake them? But no, a twisted contorted theological belief
                                perverting the words "Kingdom of God " and the essentials for entering therein to a
                                fancied change in the "new birth"—something mysterious and supernatural, instead of an
                                actuality, something applicable to daily living. What right had they, morally, to leave
                                out those two verses :—"Jesus said unto him, If thou wilt be perfect, go and sell that
                                thou hast, and give to the poor, and thou shalt have treasure in heaven : and come and
                                follow me. But when the young man heard that saying, he went away sorrowful: for he had
                                great possessions." Coming right up to the line of the meaning but not far enough to
                                declare the true intent. Drawing a perverted inference from the first point and omitting
                                the truth which would have been as destructive to their theories as ever was truth to
                                falsehood. Thus has, and thus does the great orthodox body prosper to-day and what
                                continues them in such success with men capable of thinking is what puzzles me. Men look
                                at things differently it is true, but one thing should be remembered, and that is, that
                                prejudice governs in the formation of opinions almost always.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., W. G" TEIform="persName"/>W. G. H.</byline></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Remarks" TEIform="index"/>Remarks</head><p TEIform="p">—It is very true that the several classes of religionists look upon things
                                very differently, and probably will never see eye to eye till they become of one faith
                                and one baptism. How any teacher of a religious class can illustrate this remarkable
                                interview between Jesus and the young man, without including the whole story, and make
                                it consistent with itself, is to us a puzzle. The young man sustained a good moral
                                character, and Jesus accepted him so far, and the text says, " loved him." He was also
                                in possession of some wealth,—"selfishproperty,"—and unless he consscrated this to the
                                Lord, he could not become a Christian. Jesus, evidently, wanted him to become a dis-
                                ciple, but with all his uprightness, according to the Mosaic law, Jesus says to him, One
                                thing thou lackest, "Go thy way, sell whatsoever thou hast [houses or lands, every-
                                thing you own,] and give to the poor, theu come, take up the cross, and follow me." It
                                is no wonder that the young man went away filled with sorrow To give away all his
                                earthly possessions, would reduce him to poverty and yet so long as he retained it he
                                could not be a follower of Christ.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Ed.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Waupaca, Wisconson, September 1887" TEIform="index"/>Waupaca, Wis., Sept.
                                1887</head><p TEIform="p">Henry C. Blinn, Sir:—In an article in the Oct. No. of the Manifesto, I find
                                the Elder has said that his " theology did not recognize the Bible as the word of God,
                                that Jesus was not the Christ, and that the God of Israel was not the God of the
                                Universe." I had read aloud to a dear friend, all the articles in the Manifesto, thus
                                far, which she liked much, until I came to the above mentioned words, when she said she
                                could not accept that, and seemed quite shocked. I have often thought that radical men,
                                and women too, sometimes make very unqualified remarks even when they are trying to do
                                good. If the Elder had explained why he believed so, it would probably have been all
                                right, for I think he is a noble man, and a staunch Christian, although I have never had
                                the pleasure of meeting him. Perhaps you could explain his meaning in a few words in the
                                next Manifesto, and oblige your friend and well wisher,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M., H. N." TEIform="persName"/>H. N. M.</byline></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Remarks" TEIform="index"/>Remarks</head><p TEIform="p">—1st. In the writing of articles for publication, people must write from what
                                they have read, or heard others say, or from what they know by experience. As no two
                                persons can think and feel exactly alike, at the same time, so it will be reasonable to
                                conclude that no two will be likely to represent themselves exactly alike on any
                                particular subject. Some persons almost bewilder us with a multiplicity of words, while
                                others use so few that we are left to guess what they mean. Some are very speculative in
                                    <pb n="16" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 16 THE MANIFESTO. their illustrations, while
                                others are laboriously practical. A writer must he followed carefully, if we would
                                understand fully, the thoughts he presents for inspection. When it is said that the
                                Bible is not the word of God, the mind of the sensitive Protestant is wounded, as he has
                                been taught to believe that the Bible from the first of Genesis to the last of
                                Revelation, is wholly God's inspired word. The best scholars, however, in the Protestant
                                church do not believe this, hence the revision of the Bible which they have so recently
                                given to us. A book of God with not less than 150,0C0 errors, certainly needed the care
                                of some good and wise men. On this subject there is antagonism, even in the Christian
                                churches. The Catholics say that their Bible is the word of God, and that the Bible of
                                the Protestants is a spurious record. On the other hand the Protestants call their Bible
                                the word of God, and that of the Catholic church a book not suitable to be read. This
                                being the case, we need not wonder if individuals sometimes express an opinion. It does
                                not hurt the book and need do no harm to the reader if he prays as he reads. We think
                                you will find it difficult to point out the place where it is recorded that the Bible is
                                the inspired word of God. The passage that came the nearest to this claim, has been
                                found to be spurious and as a matter of course corrected in the revision. Read the
                                sixteenth verse of the third chapter in the second epistle to Timothy. "All scripture is
                                given by inspiration of God and is profitable for doctrine, &amp;c " This has been
                                changed to read, All scripture given by inspiration of God is profitable for doctrine,
                                &amp;c. If the first reading was the Word of God, what shall we say of the last? The
                                Bible tells its own story, that it suffered from the hands of artful, selfish, de-
                                signing men who have not hesitated to change the text to advance their own religious
                                interests. Words, verses and even the half of a chapter that have been for years upon
                                years, fitted into sermons and lectures to frighten the hearers into one form of
                                theology and out of another, are now of no force in illustration, and but few would have
                                patience to hear them repeated. Do you wonder that some persons who hate to I e
                                deceived, are ready to say that the Bible is not in its every chapter, the Word of God.
                                2nd. What does the Bible say about Jesus Christ? Who was Jesus? Ans. The son of man. Who
                                was Christ? Ans. The son of God. When Jesus was commissioned to preach, he was anointed
                                at the baptism of John, and was then known as Jesus Christ, or Jesus the anointed. It is
                                of far more importance that we learn to live as he lived, than it is that we should be
                                over anxious about the name by which he was known. If we say Jesus, or Christ or Jesus
                                Christ or Christ Jesus, with the mind to depart from all unrighteousness, we shall
                                probably come pretty near the mark. 3rd. The interrogation put forth by Job would be
                                quite as pertinent at this day as it was at an earlier date. "Canst thou by searching
                                find out God? canst thou find out the Almighty unto perfection? Job xi., 7. Finite as we
                                are, it is in all probability quite impossible for us to know everything, but if we have
                                learned that the power which rules the Sun, Moon and Stars, as well as our little earth,
                                is known and feared and loved as our God, Creator of the universe and all that therein
                                is, then we have a knowledge not to be despised. This same power, evidently ruled when
                                Adam was in Eden and has ruled heaven and earth from that day to this. Theologians
                                sometimes ariange their arguments so curiously that you may take from or add to them,
                                and the change does but little or no harm. At the best, it is generally considered that
                                the study of theology is of far less value than a life of practical righteousness.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Ed.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A smooth sea never made a skillful mariner..." TEIform="index"/> A smooth sea
                            never made a skillful mariner... </head><p TEIform="p">A smooth sea never made a skillful mariner; neither do uninterrupted prosperity
                            and success qualify for usefulness and happiness. The storms of adversity, like the storms
                            of the ocean, arouse the faculties and excite the invention, prudence, skill and fortitude
                            of the voyager.</p></div2><pb n="17" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Retrospection" TEIform="index"/>RETROSPECTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tatterton, M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. Tatterton</byline><p TEIform="p">Another year has passed into eternity with its sad and pleasant records. Pleasant
                            as it speaks of victories gained over self and temptations to error. One thing is certain
                            the New Year finds us one year nearer our Eternal Home the state of perfection or vice
                            versa. A the beginning of the year it is customary for thoughtful persons to make new
                            resolutions concerning their conduct in the future ; it is generally regarded as a favorable
                            opportunity to forsake bad habits and commence the journey of life afresh determined that
                            the soul shall gain the ascendency over the g-osser elements of our natures. Wa need
                            firmness and courage to carry out a whole hearted devotion and lo arm the soul with every
                            advantage possible, to review our past lives, to test our motives, affections and
                            inclinations. What eye save one which seeth in secret notes the efforts of the soul to walk
                            with God, or the repentance for follies and sins of the past? There are seasons of soul
                            refreshing and renewing when baptized iu the love of God the Christian starts anew on the
                            heavenly journey. God grant that the closing and the beginning, and indeed every day of the
                            present and coming years may be blest by the abiding presence of the Holy Spirit; which
                            shall be the means of drawing our hearts from earth to heaven or in other words while
                            faithfully performing our work on earth, securely placing our soul's treasure, " where no
                            moth corrupteth or thief approacheth." Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Use temporal things..." TEIform="index"/>Use temporal things... </head><p TEIform="p">Use temporal things, but desire eternal.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It doesn't pay to worry" TEIform="index"/>IT DOESN'T PAY TO WORRY</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">If you would keep a book, and everyday put down the things that
                                    worry you, and see what becomes of them, it would be a benefit to you. You allow a
                                    thing to annoy you just as you allow a fly to settle on you and plague you, and you
                                    lose your temper, and you justify yourself in being thrown off your balance by
                                    causes which you do not trace out. But if you would see what it was that threw you
                                    off your balance, and put it down in your little book, and follow it out and see
                                    what becomes of it, you would see what a fool you were in the matter. The art of
                                    forgetting is a blessed art, but the art of overlooking is quite as important. And
                                    if we should take time to write down the origin, progress and outcome of a few of
                                    our troubles, it would make us ashamed of the fuss we made over them, and we should
                                    be glad to drop such things and bury them at or.ce in eternal forgetfulness. Life is
                                    too short to be worn out in petty worries, frettings, hatreds and vexations. Let us
                                    think only on whatsoever things are pure, and lovely, and gentle, and of good
                                    report.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Healthy fruit" TEIform="index"/>A HEALTHY FRUIT</head><p TEIform="p">A Lazy dyspeptic was bewailing his own misfortunes, and speaking with a friend on
                            the latter's hearty appearance. "What do you do to make you so healthy and strong?" inquired
                            the dyspeptic. "Live on fruit alone," answered his friend. "What kind of fruit?" "The fruit
                            of industry, and I am never troubled with indigestion."—</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="This world and the next" TEIform="index"/>This World and the Next</head><p TEIform="p">—If me n would be at half the pains to provide themselves " treasures in heaven,"
                            which they are generally at to get estates here on earth, it were impossible for any man to
                            be d . . . . d. But when we come to earthly matters, we do; when to heavenly, we only
                            discourse : heaven has our tongues and talk, but the earth our whole man besides.—South.
                            Every may-be hath a may-not-be.</p></div2><pb n="18" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>THE MANIFESTO. JANUARY, 1888</head><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Office of Publication" TEIform="index"/>Office of Publication</head><p TEIform="p">The Manifesto is published on the first of each month, at Shaker Village,
                                Mer. Co., N. H. All articles for publication should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, and
                                all letters on financial business to A. Y. Cochran. TERMS. One copy per year, postage
                                paid, .75 " " six months, " .40 Send for specimen copy, free.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New year" TEIform="index"/>THE NEW YEAR.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Yv ith this number we enter upon the eighteenth volume of The Manifesto. We
                                trust it may be to all a new year of peace, prosperity and spiritual growth. Our duty
                                before God and toward man should be more clearly denned, that our growth in knowledge,
                                and the order of our lives may move in harmony with each other. It is of much more
                                consequence to us what we may do and how we may live, than it is for us to be over
                                anxious about the work of redemption iu other souls. First, be assured that we abide in
                                the true vine ; that we are living branches, and that we are able to sustain other
                                branches. Like the sower that went forth to sow ; some of our efforts to do good may not
                                have met with our anticipated success. The glad tidings to humanity and the doctrine of
                                good will to man has often been received much after the same manner. We have received
                                all, however, that a disciple of the divine Teacher could ask. The compensation has been
                                liberal for the amount of labor expended. Since the publishing of our first paper many
                                remarkable changes have transpired iu the religious world, and we enjoy the tliought
                                that our little messen- ger, even in its simplicity, has rendered some aid in moulding a
                                more liberal spirit among those who are on their pilgrimage to the Holy City. The
                                Manifesto has ever rejoiced in the prosperity of the upright, and felt assured that
                                ample compensation would be awarded for every deed of charity and love. If true to our
                                mission we cannot do otherwise than walk in the path of the Savior of Men. Bear a daily
                                cross against the elements of the world ; renounce its relations and crucify all its
                                affections and lusts. Heal the sick. Cast out evil influences. Assist the lame to walk.
                                Restore sight to the blind, and in the spirit of our God "undo the heavy burdens and let
                                the op- pressed go free." '-Do unto others as ye would that they should do unto you."
                                This is the permanent, safe way, and beyond which it would be difficult to pass. In the
                                future as in the years that have passed before us, The Manifesto will work assiduously
                                for the growth of righteousness and peace in the earth. For the inflowing of the spirit
                                of God which is able to establish and to maintain the new heavens and new earth, and for
                                that increase in divine knowledge, so essential, in the judicious care of the body,—the
                                temple of God,—that we may be better able to judge correctly for the soul. The kingdom
                                of heaven, said Jesus, JANUARY <pb n="19" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 19 is
                                already within you, and the Revelator wrote, "Behold, the tabernacle of God is with men,
                                and He will dwell with them, and they shall be his people, and God himself shall be with
                                them and be their God." After this manner let us teach, and so live that God may dwell
                                in us. Our work is in the interest of freedom ; in breaking the chains that enslave the
                                body, that makes of the image of God, a beast of burden, and no less, in breaking the
                                bonds that hold the spirit of man a willing slave to the sins of the world. It is in the
                                learning and teaching of that form of truth that shall make the soul free in Christ. In
                                the testimony that brings forward a new life, and makes of every man and of every woman,
                                a new creature, that they may be known while on the earth, as children of God. With
                                those of diverse faith, and maintaining other forms of religious life we can have no
                                time to contend. God is their judge ! It is best for " every man to be fully persuaded
                                in his own mind," and then to work accordingly ; and with our best exertion, we shall
                                probably find enough to do at home. Very little, if any good can be accomplished by
                                controversy, especially as it is said to lead to the gates of h.. 1. It is our duty
                                through the columns of The Manifesto and in our daily lives, to declare our faith by
                                works of righteousness, and to establish this confidence in the minds of all men that we
                                do live in accordance with the doctrine that we publish before the world.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant roads make pleasant drives..." TEIform="index"/> Pleasant roads make
                            pleasant drives... </head><p TEIform="p">Pleasant roads make pleasant drives. Pleasant thoughts make pleasant lives.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Necessity of proper mastication" TEIform="index"/>NECESSITY OF PROPER
                                MASTICATI0N</head><p TEIform="p"> The food is often washed into the stomach with one of various liquids
                                without mastica- tion, and we may with safety and great propriety add, that unless there
                                is some change in the food habit of children, our success in the direction of
                                tooth-preservation will be but limited. Fluids must be restricted at meal time. Solid
                                food must be substituted for the semi-solid, and the eight or ten minutes usually
                                occupied in the consumption of a meal must be extended to twenty-five or thirty minutes.
                                I say constantly to the parents of my young patients : If you want to save this child's
                                teeth, you must banish drink from the table during meal time; let the children drink all
                                they want before and after meals, but at meals tlw food should be taken as nearly dry as
                                possible, and let the child spend half an hour or more in its mastication, utilizing the
                                natural secretions—not washing down its food with copious draughts without an effort on
                                the part of the teeth to triturate and prepare it for the subsequent digestive process.
                                I want to make it clear that, in my estimation, the loss of function is one great cause
                                of this rapid decay of teeth. The healthy or normal development of the teeth is exactly
                                in proportion to the stimulus of the resistance that is offered to them in the mas-
                                tication of food.—Exchange.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good rules for winter" TEIform="index"/>GOOD RULES FOR WINTER</head><p TEIform="p">Keep the back, especially between the shoulder blades, well covered; also,
                                the chest well protected. In sleeping in a cold room establish the habit of breathing
                                through the nosej and never with the mouth open. Never go to bed with cold or damp feet.
                                Never omit regular bathing, for unless the skin is in active condition the cold will
                                close the pores and favor congestion or other diseases. When hoarse speak as little as
                                possible until the hoarseness is recovered from, else the the voice may be permanently
                                lost, or difficulties of the throat be produced. <pb n="20" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 20
                                THE MANIFESTO. When going from a warm atmosphere into a cooler one keep the mouth almost
                                closed so that the air may be warmed by its passage through the nose ere it reaches the
                                lungs. Never stand still in cold weather, especially after having taken a slight degree
                                of exercise, and always avoid standing on ice or snow, or where the person is exposed to
                                cold wind. —Sanitarian.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Refreshing drink" TEIform="index"/>A Refreshing Drink</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A drink that is truly refreshing for one suffering from sore
                                        throat or cold, is made by pouring a quart of boiling water over a carefully
                                        washed handful of Irish moss. Let it stand until the water is cool, then strain
                                        through a muslin bag; add sugar and lemcn juice, with a few thin slices of
                                        lemon, until it is about like a mild lemonade; a little cinnamon is considered
                                        an addition by some people.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="American queen" TEIform="index"/>American Queen</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Temperance" TEIform="index"/>Temperance</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">About 50,000,000 pages were printed by the Woman's Temperance
                                    Publication Association last year. " What is whiskey bringing, do you ask? I'll tell
                                    you; it is bringing men to prison and to the gallows, and it is bringing women and
                                    children to poverty and want." There never was a truer answer than this. It is
                                    estimated that it sends to prison every year one hundred thousand men and women.
                                    Twenty thousand children are sent to the workhouse annually by drink. Three hundred
                                    murders are caused by intemperance every year. Two hundred thousand children are
                                    made orphans every year, by this dreadful evil; and sixty-five thousand are killed
                                    by intemperance every year, in this country.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Messenger of peace" TEIform="index"/>Messenger of Peace</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When you hear that a man drinks, it means that he does not know..." TEIform="index"/>When you hear that a man drinks, it means that he does not know... </head><p TEIform="p">When you hear that a man drinks, it means that he does not know when or how much
                            to drink. Defile not the mouth with impure words.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let in the sunlight" TEIform="index"/>LET IN THE SUNLIGHT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="De Graw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>Hamilton De Graw</byline><p TEIform="p">How that call already brightens all the hopes of the mind. Let in the sunlight.
                            To the pale sickly plant striving to grow in the damp mildew lined cellar how refreshing and
                            invigorating is the sunlight. Watch the gradual change from the faded and colorless tissues
                            to the deep green and healthy look that has been wrought in its organism through the agency
                            of the sunlight. As the sun is the material fountain from which flows the life invigorating
                            elements that make the universe habitable to both animal and vegetable organisms, so from
                            the fountain of Eternal Truth come those life inspiring forces that illumine the soul of man
                            and enable him to grow in the spirit. O the wail that comes up out of the subterranean
                            caverns where souls are pining in darkness. '' Give us the light! Let in the sunlight on our
                            souls or we perish ! !" Wheu I see souls who should stand upright walking in the image of
                            their Creator an honor to the truth and a glory on the earth, groveling in the lowest depths
                            of those appetites and passions that completely shut out the sunlight and make the chambers
                            of the soul only a fit habitation for bats and lizards, how I wish that some spiritual
                            earthquake would shatter the walls of the imprisoned soul and open it to God's blessed
                            sunlight. Refreshing showers are often needed in the spiritual as well as the physical
                            world, moral convulsions, loud peals of thunder and vivid flashes of lightning to awaken the
                            dormant sou.1; but after all it would be useless if the sunlight of God's love did not come
                            to warm and inspire with new life the now quickened soul. Sonyea, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="21" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>Juvenile</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Connecticut, 1888" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Conn. 1888</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Children :—You stand upon the portals of another New Year. What may
                                await you in 1888 you know not, but if you follow "the high path of duty," all will be
                                well. Make this year the best year of your lives, better for yourselves and for others.
                                Approach nearer to the Christian standard in those virtues that make and adorn Christian
                                character. How much room there is for improvement, and how grateful you should be for
                                further opportunities to make a better record. The use you make of your opportunities
                                decides the question of your gain or loss day by day. It is by seeking for and
                                appropriating that which is true and pure that you grow in spiritual strength. Make the
                                most of time. Time that is lost God will require. Time well spent brings abiding joy,
                                the sweetest and the best. Each hour is a priceless gift. Take care of the hours and the
                                days will take care of themselves. Don't mind the moment that is past, but the moment
                                that is present. Save all the moments you can by prudence and industry. The moments pass
                                by so swiftly, that if they are not applied to a good purpose, the years are left
                                periodically blank. Each day keep good vows. God will give you strength to live each day
                                when it comes. Strive to make each day such an one as He would wish you to live. Improve
                                the to-days and you will have no regret for the yesterdays, no fear for the to-morrows,
                                but will go onward till j ou have reached the final to ¦ morrow—the to-morrow that will
                                last through eternity. Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt</byline></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be not weary in well-doing" TEIform="index"/>" Be not weary in
                                well-doing." Gal. vi , 9</head><p TEIform="p">Why should we weary in doing well if we are striving for something better
                                than that which we already possess? Were we unwilling to make any effort to do or be
                                good we should soon find ourselves lacking that firmness and constancy which
                                characterizes the lives of our older Brethren and Sisters. We must be constant and
                                earnest if we would gain the true riches promised to those only who are willing to work
                                unceasingly for the right. Let us be constantly aiming toward that which is highest and
                                heat, for "in due season we shall reap if we faint not." We can easily perceive that if
                                the gardener did not care faithfully, each day, for his flowers and fruits, weeds would
                                grow up very soon and spoil his choicest plants. It is just so with our spiritual
                                growth, if we neglect to care for the beautiful flowers of Honesty, Truth and Purity,
                                our lives show it by a gradual development of that which is of the world; then let us
                                not grow weary in well- doing.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="L., J." TEIform="persName"/>J. L. Enfield, N. H.</byline></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Acrostic" TEIform="index"/>ACROSTIC</head><p TEIform="p">Prayer and Praise from Psalms, Judge me, 0 Lord; for I have walked in mine
                                integrity, xxvi., 1. Unto thee, O Lord, do we give thanks, lxv., 1. Let the words of my
                                mouth, and the meditation of mv heart be acceptable in thy sight, xix., 14. In the Lord
                                put I my trust, xi., 1. And they that know thy mime will put their trust in thee. ix.,
                                11. IVIy (rod, my God, why hast thou forsaken me? xxii.,1. AH the paths of the Lord are
                                mercy and truth, xxv., 10. The Lord is my shepherd 1 shall not want, xxiii., 1. | will
                                dwell in the house of the Lord forever, xxiii., 6. |_et the heavens rejoice, and let the
                                earth be glad. xcvi., 11. Draw nigh unto my soul and redeem it. Ixix., 18. And the
                                heavens shall praise thy wonders, O Lord. lxxxix., S. Deliver me from mine enemies O my
                                God. xlix., 1. Arise for our help, and redeem us for thy mercies' sake. xliv., 26. Let
                                those that seek thee rejoice and be glad in thee. lxx., 4. The Lord is my strength and
                                my shield, xxviii. 7. O Give thanks unto the Lord; for he is good exxxvi., 1.
                                Nevertheless he regarded their affliction when he heard their cry. cvi., 44. Mt.
                                Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Little men and women" TEIform="index"/>LITTLE MEN AND WOMEN </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Can you put the spider's web back in its place, That once has
                                        been swept away? Can you put the apple again on the bough, That fell at our feet
                                        to day? <pb n="22" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 99 THE MANIFESTO. Can fou put the
                                        lily-cup back on the stem, And cause it to live and grow? Can you mewl the
                                        butterfly's broken ¦wing, That was crushed by a cruel blow? Can you put the
                                        petals back on the rose? If you could, would it smell as sweet? Can you put the
                                        flour again in the husk, And show me the ripened wheat? You think that these
                                        questions are trifling, dear, Let me ask you another one : Can a hast}' word
                                        ever be unsaid, Or an unkind deed undone?</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Woman's journal" TEIform="index"/>Woman's Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True to God" TEIform="index"/>TRUE TO GOD</head><p TEIform="p">Never lower your principles to the world's standard. Never let sin, however
                                popular it may be, have any sanction or countenance from you, even by a smile. The manly
                                con- fession of Christ, when his cause is unpopular, is made by himself the condition of
                                his confessing us before men. If people find out that we are earnestly religious, as
                                they soon will if the light is shining, let us make hem heartily welcome to the
                                intelligence. And then, again, in order that the lights may shine without obstruction,
                                we must be simple and study simplicity. This is by no means so easy as it at first sight
                                appears; for in this highly artificial and pretentious age, all society is overlaid with
                                numerous affectations. Detest affectation as the contrary of truth and as hypocrisy on a
                                small scale, and allow yourselves to be seen freely by those around you in true colors.
                                There is an affectation of indifference to all things, and a lack of sensibility which
                                is becoming very prevalent in this age, which is the sworn foe to simplicity of
                                character. The persons who labor under this moral disorder pretend to have lost their
                                freshness of interest in everything ; for them, as they would have it be- lieved, there
                                is no surprise and no enthusiasm. As Christians, we must eschew un- truth in every form
                                ; we must labor to seem just what we are, neither better nor worse. To be true to God
                                and to the thought of his presence all day long, and to let self occupy as little as
                                possible of our thoughts ; to care much for his approval, and comparatively little for
                                the impression we are making upon others ; to feed the inward light with oil, and then
                                freely to let it shine—this is the great secret of edifieatio . May he indoctrinate us
                                into it. and dispose and enable us to illustrate it in our practice.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Goulburn, [Dr.]" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Goulburn,
                                in Sabbath Recorder.</byline></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To me, God has promised..." TEIform="index"/>To me, God has promised... </head><p TEIform="p">To me, God has promised, not the Heaven of the ascetic temper, or the
                                dogmatic theo- logian, or of the subtle mystic, or of the stern martyr ready alike to
                                inflict and bear; but a Heaven of purified and permanent affections ; of a book of
                                knowledge with eter- nal leaves, and unbounded capacities to read it; of those we love
                                ever around us, never misconceiving us or being harassed by us; of glorious work to do,
                                and adequate facili- ities to do it; a world of solved problems, as well as of realized
                                ideals. The many man- sions in my Father's House are many, not in number only, but in
                                variety.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Greg" TEIform="persName"/>—Greg.</byline></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New leaf" TEIform="index"/>THE NEW LEAF </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hopkins, A. A." TEIform="persName"/>A. A. HOPKINS </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> O would our leaves of life were fair With faithful writing
                                        everywhere ! O would that love shone clear and true Each plan and purpose ever
                                        through; That zeal did never faint and tire; That hope ne'er waned to low
                                        desire; That so each New Year's dawn should bring The old year's buds to
                                        blossoming; And so all plans and hopes should tend Through patient work to
                                        perfect end !</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vain expectations" TEIform="index"/>Vain Expectations. </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">If you should see a man digging in a snowdrift with the
                                        expectation of finding valuable ore, or planting seeds on the rolling billows,
                                        you would say at once that he was beside himself. But in what respect does this
                                        man differ from you, while you sow the seeds of idleness and dissipation in your
                                        youth, and expect the fruits of age will be a good constitution, elevated
                                        affections, and holy principles?</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Tribune" TEIform="index"/>Tribune</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Preserve thyself in chastity if thou wouldst wear the white robes of angelhood" TEIform="index"/>Preserve thyself in chastity if thou wouldst wear the white robes
                                of angelhood </head><p TEIform="p">Preserve thyself in chastity if thou wouldst wear the white robes of
                                angelhood.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div3></div2><pb n="23" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bright vision" TEIform="index"/>BRIGHT VISION</head><p TEIform="p">Canterbury, N. H. There's land beyond, I see the height, Press on, my soul, nor
                            fear the Efc night; A broader truth, a purer love Shall guide thee to those realms above. A
                            voice from out the "Higher plane" Calls Zion to bap tize again, To live in God in works of
                            truth, In love which over comes the earth.</p></div2><pb n="24" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Woman's work" TEIform="index"/>Woman's Work </head><p TEIform="p">Woman's Work is the title of a paper now being published in Athens, Ga., and
                                edited by Mrs. Ella K. Tenncnt. 50,000 copies of this first No. have bet n scut into
                                thousands of homes and will be read with anxious interest. It is to be a journal of "
                                Domestic Economy" and " so free from objectionable features that every line will prove a
                                benefit" to the reader. A paper that can maintain so high a standard must be a welcome
                                visitor in every family where a moral or reiigioua education is considered of value.
                                Woman's Wokk is published monthly at 50 ets. pr. yr. Address T. L. Mitchell, Athens,
                            Ga.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Heads and faces, and how to study them: A manual of phrenology and physiognomy for the people" TEIform="index"/>Heads and Faces, and how to Study them; A Manual of Phrenology and
                                Physiognomy for the People </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sizer, Nelson" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Heads and Faces, and how to Study them; A Manual of Phrenology and
                                Physiognomy for the People, by Prof. Nelson Sizer, Phrenological examiner, and Dr. II.
                                S. Drayton, Editor of the Phrenological Journal. 200 pages, Oct., 200 illust., paper,
                                40c.; extra cloth, $1.00. New York, Fowler &amp; Wells Co., Publishers, 775
                                Broadway. A new edition of this work, making 40,000 copies in about two years, has just
                                been published. Of all the interesting subjects which men and women study there is none
                                more interesting or important than the studying of the characters of each other;
                                therefore, if you want something to read that will interest you more thoroughly than any
                                book you ever read, send for a copy of Heads and Faces. It will show you how to read
                                people as you would a book, and to see if they are inclined to be good, upright, honest,
                                true, kind, charitable, loving, joyous, happy and trustworthy people, such as you would
                                like to know; or are they by nature untrustworthy, treacherous and cruel, uncharitable
                                and hardhearted, faultfinding, jealous, domineering people whom you would not want to
                                have intimate with yourselves or your families ? A knowledge of Human Nature as taught
                                in this book would save many disappointments in social and business life. It is sent by
                                mail, postpaid, on receipt of price, as above. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/> Hall's Journal of Health </head><p TEIform="p"> Hall's Journal of Health. Contents; Dec. 1887. Last Words; Concerning the
                                Food we Eat; Microbes that endanger Health; Stand up for the new and the True; Schools
                                in Medicine; A Case of Trance; What of the Potatoe : A Three Time Winner; Progress,
                                etc., etc. Office 206 Broadway, N. Y. $1. per year. The Phrenological Journal and
                                Science of Health. Contents: Dec. 1887. H. C. Potter, D. D. Shakespeare and Byron;
                                Notable People of the Day; Mathematics in Delineating Character; Pleasant Winter
                                Quarters; Concerning Margaret McKensie; A Girl's Problem; High Cultivation of the Organ
                                of Memory; A quest in Anthropometry; Penny Dinners in England; Consumption; Phthisic;
                                Salicylic Acid in Food; Malarial Exposure and Prevention; Notes in Science. Poetry,
                                etc., etc. Fowler &amp; Wells Co. 775 Broadway, N. Y. $2. a year.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind words" TEIform="index"/>Kind Words</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant Hill, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hill, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Henry ;—I kindly thank you for publishing the "Gospel Testimony
                                of Mother Ann Lee and the Elders, William Lee and James Whittaker." Their testimony is
                                the word of God, and the power of Christ to my soul. It will endure forever.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brown, N." TEIform="persName"/>N. Brown</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Preparation for death" TEIform="index"/>PREPARATION FOR DEATH</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">When you lie down at night, compose your spirits as if you were
                                    not to wake till the heavens be no more; and when you awake in the morning, consider
                                    that new day as your last, and live accordingly. Surely that night cometh of which
                                    you will never see the morning, or that morning of which you will never see the
                                    night, but which of your mornings or nights will be such you know not. Let the
                                    mantle of worldly enjoyment hang loosely about you, that it may be easily dropped
                                    when death comes to carry you into another world. When the corn is forsaking the
                                    ground, it is ready for the sickle ; when the fruit is ripe, it falls off the tree
                                    easily. So when a Christian's heart is truly weaned from the world, he is prepared
                                    for death, and ii will be the more easy for him. A heart disengaged from the world
                                    is a heavenly one ; and then we are ready for heaven, when our heart is there before
                                    us.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Guest, Louise" TEIform="index"/>Louise Guest </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Guest, Louise" TEIform="persName">Louise Guest</persName>, at Pleasant
                                Hill, Ky., Oct. 30, 1887. Age 63 yrs. 7 mo. and 11 days. She is blessed with those who
                                die in the Lord, they rest from their labors and their works do follow them. N. B.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Torry, Lemuel C." TEIform="index"/>Elder Lemuel C. Torry </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Torry, Lemuel C." TEIform="persName">Elder Lemuel C. Torry</persName>, at
                                Watervliet, Ohio. Nov 4, 1887. Age 63 yrs. 7 mo. and 22 days.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wallace, Rachel" TEIform="index"/>Rachel Wallace </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Wallace, Rachel" TEIform="persName">Rachel Wallace</persName>, at South
                                Family, Union Village, Ohio, Nov. 15, 1887. Age 39 yrs. 2 mo. and 7 days.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Advertisements" TEIform="index"/>[Advertisements]</head><p TEIform="p">[Advertisements deleted.]</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>