<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2211" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">22</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><date value="18921101" TEIform="date">November 1892</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">241-264</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="22" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
NOVEMBERPublished by the United Societies.
vol. XXII.
"For what is a man profited, if he shall gain the whole world, and
lose his own soul ? or what shall a man give in exchange for
his soul."Matt. XVI., 26.
Canterbury, N. H.
1892.
THE
MANIFESTO
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.	
	Page.
Fruits of Meditation,	241
Chastisement,      ....	-     242
Forms and Forces,   -	243
The Head of the Church,	-     245
At Last,            ....	247
Letter,H. DeGraw,	"
D. Offord,	248
In Memory of Annie Booker,	-     350
Marriage a Civil Right,	"
The Shakers,        ....	
Serenity,           ....	251
I Asked the Lord,         ...	"
Editorial,          ....	252
Removal,               ....	-     253
Notes About Home,	254
Consideration,	-     259
Mentor's Maxims,	"
Inquiry, No. 8.                 ...	-     260
Scripture Text,	"
The Face of an Angel,	-     261
Deaths,              ....	262
Music,Stewardship,	-     263
Books & Papers,	2G4
64 Sudbury St.,  Boston, Mass.
FIRE AND BURGLAR-PROOF SAFES.
Bank Safes, Bank Vaults, Bank Vault
Doors, and Deposit Work of all kinds.
The Mest Safe in the World.   160,000 in use.
Always preserve their contents
150 sold in Lynn, Mass., since that great lire
where 50 of our safes were subject to intense
heat, preserving their contents.
Cbampion Record also in the Great Chicago Fire in 1871, in the Great Boston Fire, in
1872, and in all the great fires since. Send
for circulars.        Agents Wanted.
IF you wish   to   advertise   anything anywhere at any time, write to GEO. P.
ROWELL & CO., No. 10 Spruce St., N. Y.
AGENTS WANTED
ON
Salary
OR
Commission,
FOR
JOHN L. STODDARD'S
"GLIMPSES OF THE WORLD,"THE    WORLD'S   COLUMBIAN
EXPOSITION,    MEN  AND ISSUES
OF '92.
BEST BOOKS.     BEST SYSTEM.
BEST   TERMS.
Address TVilley <fe Co., 1951.&T
State St., Springfield, Mass.
The Celebrated
BAND  INSTRUMENTS,
Snare and Bass Orums. Fires.   Piccolos, Clarionets, Cym
bats and an other irtatrumenta pertaining toBrass- Bands and Drum Corps.
a
JOHN P. 8THATTOW & SOIV,
43   &   45   Walker   Street.   NEW   YORK.
If Ton CABiroT set them or Tons
LOCAL   OEAI.KB8,   WE   WHJ.   Fnfl> SOMB
WjiT  O BUPPLTINO  TOO WITB -TfflB
STRATTON
RUSSIAN GUT
VIOLIN STRrNGS.
OuSen and tor CsMlogue and Prlct List.
john f stratton & son,
Musical Merchandise.
43  4i Walker 8t        SEW YOKiL
 A Noi-mai Course
 for Teachers.
 20   Complete   Courses
 for   Student and    Teacher.     All  instruc tion   by mail.  Send stamp /or  catalogue
 American     CorresPndence      Co"e&ei
 S. dansville, New York.
E. C, Morris &. Co,
SHEPP'S PHOTOGRAPHS
HOME STUDY
Vol. XXII.
NOVEMBER, 1892.
No. 11.--><pb n="241" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fruits of mediation" TEIform="index"/> FRUITS OF MEDITATION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/> Abraham Perkins.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Man is an enigma, creation a mystery and life a law unfathomable. We view objects from
                            different standpoints, and weigh mind, motive and matter from personal experiences and
                            individual status. Judgment is many times correct, but oftener false. As many have no
                            appreciation of the value of money, so is it evident, that a number no less, have no
                            appreciation of the qualities of man, of his talents, or goodness. We are prone to judge,
                            approve and condemn from conceit and estimation of self; from prejudice and fear of another
                            being preferred before ourselves ; and, (because of our ignorance,) from ambition aspiring
                            to positions beyond our creation, and from desire for the high consideration of man beyond
                            our merits. It is difficult for a selfish man to value the favors and kindness of friends.
                            It hardly occurs to him that he is under obligations and should make returns. From ambition
                            for name, for honor and authority, he thinks little of the wants, the comforts or the
                            deserts of his neighbor, and does less to aid or extend assistance. Ordinarily, the rich
                            have little realization of the sufferings of the poor ; the master has but little sympathy
                            with the servant, or the unrestrained with the oppressed. Well may the infidel question the
                            virtue of professed Christian religion where is to be found no brotherhood, affection or
                            relative sensation. Well may we all ask,is there nothing more noble or better to be derived
                            from Christianity? Are emanations from the Divine found in such conditions? Is this doing as
                            we would be done by ? Is it a spirit higher than is prominent in the lowest order of
                            animals? Oh, may we, who boast of endowments from on High, who claim the power of Christian
                            religion, purity of heart and a kinship with angels become so enlightened as to be able to
                            discern human composition, benighted conditions and the character of our own souls. May we
                            see ourselves, "be what we seem to be, and seem to be what we really are," make no
                            pretentious beyond our conditions, or claims beyond our deserts. Knowing our poverty, being
                            poor in spirit, may we be so humble as to acknowledge our status, and seek for <pb n="242" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> that which maketh rich in spirit, unselfish at heart, and Christian in all the
                            walks of life; thus bearing love and kindness to our neighbor, and humanely sympathizing
                            with the afflicted ; yea seek that power which gives a broken heart, a spirit of forgiveness
                            for the wrongs and troubles wrought by the envious and evil minded. Here comes in the final
                            call of God to man, which is designed to work his redemption; the sacrifice of the animal
                            within, which was prefigured by the offering of beasts at the Hebrew altars. No greater
                            offering can we bring to the altar than that of self, which is the only acceptable sacrifice
                            and power of atonement for life in Christ the Resurrection. Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Chastisement" TEIform="index"/> CHASTISEMENT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/> Martha J. Anderson.</byline><p TEIform="p"> " Whoso God loveth He chastenetfi, and scourgeth every son (and daughter) whom He
                            receiveth." In our present imperfect state of mental and spiritual unfoldment, there is much
                            in our lives that can not bear the test of virtue and goodness, and we unconsciously
                            manifest the crude elements of a yet untutored and undeveloped character. We need
                            continually the chastening and scourging of God's Spirit, administered through those who
                            have passed the searching ordeal, till somewhat of the earthly and sensual are eliminated
                            from their spirits, and they are able to speak the truth in the love of God, for "whoso He
                            loveth He chasteneth." Yet how unwelcome is reproof, and how grievous to be borne by those
                            whose aspirations have not risen above self-worship, and whose vision is so beclouded by
                            gross conditions, that they can not discern any thing higher, neither do they desire to
                            conform to the ways and means that shall effect a radical change of heart. There are moral
                            as well as physical diseases that need the help of the good physician to remove, and there
                            is no medicine so effectual as just criticism. If we would become the sons and daughters of
                            God, be received in his heavenly kingdom, and form the white stones composing the structure
                            of the spiritual temple, we must bear the polishing process that alone can fit us for our
                            place. To live in communal relation, necessitates a cleansing and purification exceeding
                            that which obtains in ordinary society, also a self-renunciation that places the love of
                            neighbor above the love of self. Persons may have a certain degree of friendship and
                            fellowship, and closely fraternize in thought and feeling in many things ; yet casual
                            acquaintance and social relationship, does not reveal true innate selfhood with all its
                            defects and deformities ; but, bring people in close every-day association and communion,
                            and lo ! the latent diseases of heart and mind become visible; hidden faults come to the
                            surface, and there is often a decisive encounter with evils that need to be removed from the
                            individual. "God purgeth every one whom He receiveth." In nature, man exhibits little of the
                            essential essence of virtue. He is the child of circumstances and environment, and brings
                            into the world with <pb n="243" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> him the inheritance of the past. Disciplinary
                            processes througii many generations modifies natural proclivities and tendencies, and this
                            is accomplished through personal improvement; and whether development and perfection come
                            through a thousand earth lives and experiences, are the result of the soul's unfoldment
                            through many eons in the world of spirits; it is obvious that no conscious, immortal being
                            can attain to the altitude of ethical and spiritual excellence tnat ensures unalloyed
                            happiness, without severe and protracted discipline. "To transform from the carnal into the
                            spiritual, is the purpose of every true religion," and the great motorforce that shall
                            accomplish this, is love; love born of sacrifice, true Godlove, generated in the coronal
                            region of the brain, inspiring and filling the heart with emotion and affection, pure and
                            divine; translating human sympathy into beneficent deeds of unselfish devotion, kindness,
                            mercy, longsuffering and patience, as was beautifully exemplified in the exalted life and
                            ministration of the lowly Nazarene, whose testimony was a continual rebuke to all foims of
                            evil; yet whose soul was drawn out in charity and love to poor erring mortals. Who suffers
                            most, those who harden their hearts against all needful chastisement and reproof, and carry
                            with them a bold, defiant spirit which brooks all restraint; or, those who bear with the
                            infirmities of a blind self-will, while they strive as does the master with untamed beasts,
                            to subdue, train and direct the misdirected energies of unregenerate nature ? No*t in
                            external circumstances, but in the soul itself are the real causes which produce happiness
                            or misery. "The heaven ye seek, the hell ye fear, Are with yourselves alone." We carry
                            ourselves wherever we go, even beyond the grave; and those who recklessly wish they were
                            dead, when they meet with criticism or mortification, will be astonished and chagrined, to
                            find their own imperfect selves revealed in the light of immortal existence. "Still in
                            perpetual judgment I hold assize within, With sure reward of holiness And dread rebuke of
                            sin." "How good it is when thou art reproved to show repentance." The spirit of Truth comes
                            to us all as a purifier and refiner, to create us anew, and prepare us for the companionship
                            of those who, through great tribulation, have reached the goal of redemption. Mount Lebanon,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Forms and forces" TEIform="index"/> FORMS AND FORCES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/> Oliver C. Hampton.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Spirit is ceaseless and eternal activity. The infinite varieties of this energy are called
                            forces. Every force evolves a form. In fact a form is only a crystallized force, so much
                            arrested as to become outwardly visible. The irresistible result of all force, spirit,
                            energy, or whatever you may call it is an eternal tendency to higher and more perfect forms
                            and conditions ; called evolution. The Indians used to produce fire by two sticks rubbed
                            together. Electricity is a much improved form of producing <pb n="244" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> fire. This
                            new method has to have a new form of visible expression. So of every phenomenon of force.
                            The reason I suppose, of all improvement from year to year and age to age is because the
                            energy moving to that end is benevolent and intelligent. It seems as if there could be no
                            other reason. Well then, change is written upon all things and we must try to believe that
                            all is evolving night and day, year in and year out for the better. Jenghis Khan, through
                            his ambition and cruelty and resulting wars, destroyed fourteen millions of persons in fifty
                            years. Not half that number have been destroyed in perhaps the last five hundred years. Here
                            is a vast improvement. It shows that the world has progressed. How many saurians,
                            mud-mongers and reptiles of hideous form and nature, have long since left the earth never to
                            return. All these have been replaced by more beautiful and nobler species. Let me come a
                            little nearer home. About sixty yeirs ago I lived fulsome years in a log cabin with a
                            chimney of mud and sticks. It was roofed with clapboards and daubed with mud between the
                            logs; and the battened doors were furnished with wooden latches with a string to raise them.
                            My diet was rye bread and milk, the latter served in a black potter's bowl. Now all that is
                            replaced by a splendid dwelling and plenty to eat. This same law of evolution to better
                            things obtains in social, moral and spiritual matters as well as temporal, economical and
                            financial. My school books were the Testament and Webster's spelling book; toward the last,
                            readers, very elementary geographies and arithmetics were added. At present the status of
                            the schools is almost infinitely improved and enlarged. Again, wrhen young, I was sick,
                            melancholy and despairing. But as the years rolled by, I came to discover that wonderful
                            kingdom which Jesus declared was Avithin us. Here was an immense improvement in my condition
                            ; and doubtless the form of my countenance evidenced it. At the same time I found the
                            kingdom I found also the King. Herein is a' divine mystery sealed up to those not initiated
                            by actual experience in the unspeakable arcana of a long spiritual life. But at this sublime
                            point in Zion-ward travel one can say with Jesus "I and the Father are one." Also is it come
                            to pass that the wise man's saying is verified; viz. "A man's own mind is sometimes wont to
                            tt 11 him more than seven wise men sitting above on a high tower." How glorious and how near
                            to the fountain of everlasting consolation do these sublime experiences place the faithful
                            Zion traveler! This is all beautifully expressed in four lines of the most remarkable poem
                            which has as yet appeared in the Manifesto, entitled "Evolution." "Buried in matter for high
                            tuition, Wrought by earnest and ceaseless strife. Growing brighter through time's attrition,
                            Reaching Nirvana, the goal of life." Soaring amid such altitudes of inward glory, who can
                            care for meats and drinks, or gaudy apparel, or World's Fairs, or perishing externals of any
                            kind? O that men would try the experiment of living our holy, <pb n="245" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> pure
                            Shaker life, which is the quintessence of all Christian science so-called. If faithful to
                            its sacred obligations, they never would, naynever could abandon it for the husks of the
                            rudimental plane. Union Village, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Elder Henry;--Enclosed I send you an article..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Beloved Elder Henry;--Enclosed I send you an article...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Sonyea, August 1892" TEIform="index"/>Sonyea N. Y. Aug. 1892.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Henry;Enclosed I send you an article, which was taken from the Rochester Post
                            Express. I should be glad to have it placed in the Manifesto, as it refers to our beloved
                            Elder Daniel Boler. Your Gospel brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sevester, E. P." TEIform="persName"/> E. P. Sevester.</byline></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How the shakers regard the head of their church" TEIform="index"/> HOW THE SHAKERS REGARD
                            THE HEAD OF THEIR CHURCH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Basting, Louis" TEIform="persName"/> Louis Basting.</byline><p TEIform="p"> West Pittsfield, Mass.Elder Daniel Boler, the head of the Shaker church in America, has
                            resigned his office. Being almost ninety years cf age, the infirmities of body have
                            compelled him to relinquish a position he has held for almost fifty years. Elder Daniel
                            comes from sturdy Kentucky stock. He was a 3Toung child when his parents united with the
                            Society then forming at South Union. Attempts being made at that time to enact laws hostile
                            to the interests of Believers by endeavoring to prohibit the admission of children and
                            minors to their ranks, young Daniel, then ten years of age, earnestly urged his father to
                            take him to one of the Societies in the Eastern states, where a more liberal spirit
                            prevailed. In compliance with this request, the father and his enthusiastic son set out on
                            their long journey of almost a thousand miles on foot. "With the exception of an occasional
                            ride offered by a driver of an ox team, they walked the whole distance. While father and
                            son, exiles for conscience's sake, were pursuing their memorable journey, British cannon
                            were assaulting Baltimore, and the national capitol went up in flames kindled by hostile
                            hands. But young Daniel felt, even if he was not clearly conscious of it then, that the
                            warfare to which he was anxious to devote himself required a finer heroism than the
                            profession of arms, and an endurance more rugged than the length of a campaign in the field.
                            Upon their arrival at Mount Lebanon they were received with tender affection. The father,
                            after many years of consecrated labor, died in the faith ; and the son, when he had reached
                            manhood, was called from one place of responsibility to another, until finally he became the
                            head of the church. Elder Daniel is one of the best examples of Shakerism. Besides the
                            rudiments of education he received no literary training whatever; but his mechanical talents
                            found ready employment in the workshop, and his industry and good judgment were valuable
                            factors in the management of the farm. Whatever position he was placed in he was sure to
                            give the best of his abilities to the performance of his duties. The characteristics which
                            distinguished his direction of temporal affairs became still more conspicuous in his
                            administration of the spiritual concerns of his people. His judgment was always impartial,
                            being no respector of persons; and while he has allowed many changes and inno- <pb n="246" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> vations to take place whenever he felt that it was best to do so, he has never
                            yielded to the clamors of noisy faction or permitted any departure from the fundamental
                            principles of the Society. He has exercised his functions in a fatherly spirit, seeking to
                            rule by kindness and love rather than by authority, but when necessity seemed to demand it
                            he could be stern and firm as a rock. The gratitude and respect of the people are
                            brightening the well-earned repose of his declining years. It may be of interest to the
                            public to state the nature of government and the appointment of officials among Believers.
                            The chief authority is vested in a ministry usually composed of four memberstwo of each sex;
                            but the first elder of that body is virtually the supreme leader; his decisions are final.
                            Ordinarily, however, all orders and directions are issued by the ministry in union and with
                            the advice and consent of the leading elders and covenant members of the different Societies
                            directly concerned. It has been the policy from the beginning to make no appointment and
                            enact no important legislation without the general union and the assent of the church; but
                            the practice of voting and electioneering is utterly unknown. The system of government is
                            held to be theocratic, or divine; not, indeed, claiming special inspiration or infallibility
                            for its operations, but in the sense that it acts from the purest motives, without
                            partiality or self-interest, simply for the highest welfare of individual, family, or
                            society, as far as human wisdom can decide such matters. The newly chosen leader is Joseph
                            Holden, who has been Elder Daniel's able coadjutor for several years. The general verdict is
                            that Elder Joseph is "dignissimus"the most worthy among all the brethren. The appointment
                            could not be improved upon unless the lot had fallen upon some bright and talented sister
                            like Eldress Harriet Bullaid or Eldress Anna White. The equality of the sexes is a well
                            established principle among Believers. Lucy Wright was head of the church for twenty years,
                            and her administration was successful in every respect; her wise and practical sayings are
                            often referred to and her memory is held in affectionate remembrance. The induction to
                            office is a simple announcement, without formality or ceremony, and the appointment is made
                            without any reference to length of tenure ; it may extend through the balance of life, or to
                            be terminated through some form of inability, or the incumbent may be removed to give way to
                            some one judged to be more efficient and capable. In all cases the interests of the Society
                            are considered paramount to private wishes and preferences. If it be admitted that such a
                            system of administration is rational and divine, can the same be said of the mode of
                            election of the head of the Church of England, for example? Mr. Gladstone appointed Dr.
                            Benson to that high office, and when he notified the chapter of the diocese of. his pleasure
                            those married priests as- <pb n="247" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> sembled, clothed in their canonicals,
                            chanting and praying and invoking the Holy Ghost to guide them in their election of an
                            Archbishop, and, io! a miracle happened, for their choice fell upon Mr. Gladstone's man who,
                            by the way is a most estimable and worthy gentleman. That some miracle has happened at the
                            election of every bishop of the established church. It is said to be a historical fact that
                            only one chapter ever ventured to disregard the government's mandate, but when they received
                            a peremptory communication they hastened to rectify their action. Can it be possible that
                            the Holy Ghost was coerced? What a travesty and mockery of pure religion those performances
                            are ! Or what shall we say of the recent proceedings at Minneapolis and Chicago, where one
                            party shouted and yelled for its candidate for twentyfour minutes, and then the other party
                            yelled for its nominee for twenty-five minutes? Where was reason, argument, the dignified
                            discussion of principle that should distinguish the deliberations of the representatives of
                            many millions of people? The Shaker form of government is, of course, unsuitable to society
                            at large, but if its leading principle of justice and benevolence should find a fuller
                            expression in the conduct of rulers and the enactments of law-makers throughout the world,
                            all mankind would be greatly benefited.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I want to become more able and capable of blessing..." TEIform="index"/>
                            I want to become more able and capable of blessing...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> "I want to become more able and capable of blessing the sorrowful, soothing the 'afflicted
                            and bringing souls to Christ in all the fullness of his spirit."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="At last" TEIform="index"/> "AT LAST."</head><p TEIform="p"> To John G-. Whittier, Friend and Poet. Maktha j. Anderson. Entered at last "the humble door"
                            And mansions blest, "The sheltering shade" and calm retreat From earth's unrest. And found
                            beside the silvery tide Where strivings cease, The "green expansions," of eternal Love and
                            peace. In strains seraphic heard "the new And holy song;" And "neath the healing trees," Oh
                            may Thy rest be long. The soulful lays of by-gone years Remain to bless; Sweet benediction
                            of thy life Of righteousness. O poet-heart! through eons past Thy mould was cast, In full
                            perfection's glory wrought To shine at last. The star of heavenly poesy, The peerless gem,
                            That glistens in the world's Immortal diadem. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Brother:--I received an excellent letter from Elder Fredrick..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Beloved Brother:--I received an excellent letter from Elder Fredrick...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Sonyea, August 24, 1892" TEIform="index"/>Sonyea, N. Y., Aug. 24, 1892.</dateline><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Offord,</byline><p TEIform="p"> Beloved Brother :I received an excellent letter from Elder Frederic to-day, and I said, how
                            beautiful are the gifts of the spirit. Last Sabbath I was strongly impressed to write to the
                            good father, and I trust he has received my letter before this time. To hear from him seemed
                            like a blessed gift, and I was thankful to be in union with it. I will accept his admonition
                            and be more prompt in the future to keep a <pb n="248" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> closer union with my
                            Gospel relation that the spiritual emanations flowing to them may also be my portion. We
                            think of you quite often and deeply appreciate the love extended by our friends at the North
                            Family. We are also pleased to hear from the Chicago Society, that they are gathering to the
                            more experienced and spiritual body. The time is nearing and even with us now when the old
                            heavens and earth are passing away with a great commotion, and to gather into the Lord's
                            pavilion "till the tempest and the storm passes by" is a blessed privilege. Every one that
                            is faithful in the Gospel cause will yet see the coming of the new dispensation and rejoice
                            with an exceeding great joy. I want to relate to you a vision, beautiful to me, that I had
                            recently. In the small hours of the morning there appeared before me a grand structure
                            unfinished, but magnificent in proportions, and upon asking what it was, the reply came, it
                            was the (not a) Baptist Church and the name did not have any connection with the religious
                            sect called Baptist. But it implied that whosoever worked to build it must labor for, and
                            attain unto a spiritual baptism. It appeared that I was one designated to go and work upon
                            it, though it was not revealed to me the part I was to take, yet in obedience to the
                            appointment I accepted. I was led to climb scaffolding after scaffolding until I was lost in
                            the magnificence of the structure, and then I returned to consciousness. That was a
                            spiritual gift to me, and has a significance ; it shows the nature and work of God, and that
                            individuals as they ascend from one scaffolding, or degree of height to another, their whole
                            being becomes absorbed in the grandeur and beauty of the work. Dear brother we ask your
                            prayers, and may the angels of power minister to you in the arduous duties of your calling.
                            From your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="De Graw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>Hamilton De Graw.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Brother Hamilton:--Your very interesting letter of Aug. 24th..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Beloved Brother Hamilton:--Your very interesting letter of Aug. 24th...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, September 4, 1892" TEIform="index"/>Mount Lebanon, N. Y.,
                            Sept. 4,1892.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Beloved Brother Hamilton : Your very interesting letter of Aug. 24th., has been read with a
                            great deal of interest. Your vision is very suggestive. That a structure has been reared
                            there is no doubt; that its foundation is on the rock, is also certain; that the structure
                            is incomplete is apparent to all progressive minds. Has the time not arrived when the floor
                            just above the foundation should be laid, that the Temple of God may be in a condition to
                            receive the sin-sick and heavy laden of all nations ? There is certainly a mighty revolution
                            going on in the world of mind, and must and will most assuredly burst forth upon the world
                            of matter, reorganizing the social, political and financial conditions now prevailing, but
                            tottering by reason of false, unjust and iniquitous foundations upon which they all rest. We
                            call, falsely, the age in which we live civilized and Christian: What a perversion of terms!
                            In our civilization the strong oppress the weak; and those who labor eat not of the fruits
                            of their toil, except in a starvation way. The laws are all made to favor the few at the
                            expense of the many: Un- <pb n="249" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> righteousness is "winked at, and where, as
                            "The Flaming Sword" says, "the hungry are unfed, and the naked unclothed ; where immorality
                            and bestiality run riot; where woman must sell herself for food; where man will degrade
                            woman to lustful indulgence" etc., etc. Read "The Flaming Sword," it is a live paper,
                            dealing with the living issues of the day without any compromise with the flesh. And can we
                            apply the name of Christian to such a state of things ? Are not the most highly Christian
                            nations veritable armories? Millions of their subjects being trained scientifically in the
                            art of human butchery, while the best talent of the chemical and mechanical class is turned
                            to invent the most destructive compounds, weapons and engines? Have we not come up to the
                            last days? and unless the power of God is manifest, will not the nations be destroyed by
                            their own hands ? Let Believers never be ashamed of the testimony of Mother, nor of the
                            power of God. What a blessing it would be if we were free from earthly and financial
                            encumbrances and could go forth and minister the saving power of the Gospel of Christ in its
                            increasing light. . Elder William Leonard's article in the Sept., number of the Manifesto
                            touches the key note of the increase. Those who do not live in the light will find
                            themselves in darkness and entirely unable to minister the Gospel of Christ, as revealed
                            through Mother, in power and demonstration of the Spirit. The world needs the power of the
                            resurrection minjstered to their bodies as well as their souls. We shall find that in the
                            days that are just upon us the Gospel will be a Redeemera Savior of the bodies of the
                            people. Not only from an understanding of the laws of the physical being, but by bringing
                            into operation the higher law exemplified in the life of Jesus, who healed the people of all
                            their infirmities, then put the law upon them to "6ro and sin no more." Can there be
                            anything more consistent than that a people living a pure, chaste life, should have a diet
                            corresponding to that life and in harmony with its laws? How often have some quoted the
                            saying of Jesus, "take no thought what ye shall eat or what ye shall drink or wherewithal ye
                            shall be clothed," to prove that the Gospel had nothing to do with people's eating and
                            drinking: "For after all these things do the Gentiles seek." Not considering how the
                            Gentiles took thought. What was their thought on their eating and drinking, was it not just
                            as it is with all flesh-loving people to-day, how they can gratify their appetites and
                            concoct drinks and food that will stimulate their passions and keep burning in their bodies
                            the fires of lust? Also, as to their clothing, do they not bow down to fashion's shrine, and
                            put on that outward adorning that feeds their pride, excites and continually keeps alive the
                            animal desire towards the opposite sex? Most assuredly should we not take thought as do the
                            Gentiles; but, as becometh the saints of God ; whose aspirations are ever upward, to know
                            and to obey the Divine both pertaining to our bodies and souls. Just so sure as the work <pb n="250" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> of God is moving from faith to faith, and that "light is sown for the
                            righteous," so sure must Believers have a diet in accord with their interior spiritual life,
                            before they shall be able to minister the Gospel that will alone supply the needs of a
                            sin-bound, suffering humanity. Our work is to perpetuate a Divine institution by obedience
                            to its laws ; every jot and tittle of which must be fulfilled. Thanks for your article in
                            "The Manifesto." May the spiritual gift control our every movement to the honor and
                            spreading of the Gospel of Christ as manifested in the testimony of Mother Ann, is my
                            earnest prayer. In kindest love. Your brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/> Daniel Offord.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memory of Annie Booker" TEIform="index"/> In Memory of ANNIE BOOKER.</head><p TEIform="p"> We love one that's zealous to fill up their station, As bold as a lion yet meek as a lamb;
                            In all their deportment without ostentation; The memory of such is like ointment and balm.
                            The soul that is willing to suffer temptation And never afraid to encounter the foe; Such
                            often are mentioned in good conversation And such we'll remember wherever we go. With all
                            that is lovely such souls are surrounded; Their very appearance is comely and fair. And all
                            who behold them shall yet be confounded, And have to acknowledge salvation is there.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Idumea" TEIform="persName"/> IDUMEA.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Marriage is a civil right, and that the children..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Marriage is a civil right, and that the children...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Marriage is a civil right, and that the children of this world, distinctly, from
                                    the followers of Christ, should marry, is quite natural, and this shows to what
                                    class marriage belongs. Marriage is a civil institution, properly belonging to the
                                    citizens of the world, and therefore the privilege of every man who chooses to use
                                    it.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Dunlavy" TEIform="index"/>Dunlavy.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The following letter was taken from an article sent to the Boston Transcript..." TEIform="index"/>
                            The following letter was taken from an article sent to the Boston Transcript...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, East Canterbury, July 1892" TEIform="index"/></dateline><p TEIform="p">The following was taken from an article sent to the Boston Transcript by S. P. B. who was a
                            boarder at the North Family. East Canterbury, N. H. July, 1892. The Shakers of the olden
                            time showed a keen s-ense of the beautiful in nature by selecting this place; a hill with
                            valleys below and mountains beyond and beyond and beyond. There were in the family stone
                            cutters and brick makers. They utilized the clay of the meadow and made many of their
                            buildings of brick, some of them three stories in height. Granite was used in profusion for
                            steps, walls, posts of fences and walks. Our bread is baked in a huge stone oven. We visited
                            the laundry and saw the working of the machinery. The clothes are put through a switch and a
                            mill, the power of which is furnished by an engine which also churns the butter and pumps
                            water into a tank for supplying some of the buildings. There were forty pounds of steam in
                            the boiler, though Jennie, the Shaker girl who runs it said, "that is rather more than is
                            really needed." We saw knitting machines and a loom where the Sisters were preparing to
                            weave the quaint Shaker bonnets from the oat straw. They use wood for fuel sawed in the mill
                            down by the pond where they cut their ice. Every thing has been done for the comfort and
                            convenience of the family. There is an infirmary where those who are ill or indisposed may
                            go and find rest and quiet. The beds are home made, but good and clean. We have good food,
                            plenty of milk, fresh butter, berries and vegetables fresh <pb n="251" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> from the
                            garden. The Shakers do not eat pork. They raise swine to consume the waste from the tables,
                            but they sell them. The air here is indescribably pure and soft, and it is always breezy
                            here, we are so high, and we find delightful shade of chestnut and maple trees. The floors
                            are painted or covered with oil cloth and numerous rugs. Walls and ceilings are of spotless
                            wThite. Each Sister has an allotted task. One superintends the kitchen, another the dairy,
                            and another makes articles of fancy work, which are sold. All are busy and every thing seems
                            to go. along without hitch or friction. They depend upon the outside world for increase of
                            numbers.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Serenity" TEIform="index"/> SERENITY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Annie R." TEIform="persName"/> Annie R. Stephens.</byline><p TEIform="p"> O calm, sweet morning air! all earth is still With sweet serenity of Sabbath day, The early
                            light of morning's golden ray Rests like the smile of God on plain and hill. Subdued the
                            songster's lay, and babbling rill; The grasses, glittering in their gemmed array, Wave low,
                            as if an angel passed that way; This holy stillness chides each erring will. Calm us, O God!
                            and let thy balm of Peace Drop soothingly, like dew drops on the flowers; And may thy love
                            our aching hearts release From the harsh tumult of life's weary hours. For in thy Peace our
                            fevered longings cease, And in thy Love, reststrength for toil are ours. Mount Lebanon, N.
                            Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Come to me ye heavy laden..." TEIform="index"/>Come to me ye heavy laden...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Come to me ye heavy laden And I will give you rest; Take my easy yoke upon you And be
                            supremely blest. 'Come to me," divine injunction, Come ye poor and needy, come; In a
                            Savior's love and mercy Find thy soul's abiding home.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="N., A. E." TEIform="persName"/>A. E. N.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I asked the Lord that I might grow..." TEIform="index"/>I asked the Lord that I might grow...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">[Contributed by Thomas J. Stroud.] "I asked the Lord that I might grow In faith,
                                    and love, and every grace; Might more of his salvation know, And seek more earnestly
                                    his face. ' Twas He that taught me thus to pray And He, I trust, has answered
                                    prayer; But it has been in such a way, As almost drove me to despair. I hoped that
                                    in some favored hour, At once He'd answer my request, And by his love's constraining
                                    power Subdue my sins, and give me rest. Instead of this, He made me feel The hidden
                                    evils of my heart, And let the angry powers of hell Assault my soul in every part.
                                    Yea, more, with his own hand, He seemed Intent to aggravate my woe; Crossed all the
                                    fain designs I schemed, Blasted my hopes and laid me low. Lord why is this? I
                                    trembling cried, Wilt Thou pursue thy worm to death? 'Tis in this way, the Lord
                                    replied, I answer prayer for grace and faith. These inward trials I employ, From
                                    self and pride to set thee free; And break thy schemes of earthly joy That thou
                                    may'st find thy all in Me."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Steppings in God" TEIform="index"/> H. M. H. in ''Steppings in God.''</bibl></cit></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., H. M." TEIform="persName"/></byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To perceive where one is wrong is the only sure way..." TEIform="index"/>
                            To perceive where one is wrong is the only sure way...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"To perceive where one is wrong is the only sure way of reaching the right. Every time an
                            error is corrected, a delusion banished, a deficiency supplied, a fault overcome, progress
                            is made, and he who makes it occupies a higher plane than before. But for this result it is
                            needful that he freely admit and acknowledge his error, otherwise he cannot abandon it.
                            Instead of being ashamed to do this, he should be ashamed to hide it and to pretend he has
                            not erred. And those to whom such candid confession is made will, if they are wise and kind,
                            offer help and encouragement instead of scorn or censure, thus aiding instead of crushing
                            the good work."</p><pb n="252" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> THE MANIFESTO. NOVEMBER, 1893. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the
                            "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All
                            communications should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. .75
                            .40 One copy per year, postage paid, " " six months, " " Send for sample copy, free. Entered
                            at the Post Office at East Canterbury, N. H., as second-class matter.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial.</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Believers, to have a growing care for our precious landmarks..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Believers, to have a growing care for our precious landmarks...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">It may be quite as well for us, as Believers, to have a growing care for our precious
                                landmarks, lest in an untimely hour we may be found wandering in broad or crooked paths.
                                Those who have entered in through the strait gate, and have learned to love the narrow
                                way, as taught in the testimony of the Christ, may yet dwell in the fulness of God's
                                love. With a confidence in harmony with the prophet, we know that the Lord's arm is not
                                shortened that He can not save, neither is his ear deaf that He can not hear. Whatever
                                may have been the privileges of those who preceded us on the journey through time,
                                either as workers on the natural plane, or as illuminated minds in the ministration of a
                                more orderly and indeed, of a more exalted, spiritual life ; we can in the fulness of
                                our hearts' measure rejoice with them, as we gather from their storehouse, the many
                                valuable treasures of God's unbounded love. If the keeping of the Mosaic law wTas able
                                to raise the family of man, to whom it was given, even one degree above the position
                                they were in at the time, then it was the law of God to them and must remain good
                                through all generations. Jesus, in his careful spirit, gave the disciples to understand
                                that his mission was not to destroy men's lives, nor to harm any good thing. He would
                                not even destroy the Mosaic Law, as do the modern Christians, nor would he lessen the
                                testimony of the prophets in their witness against the sins of the world. Many of God's
                                dear witnesses are yet standing at our right hand, and their words of living truth have
                                not lost their vitality to those who love the light. These witnesses are today our
                                Saviors in the Mount Zion of our God, and while one gives this assuring invitation :
                                "Take my yoke upon you, and learn of me, for I am meek and lowly in heart, and ye shall
                                find peace to your souls." For "Blessed are <pb n="253" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> the pure in heart;
                                they shall see God." And at a still later date another beautiful witness has given us
                                his testimony as a clear light on our pilgrimage to the better land. This man of God
                                seems to be standing even at the threshold of the door and repeating anew the words of
                                prophecy and love. "This is the Second Appearing of Christ, and we are God's witnesses
                                through whom Christ has manifested himself in this day; and the only means of salvation
                                that ever will be offered to a lost world is to confess and forsake their sins, take up
                                their crosses, and follow Christ in the regeneration." These testimonies, to the
                                Believer, are the inspiration of God, the baptism of the Holy Spirit and the power of
                                the world to come. With these we shall share the hundred fold blessing, so much to be
                                desired, and so fully awarded to the faithful disciple of the divine Teacher. Do we
                                wonder that the one says, "Learn of me and ye shall find rest to your souls," and then
                                so kindly solicits us to enter in at the strait gate, and continue our journey till we
                                reach the City of our God; or that the other invites our attention in these words, "My
                                only treasure on earth is in those that believe ; I have no relation but in the people
                                of God." "Let us not be weary in well doing, for in due season we shall reap, if we
                                faint not." Let us accept the inspiration of this word of God through those who have
                                been faithful before us. In the hours of our trials and burdens the light has not wholly
                                been obscured. Some good angel has stood at our right hand and proffered to us this
                                comforting assui^ancc, "They that wait upon the Lord shall renew their strength: they
                                shall mount up with wings as eagles ; they shall run and not be weary, they shall walk
                                and not faint."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Removal" TEIform="index"/>Removal
                        </head><p TEIform="p">For the full information of all our dear friends far and near, we would say,That taking all
                            circumstances into consideration, the distance the Groveland people are from all other
                            Believers, we have concluded to have them remove to the North Family at Watervliet, N. Y.,
                            the removal to take place the last of the present month and first of next. By the prayers
                            and interest of all good Believers extended for them, we hope and trust a blessing may
                            attend the movement. Ministry, Mount Lebanon, N. Y. Oct. 10, 1892.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A person has no more right to say an unkind..." TEIform="index"/>
                            A person has no more right to say an unkind...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A person has no more right to say an unkind or an uncivil thing than to act one; no more
                            right to say a rude thing to another, than to knock him down.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Johnson.</byline><pb n="254" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/> NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/> Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Average of Weather at Mount Lebanon. September. Thermometer. Bain. 1891. 65.60 2.18 in.
                                1892. 58.72 3.19 in. Highest Temp, during this mo. 78. Lowest " " " " 32. Number of
                                rainy days " " 5 C. G. E. Oct. 11. 1892. Seeing by the October Manifesto that it is
                                interesting to speak of our little outings, and the good attained thereby, we would add
                                a paragraph to that same chapter. It was our good fortune in August to make a short
                                visit on business to Watkin-Glen, N. Y. Traveling by rail through a very level tract of
                                land in central New York, we were surprised at the close of the first day out, to find
                                ourselves amid scenery nearly equaling the far famed Alps. This wonderful Glen lies at
                                the head of the beautiful Seneca lake, and we could but wonder, how, with all its
                                advantages and romantic beauty, any one could wish to cross the ocean or the continent,
                                for a peep at the grand and beautiful, combined with an assurance of health, rest and
                                quiet. The Mountain Glen House, the only hotel of the Glen, with its perfect ventila
                                tion, has advantages worthy of imitation. The cooking department and dining hall, is in
                                an airy, Swiss cottage, on the opposite side of the Glen, and connected with the hotel
                                by a covered bridge. The hall of amusement with its innocent games and different kinds
                                of music, is also separate from the hotel; thus guests or boarders, wishing quiet and
                                rest are not disturbed by the clatter of the kitchen, nor the midnight entertainments so
                                frequent at summer resorts. All these things combined with the cordiality of the
                                managers and assistants in charge, make Watkin's Glen a most desirable place to visit,
                                to say nothing of the wild beauty of the two glens, the lovely scenery of the lake and
                                opposite shore as viewed from a point far above it. Here also we find a Sanitarium on a
                                hill bathed in sunshine, said to be filled with seekers after health during the entire
                                year. From here we proceeded farther west, and stayed a few days in the pleasant town of
                                Cattaraugus, and one having special privileges. Here we find no loafers, no drunkards,
                                no beggars, no ragged, saucy children, and why? The simple answer to this question,
                                explains the striking contrast to Br. Daniel's experience in Hudson. No Saloons. The
                                land owned by the town was originally deeded with a strict injunction, that no saloon
                                should ever be allowed within its precincts. This plan of the pioneers of the town, has
                                been faithfully adhered to, by its present leading men, and though failure of its
                                success was prophecied, it is a growing town, alive to the interests of education,
                                morality and Christianity; and as I witnessed its almost constant Temperance gatherings
                                and work, I wondered if all of us who condemn the whole list of intoxicating beverages,
                                from hard cider to the licensed alcoholic medicines, are doing all we should, to crush
                                the head of this deadly serpent, that entwines so many of the would be great and useful
                                of the earth. Let us beware of giving or receiving "a little something to take," lest we
                                become that stumbling block, which shall hurl some weaker one to destruction. The breath
                                of the winter king has dealt kindly with us this autumn. No frosts to injure even the
                                most delicate plant, until October; giving us time to secure our fine crop of
                                cranberries during clement weather. Apple picking finished on the 10 inst. and a
                                plentiful harvest is ours, while in many localities, apples are a failure. Being in
                                possession of so many temporal blessings, can we not, as winter closes in upon us, so
                                increase our spiritual culture, that its fruits may be a rich harvest of good practical
                                Christianity. A. J. C. <pb n="255" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> Center Family. Summer has gone, yet beauty
                                hovers over wood and dale. The mountains present a pretty and picturesque scene, upon
                                which fall the beautiful sunbeams of October. The orchards ladened with luscious red
                                apples are now being harvested, and a comfortable supply of this indispensable fruit is
                                ours. The frost kindly favored us until our cranberries were picked; the marsh yielding
                                a little over one hundred bushels; much better than we anticipated, considering it was
                                under no cultivation. Brethren report corn and potatoes favorable, and with cellars
                                filled with fruits of the past season ready for our consumption,we can eat, drink and be
                                prayerful, that we may keep our health, and live long in this glorious land which the
                                Lord hath given us. The injunction of "hands at work and hearts to God," is practically
                                the life of the little Center Family. When we see the interest of the aged, who have
                                seen and felt the summer heat, and wintry blasts of eighty-four years, toiling daily to
                                do a little more good, and from whom never comes the selfish cry, "I have done my part,"
                                one seems to sing aloud, "Glory to the righteous, who can know their worth." Health
                                generally fair, and weather delightful. Love unbounded to the household of faith. "This
                                is our prayer: to love the good To do the right, to seek the true, To keep eternity in
                                view The truth of human brotherhood." C. B. There are more apples in this section than
                                we could expect. Potatoes have not yet been harvested. It has been a good time to put
                                into practice, Mother Ann's injunction, "hands at work, and hearts to God," and while we
                                are gathering the temporal blessings, could we not also gather more spiritual strength?
                                But alas! human nature does not love the cross any better now than it did 1800 years
                                ago. From Adam to the present time there has been a struggle, and will be to the end of
                                time. But "in Zion's great need" we pray for a wave of conviction that will gather and
                                reap souls from the worldly life, and give strength and hope to the few faithful ones
                                who are trying to keep alive the gospel of Christ and Mother. We need a spiritual
                                harvest as well as a temporal one. May God in his own time awaken both the world and
                                Zion, by a mighty wave of true conviction and Godly sorrow for sin, i is our prayer.
                            t</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, New York" TEIform="index"/> Watervliet, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Second. Family. Oct., 1892. The weather the past month has been very favorable to gather
                                crops. Sweet corn is all cut and dried, also tomatoes are nearly all canned. Frost has
                                held off remarkably, and it is well it has. As crops were so backward an early frost
                                would have destroyed half of the crop.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p"> Oct. 1892. AST armed band came with swords and surrounded Jesus in the garden to take
                                him. The kiss of the betrayer had been given and Jesus was in the enemy's power. Peter
                                drew his sword and struck off the ear of the high priest's servant. Jesus rebuked him,
                                saying, "Put up thy sword. Thinkest thou that I can not now pray to my Father, and He
                                shall presently give me more than twelve legions of angels?" Many professed followers of
                                Christ have erred as Peter did. They have fought with carnal weapons and have been
                                defeated. But the sword of the spirit is a death-dealing weapon to foil temptation and
                                destroy sin. Let us stand fast by this sword and wield it daily. Let us demonstrate that
                                we are conquerors, "and more than conquerors." Let us fight the good fight and we shall
                                overcome. No time to lose now. So many things to be done to prepare for winter. We <pb n="256" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> should have a plan for every thing and try to live up to it as
                                near as possibleThanksgiving day is one of our old land" marks that should be handed
                                down to future generations. Let us make the most of it. Boiled turnips, with wheat bran
                                and ground oats added, make an excellent meal for poultry in winter. Such food is bulky
                                and may be fed liberally, without being liable to fatten. A remedy for low prices in
                                poultry is the home table. Better feed hens too little than too much. To feed poultry
                                properly requires care and thought as well as proper food. There are always losses of
                                some kind in growing poultry, but by practical experience a knowledge of how to avoid
                                mistakes is gained. D. Orcutt. Soxitli Family. Oct. 1892. "O Home for the soul," and
                                body we might addthat is something to satisfy both soul and body! If we use our earthly
                                home so as to fit and prepare ourselves for an eternal one, it will be well; but is not
                                "that house not built with hands," our eternal home now and forever? By aboring
                                diligently to build up our outward visible home, and our inward spiritual one, we
                                fulfill all conditions required of us. Of our outward home we would say that indications
                                of approaching winter are not wanting. Will it be severe or moderate? Animals and
                                vegetables seem to be the best weather prophets. Squirrels are laying up no stores,
                                blackbirds fly north and corn husks are thin, therefore we believe the winter will be
                                mild. Now let us hear from science. Harvesting of crops is in progress, also sowing rye
                                and grass seed. Having tried all the potato diggers in the market, we pronounce the
                                Hoover the only successful one. Potatoes are half a crop. Corn is good and husking will
                                begin in a few days. For some reason, hardly accounted for, milk has been short this
                                season. For handling potatoes we find boxes made to hold just a bushel are very
                                convenient. We read with interest the account of the evangelizing expedition from the
                                North Family at Mount Lebanon. We are also interested in the Koreshan movement in
                                Chicago. It is certainly remarkable how many witnesses are arising in different parts of
                                the world, to the truth that community and virginity, i. e. unselfishness and sexual
                                purity, are the foundation principles of the Christian life. Also these movements are a
                                protest against corrupt Christianity, or the attempt to unite the spirit of the world
                                with the spirit of Christ. T. J. S.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ayer, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/> Ayer, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> Dear Editor :With us nature begins to take on the look of change from the warm and
                                beautiful to the cold and dreary. What a beautiful season the past has been to us;
                                though at times uncomfortably warm and the heat almost unbearable, yet we have been
                                blest with the bounties of nature, beyond our expectation, and to whom shall we give
                                credit if not to the industrious hands that have worked in faith, believing that God
                                would help those who help themselves. Our Sisters have been busily engaged in preparing
                                for market the great quantity of herbs that is yearly raised in Harvard. Those not
                                personally acquainted with our home can form but a faint idea of the amount of work this
                                requires at our hands. All must pass through the hands of the Sisters, before they are
                                ready to be sold. Much of this work is performed during the heated part of the season.
                                As I have seen the happy companies sitting at their tables, stripping the herbs, I have
                                thought; How could they show more zeal or energy, even though they were at work for
                                their selfish interest? Homes are like harps; some are finely carved and bright with
                                gilding, but ill tuned, while another is old and plain but from its chords we hear some
                                beautiful music. Step by step we may finally cross the highest mountain; so will a
                                little self-denial, used every day work wonders in our <pb n="257" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> home
                                circle. The divine arrangement of the laws governing men's lives, decrees that he who
                                lives only for self, lives for no one, while the person who lives to bless others, also
                                blesses himself. The person who carries grace and sweetness into the lives of others,
                                finds that his own life has imparted to it a brightness and buoyancy that continually
                                increases. "How good I feel," exclaimed the little boy, when he had helped his classmate
                                over a rough place. "I wonder why it raises one up so to help any one who needs help?"
                                God bless the liberal heart. Let us give and give as to God. Shirley met with Harvard on
                                the Sabbath for worship, and two Sisters are with us from Enfield, Conn. A. D. B.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p"> Oct., 1892. Beloved Elder Henry:Not forgetting your consecrated efforts in issuing the
                                monthly Manifesto, fraught with so much that is worthy our acceptance, our thanks are
                                due to you and the kind friends who suggested the more social correspondence, which
                                gives us a better opportunity to hear from our kindred Societies both East and West. We
                                find that it yields great pleasure to its many readers, and opens the avenues which
                                serve to broaden our acquaintance and strengthen a kindly interest that might never
                                otherwise be realized: so we bless the good wherever found. Some days since we
                                entertained a gentleman and lady from Braintree Mass., by the name of Watson, who called
                                upon us to spend the Sabbath; they belonged as they said to a growing party, termed
                                Nationalists. These people seemed to have the conviction that mankind were growing to
                                endorse to some extent the practicability of Edward Bellamy's dream as pictured in
                                "Looking Backward." They gave us an outline of what they were doing. They were in
                                earnest in their work, and we bid them God-speed, for well we know the world needs a
                                mighty revolution. We are now in the midst of Harvest; with a view of preparing for
                                winter. Potatoes are all dug; not a medium crop, and poor quality. Have just finished
                                gathering our apples and think it safe to say that we have never known so few, in our
                                remembrance. Of tomatoes, grapes and plums we have a good supply. On the 5th. inst. a
                                cold wave struck us, and the snow fell sufficient to mantle the high mountain just east
                                of our Village. We have had some hard frosts but have been fortunate in securing our
                                vegetables so that nothing has been injured. We find enough work each day for willing
                                hands and hearts, in striving to keep our home as near the standard of the Shaker Church
                                as is possible, asking in faith and trust that a blessing crown our every effort for
                                good. J. R. 3STortli Family. Esteemed Editor:Acting upon the suggestion of friends, we
                                have contributed the "Home Notes," hoping they will not take the place of more valuable
                                items. We sincerely appreciate the varied thought given each month for the pages of our
                                Manifesto, and hope its precious sheets laden with soul elevating truth, will ever
                                appear before the public. Antagonistic, as the Christ virtues are to the carnally
                                inclined, we do not marvel that mortals should seek to retard the reforming powers, that
                                would shatter all idols not bearing the stamp of holiness. Elaborate, may be the
                                comparisons portraying the richness, glory and joy of a Christian life, and the
                                unsatisfactory demoralizing effects of an ungodly life; still the unregenerate heart
                                will crave the food of self-indulgence, and ignore and scoff at virtue. In our religious
                                and social meetings is manifest a zeal to keep step with the class of earnest workers
                                for the truth, and to develop those soul traits approved of God. Each day finds us busy
                                in securing the fruits of the season. With the majority of New England farmers we have
                                to report a small crop of apples, pears and potatoes as compared with former years,
                                while of other fruits including berries, plums, etc., we have an average crop. <pb n="258" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> The Sisters have acted well their part in preserving fruits and
                                making jellies to enrich our table during the long and dreary months of winter. During
                                the summer months, from a herd of thirteen cows, we have realized a yield of 1,125 lbs.
                                of cheese, and averaged 25 lbs. of butter per week, besides being liberally supplied
                                with cream for home consumption. Our family has raised and prepared for Boston market,
                                1,300 lbs. of Lavage, and at this date are engaged digging and preparing Dock root for
                                J. C. Ayer, of Lowell, Mass. Amount not yet ascertained. Last but not least among our
                                blessings, we are able to report a healthy condition physically, and spiritually, hence
                                are realizing the happiness attendent upon this state of things. Kindest wishes for all
                                the readers of our Manifesto. G. H. B.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/> Alfred, Me.</head><p TEIform="p"> Oct. 1892. Beloved Elder Henry;Seed time and harvest, that were promised so many years
                                ago, continue to come to us. If we are faithful in the one, we are sure to be blessed
                                with a good result whether in temporal or spiritual things. Elder John Vance tells us
                                that we must add another hundred bushels to the account of our potato crop, so will try
                                and report more correctly. If all the little potatoes had been large ones, there would
                                have been 1,000 bushels instead of seven hundred- However, we have enough and some to
                                spare. That tall ensilage corn filled the silos rapidly. The 1*75 tons will help to make
                                up for the shortness of the hay crop. The apple harvest is hardly commenced. It will not
                                be an abundant one. The first heavy frost of the season came Oct. 2nd., too late to do
                                any harm to the garden. Our dairy Sister thinks the 35 gal. Stoddard churn recently put
                                into the dairy cannot be excelled. Our beloved Ministry returned to us on the 11th.
                                inst. We are always thankful for their presence which adds love and strength to the
                                store we possess. Let us love and bless each other and the blessing will return to us
                                four-fold. t</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dayton, Ohio" TEIform="index"/> Dayton, Ohio.</head><p TEIform="p"> Oct. 1892. We are having very nice weather at the present time. Wheat is all sown and
                                looks well. We have been digging our potatoes and they have afforded us a very nice
                                yield. Several visitors from Union Village and one from White Water have been to see us.
                                I have just spent several days at White Water, my former home, and on returning to
                                Watervliet was accompanied by Br. Thomas Beechey. On reaching home I received word that
                                one Brother and four Sisters from Union Village would make us a visit. The party were,
                                Br. Thomas Mann, and Sisters, Susanah Armstead, Susan Corthran, May Kuth and Anna
                                Goepper. We visited the Soldiers' Home, and while there partook of our lunch. In our two
                                baskets, we found yellow legged chickens, biscuits, cake and pie. Later in the day we
                                ride a few miles from Dayton and then alight to spread our table cloth on the ground anu
                                partake of our supper. We reached our home in Watervliet at 6-30 P. M. Hoping to meet
                                our gospel friends again in the near future, we will pass on to another company of
                                friends from Mount Lebanon, N. Y., who have come to see us. Br. Benjamin Gates and
                                Eldress Elizaabeth Sears, and Cornelia French. We enjoyed a very pleasant visit with
                                them and one that we shall remember for many years. It does our little gospel band good
                                to have our friends from other Societies come and see us. There seems to be a great deal
                                of good come with them and also a precious gift of inspiration. We also enjoyed the
                                company of our beloved Ministry sisters, Eldresses, Elizabeth Downing and Emily Eobinson
                                from Union Village. If we could visit more among Be. lievers I think it would help us
                                all and <pb n="259" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> increase our desire to labor and seek for the good things
                                of God. I am interested in the union of all Believers and in their gospel work. It will
                                never fail in the hearts of the faithful. Br. Moore Mason and Eldress Hester Frost
                                accompanied the visitors to White Water. I wish to say that for nearly a year we have
                                not had a hired man in our Village. H. W. F.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/> East Canterbury, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p"> Weather Record, for September, 1892. Highest Temp, during the mo. 15. Lowest " " " " 40.
                                Mean " " " " 56.7 Total precipitation 1.65 in. Number of days in which .01 in. or more
                                fell, 5. N. A. Beiggs. Oct. 13, 1892. Beloved Editor:We are pleased to present at this
                                time our "Home Notes" to the readers of the Manifesto. The changing hues of the
                                beautiful trees remind us that winter is approaching, and with it that auspicious day
                                when, at least, all professed Christians, are supposed to turn over a new leaf in their
                                life history, and endeavor to make a radical change for the better. With this class must
                                be numbered the printers, who in spite of all the mistakes which they unluckily have
                                made, and which, alas for them, the reading public must know, still keep up good
                                courage, undaunted by the fact that they must needs turn over many a new leaf before
                                they reach perfection, even in the printers' art. With the autumn, comes the preparation
                                for the winter months. We have been blessed in our "basket and in our store." Gathered
                                in Sept. about fifty bu. of peaches, which were rapidly converted into sauces and
                                preserves. During the present month forty bu. of grapes have been gathered. The potato
                                crop has been a partial failure, very much to our sorrow. Of apples we may have a medium
                                supply. The gardeners report one hundred and fifteen bu. of tomatoes, and a peep into a
                                corner of the garden barn revealed a goodly store of squashes. Industry through the
                                summer is amply rewarded and we pleasantly realize the truth of the maxim, "Labor is
                                Worship." *</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Consideration" TEIform="index"/> CONSIDERATION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/> Mary Whitcher.</byline><p TEIform="p"> God of love and mercy too, By thy love and care for me Great the kindness I should do, Great
                            the love for all I see. Gently bind the broken heart, Walk in friendship with the poor;
                            Knowing not an ill or smart But to lay it at my door. With the aged and infirm Place myself
                            as needy there; With the young who need to learn, Patient with their lacks to bear. Christ
                            the Savior left his charge With his followers for care, Nothing bounded, but at large, Doing
                            good e'en everywhere. Who are we who speak his name? Who but follow his advice? Shall we
                            bring our Master shame By withholding half the price? Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mentor's maxims" TEIform="index"/> MENTOR'S MAXIMS.</head><p TEIform="p"> [Contributed by Ernest Pick.] "Moke love." Take the apple for your symbol. Consider the time
                            it takes, from the planting of the seed, to ripen the perfect fruit; and then it is only an
                            apple, perishable in the same season, whereas the growth of the soul is eternal. When
                            growing, or half grown, do not attempt to hasten maturity by throwing stones and sticks at
                            the promising fruit. <pb n="260" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> Education is for the child painful effort, hard
                            work, conflict and suffering. Make happier him whom you would make better. Be yourself what
                            you wish the child to be. Do not expect visible progress every single day, but remember the
                            symbol and put yourself in the child's place. In Christ is hidden the wisdom to deal rightly
                            with the stubborn, the impertinent, the lazy and the silly. Do not attempt to drive, but
                            lead always. Never give a command, without seeing that it is performed in the proper manner.
                            Let firmness be the border, wisdom the direction of your education, love be the means and
                            end. Let not one offence pass unnoticed. Treat one with forbearance, another with kindness,
                            some with wit and humor, others with cunning, firmness, reproof; others with fire and sword,
                            but one and all with wisdomwithout passion. "More love."</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inquiry. no. 8" TEIform="index"/> INQUIRY. No. 8.</head><p TEIform="p"> Does a community of interest require that all the personal property of those joining a
                            Shaker Society shall immediately become the property of the Community? It does not.
                            Probationary members may retain the lawful use of their property, and if living separate
                            from the family may manage their own temporal concerns. If they enter a Shaker family, an
                            inventory of all the property received, will be taken, and then used as the parties may
                            agree. If at any time they desire to make a donation to the Society they are at liberty to
                            do so, provided they are clear of debt and their temporal abilities will admit of it. If
                            such members withdraw from the Society, the property may be resumed according to contract,
                            but no interest can be claimed for its use.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scripture text" TEIform="index"/> SCRIPTURE TEXT.</head><p TEIform="p"> Explain Matt, xxviii., 19. "Go ye therefore, and teach all nations, baptizing them in the
                            name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Spirit." The manifestation of the spirit
                            of Christ was to bring light into the world, and to teach a life of righteousness before God
                            and man. During the time that Jesus walked with his disciples, he manifested an anxiety that
                            they might be baptized, and no less that they might learn to hunger and thirst after
                            righteousness. Speaking of baptism, he asked the two brothers, "Are ye able to be baptized
                            with the baptism that I am baptized with ?" If the baptism had only been to walk into the
                            water as the thousands had walked in before them, they might have answered without a
                            moment's hesitation and said they were able. The baptism of Jesus was, as testified by John,
                            into the Holy Spirit, and into the consuming fire of God's word. <pb n="261" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> The
                            baptism of John can be administered to every shade of character, even to the worst grades of
                            human nature, while the baptism of Jesus can be received only by those who live as he lived.
                            This antichristian formula of being baptized in the name of the Father, Son and Holy Ghost,
                            can be no more than a ceremony with water, and indeed, this is the course the church adopts.
                            As the confession of sin at the time of the baptism has been ruled out, the work falls so
                            much short of that which John did at the Jordan. In Mark it was said, "He that belie veth
                            and is baptized shall be saved ; but he that believeth not shall be damned." This censure,
                            however, has been softened by the revision into "condemned," and the whole subject in Mark,
                            thrown out as spurious. Even in Matt., the remark was made after the physical resurrection
                            is said to have taken place, and while a pai't of the disciples were in doubt about the
                            presence of their divine Teacher. Those who believe in the resurrection of the physical body
                            may possibly find a little consolation in thinking tiiat Jesus was the same as before his
                            death, and could walk and talk as did the other disciples. Believers in a spiritual resurn
                            ction, a resurrection in which Jesus lived while he walked upon the earth, can have little
                            or no interest in this dogma of a physical manifestation which has been forced upon the
                            world by a church of Gentile Christians. It was the mission of Jesus to urge others to bear
                            the cross that would separate them from a worldly life and raise them from their graves of
                            selfishness and shame, into a resurrection where God would take up his abode with them. In
                            this spirit they could teach all nations and baptize them into the same to the glory of God
                            and to the honor of all men. They would have no fear of being damned or even of being
                            condemned.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Elder Henry:--I enclose a slip cut from a Montreal paper..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Beloved Elder Henry:--I enclose a slip cut from a Montreal paper...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Shirley Village, August 1892" TEIform="index"/>Shirley Village, Mass.,
                            Aug. 1892.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Henry :1 enclose a slip cut from a Montreal paper, that I think worthy of a
                            place in the Manifesto. We are progressing with fall work nicely. How true it is"God works
                            in a mysterious way his wonders to perform," to the natural mind at least. To those standing
                            in the light of his truth, much of the mystery disappears, and to them it will shine
                            brighter and brighter unto the perfect; day. Yours very iruly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitely, John" TEIform="persName"/> John Whitely.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Face of an angel" TEIform="index"/> THE FACE OF AN ANGEL.</head><p TEIform="p"> There are many different types of beauty. There is the beauty of youth, which all enjoy for
                            a season; there is the beauty of form and color, which is the most attractive form of
                            beauty; there is beauty of intellect, which sharpens and refines the most rugged features,
                            and redeems them from the charge of plainness; and lastly, there is the highest beauty of
                            all, the beauty of holiness, which comes from close and frequent intercourse with God, and
                            is the reflection of his glory. This is the beauty spoken of in the Acts of the Apostles,
                            when it is said that all that sat in the council, looking steadfastly at Stephen, a man full
                            of the Holy Ghost, "saw his face as it had been the face of an angel." The beauty of youth
                            is fleeting. Beau- <pb n="262" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> tiful features are rare, and the most brilliant
                            complexions fade. The beauty of intellect is rarer still, but the beauty of holiness is
                            within reach of all. All may acquire that if they choo-se, and there is a beauty that never
                            fades, but daily increase, though the outer man may wither and decay. We see it sometimes
                            illuminating the faces of the poorest and the oldest, even of the deformed and afflicted, as
                            well as of the young, whose natural beauty it hardens and adorns; and whenever we see it we
                            may be sure that he or she who possesses it is in the habit of holding in. tercourse with
                            Goda child of prayer, for it is prayer and meditation on holy things which makes the face,
                            as it were, "the face of an angel." THE COMFORT OF THE SORROWING. The people of God have
                            many causes for sorrow. There is the sorrow for their own sins without which they would
                            never have entered the divine family; there is the sorrow for the sins of others, which is a
                            mark of the grace which God has wrought within them: and then Christians have also their
                            share in the common sufferings, bereavements, afflictions, and trials of this life. And yet
                            though sorrowing, it is their privilege to be "always rejoicing." They may rejoice in the
                            blessing and presence of the Lord, who "giveth songs in the night" and gladness in the
                            darkest hours, and who is ever near his suffering, afflicted, and troubled people, speaking
                            to them words of comfort, hope, and cheer. They may rejoice "in hope of the glory of God,"
                            in prospect of that eternal gladness which awaits the redeemed when the sorrows and
                            afflictions of the earth shall be no more, when "the ransomed of the Lord shall return and
                            come to Zion with songs and everlasting joy upon their heads;" and when "they shall obtain
                            joy and gladness, and sorrow and sighing shall flee away." No matter how dark the
                            afflictions of the present hour may seem, there is always this rift in the clouds, this
                            lifting of the shadows that overhang a weary, dreary world: the sure and certain hope of
                            life and joy and gladness in the world to come. Well may the tempted, and tried and troubled
                            take courage with such a hope as this. No matter how severe their trials may be, there will
                            be rest, and peace, and gladness, and glory at the end; they may be clothed in sackcloth
                            to-day, but they shall bye-and-bye put on their brighter robes; they may shed tears today,
                            but their mourning shall be turned to gladness; they may walk to-day beneath the shadow of
                            false accusation and reproach, but the time will come when every blot and stain which men
                            have cast upon them will be removed, and their light and joy will be unspeakable and
                            eternal. "Oft-times my heart grows weary For tile songs tlie ransomed sing, And the waiting
                            seems long and dreary For the coming of the King. And then I take courage and patience, In a
                            little while He will come, And take all His faithful children To His own glorious heavenly
                            home. There all their sufferings will be ended, And their tears He will wipe away; There
                            every voice will be blended In rich and heavenly harmony."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.
                        </head><div3 type="death notices" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Robinson, Deborah" TEIform="index"/>Deborah Robinson
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Deborah Robinson, at West Pittsfield, Mass. Aug. 26, 1892. Age 91 yrs. 2 mo. and 14
                                days. </p></div3><div3 type="death notices" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Booker, Annie" TEIform="index"/>Annie Booker
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Annie Booker, at North Family, South Union, Ky. Sept. 21, 1892. Age 78 years. She
                                was eminently faithful in every duty. A bright and shining light. She has been a member
                                of the Community for nearly half a century and her presence and sweet influence will be
                                sadly missed by those to whom she was attached by the most endearing ties of Christian
                                love. N. C. </p></div3><div3 type="death notices" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Norton, John" TEIform="index"/>John Norton
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> John Norton, at Watervliet, O., Oct. 13, 1892. Age 78 yrs. 5 mo. and 10
                                days. Br. John lived at North Union forty-six years and moved to Watervliet in 1889. He
                                has been a faithful Brother in the vineyard of the Lord. H. W. F.</p></div3><pb n="263" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stewardship" TEIform="index"/> STEWARDSHIP.</head><p TEIform="p"> " Give an account of thy stewardship." Luke xvi., 2. Canterbury, N. H. Be lifted up, my
                            soul, Till the heavens shine upon thee, And in the majesty of truth and love Thou art able
                            to walk. Thou shalt set no bounds for labor, But as a steward faithful, In God's service
                            shall thy life In unceasing measure flow.</p><pb n="264" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers
                        </head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>Phrenological
                                Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> In the October number of that veteran among American magazines, the Phrenological
                                Journal and Science of Health, an appreciative sketch of the late Cyrus W. Field is
                                given, with an account of the laying of the first Atlantic telegraph line. The Editor
                                gives another installment of the descriptive series relating to the World's Fair at
                                Chicago. A Plea for Individuality is well stated by Gracia. A story from life is that
                                entitled The Secret of Amy's Wedded Happiness. In Child Culture, an excellent paper on
                                The Responsibility of Childhood, occupies several pages. "I Couldn't Say No" comes from
                                an English writer, and sets off a common domestic folly. Teasing Children hits the mark,
                                too. A Strange Essay has its common parallel, as the reader will recognize. The Coming
                                Food Exposition at New York City is illustrated, and a good variety of valuable
                                suggestions appear in the Health Department. The Editor discusses certain current
                                questionsthe strikes, for instanceand very appreciatively refers to the late poet
                                Whittier and Mr. George W. Curtis. The Journal is published at $1.50 a year or 15 c. a
                                number. The last three numbers of this year are offered free to new subcribers for 1892,
                                or three numbers "On Trial" for 25 c. Address Fowler &amp; Wells Co., 25 East
                                Twenty-seventh street, New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Hall's Journal of Health. Oct. Contents. The Cholera;
                                Shocked into Silence; Nurses in the Sick Room; Summer Complaint; Healing in Precious
                                Stones; Christopher Columbus; Asleep for Nine Years; A Simple Remedy for Sprains;
                                Sulfonal in Insomnia: Ancient Hospitals; Objection to New Bread; Round Shoulders;
                                Anti-Tobacco, etc., etc. Office, 340 West 59th. St., New York City. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>Ladies Home Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">HOME LIFE OF
                                DICKENS. The series of reminiscent articles of "My Father as I Recall Him," by Mamie
                                Dickens, the oldest and favorite daughter of Charles Dickens, will begin in the next
                                issue of the Ladies Home Journal by an entertaining narration of Dickens' personal
                                habits, and an inner glimpse of his home life. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New England magazine" TEIform="index"/>New England Magazine
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The October New England Magazineis
                                specially attractive for the quantity and quality of its poetry. Everett S. Hubbard
                                contributes a fine Columbus poem, "The Three Ships," which has the place of honor in the
                                number. Charles Edwin Markham, the Californian poet, is represented by a poem in his
                                best vein, "A Harvest Song." Madison Cawein, of Kentucky, is somewhat metaphysical in
                                "The Ordeal." James B. Kenyon contributes a pretty fancy, "The South Wind." St. George
                                Best is topical with "MaTs." Stuart Sterne, a New York poet, in "Vespers" and "Matins,"
                                gives us true poetry and sentiment. All these poets are of the younger generation, and
                                are scattered throughout the Union, so that it cannot be said that the New England is
                                bound by local prejudices, or closes its columns to the younger singers. And poetry is
                                undoubtedly still read, the croakers to the contrary notwithstanding. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Evangeline" TEIform="index"/>Evangeline
                            </head><p TEIform="p">THAT PRETTY
                                EVANGELINE. VTE published recently under the head of "A Pretty Surprise" a notice of a
                                now and very charming edition of Longfellow's most cele brated poem "Evangeline." Upon
                                examination, the book proves so delightful in every way that we believe it will be a
                                favor to our readers to refer to it again, It is handsomely illustrated, mainly by
                                Birket Foster , one of the most famous of English artists, and bound in exquisite taste
                                in a combination of white and blue cloth, with gilt edges and ornaments, and is sold
                                only by the publishers direct (not by booksellers), at approximately the actual cost of
                                manufacture by the hundred thousand 19 cents a copy, plus 6 cents postage, if by mail.
                                His object is to place an example of his bookmaking in the hands of a vast number of
                                readers. He could certainly choose no more excellent volume, to please all people of
                                good taste. His catalogue of books, covering every department of literature, a veritable
                                feast of good things for book-lovers, and at wonderfully low prices, considerably over
                                100 pages in size, is sent post-paid for 2 cents. Address, John B. Alden, Publisher, 57
                                Rose St., New York.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Suggestions for organizing temperance covenance bands" TEIform="index"/>Suggestions for organizing Temperance
                                Covenant Bands
                            </head><p TEIform="p">THE "NASTY" SUNLIGHT. "The town that does not need any temperance
                                work done in it, is probably something like the gii'l's room, which was clean
                                enough.until some one raised the curtain and let the nasty sunlight in." The above is a
                                fair sample of the many good hits and points in "Suggestions for organizing Temperance
                                Covenant Bands," which will be mailed to any applicant entirely free, by W. H. Brearly,
                                of Detroit, Michigan. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Onward Christian soldiers" TEIform="index"/>Onward Christian Soldiers
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"Onward Christian Soldiers." Whoever wishes to be the owner of a
                                beautifully bound Book, and made happy even before they lay back its covers, will do
                                well to send for the above work. Within, it will be found very interesting, as it covers
                                a large field of usefulness, for those who are anxious to work in the Lord's vineyard.
                                It is a year Book; on the pages of which the names of many dear friends may be written.
                                The selections of poetry and prose that follows every date throughout the year, are
                                accepted from the best sources now known. The Christian Endeavor movement occupies many
                                pages and comes from the pen of Rev. Francis E. Clark, D. D. A history of the King's
                                daughters and sons is an interesting feature, written by the General Secretary of of the
                                Order. Mary Lowe Dickenson. The work is beautifully illustrated. Published by the Brodix
                                Publishing Co., Washington, D. C. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Testimony of Christ's second appearing" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Testimony of Christ's Second Appearing
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> The Testimony of Christ's Second Appearing,
                                exemplified by the principles and practice of the true Church of Christ. History cf the
                                progressive work of God, extending from the creation of man to the "Harvest," comprising
                                the Four Dispensations now consummating in the Millennial Church. Price $1.50</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
Scientific American
Agency for
CAVEATS,
TRADE MARKS,
DESIGN PATENTS
COPYRIGHTS, etc.
For information and free Handbook write to
MUNN & CO., 361 Broadway, New York.
Oldest bureau for securing patents in America.
Every patent taken out by us is brought before
the public by a notice given free of charge in the
Largest circulation of any scientific paper in the
world. Splendidly illustrated. No intelligent
man should be without it. Weekly, S3.00 a
year; $1.50 six months. Address MUNN & CO.,
Publishers, 3a Broadway, New York.
JOHN F. STBATT0U & SON,
43 & 46 Walker St.            N EW YORK.
MUSICALPrtMERCHANDISE,
Violins,  Guitars,   Banjos,
Accordeons,  Harmonicas, &c.
All kinds of STRINGS, etc., etc.
By MARY LOWE DICKINSON,
Gen'l Secretary " King's
Daughters and Sons."
A Full Account of "The Epworth League," by the
R.ev. J. F. Bevry; " Christian Endeavor," by the
Rev. Francis E.Clark;" Baptist Young People's
Union," by Rev. J. M.Coon; "Woman'sChristian
Temperance Union," by Frances J. Barnes; and
'ChautauquaCircles,"by KateF. Kimball.12
Books in One.-Profusely Illustrated.- Portraits of Leaders.-Handsome Illuminated
Cover. AGENTS ARE COINING MONEY.
Second Edition Now in Press.
.. Great Offer for the Next Thirty Days ..
BEIEF EXPOSITION
OF TEE
Principles   and   Regulations
ft                         of the
SOCIETY   OB1   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
A Trip to tie World's Fair
FREE!
To any   worthy man or woman, loy or
girl.   If you wisn. to visit tlie
WORLD'S COLUMBIAN EXPOSITION
at Chicago, for one week or more, free
of all expense, on easy conditions,
write at once. Enclose self-addressed,
stamped envelope,
Worlcl's Fair Entertainment Jejt.
XOO2 Monadnock Building-,
Cor, Dearborn   and  Jackson   Sts.   Chicago,  III.
If so, send your name and address for a Free
Sample of the AMESICAB' EES ,TOUSHAIi
Weekly32 pagesOne Dollar a year.
GEORGE W, YORK, & CO,,
199 Randolph Street, CHICAGO, ILL.
THE FLAMING SWORD
A Radical, Rational  and. Racy
Reform Paper.
The bitter foe of every form of social abuse
in church and state, the expositor of Koreshiinity, which is primitive Christianity revived, and the promulgator of an equitable
system of exchange which is destined to revolutionize commercial methods and
Crush  the Iniquitous  Money Power
SAMPLE    COPY    FREE.
Tie finite Star Pi. House.
3619 Cottage Grove Avenue.
CHICAGO, ILL.
Much knowledge for a few pennies.
Sent Postage paid to any address in the
U. S. We have on hand a few copies of
"Rip Van Winkle and other Sketches."
240 pages, 4x6.                         .10 cts.
"A treatise on The Horse," by Dr. B.
Kendall. 90 pages. 5x7j^. Profusely illustrated.                                 .12 cts.
Gazetteer of K H. Published 1823 at
Concord, N. H. Has a map of the State
of ~N. H. and several illustrations.    50 cts.
Noah Webster's Spelling Book. Published 1808.    168 pages. Illustrated.  25cts.
The Great Fire in Newburyport, Mass.
in 1811. Pamphlet much worn. .10 cts.
Address H. C. Blinn, E. Canterbury, N. H.
DO YOU KEEP BEES
GOOD AGENTS WANTED FOR
Onward Christian
Soldiers
Prospectus Free
HciQuick
Send 12 2-ct. Stamps
for postage & pack'g
Write for Confidential Terms to
The Brodix Publ'ng Co., Washington, D. C.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure*
A cream of tartar baking- Powder. Highe- -t of all in leavening strength..Latest
United States Government Food Heport.
Eoyal Baking Powdek Co., 106 Wall St., N. Y.
JOHN   F.   STRATTON   &   SON'S
CELEBRATED
Importeriofand Wholesale Dealer, in all kinds o f
MUSICAL     MERCHANDISE,
Violins, Guitars, Banjos, Mandolines, Accordeons,
Harmonicas, &c, ail kinds of Strings, etc.,etc.
<S & 45 Walker St.,                    SEW YORK.
WANT Fn^
r.ike workers  everywhere for
____________ -'SHSPP'S PHOTOGEAPES of tha WORLD"
the greatest book o:i earth; costing $100,000;
?retail at $3.25, cash or installinients; mammoth illustrated
'circulars and terms free; daily
output over 1500 volumes. Agents wild with
success. Mr. Thos. L. Makthst, of Centreville.  Texas, cleared
$711 in nine                                                _
Wooster, O., $23 in40 minutes; Rev. J.Howard
Madison, Lyons, N. Y., 101 in 7 hours;  a bo
nanza; magnificent
outfit only $1.00.
Books on credit.
Freight paid. Ad. GLOBE BIBLE PUBLISHING
00,, 723 Chestnut St., Phila,, Pa,, or 358 Dearborn
St., Chicago, 111.
OF THE WORLD.
WROO U ^SP| A MONTH can be
8/81 10 Saflai made working for us.
Persons preferred who can furnish a horse
nnd give their whole tirne to the business.
Sparc moments may be profitably employed
also. A few vacancies in towns and cities.
B. F. JOHNSON & CO., 26th. and Main St..
Kichmond, Va.
THE   ALTRUIST.
Is a monthiv pr.per, paitly in Phonetic
S"peJlii;g, and devoted to common property, united bibor, Community homes, and
equal ri^bte to all. It is published by the
Aitruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold ail
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Long-ley.
901 Olive St.,   St. Louis, Mo
THE HOLIDAY GIPT BOOK!
"The Birds of North America."
A magnificent imperial quarto volume. Contains  ONE HUNDRED   AND NINETEEN engraved
plates, representing all our birds, colored from
nature, including a reliable and interesting
account of their habits and characteristics.
Edition limited to 1,000. Subscribe early
and secure a copy foll the holidays.
The work is sold to subscribers, bound handsomely and substantially, at following net
prices; fine Russia Seal, or Turkey Morocco
half bindings, gold gilt edges $40.00; full bindings, same materials, $45-00
ENCOMIUMS FE0M TEE PEESS.
"A superb Work."Publisher's Weekly.
"A great work."National Teacher.
"A magnificent Ornithological Work."Turf
Field and Farm.
"It is one of the most ambitious publications
ever attempted in this country or abroad."
Cleveland Leader.
"It is a marvel of beauty and excellence."
Ohio State Journal.
"No work evincing such perfect care and finish, at such a reasonable rate, has ever been
published either in this country or abroad."
Inter-Ocean, Chicago.
TIME, STRENGTH)      By
AHD PATIENCE \   Using
MX WORK
SERIES.
A copy, FREE, of Normal Instructor, the best educational
paper in America,will give full particulars. Uaissville, K.".
SHEPP'S
PHOTOGRAPHS
lays;
Miss Eose
Warns,
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>