<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2911" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">29</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><date value="18991101" TEIform="date">November 1899</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">161-176</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="29" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
WONDERFUL strange REVELATIONS,
DANIEL'S & STJOHN'S
_____
48 page pamphlet.      Price 10 cts.
1 3 f     $1 00
Address,   H. B. Beak, Preston, Ohio.
Sketches of Shakers and Shakerism. A synopsis of the United Society of Believers in Christ's Second
Appearing. Illustrated. By Giles
B. Avery.    Price 15 cts.
A SUMMAET VIEW
OF THE
MILLENNIAL   CHURCH,
OR
"United   Society   of  Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together xoith the general Prin
ciples of the Faith and Testimony.
Price, 50 cts.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
or the
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF  BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
THE ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to ommon property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all their
property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. It now has 5,000
acres of land in Southeast Missouri on
which it offers a home and employment
for life to all acceptable persons who may
wish to join it.            50 cents a year;
specimen copy free.    Address A. Longley, 2819  Olive St. St. Louis, Mo.
NOVEMBER, 1899
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
Frank Leslie\s Popular Monthly for Oct
ober contains the first part of a masterly review, by the Hon, Lyman J. Gage, Secretary
of the Treasury, of The Finances of Our Wars
In this article, which is elaborately illustrated
from official sources, Secretary Gage discusses most interestingly, and without resort to
dry figures or statistics, the finances and financiers of the Revolution, the Continental pa
per currency, and the war of 1812.   The Mexican War, the Civil War and the late SpanishAmerican conflict, will be treated in a second
paper.   Walter Camp writes a seasonable and
sensible article upon College Athletics.   Edgar Allan Poe's College Days, at the University of Virginia, Charlottesville, are discussed
in a richly illustrated article by Jennie Bard
Dugdale, apropos of the unveiling of Zolnay's
famous bust of Poe, in commemoration of the
fiftieth anniversary of the poet's untimely
deathOctober 7th.   Liquefied Air and Its
Uses, by Dr. George II. Johnson, is an ideal
"popular science" paper, sound in its physics
and entertaining in its illustrated account of
the marvelous experiments. Women as Farmers, are written about by W. R. Diaper, who
asserts that women who own and run their
farms, without any male assistance, constitute thirty per cent of the farming population
of Kansas and Oklahoma.   Fritz Morris makes
instructive comparisons in his illustrated article about European Fire-Fighters.   Frank
R. Stockton's wonderful sea yarn, entitled
The Snowflake of the Service and capitally illustrated by Rosenmeyer, is the leading
short story and there is much other interesting matter.
A .B. Frost, the artist, has undertaken what
is thus far his most ambitious and sustained
piece of work in a series of eight paintings,
entitled A. B. Frost's Country Folks.    The series will present the best of the American rural types in the different aspects of their social and neighborhood life.   Each paintingwill be distinct and be given a full-page reproduction in The Ladies' Home Journal, the
series running through that magazine for
eight issues, beginning with the Christinas
number.
Yale graduates will turn with special interest in the illustrated Educational Number of
The Outlook to the extremely readable article by Mr. Arthur Reed Kimball on Yale as a
University.   The occasion, as indicated by
the sub-title, is the fact that Yale is now almost at the threshold of her third century,
and the immediate forward movement expected under the newly chosen President is a
matter of great importance.   Mr. Kimball
describes the actual condition of Yale, in
equipment, purpose and spirit, very fully,
and at the same time in anything but a dryas-dust manner.   There are many pictures
accompanying the article.   ($3 a year.   The
Outlook Co., N. Y.)
The Journal of Hygeio Therapy for September has for its table of contents,Our duty to Hygeio-Therapy and her needs by Rose
B. Jackson, M. D.   Hygeio Therapy by Annie
M. Goodale.   Meat eating is injurious to
health, by E. G. Schafer.   Supreme Court decision by Dr. Gifford.   Following these articles are several very interesting letters by
those interested in "Invalid's Home."   The
whole Magazine contains a fund of valuable
knowledge.   Dr. T. O. Gifford & Co., Kokomo,
Ind.
One hundred and thirteen years before the
hour in which Voltaire was crowned, a
French priest was borne, in a dying state,
down to the shore of Lake Michigan, borne
tenderly in the arms of the children of the
forest whom he loved and who loved him in
return.   And they laid him down to die as he
prayed to diein the wilderness and amongst
his beloved Illini.   He called those children
of the forest around him one by one; and
when they came he spoke their names and
kissed them, and taking off the crucifix his
mother in far-off France had given him, he
placed it in the hands of one of them, asking
him to hold it raised before him, and then,
with his hands clasped and his eyes raised to
the sacred symbol, he thanked God for the
grace He did in permitting him to die a missionary of Jesus Christ.   Silent for a time, he
said slowly, 'my soul hangs upon His word,' and
the spirit of the great Marquette, priest, missionary and explorer, had passed to its Creator and Savior.   ' Greater love than this no man
hnoweth.'   Marquette, Voltaire! whose tomb
is to-day the more glorious?    He who unfolded to the savage outcasts of civilization their
high immortal destiny, or he who strove with
all his might and power to erase every vestage of hope from the tombstones of the
world.Rev. J. T. lioche in October Donahoe's.
An Antidote for Poison by Mary and Margaret W. Letcti.   This little work is an earnest appeal for help by the missionaries of India.   "There is a great thirst for education
throughout India.   Education is spreading
like wild fire.   Hindoos are already beginning
to tax themselves for education and that will
be the most popular tax in the country.   But
what is being done?   They are going in for
the education of these 250 millions.   But it
will be a godless education."   Pub. by H. L.
Hastings, 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass.
The Proof of Miracles by Henry F. Brownson, L. L. D.   "No man can say that miracles
are not possible, for we know that God can
work a miracle if he chooses, since he is omnipotent and a miiacle implies no contradiction."   Pub. at Notre Dame, Ind.   Price 5 cts.--><pb n="161" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Heart and the hands" TEIform="index"/>THE HEART AND THE HANDS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder Henry C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">SOME persons who may love to quibble, better than they love to confine themselves to a
                            Christian discipline, can only speak of the body as an anatomical structure, and that a
                            reference to the affections of the heart, or the compassion of the bowels, is foolish, as
                            everything, they say, comes under the domination of the brain. It is well, however, that all
                            are not forced to think alike. In speaking of a pure heart, an earlier race has been pleased
                            to designate it as the place of the affections. "Our heart shall rejoioe in Him, because we
                            have trusted in his holy name." The prophet in his ecstacy then said that God would give a
                            new heart to his people, and would also put a new spirit within them. Clean hands are
                            equally as necessary, as we make reference to a spiritual work. "He that hath clean hands
                            and a pure heart shall receive the blessing of righteousness from the God of his salvation."
                            The taking of bribes was so potent in its influence, that the prophets had no hesitancy in
                            saying that it was a fraudulent and unclean transaction. So carefully were the hands to be
                            guarded that even the giving of alms came under a close inspection, to avoid the stimulating
                            of vanity. On this point the people were advised not to let the left hand know what the
                            right hand did, while under the influence of a generous spirit. This is all very nice, and
                            just as it should be in the language of the Bible, and a careful study of this beautiful
                            form of exNOVEMBER, 1899. <pb n="162" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 162 THE MANIFESTO. pression is very
                            commendable. While we have the enjoyment of this spiritual thought, we must not forget the
                            great necessity of having clean hands as a sanitary and a moral influence. Everything
                            pertaining to our lives, forms a more or less direct impression upon those who are with us,
                            and no duty is so small or so obscure but that it needs our careful attention. The hands are
                            easily soiled and without special attention will soon become very unsightly. Our only remedy
                            in this case is a conscientious use of soap and water. Although there may be individuals and
                            families, and even tribes, who seemingly belong to the family of the "great unwashed," and
                            whose spirituality must be equally as low, yet it would seem that cleanliness was
                            prominently in the creative plan. The better class of human beings, in all probability soon
                            devised a way to accomplish that which adds so much to the comfort of life, and to the
                            pleasure of society. A few years since, a wise, but seemingly eccentric individual gave
                            notice publicly, that he should refuse to shake hands with either man or woman, and gave as
                            his reason for arriving at this singular conclusion, that the majority of people presented
                            hands that were not only unwashed, but often repellant. While it is very essential that we
                            should hold in remembrance the great value of spiritual, clean hands, and a spiritual pure
                            heart, we must not forget that "Cleanliness comes next to godliness," and may be so closely
                            conjoined that it would be difficult to make a separation. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soldiers of christ" TEIform="index"/>THE SOLDIERS OF CHRIST.</head><p TEIform="p">[The following hymn will find a ready response in many
                            hearts. It was evidently written at the time of the organization of the Community, by one
                            of the old heroes of the American Revolution. Ed.] 
                            The King of kings, and Lord of hosts, Has blown his trumpet in our coasts, And round his
                            standard now appears A valiant band of volunteers. Their loins are girt, their feet are shod
                            With the unerring truth of God, And by the truth they now begin To overthrow the man of sin.
                            Against the foe they now advance, Each with his bow and glittering lance, And though they're
                            friends to all mankind, They crucify a carnal mind. They spare no idol, great nor small, But
                            pass one sentence on them all. <pb n="163" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 163 And cut and slash on
                            every hand, To purge all evil from the land. They're well equipt with gospel arms, And make
                            no peace on any terms, Nor with the flesh will stand to treat, But strike at every lust they
                            meet. They will admit no vain excuse, To let one vile affection loose, But bind the captive
                            fast in chains, While one flesh-pleasing tie remains. Now every soul that would do right, Is
                            welcome to enlist and fight; These weapons of victorious truth, Are for the aged and the
                            youth. No soul of man does God exclude From hating sin and doing good; And in such souls, we
                            do maintain, The God of truth will ever reign. While living truth, like burning coals, Is
                            purging evil from our souls, We know we are in Him that's true, And what He says we freely
                            do ; The empire of eternal bliss, Has its foundation laid in this, And all who gain this
                            noty ground, With everlasting life are crowned. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He giveth power to the faint" TEIform="index"/>HE GIVETH POWER TO THE FAINT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Breedlove, Virgie" TEIform="persName"/>By Virgie Breedlore.</byline><p TEIform="p">SAY what you may to the contrary, whoever lives in this world without communion with God,
                            lives poorly. There is nothing which th.e human mind can feed upon and thrive thereby, that
                            can so strengthen it and give it the needful thrift and culture as the living forces which
                            God can impart. Human nature can not develop its best by the sources of strength which are
                            fitted for bodily uses alone. The soul needs to be nourished as much as the body, and the
                            food on which it can thrive the best is that which it obtains when it is in sympathetic,
                            loving communion with its Maker. Such intercourse is easy if we will but have it so; the
                            Bible describes with minute precision the true way to get to God, and having found Him, to
                            draw upon Him for the supply of his needs. This way is through Jesus Christ. <pb n="164" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 164 THE MANIFESTO. Jesus has said "I am the way, the truth and the life."
                            There is nothing derogatory to the dignity nor to the freedom of human nature therein, so
                            let us not live alone, nor be down-hearted, for he giveth power to the faint, and they that
                            ha,ve no might, he increaseth their strength, for the heavens declare his glory, and the
                            firmament showeth his handiwork. Day unto day uttereth speech, and night unto night showeth
                            knowledge. Nevertheless, no human soul is satisfied with merely sensuous apprehensions of
                            God. It seeks to pass beyond what the eye can see, or the ear can hear, to that condition of
                            apprehension where interior consciousness is satisfied only by personal communion,is
                            satisfied to live in God, that our lives may be hid with Christ, and then throughout the
                            endless ages there will be neither defeat, decay nor death. South Union, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We are able" TEIform="index"/>"WE ARE ABLE."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, Jessie" TEIform="persName"/>By Jessie Evans.</byline><p TEIform="p">IT is not difficult to pass in imagination to the scene which Scripture throws upon and
                            around the three simple words under consideration. We see the Savior and his twelve
                            disciples on their way to Jerusalem. St. Mark pictures Jesus as leading the way, and the
                            privileged twelve following, awed by the silent, forceful spiritual ministration which
                            emanates from his thought as legitimately as does fragrance from the heart of the rose. Kis
                            mind is not earth-born, and at this moment is with its parentage. He is communing with his
                            heavenly Father about the bitter cup, the Gethsemane agony which is soon to close his
                            earthly portion. He walks on for a while forgetful, perhaps, of the presence of even his
                            beloved companions. He and his "Father are one"not an unconscious unity, but the positive
                            absence of all separateness, a oneness established by the tests of the Jordan, the
                            wilderness, the mountain, and by the prophetic current coursing through his mind, which has
                            laid open to him his future betrayal, scourging, death. The human nerves shrink at the
                            divine decree, but "I and my Father are one" throws strength over the human and its
                            momentary quiverings are lost in the contemplation of the almightiness of the compact.
                            Suddenly he remembers the twelve, and turning he. speaks to them of his approaching agonies,
                            dwelling with his usual tender consideration upon the happier thought of his resurrection
                            upon the third day. Little apprehend they of the awfulness that is to characterize the
                            closing days of their Master's life, but he knows. James and John, thinking mainly no doubt,
                            of the glory of Christ's ascension, move forward eagerly, pleading, "Grant unto us that we
                            may sit, one on thy right hand, and the other on thy left hand, in thy glory." The disciples
                            instantly look indignantly toward the speakers, but Jesus is strangely <pb n="165" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE MANIFESTO. 165 moved by the petition. Coming either from the mother or from the
                            disciples themselves, it stirs his heart to its depths. "Ye know not what ye ask," he says,
                            as the Gethsemane passport to that glory drops again into the horizon of his mental
                            suffering. Then he remembers that they are his chosen ones, they have walked with him in his
                            temptations, they worshiped at his transfiguration, and upon their hearts must the burden of
                            the transmission of his gospel fall. He feels the pulse of their loyalty beneath the selfish
                            appeal, he is assured of their ingenuousness ; yet he gently asks ; "Are ye able to drink of
                            the cup that I shall drink of, and to be baptized with the baptism that I am baptized with?"
                            They say unto him, only this: "We aie able." The ambiguous verbosity of the Pharisee, the
                            secret "if" of compromise rankling in the breast of the Judas so nearby, breathe no poison
                            into the simple clearness of the words. They stand out upon the sacred page embossed in an
                            almost child-like simplicity, yet upon the sensitive ear of the suffering Savior they rest
                            as balm. In this hour of bitter thought, their confident sincerity comforts him, and in
                            tender earnestness fall the words : "Ye shall drink indeed of my cup and be baptized with
                            the baptism that I am baptized with." But he promises not to them the place in his Father's
                            kingdom, for which they ask. He well knows that in drinking the cup of self-crucifixion, in
                            experiencing the baptism of the Holy Ghost and fire, they will know no preference of place
                            or name. No seat at the right or the left hand on any ideal throne of glory is the acme of
                            the Christ work. As his heart bleeds even now for the world's great sorrow, so will theirs
                            do ; and in the virtue of service thereto they will find all the throne and heaven that
                            heart can desire. The subsequent history of the two brothers verifies the prophecy of Jesus.
                            In the work of discipleship they figured prominently and well. Alas ! they slept during the
                            Savior's hour of deepest anguish, and it is recorded that only the beloved disciple John
                            lingered to catch the last appointment of his Master ; yet when the glorious day of
                            Pentecost dawned, they who had declared themselves able to drink the cup and receive the
                            baptism, were there "filled with the Holy Ghost" to preach the power of the risen Christ. He
                            who walked the streets of the material Jerusalem is no more, the Christ that reigns to-day
                            in the spiritual Jerusalem, the Christ that is ever cognizant of the needs, the sins of the
                            world that "God so loved" is an omnipresence. His spirit inclines as two or three meet
                            touching any thing we would ask. In our human thoughtlessness we, too, like James and John,
                            may ask for an end, but Christ will teach us that the means only are for us ; we may desire
                            an effect, but it springs from its corresponding cause. The life which Jesus lived is a life
                            of processes. Was ever intimation given by him of a goal, a resting-place for his workmen?
                            The eternal knows no boundary lines, and recognizes neither time nor space. To the rich
                            ruler, after teaching him the initiatory step to be taken, he said, "Then come and follow
                            me." Where would he lead? To a final throne where he would rest <pb n="166" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 166
                            THE MANIFESTO. with his disciples on the right hand and the left hand in a flood of heavenly
                            glory? More likely he would send him to the cold mountain-side after the hundredth sheep
                            that had gone astray. The prodigal in the far country, the bowed head of the publican, the
                            little children behind the angry disciples, Zaccheus in the tree-top, were the sights that
                            arrested the Savior's attention, and the disciple must be "as his master." Nothing in his
                            testimony suggests other than that "the Son of man came not to be ministered unto, but to
                            minister and to give his life a ransom for many." Christ's thinking moved always along
                            divine lines, ours is sadly on the human, selfish plane. Yet with the confidence of James
                            and John we may apply for a part with the Savior. The cup will bring its full bitterness,
                            every heart must drink the heavenly elixir necessary for its purification, however
                            uninviting. The baptism will inflict a straitening of all that interferes with the
                            operations of the Holy Ghost and the fire. Then when the fan has thoroughly purged the floor
                            the freed faculties will follow the Savior. Christ says to us, "Are ye able to drink of the
                            cup that I shall drink of, and to be baptized with the oaptism that I am baptized with?" And
                            the greater Voice adds, "Fear not, for I am with thee. When thou passest through the waters,
                            I will be with thee; and through the rivers, they shall not overflow thee : when thoTi
                            walkest through the fire, thou shalt not be burned ; neither shall the flames kindle upon
                            thee." Hence, in implicit trust in God's protective promise, in the strength of our
                            convictions, in our love toward the questioning Christ, we eagerly, lovingly respond, "We
                            are able." East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peace conference" TEIform="index"/>THE PEACE CONFERENCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="McKechnie, Frederic" TEIform="persName"/>By Frederic McKechnie.</byline><p TEIform="p">ON the 21st of August, a small party from the North family, consisting of Brothers, Frederic
                            and Daniel, Eldress Anna and Sisters, Sarah and Cecelia set out to attend the conference of
                            the Universal Peace Union, at Mystic, Conn. We went by the way of the Hudson river to New
                            York, and thence by steamer to Stonington, and a brief railway ride in the early morning of
                            Wednesday brought us to the Mystic. The sessions of the first day were only sparsely
                            attended, but on Thursday and Friday the auditorium was filled both morning and afternoon,
                            and in the evening there was a very fair attendance. The first speaker was Benjamin F.
                            Trueblood, of Boston. He had been to the great Disarmament conference at The Hague, talked
                            with many of those who took part in it, and gave us a very interesting account of its
                            proceedings, predicting as one of its results that conferences of a similar nature would
                            become more and more frequent. He was hopeful that its influence <pb n="167" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 167 would be potent for peace in the future, notwithstanding that it seems to
                            have done so little of immediate importance for the cause of peace and goodwill between
                            nations. It was a feature of this year's conference at Mystic, that speakers did not content
                            themselves with merely calling for peace, but took a wider sweep of thought and dealt with
                            the causes that helped to produce its oppositewar. Thus, one speaker dealt with the dietetic
                            question. She respectfully submitted that if we ate what nourished the body and yet did not
                            supply stimulus to the animal nature in us, namely, fruits, nuts and grains we should be
                            helping along the cause of universal peace in a very substantial way. A man, she said, who
                            spent his days slaughtering oxen, sheep or hogs, would not find it so difficult to go out
                            and slaughter his fellowmen as would one who habitually abstained from eating scorched or
                            parboiled portions of these animals, and those who habitually eat flesh-food are responsible
                            for the existence of slaughter-houses and all the horrors connected therewith. Another
                            speaker took up the temperance aspect of the question, and contended for the total
                            prohibition of the sale and manufacture of intoxicating liquor as a means whereby men would
                            come into a more peaceable frame of mind. He said that many times men had to be maddened
                            with ardent spirits before they were fit to fight and if they never tasted these fiery
                            waters, they would be unfit to and never want to fight. William Lloyd Garrison, son of the
                            famous anti-slavery apostle, read an able paper on the general ethics of war. He condemned
                            war as wrong, absolutely and always wrrong, and never under any circumstances a necessary
                            means of settling international disputes. Professor Batchelor was the name of another
                            speaker, but his remarks consisted of an explanation of the work he wras doing among the
                            children of Mystic. He said that children were educated into w^ar by "Boys' Brigades" and
                            the like, and he thought they had a right to be educated into peace. His method is to take
                            the children with him out into the neighboring fields and woods, and by the sea-shore and
                            taking up anything that interests them in the course of their ramble, explain it to them in
                            simple language. He carefully avoids all display of learning but at the same time tries to
                            give them a correct idea of some of the wondeiful processes of the natural creation. He
                            finds that this wray of studying natural objects has a very refining effect on the children.
                            Some that were rude and uncouth are become mild and well behaved, and they ail are very much
                            attached to him ; and for a good reason; the Professor is attached to them, literally gives
                            himself to them, and it does not take children long to find out who love them and who do
                            not. These were the principal speakers, but there were many moi'e; so many that time could
                            not be found for all of them to address the audience. Eldress Anna, of our party, read a
                            paper she had prepared entitled "Voices from Mt. Lebanon." It was very well received. And
                            Bro. Daniel read a poem <pb n="168" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 168 THE MANIFESTO by Sister Cecelia,
                            entitled, "The American Flag." We were frequently called upon in the course of the three
                            days we were there to sing, which we did, trying through that medium to convey the sympathy
                            and support we felt for the great cause of peace and good-will on the earth. From the many
                            expressions of good feeling we met with, we believe we succeeded in our efforts in this
                            direction and it was felt that in us they had those who would stand by the white flag of
                            purity and peace until the whole earth was gathered beneath its snowy folds. It did us all
                            good to meet with so many real live people and whether we visit Mystic again or not we shall
                            not soon forget the conference of 1899. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Search light" TEIform="index"/>A SEARCH LIGHT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pick, Ernest" TEIform="persName"/>By Elder Ernest Pick.</byline><p TEIform="p">" "XT OU did run well; who did hinder you that ye should not obey the JL truth, so that ye
                            can not do the things that ye would.-Gal. v., 7-17. The present state of our Society is one
                            of unrest, confusion and dissatisfaction. Wherever we turn, whomsoever we meet, we find
                            discontent, criticism and a strong desire for reform. Is communism a failure ? Is Shakerism
                            on the decline? All of us agree that some reform is needed to resurrect our cause to its
                            former prosperity in labor and in spirit. Nobody, however, sees the way clear, out of the
                            woods. The reason for this is, that as a people at large we lack purity of heart. "The pure
                            in heart shall see God." But this is nothing new. History repeats itself, and our conditions
                            havo been among professing Christians before this day. After the mighty impetus for
                            righteousness, started by the presence and life of Christ, had weakened in the time of the
                            Apostles, similar to the relaxing zeal of Mother Ann's followers of the present day, Paul
                            gives them and us the reasons in language not to be mistaken. "Ye did run well, who did
                            hinder you that ye should not obey the truth?" "For all the law is fulfilled in one word,
                            even in this; Thou shalt love thy neighbor as thyself." "But if you bite and devour one
                            another, take heed that ye be not consumed one of another." "This I say then, walk in the
                            spirit, and ye shall not fulfill the lust of the flesh." "For the flesh lusteth against the
                            spirit, and the spirit against the flesh ; and these are contrary the one to the other; so
                            that ye can not do the things that ye would."Gal. v., 7-17. And this is just the dilemma we
                            are in as a people, "so that we can not do the things that we would." In Gal. v., 19, 20,
                            21, Paul gives us that appalling catalogue of evils our mortal natures are and have been
                            suffering under. How dreadful these accusations ! They are incomplete, and in our modern
                            days we could add to the list;the degrading habit of the use of to- <pb n="169" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE MANIFESTO. 169 bacco in all forms ; the use of vile language ; the monkeyish way of
                            dressing some among us have adopted who are after the changing fashions of the world. Last,
                            but not least the growing element of a class of modern Shakers who are above a certain class
                            of work and household duties, generally called drudgery. My heart burns with indignation to
                            see old and young, those of tender age and those whose hair has grown gray in a life-time's
                            labor, toil from morning to evening, while others strut around in the door-yard or read
                            novels and papers in their rooms, willing enough to handle the dishes, food and tools at the
                            table, but not in the sink. These drones would soon undermine the fundamental principle of
                            our order, the brotherhood and sisterhood and institute the relation of master and servant,
                            madam and servant-girl. Let each tub stand on its own bottom. "Work out your own salvation,"
                            often we find, "in fear and trembling." There is no salvation by proxy, whether in temporal
                            or spiritual labor. Let us then turn from the flesh-pots of Egypt and stretch out our hands
                            for the manna of a higher life, which gives us the fruit of the Spirit. "If we live in the
                            Spirit, let us also walk in the Spirit." "Let us not be desirous of vainglory, provoking one
                            another," for plunder and rubbish that can be had in any dry goods store. But let us get a
                            firmer hold, a stronger grasp on the treasures of heaven. The Gospel is not a dead issue
                            yet, not by any means. Like a thief in the night, it may, and will surprise us with
                            revelations new. The prophets of old have not yet proved liars and fools, uttering vague
                            imageriesyea, their most sanguine promises may and will be left far behind by the glory of a
                            coming day and work. The mountain of doubt, darkness and confusion will be removed by one
                            single word of faith,true faith ! Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Instrumentalities" TEIform="index"/>INSTRUMENTALITIES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>Oliver C. Hampton.</byline><p TEIform="p">NO one need to look further than the solar system, to be convinced that system, as inexorable
                            as mathematics, governs the universe. All the planets revolve about the sun with undeviating
                            exactness; so much so, that in the history of the science of astronomy, no important
                            discrepancy has been known. Although we know all this gigantic phenomenon of the solar
                            system, to have been the word and breath of the Almighty; yet there seems to run through the
                            whole, a plan of instrumentality. The conditions of the earth are dependent, upon the
                            influence of the sun. His direct effects are almost infinite. Again, vegetables seem to be
                            dependent upon minerals, animals upon vegetables, as instrumentalities in their production
                            and existence. The gradual evolution of the race of man from the savage to its present
                            advanced state of perfection, seems to have progressed in a scientific and <pb n="170" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 170 THE MANIFESTO. perfect order of instrumentalities. "Without variableness
                            or shadow of turning," and man has so far copied the wisdom of nature, in his upward
                            progress that he too seems to come under the category of all the phenomena preceding him.
                            For almost all objects and projects, looking to improvement in any and all directions, men
                            organize themselves into companies, bands, associations, syndicates, trusts, monopolies, and
                            church institutions. Each branch of such organizations is run, not by the great Spirit
                            himself, but by some personal instrumentality best adapted for it. Jesus knew this science
                            of systematic arrangement and its necessary operation through human instrumentalities far
                            better than we do. He founded the Pentecostal church on the plan of human instrumentalities,
                            both in its temporal and spiritual character. Although all the members of his Church could
                            and did at all times invoke the aid of the Most H:gh, for aid and strength in the hours of
                            adversity and sorrow ; yet th jy could not walk in utter independence of the order and
                            systematic organization of the church, without becoming gradually dissevered therefrom and
                            losing the united strength thereof to such an extent as to fail of the salvation of a united
                            church which was as much greater than any isolated effort as the heat and efficacy of a
                            gathered heap of fuel is greater than one isolated fire-brand. When a man steps out of a
                            corporation or syndicate he knows instantly how much his isolated ability is likely to stand
                            him in stead, compared with his power while belonging to a united institution all pulling in
                            the direction of his interests and he toward theirs. But alas ! This condition of systematic
                            organization requires obedience to its regulations, (not to any man or men as such, but to
                            their gift of direction and authority as instrumentalities for the upbuilding, prosperity
                            and perpetuity of the church.) Here is where a great deal of friction comes, and a great
                            deal of self-sacrifice. But without just this condition of things how is selfishness to be
                            destroyed, and without the destruction of selfishness what possible hope is there for our
                            happiness, here or hereafter? In this church, the instrumentalities for our discipline and
                            travel out of all lust and selfish propinquities are unspeakable advantages which can not be
                            discussed at length without making this article too long, but after seventy-seven years'
                            experience in all situations, both lay and clerical, I am ready to give it my heartiest
                            indorsement and to agree that the rapt Prophet saw the beauty and poetry as wTell as the
                            divine and saving efficacy of this Pentecostal church of our Savior and Mother when he
                            exclaimed "Behold a King (Christ) shall reign in righteousness, Princes (Officers in the
                            Church) shall rule in judgment, and a Man (Men and Women) shall be made as an hiding place
                            from the wind and a covert from the tempest; as rivers of water in a dry place and as the
                            shadowr of a rock in a weary land." Union Village, Ohio.</p></div2><pb n="171" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Retaliation and forgiveness" TEIform="index"/>RETALIATION AND FORGIVENESS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Phelps, Lillian" TEIform="persName"/>By Lillian Phelps.</byline><p TEIform="p">1) EFORE Moses' day the people were accustomed to live according to their I ) human feelings
                            which repaid doubly every injury received, knowing no higher law. Then Moses, under divine
                            guidance, taught the law of Justice, "An eye for an eye, and a tooth for a tooth;" which was
                            to give as much, and no more than was received. But Jesus brought to the knowledge of men
                            the divine law of Love, for "Whosoever shall smite thee on thy right cheek, turn to him the
                            other also." These three stages are types of the growth of a soul. From birth, the first
                            thought is to defend one's self against censure, injury or that which wounds the selfish
                            nature. As the soul matures it learns to deal in strict justice, giving only in the measure
                            that has been received. Yet this leavesthe soul in the state of nature. When a soul attains
                            the divine law of Love, he finds no place for revenge or retaliation for he is governed by
                            this law ; "Love thy neighbor as thyself.'* Where this Christ love has taken possession of
                            the heart no hatred or hard feelings can find a place, and the divine command, "Love your
                            enemies" is no longer a hard saying; neither is it difficult to forgive as we would be
                            forgiven for the indwelling spirit of Christ, if it is there, can manifest itself in no
                            other way. One writer has beautifully worded this sentiment in the following lines, Oh
                            forgive and forget, if the friends we love fondly Prove themselves to be false, and unworthy
                            of trust, Oh deal with them kindly, for they are but mortals, Erring like usfor we too are
                            but dust. Oh deal with them tenderly, pity their weakness, We know every heart hath its evil
                            and good, We all have one Father in heaven, hence are brothers, Then let us forgive and
                            forget, as we should. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My human patience drooped amid the trial..." TEIform="index"/>My human patience drooped amid the trial...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">My human patience drooped amid the trial And wearily my soul sought Christ in tears, O
                            Teacher blest, what heavenly lesson needful Hast thou to-day to soothe these anxious fears?
                            His gentle spirit readily gave answer, 'When earth denies thee peace and rest of mind Thy
                            love to God express by help to neighbor And as thou yivest comfort thou shalt find."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="E., J." TEIform="persName"/>J. E.</byline></div2><pb n="172" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. NOVEMBER, 1899. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the
                            "United Society of Believers, and is the only work issued regularly by the Shaker Community.
                            Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious views of the Order and
                            to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address, Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, N. H.
                            NOTICE. Our little Magazine which at the present time is known as "The Manifesto," issued
                            its first number in January, 1871, at Watervliet, N. Y. At that time it bore the very
                            pleasant but modest title, ''The Shaker." It was the messenger of "good news," and in its
                            advocacy of the testimony of the Christ, gave no uncertain sound. Its publication has been
                            sustained by the liberal contributions of the several Shaker Communities, as they have
                            manifested a deep interest in its success as a medium for good to its own members, and no
                            less to those who were not residents of the Community. Possibly it may be after a term of
                            some thirty years, "The Manifesto" has accomplished all the good it can for the present, and
                            may now go into retirement till another wave of enthusiasm calls it again into action. To
                            all who have ministered to the success of the little paper, as writers or readers, or to its
                            circulation, we extend our kindest thanks. Times have changed. Money is scarce and the
                            several Societies have suffered with the laboring classes in the common distress. It is now
                            proposed that the December number of "The Manifesto" for 1899, shall be the closing of the
                            publication. The- Directors.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">September. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Kain. 1898. 05. 2.25 in 1899.
                                62.4 5.815 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 80 above 0. Lowest " Number of rainy days " "
                                " clear " " " 7 " " cloudy" " " 14 Oct. 1899. Xotes About Home should give an account of
                                the tangible things of life which our eyes have looked upon; our hands have handled; our
                                tongues have tasted; and our every sense has passed judgment upon and pronounced very
                                good. Of this class I must number our apples, pears, cherries, and plums which are
                                beauties to behold. This is the result of careful cultivation. AVhen I look upon fruits
                                which in form are as perfect as though dropped from the turning lathe without a mar, I
                                say, certainly an artist's genius formed them. Such have been the fruits of our
                                orchards, gardens, and farms. Our potatoes are as days of yore when we would as quick
                                think the stones would rot as the potatoes. The ears of sweet corn look as if they had
                                been cast in a mould. Hubbard squash vines have borne loads of fine squash. The same may
                                be said of the cabbage supporting heads nine, ten, and eleven inches in diameter. But
                                why begin to individualize; truly we are blest in our basket and our store. We have been
                                promised if we are faithful in temporal things we shall be blest with a fruition of the
                                good things of the spirit world. Health and prosperity we certainly appreciate and daily
                                are striving to secure. Folks generally well. Calvin O. Reed. <pb n="173" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                MANIFESTO. 173 South Family. Oct. 1899. Dear Manifesto ;A few more greetings from absent
                                friends through your valuable mediumship, then we repeat the final good-bye. We shall
                                not forget the happy interchange of thought wrought through the circulation of our long
                                loved Manifesto. Sunday afternoon of the 24th ult. in the Hall of the Church family
                                Amanda Deyo, Vice president of the Universal Peace Union, delivered a soul-stirring
                                address on the subject of Peace, portraying the beautiful effects of Universal Peace and
                                the terrible degrading results of war in its varied forms. Her friends, Amanda Sholl and
                                Martha Comegy were present; both are engaged in the same work. Annie M. Moody a leader
                                in the spiritual and literary advancements of the day was present also. Sunday morning,
                                Oct. 1st, at the Church family, Prof. Daniel Bachelor a member of the Peace Union gave a
                                very interesting and instructive lecture on the "Spiritual Teachings of Nature," showing
                                how wonderfully all things material are sustained by spirit forces. Ah! said the
                                Professor do trees think and talk? They most surely do. They show character, even as the
                                human family. Notice how some display a disposition to shirk while others represent a
                                more noble type; they work and hunt for nourishment and grow by their own efforts. One
                                and a half hours the Professor discoursed on this wonderfully enchanting subject. Our
                                sweet corn harvest has exceeded our highest anticipations, a better yield was never
                                known. Our apple crop is of the finest and best, large, fair and plentiful, just the
                                kind to suit the taste of the most fastidious. Potatoes are splendid of mammoth
                                proportions and delicious flavor, no one need hunger and thirst for the food of the farm
                                is sufficient to supply all needs. The nutting season is much enjoyed by the children
                                whose bright eyes and nimble fingers make sure of all that fall within their reach.
                                Genevieve DeGratv.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1899. It is a very true saying that we many times appreciate those treasures the
                                most that have been lost or removed from our possession. From our correspondence we
                                observe that almost universally the regret is expressed that our monthly Magazine is to
                                be discontinued. We will then realize that it was a factor in helping to solve the
                                problem of which of the forces shall dominate,those that tend to consolidate and
                                strengthen or disintegrating ones? The age that we live in may properly be termed the
                                reading age, as witnessed by the amount of literature, good, bad, and indifferent which
                                is presented to the peo- ' pie. Where one listens to a verbal sermon, one thousand read
                                it when published, and the necessity is becoming yearly more apparent that the best way
                                to come into communion effectually with the mass of people is through the press. The
                                statement of Hawthorne, that under whatever conditions human life is found acting, the
                                tendency is toward the brute, seems based on false reasoning, for the most effectual way
                                to brutalize a human being is to insist that he is not capable of attaining any other
                                standard; and it would need a very strong mind to advance above and beyond that
                                condition when that doctrine was perpetually asserted to their minds. While in all
                                phases of human life there is need for impi'ovement, the most effective way for it to
                                advance is to present it with a superior ideal and insist that it can be attained and
                                whatever the mistakes made keep that light before them, asserting that it must be
                                followed; that the ideal thought must be actualized in life. The Oct. number of "The
                                Coming Age" presents a very able essay on "The Natural Laws of Permanent Peace," by
                                Samuel Richard Fuller, When wars and the ru- <pb n="174" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 174 THE MANIFESTO.
                                mors of wars are perpetually heralded and the glorification and exaltation of hero
                                worship has placed those on fame's pedestal, who have given their energies to the
                                destruction of life, and the nations are proclaiming with a loud voice "See the
                                conquering hero comes." It is blessed to come into communion with those souls who are
                                able and willing to present something better than the old barbarian worship which
                                crowned their oppressors and crucified their Saviors. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1899. One glance at the beautiful October woods reminds us that lovely summer has
                                gone; that winter will soon take the place of autumn, and we shall all once more gather
                                around the evening lamp, beside a cosy fire, away from the bitter winds that are so sure
                                to accompany that dread season. Notwithstanding the long drought we have a fair harvest.
                                Of ensilage corn crop never was better. The silo is filled with choice food for the
                                cows. While cutting the corn the Brethren run the ensilage-cutter with a belt 160 feet
                                long to prevent fire from the boiler. It worked nicely and no power was lost from length
                                of belt. It may be of interest to add that the potato-field from which our main crop was
                                raised, is 70 rods long and is in two towns, two counties, and two congressional
                                districts. Although we expected very few apples the harvest brings us a goodly supply.
                                The past week 13 bbls. of Baldwins were picked from two trees, in one p.m. We were very
                                glad to hear from the new Shaker Home at White Oak Ga., and we wish it every success in
                                its spiritual and temporal growth. The Trustees in Maine say they are sorry that the
                                other Trustees did not feel able to furnish means to keep The Manifesto moving. The
                                people in Alfred and Gloucester are united with the Trustees in the same spirit. Ada S.
                                Cummings.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>-Alfred., Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1899. Summer has left us with the record of a busy season. We have had success
                                indisposing of our fancy work, among the mountains, and at the summer resorts along the
                                sea shore. Our potato crop was light but of good quality, apples are few. Have harvested
                                two hundred tons of ensilage corn with which the two silos at the barn have been filled
                                and a large surplus left over which is being fed to the cattle. We have gathered a
                                hundred bushels of cranberries from our meadows; would have had more if the frost had
                                not come to spoil them. On the 2nd inst. a few snowflakes came fluttering down to warn
                                us that winter is approaching. Colds are prevalent in society caused by sudden changes
                                in the weather. Our Laundry is receiving a new coat of paint on the outside. While we
                                are gathering temporal blessings may we be mindful of the blessings which our Heavenly
                                Father bestows on the faithful worker. Eva M. Libbey.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1899. Autumn, by right of inheritance, has once more ascended the throne and become
                                monarch of the year. Summer occupied a back seat by the door through the greater part of
                                her time, and now that she is banished, Autumn reigns with nothing to molest. At his
                                very first appearance his chilly air completely prostrated the tender plants of the
                                garden, and the trees yielded up their luscious fruits to the hand of the harvester, and
                                with drooping leaves, seemed to have resigned all pleasure and beauty. The maples, oaks
                                and beeches, however, have decided not to withdraw without showing their colors, and
                                stand arrayed in gorgeous apparel; the distant mountains are radiant with their beauty.
                                So quietly and obscurely did Summer do her work that we did not realize the <pb n="175" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> TJ IE MANIFES TO. 175 amount she had performed until now that we come to
                                gather her golden legacy. In early summer we said, "we shall have but just enough apples
                                this year to fill the home measure, scantily," but lo, already 300 bbls. of the rosy
                                balls have been sold and sent to other homes. Pears have been both pleasing and
                                plentiful and have been duly picked, pared, preserved, pickled and,peddled. The potatoes
                                have started out to see the world, a well-conditioned band, more numerous than for many
                                years. The sweet corn was very satisfactory and was sold before the drying process was
                                completed. Some 110 bbls. of it left yesterday and other car-loads will soon follow. We
                                find by collecting and counting our gifts that we have cause for much gratitude to the
                                "Lord of the Harvest" who has thus kindly blessed us, and the Thanksgiving day
                                approaching should be filled with the expressions of praise and thankfulness which we
                                daily feel. Our gifts have been and are many; our blessings are great. Can we, as
                                stewards of the kingdom of God withhold them from the needy? Our faith is noble, the
                                light of our leaders, of our parents, glows brightly over us and can we hide its light
                                or allow selfish interests to cloud its brightness? The seed for the kingdom of Christ
                                on earth has been sown and can we allow it to perish, to be destroyed or crushed or
                                choked in its growth? Let us arise and in Christ's resurrection power roll away the
                                stones of doubt and indifference, and come forth in newness of life. We are sowing daily
                                sowing and what will the harvest be? We are building ever building for a great eternity.
                                Shall the structure we are raising hold a light to all around, And the seed we now are
                                sowing cause Christ's kingdom to abound? Fidelia Estabrook.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1899. Like Ruth of Bible days, we have been busy gleaning, until now there remaineth
                                none of the fruits of the land out of either storehouse or barn. The winter apples are a
                                good crop, and pumpkins are unusually fine in flavor and huge in form. Three of the
                                latter sufficed for a meal of the timehonored pumpkin pie for one. hundred tasters. The
                                first snow-flake blew into sight on the 2nd inst. accompanied by a number of its mates,
                                but so timid and tiny were they that they melted when we looked at them. When they grow
                                up, we shall see more of them; they will, no doubt, be active and gregarious long after
                                Home Notes have passed from sight if not from memory. But we are reminded that as
                                Christians, "we look not at the things which are seen, but at the things which are not
                                seen; for the things which are seen are temporal, but the things which are not seen are
                                eternal." The bond of fellowship between the various societies of Believers and the true
                                friendship which sanctifies in Christ the relation we bear one to another, are among the
                                real things and upon them we ask the blessing of God, that they may be multiplied and
                                enriched until, as a people, we are what Christ our Pattei'n, would have us be, and what
                                we all long to be. Jessie Evans.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Worrying" TEIform="index"/>WORRYING,</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> One of the hardest lessons in the school of life is the avoidance of worry. Some
                                    scholars learn it much faster and more thoroughly than others do. Indeed, they seem
                                    to have been born without the capacity of worrying, and those who have not been so
                                    fortunate are sometimes disposed to deny that such beings are entitled to any credit
                                    for their philosophical behavior. Others never seem able to learn the lesson at all,
                                    but have to wear the dunce's cap for their obtuseness to the end of the chapter. The
                                    great majority of the men and women manage to learn the lesson more or less
                                    perfectly after spending years in the effort, and after bitter experiences. Even the
                                    most chronic and appar- <pb n="176" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 176 THE MANIFESTO. ently hopeless
                                    worriers will willingly admit that there cannot be any intellectual and moral
                                    condition that^is"so*absolutely useless. That it never made the future a bit
                                    brighter if it looked gloomy, nor in the slightest degree atoned for the errors of
                                    the past, is admitted by all. Indeed no sane person can deny it. And yet how prone
                                    most of us are to indulge in it more or less. Our reason tells us it is foolish and
                                    even sinful, that it is vain and profitless, and yet we indulge in it! Nowhere
                                    surely could a more convincing proof be found of the weak and unnatural condition to
                                    which man has been reduced by sin. For certainly, in its essence worrying is either
                                    an evidence of entire forgetfulness of God or distrust either of his willingness or
                                    his ability to help us and provide for us. Worry is always weakening, it fevers the
                                    brain, injures the digestion, impairs self-control, deranges the temper, enfeebles
                                    the whole nature, unfits a man or woman for making to the best effect those efforts
                                    which are necessary to rescue them from the very circumstances which are the bane of
                                    their existence and under the stress of which they are apt to say they "cannot help
                                    worrying."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Refiner's fire" TEIform="index"/>THE REFINER'S FIRE.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> He sat by a furnace of seven-fold heat, As He watched by the precious ore, And
                                    closer He bent with a searching gaze As He heated it more and more. He knew He had
                                    ore that could stand the test, And He wanted the finest gold To mold as a crown for
                                    the King to wear, Set with gems of a price untold. So He laid our gold in the
                                    burning fire, Tho we fain would have said Him "Nay" And He watched the dross that we
                                    had not seen, As it melted, and passed away. And the gold grew brighter, and yet
                                    more bright, But our eyes were so dim with tears, We saw but the firenot the
                                    Master's hand, And questioned with anxious fears. Yet our gold shone out with a
                                    richer glow As it mirrored a form above, That bent o'er the fire, tho unseen by us,
                                    With looks of ineffable love. Can we think that it pleases His loving heart, To
                                    cause us a moment's pain? Ah! no, but He saw thro' the present cross The bliss of
                                    eternal gain. So He waited there with a watchful eye, With a love that is strong and
                                    sure, And our gold did not suffer a whit more heat Than was needed to make it pure.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God has so arranged the chronometry of our spirits..." TEIform="index"/>God has so arranged the chronometry of our spirits...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">God has so arranged the chronometry of our spirits that there shall be thousands of moments
                            between the striking hours.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The man who has so little knowledge..." TEIform="index"/>The man who has so little knowledge...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The man who has so little knowledge of human nature, as to seek happiness by changing
                            anything but his own disposition, will waste his life in fruitless efforts and multiply the
                            griefs which he proposes to remove.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Colton" TEIform="persName"/>Colton.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Bible is its own witness..." TEIform="index"/>The Bible is its own witness...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The Bible is its own witness. It bears its own fruits and tells its own story. The great
                            trouble with us is, we do not read this book, we do not use it, we do not understand it.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hastings, H. L" TEIform="persName"/>H. L. Hastings.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My neighbor in Christ..." TEIform="index"/>My neighbor in Christ...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">My neighbor in Christ is he to whom I minister in time of need with no thought of reward.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prouty, Harriet" TEIform="index"/>Harriet Prouty
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Harriet Prouty, at Shirley, Mass. Aug. 2, 1899. Age 88 yrs. 9 mo. and 20 days. Sister
                                Harriet had lived in the Community from childhood, and has been a faithful
                                burden-bearer. J. W.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
Do your work heartily.    "A man is relieved and gay when he has put his heart
into his work and done his best; but what
he has done or said otherwise, shall give
him no peace."    So wrote the Sage of
Concord.
Who of us has not proved the truth of
his words!   Do we shrink from our work?
Do we deem it uninsportant, and therefore
worthy to be only slightingly performed?
What a mistake we make!   What wormwood in it all. as we drag through the
allotted task; and is the result likely to
be much more gratifying than our enforced toil?
A little girl whose bugbear was washing
dishes, one evening surprised her mother,
and the family circle generally, by joining
them much earlier than was her wont.
In reply to a question concerning the supper dishes she burst forth impetuously,
"Oh, mamma! I just put my heart in it
and did it up quick, and I want you to go
out and look in the cupboard, and see if
my dishes don't shine!''    So it is in all
things, great and small.    If we put into
our work the spirit of devotion and a hearty determination to make it "shine" we
need call nothing drudgery.    So whatever
your hands find to do, do it with thy
might.Selected.

NOT   YET.
Francis Ridley Havergal.
 yet thou knowest what I do,
O feeble child of earth,
Whose life is but to angel view
The morning of thy birth!
The smallest leaf, the simplest flower,
The wild bees' honey-cell,
Have lessons of my love and power
Too hard for thee to spell.
Thou knowest not how I uphold
The little thou dost scan;
And how much less canst thou unfold
My universal plan.
Where all thy mind can grasp of space
Is but a grain of sand;
The time thy boldest thoughts can trace
One ripple on the strand!
Not yet thou knowest what I do
In this wild, warring world,
Whose prince doth still triumphant view
Confusion's flag unfurled:
Nor how each proud and daring thought
Is subject to my will,
Each strong and secret purpose brought
My counsel to fulfill.
Not yet thou knowest how I bid
Each passing hour entwine
Its grief or joy, its hope or fear,
In one great love design;
Nor how I lead thee through the night.
By many a vaiious way,
Still upward to unclouded light,
And onward to the day.
Not yet thou kuowest what I do
Within thine own weak breast,
To mold thee to my image true,
And fit thee for my rest.
But yield thee to my loving skill;
The veiled work of grace,
From day to day progressing still,
It is not thine to trace.
Yes, walk by faith and net by sight,
Fast clinging to my hand;
Content to feel my love and might,
Not yet to understand.
A little while thy course pursue,
Till grace to glory grow;
Then what I am, and what I do,
Hereafter thou shaltknow.Selected.
The Spaniards have a proverb, "The
stone fit for a wall will not lie long in the
road."    Prepare yourself for something
better, and something better will come.
The great art of success is to be so faithful
to the trusts committed to your keeping
that you make yourself a necessity in the
place you now are.     Some one will recognize your worth, if it outshine your brother, and patient perseverance in your duty
will most surely bring this about.    The
lesson which our Loid teaches us as to
higher things is applicable to our daily
pursuits, "He that hath to him shall be
given, and he shall have abundance."
Sunday at Home.
Not
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
"GENTLE   MANNERS."
A Guide to Good Morals.
Published   at  East  Canterbury,   N. H.
"Nothing on earth is more beloved and
honored in the world's great heart, than a
noble youth, whose aims are high, and
whose life is a moral essay."
Gilt edged20 cts., postage 4 cts.
Boards, 16 cts. postage 4 cts.
Paper, 10 cts. postage 2 cts.
AddressH. C. Blinn.
East Canterbury, N. H.
SHAKER HAMAMELIS
(WITCHHAZEL,)
A. remedy for Cuts, Burns, Scalds,
Headache, Sore Throat and all
oases of external inflammation
Taken internally for Bowel
Complaint, 33!eeding of the
Lungs or Bowels, and for
all aches and pains.
For use externally, bathe the parts and
lay on a cloth wet with the Extract.    Internally, take one half teaspoonful three
times a day.    Use hot or cold.
Ask your druggist for it or send your
order to Arthur Bruce,
East Canterbury, N. H.
"INTERPRETING PROPHECY"
AND THE
"Appearing of Christ,"
is the title of a neat little pamphlet of
some forty pages, just sent out by A. G.
Hollistee of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
The many at the present time who are
interested in the fulfillment of prophecy,
and in its mathematical calculation, will
find themselves by the side of the good
old prophet Daniel, and with him illustrating the Coming of Christ so clearly
that no occasion can arise for the least
doubt.                             Price, 10 cts.
50  YEARS'
EXPERIENCE
Trade Marks
Designs
. .             Copyrights &c.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain our opinion free whether an
invention is probably patentable. Communications strictly confidential. Handbook on Patents
sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice, without charge, in the
Scientific American
A handsomely illustrated weekly. Largest circulation of any scientific journal. Terms, $3 a
year; four months, $ 1.  Sold by all newsdealers.
MUNN &Go.361Broadwa>' New York
Branch Office, 625 F St., Washington, D. C.
WT5 TJ'T? t advanced thought peoplesamJ. Xulipie copy of the most original and
practical occult journal of the age.
The exponent of West Gate Philosophy.
-A. new occult system.An unlimited field of labor open to teachers, lecturers
and healers.   Address,
The ORACLE, Sta. A.    Boston, Mass.
HAVE YOU ''00MM0I SENSE?"
If not, send at once for a free copy of this
liberal-minded  advocate of advanced
thought, which brings health and
success.    Address
"Common Sense," M. O. 55 State St.
Chicago, 111.
AUTHORISED   RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY.
The religious basis of the Order must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>