<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0510" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><date value="18751001" TEIform="date">October 1875</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">73-80</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="73" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">Vol. V. No. 10. F. W. EVANS, Editor. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. Mt. Lebanon Col. Co. N.
                        Y. October, 1875 Sixty Cents per annum.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Second visit to the Eddys" TEIform="index"/>SECOND VISIT TO THE EDDYS</head><p TEIform="p">In company with two Sisters — representatives of their Order—we made, in July, a second visit
                            to " Spirit Vale " — Chittenden, Vt. We were kindly received by the Eddys, by their
                            visitors—some forty-five or fifty—and by the Spirits. We witnessed many materializations and
                            communications of Spirits. That the Mediums are true and honest in the part they act, was
                            the general verdict of those present. There was one exception — a reporter of the Boston
                            Herald — a young man, whose manner and bearing impressed all with whom he came in contact,
                            as an entirely untrustworthy describer of any thing he might see, or hear, pertaining to
                            Spiritualism. His report of the stances, each of which we witnessed, is untrue in fact and
                            egregiously wrong in spirit. And here I would make a few remarks upon unprincipled
                            Journalism. Perhaps, I cannot better illustrate than by stating, that I, as Editor of the
                            Shaker and Shakeress, am, from time to time, in receipt, from parties styling themselves "
                            Publishing Bureaus." They offer to contract to furnish any quantity of matter, from one
                            column, to a dozen, at a rate to be agreed upon. The matter to be in the form of letters or
                            communications, and upon any subject designated. Any grade of theology, or shade of
                            politics, that the Editor may desire, will be presented ! ! It is a common practice, in our
                            great cities, especially New York, for Editors to send Reporters to meetings, of different
                            kinds, to write them up or down — to represent or misrepresent their sayings, and doings,
                            just as the Journal inclines, for, or against the cause advocated, the principles
                            enunciated, or the parties engaged. When I conversed with the Herald Reporter, I had no more
                            doubt, than after reading his report, that he was hired and sent, by his employers, to
                            denounce, ridicule and utterly condemn the Spirit Vale, or Eddy materializations, regardless
                            of what might be the facts of the case. How far the poor young man is responsible for the
                            consequences of his service to his employer, I leave an open question, of little moment. But
                            what of such Journalism ? — Every new and true phase, of human progress, must pass through
                            this trying ordeal. In the end, Truth triumphs — Error, alone, is slain by such weapons. The
                            Blood of Martyrs is the seed of the Church. By the sufferings of pioneers, the soil of
                            freedom is cleared of the gigantic forests of evils, and opened to the Sun of
                        Righteousness.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In St. Louis, Aug. 10 — W. C. Clark, medium, Henry Twinkins paid fifty dollars for..." TEIform="index"/>In St. Louis, Aug. 10 — W. C. Clark, medium, Henry Twinkins paid fifty dollars for...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">In St. Louis, Aug. 10 — W. C. Clark, Medium — Henry Twinkins paid fifty dollars for liberty
                            to shoot a Materialized Spirit. The Medium directed by Mother Ann Lee to proceed to Mt.
                            Lebanon. Letter and answer next number.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ghostly stone throwing" TEIform="index"/>GHOSTLY STONE THROWING</head><p TEIform="p">The Albany Express, August 10, had an article concerning Ghosts. It states that in a neat
                            little village in Michigan, called Byran, a family of the name of Turner are stoned by
                            Ghosts. It commenced last fall, while the woman was milking, and is still in operation.
                            Stones fell several days, puzzling all searchers and inquirers, " when the neighbors came,
                            and the stones continued rapidly falling about them in their search for the person throwing
                            them." — When the snow was deep the stones still kept falling. " A thousand, or more,
                            persons have visited the place, and all are convinced that there is a Ghost in the case."
                            Does the Express remember the Stratford, Ct., excitement, of some twenty years ago ?
                            Stratford was a beautiful little village, inhabited mostly by retired D. D.'s and their
                            prosperous deacons. Their godliness had been profitable to them, in all things pertaining to
                            this life and the world that now is ; but it had net enlightened their understandings
                            relative to the world " that is to come." They had taught the people to believe, devoutly,
                            all the Bible marvels, as set forth in King James' translation — the Protestant word of God.
                            Men carried, for miles, by Spirits, who held them by the hair of their heads. Through their
                            agency, Women, past age, became happy mothers. They fed Elijah with food that lasted him
                            forty days. At his word they improvised primitive fire that burned up fifty men, and then
                            repeated it and consumed the second fifty. On another occasion they caused 80,000 Syrian
                            soldiers, in one night, to become " dead corpses." Even this was no great marvel, compared
                            with what they did in drowning all the inhabitants of Earth, except a small remnant, to
                            continue the practice of their marvels upon. Some men they made to walk upon water. Others,
                            to pass through the waters, dry shod. Three men they kept from burning, when in the midst of
                            a fiery furnace, so that their garments had not a singe upon them. When one of these same
                            men was thrown into a den of Lions, the Spirits made those Lions to be at peace with him
                            till morning. He being taken out and his enemies thrown in, they broke their bones and ate
                            them up for breakfast. Considerate and discriminating Lions!! Are our religious guides blind
                            to these and a long list of similar facts ? Have they been deceiving us for filthy lucre's
                            sake, or are they only blind to the underlying Laws — the occult forces of Nature ? Is it
                            really " like Priest, like People?" so that ghostly stories, if modern, puzzle ? Dr. Phelps'
                            son Henry, of Stamford, was a medium for ghostly stone throwing. They broke the Dr.'s
                            windows, daily, with stones. They stoned the carriage when Henry was in it, passing to the
                            neighbors. They threw stones all the way from house to house, and when he was in the house
                            they threw stones on to the roof and all around the premises. How would it work for our
                            Protestant Clergy and their people, who so freely and so fully believe the ancient records
                            of this class of marvelous facts and phenomena, upon the evidence of other people's senses,
                            to attend at Chittenden, examine, investigate and report to us, upon the evidence of their
                            own senses and upon the evidence of witnesses living there, as capable and credible as
                            themselves ? And thus teach us the scientific laws upon which those ancient facts — Bible
                            marvels — rested; that we simple people may avail ourselves of the same laws, by which to
                            explain and make plain the far more incontestable and better substantiated modern facts and
                            phenomena of our own day and time ? Or else, let us all be consistent, and reject the
                            so-called supernatural manifestations, both ancient and modern.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Catholics and protestants vs. spiritual phenomena" TEIform="index"/>CATHOLICS AND PROTESTANTS
                            VS. SPIRITUAL PHENOMENA</head><p TEIform="p">" The protestant church begins by denying their occurrence, except as examples of legerdemain
                            ; but when confronted with some peculiarly striking phenomenon, either attributes it to an
                            occult force, under control of the medium, or circle, or as a last refuge, finds a
                            satisfactory explanation in the direct interposition of the devil. The church of Rome, on
                            the other hand, admits the facts without argument, and if they happen outside her own
                            jurisdiction, passes them to the credit of Satan."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Alcott, [Dr.]" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Alcott</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jesus Christ" TEIform="index"/>JESUS CHRIST</head><p TEIform="p">If there was ever a thorough non-sectarian, that individual was Jesus. Yet this same name has
                            been misused by an almost innumerable body of sectarians, as the corner-stone of peculiar
                            dogmas, each crying " Lo, here is Christ!" and declaiming with as strong vehemence, and much
                            unchristian grace, against all differing, yet neighboring persuasions. To be " evangelical
                            always, sectarian never," is " the blest tie that binds our hearts in Christian love."
                            Herein is the true life-line of conduct by which we may all be " made fishers of men," for
                            their salvation. That the gospel of Christ " is the power of God, unto an increasing
                            salvation," there is no room for doubting, in the minds of any truly consecrated Christian.
                            Christ came upon the earth to lay down and leave a rule of life that would save men before
                            they died; to relieve all from becoming " dead in trespasses and sins." This rule of life is
                            not an arbitrary commandment to any, but a loving invitation to all, to live as Jesus lived.
                            In the simplest and most affectionate <pb n="74" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 74: SHAKER terms does Jesus
                            address all: "If any one would be my disciple, let him live as I do ;" which, being
                            continued or transposed, teaches us simply that if we do not live as Jesus lived, we cannot
                            be his disciples — cannot be rewarded as hiu disciples are and will be. Nowhere do we find
                            the good man, Jesus, enunciating anathemas because men chose not to follow in his footsteps.
                            He sorrowed for them ; he prayed for them ; he died, and more, he lived for their conviction
                            and conversion. But he never needed to send apostates to the punishments of endless
                            torments, for he well knew that with their light becoming darkness they had hell enough
                            already. He was " lifted up," a character purer, better, more lovely in every sense than
                            aught on earth ; and by this elevation he " would draw all .men unto " the principles he
                            loved and practiced. If we ever become like him, it will be by persuasion, conversion ;
                            never by compulsion. Who can read a certain sentence in Christian at Work for October 29,
                            under head of "At the Confessional," without the conviction that we have in it the boiling
                            down of multitudes of arguments for Christ-—the whole rule of life for a Christian, printed
                            in five lines t Remembering that any other sect might, with the same propriety, displace "
                            Episcopalians," editor Talmage writes those words that can never die : "Episcopalians are to
                            learn * * * and not forget that those who are living the Christ life on earth, under
                            whatever denominational banner, are all one Church — all one under their glorious Head!"
                            Here we have the gospel in so simple and plain language that " he who runs may read," and
                            none need be mistaken. To live the Christ life here on the earth is the resurrection most
                            desirable ; because, by this rising up out of ourselves and donning the character of him who
                            died daily unto sin, we have a perfect example, the results of which accrue to us the
                            hundred fold of heavenly blessings, heaped up and running over with the life that is eternal
                            today. If all should live the life of Christ, as did Jesus, would they not already be in
                            possession of the eternal life promised ? And wherein did Jesus ever die, but unto a worldly
                            life ? True, he was crucified, and passed beyond ; but that was not death to him. So, if we
                            will live the Christ life, we shall never die, except unto the world, with all its
                            affections and lusts. " Evangelical always," we shall want to live the Christ life, and then
                            teach it. " Sectarian never," we shall care not by what name a brother or sister is called ;
                            the only question we need ask is, Do you love and live the Christ life?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. Lomas, Watervliet, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Second appearing of Christ, order of its increase" TEIform="index"/>SECOND APPEARING OF
                            CHRIST, ORDER OF ITS INCREASE</head><p TEIform="p">In the First Appearing the following facts were manifested: First, a virgin life ; Second,
                            goods in common; Third, non-resistance; Fourth, separation from the world. Observe how these
                            testimonies refer themselves to the life and teachings of the man of Nazareth 1st, " He who
                            looketh on a woman to lust after her hath committed adultery." " Blessed are the pure in
                            heart." And the example of his life. 2nd, Jesus and his disciples had goods in common. 3d,
                            Non-resistance, V My kingdom is not of this world, if it were, then would my servants
                            fight." When one who was with Jesus smote off the ear of one of those who came to take him,
                            he healed the ear, and said, " Put up thy sword within it sheath," etc. Again, when asked if
                            fire might not be called down and consume his enemies he said, " Ye know not what manner of
                            spirit ye are of." Lastly, when he had gathered a few under the shadow of his spirit, he
                            said "Ye are not of the world, even as I am not.' Note A. The primitive church followed in
                            the same line, a virgin life, goods in common separation from the world, and non-resistance
                            Some of the early Christians suffered death rather than bear arms. We see that the con
                            ditions of a sinless life in the First Appear ance, were purity of thought and person. No
                            selfish interests. Non-assimilation with the world, and an attitude of peace toward all men.
                            All who abode in the teachings of the Apostles embodied the foregoing testimonies. After a
                            lapse of time, the gentile Christians, composed of married people, carnal Corinthians, etc.,
                            overshadowed the primitive church, and trod it under foot. Finally, nothing remained as a
                            whole, of these cardinal testimonies. This state of things remained during the dark ages,
                            and for more than a hundred years after the Reformation. The Puritans, the Non-conformists,
                            the Covenanters, the Quakers and the French Prophets, prepared the way for the Second
                            Appearing of Christ. Ann Lee embodied in herself, as did Jesus, the foregoing testimonies.
                            And the Shaker church is a living transcript of the Primitive church, on a broader
                            foundation. It includes the woman as an integral part in government, and in procedure. The
                            Shaker church, its homes and property, are open to all who will embody, in themselves,
                            purity of thought, devotion to the body of Christ (not to self), nonassimilation with the
                            world, and the spirit of peace. The lust of the flesh is chief of the propensities. The
                            Shakers, of to-day, freely declare, that not a single animal propensity can have a place in
                            heaven; the products of the propensities — flesh and blood — cannot go there. Hence, the
                            order of the increase, in the Second Appearing, will be in the line of giving no place to
                            any propensity. The lust of eating is nearly allied to the lust of the flesh, feeds its
                            fires, and is prone to unfit the body for the in-dwelling of the Holy Spirit. This lust,
                            when indulged, creates disease, bodily inefficiency, and premature decay. The signs of the
                            times in and out of the Shaker church, point to this lust as the next in order to be dealt
                            with, not smoothly, and fearfully, and very gently, brt that each one, him and her, grapple
                            with it, put it in its place, and so render the digestive functions subservient to health,
                            strength and purity of life. There is no need of sin; neither is there any need of sickness.
                            Put them both away. The more advanced, outside of the Shaker church, advise the use of
                            unbolted flour and the fruits in their season, in preference to much animal food. The more
                            advanced, inside, testify, that over-eating, and all animal foods, oysters, etc., stimulate
                            the lust of the flesh, and ought to be discontinued in the Church of Christ. Killing animals
                            for food, violates the higher instincts of our being, hardens and petrifies the feelings,
                            and is so repulsive, that it is a hard matter to find a Shaker brother willing to butcher
                            animals. The use of superfine flour is a great waste, and directly contrary to the
                            injunction " Gather up the fragments that nothing be lost." It is deficient in brain or
                            nerve food, and when combined with saleratus or soda, the case is aggravated. The chemicals
                            impart to the tissues placidity, and are, no doubt, a predisposing cause to a softening of
                            the brain ; and of course to insanity. When the cooks get up a dish of superfine flourbread
                            toast, just think of this. The prevailing debility, and all the disorders of the digestive
                            organs refer themselves to improper food, over-eating, and to bad air. Flesh meats, butter,
                            milk, pastry, etc., at one meal, are all together out of place. Live to be well,and not for
                            indulgence. Let each one, according to his or her calling, be a power for good in this
                            direction. There is such a thing, at all times, as the patience of the saints. All true
                            progress in this, or in any other direction, will consolidate existing order. " I am the
                            vine, ye are the branches." It is the function of the branches to show growth — to progress
                            to more light. It is the function of the trunk to consolidate the eliminated products of
                            growth. So in the Church of Christ, the novitiate orders will be the first to show growth ;
                            that is, if they are good for any thing; and when the crudities of that growth are
                            eliminated, let the choicest atoms be consolidated into the appropriate orders. The branches
                            cannot bear fruit of themselves; the leaves cannot be the roots. The order of divine life
                            cannot be less perfect than plant life. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Fraser, Shirley, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Berlin, New Jersey, January 26, 1875" TEIform="index"/>Berlin, N. J., Jan. 26th, 1875</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Friend Evans: — For several years past I have desired to write an article for the Shaker
                            and Shakeress, on the position of Christ in relation to war, but you have so many better
                            writers within your own society, I have thought you would not care about communications from
                            so imperfect an outsider as myself, I will however, send you a few lines and you can do with
                            them as you think best. During the late terrible war, nearly all the ministers in this
                            nation, preached war as a Christian duty. Their texts were always tfie words of Christ,
                            where he commanded his disciples to take swords. Had they understood the true meaning of
                            that command, instead of its favoring war it would have been a most emphatic and decided
                            testimony against war. When he sent forth his apostles to preach, he commanded them to take
                            neither gold, silver, brass, purse or scrip, nor two coats apiece, and at the same time told
                            them he sent them even as sheep among wolves, and that they should have power over all
                            devils. Now, if swords are necessary for protection, by whom could they be needed more than
                            by people who go, as sheep, in the midst of wolves ? If Christ believed in war, why did he
                            not arm them then ? What was the sequel ? Why, they went forth as he had commanded, and a
                            divine power went with them and opened the hearts of certain classes to supply their wants,
                            and the same divine power restrained the wolves, their enemies, so that no one could lay
                            hands on them. They needed no swords, though like sheep among wolves, for the Lord God of
                            Hosts was as a wall of fire round about them. When they returned he said unto them, Lacked
                            ye any thing ? and they replied: No, nothing. He said to them, Take swords, and he that hath
                            no sword, let him sell his coat and buy one. They answered; here are two, and he told them
                            they were enough. If his intention was to fight, would he have expected to conquer all that
                            would come against him, with two swords ? Nay, verily. He had no intention of fighting. The
                            same scripture declares that he knew his hour had come. Why then did he want swords ? For
                            the purpose of bearing a final and decisive testimony against war, by showing that though
                            armed he would not permit his disciples to fight. If his disciples had no swords, people
                            might have questioned whether he would not have fought if he had been armed. But having
                            swords and forbidding his disciples to use them, even to save his own life, was a testimony
                            that none need doubt nor mistake. Yet the blind leaders of the blind, who with their
                            followers are all wallowing in the filth of their own lusts, have taken this last testimony,
                            of Christ against war, plain and simple as it is and made it mean just the opposite of what
                            Christ intended, so that in the late war were seen people who professed to be the followers
                            of the Prince of Peace, mangling and destroying each other. Orthodox arrayed against
                            Orthodox, Methodists against Methodists, and so on through a hundred different sects, all
                            arrayed against each other, all praying to the same imaginary War Demon for success, against
                            each other, while priests all over the nation were shouting, " Christ commanded his
                            disciples to take swords, and therefore it is the duty of Christians to mangle and kill
                            thoee who never harmed them, at the beck of ungodly demagogues, to preserve a Union that
                            each generation has a right to dissolve ! Your Friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hacker, J." TEIform="persName"/>J. Hacker</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Friend Hacker is right—and wrong..." TEIform="index"/>Friend Hacker is right—and wrong...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Friend Hacker is right—and wrong—right, in his idea that war is wrong — wrong, in his idea
                            that Jesus and the apostles were infallible in judgment, perfect in knowledge, and that the
                            Protestant Bible is the word of God, a finality. Jesus and the apostles were all born Jews—
                            born of Jewish women, and educated, by them, under the Mosaic Law, and traditions then
                            existing. John, the Baptist, and his disciples had a similar schooling. Jesus was over
                            thirty, when he began a new departure, under influences, coming from far above all heavens
                            ever known to the Jews, j^njd <pb n="75" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> and from spheres into which David had not
                            yet ascended. Tilton has borne strong testimony to the fact, that early imbibed theological
                            ideas have a tremendous power of cohesion with the soul. Jesus and his disciples, like Ann
                            Lee and her disciples, were converts to the missionary labors of the Christ-spirit, who came
                            to introduce, to humanity, a New Order — the Resurrection. By the Law, was the knowledge of
                            the sins of the flesh, in the marriage relation. It taught use, not indulgence, of the
                            reproductive forces. Under that Law, Jesus and his disciples could attend weddings. In
                            Christ, they ceased to marry, and to attend marriages. They neither bought nor sold private
                            property. If they used war power, in the Temple, it was while under the inspiration of the
                            God of the House, for the purpose of restoring that House to its normal condition, as a
                            Jewish Temple. There was no Christianity about the Temple, nor any Christian service
                            performed therein. The Christ spirits impressed Jesus that he had been transgressing. Calvin
                            Green, a deeply-inspired man, claimed that Jesus, himself, put the sword into the hands of
                            the Jews, by which they took his life. Is it not quite as simple to admit, that when Jesus
                            and his disciples armed themselves with two swords, they anticipated spirit assistance,
                            similar to what they received when clearing the Temple ? that the Christ-spirit withdrew
                            from them? Hence the exclamation. " My God, my God, why hast Thou forsaken me 1 ! ! " This
                            accords with the present light of the writer of this article, for which none other is
                            responsible, accountable, or accusable.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cutting off and putting on" TEIform="index"/>CUTTING OFF AND PUTTING ON</head><p TEIform="p">Did Jesus ever travail beyond that mixed condition ? Was it one of the cases wherein he
                            learned obedience, to the Christ-spirit, by what he suffered — for what he had done, or
                            allowed to be done, under the impulse of his Jewish proclivities ? Did not Ann Lee
                            illustrate the same forces, while travailing out of her inherited and acquired Gentileism 1
                            Did putting on the ear, by a Gift of healing, under the law of materialization, prove both
                            the War and the Peace principles to be of the Christ-spirit? Or was War Jewish, and Peace
                            Christian? Is it advisable to thus blow hot and cold with the same breath ? Babylon means
                            mixture. Was not the whole transaction of that character ? Would any of us be willing to
                            have any one man cut off our ear, or nose, for the sake of letting some other man replace
                            it, by supernatural agency ? If right to put the ear on, was it right to cut it off ? Or had
                            Jesus missed the mark, when he gave his disciples liberty to possess themselves of swords —
                            carnal weapons ? They not only had arms, like soldiers, but used them. As a natural man,
                            history furnishes none more perfect, in generation, than Jesus. Ann Lee, in relation to war,
                            was, in testimony and practice, equally perfect. The council of Peace is betwixt them both.
                            Neither, without the other, is complete — for it is not good for man to be alone — and vice
                            versa. After the experience of many centuries, with the reflection that comes of leisure,
                            Jesus may have helped Ann, in her travail. She affirms that he walked and talked with her in
                            the Spirit World. May we not be pardoned, should we presume to think that the twelve
                            Apostles, as they sit upon their twelve thrones, judging the twelve tribes of Israel, look
                            down upon the world of Gentile Christianity, and judge the great, bloody Whore ? All
                            Religious Organizations that preach peace and practice war, outside of their organizations,
                            and, to this day, maintain the Inquisition, in some of its hydraheaded forms, inside of
                            every religious institution in Christendom. Babylon Christians, who worship Jesus as God,
                            justify marriage, and hold it a Sacrament, because Jesus attended a wedding. And they
                            equally justify war, because his disciples had war weapons, up to the time of his final
                            arrest by the Romans. Why is the Testimony of Christ's Second Appearing superior to the
                            First? Is it not because more perfect in separating the chaff from the wheat — the false
                            from the true — the flesh from the Spirit ?</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New Enfield, New Hampshire, December 25, 1874" TEIform="index"/>New Enfield, N. H., December
                            25,1874</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Elder Frederick :—On this Christmas day, I feel in duty bound, in profound respect, to
                            express my gratitude to you, believing you a true Prophet and radical Reformer of Reforms —
                            removing the rubbish and superstition of by-gone ages — clearing and preparing the way for a
                            new structure, both in physical and spiritual philosophy. I go with you, heart and hand, as
                            far as I comprehend your logic. Your ideas of Jesus of Nazareth, as given, from time to
                            time, agree with my perceptions of right — also the Thunders, uttering their voices.
                            Testimonies against divers evils. I'm glad the " Old Dams " are giving way, to make room for
                            something better. I love the Shaker and Shakeress. It affords me much satisfaction. Above
                            all other things, I desire a pure heart and clear understanding of spiritual things. The
                            work of God is moving swiftly. Quite a number are gathering here. I am thankful for the "
                            Seven Thunders that are uttering their voices." Am glad that some are privileged to hear,
                            understand and obey, as far as I have. I can say, with you, " It comforts my spirit to see
                            the young men and women coming up to the help of the Lord, against the mighty influences of
                            evil." You have fought the good fight, and kept the living faith, in your own soul, and in
                            the souls of many others. The " Second Thunder" is roaring in the heavens. The old
                            Theological Dams are giving way. The stagnant waters are being stirred, as never before. I
                            am thankful for all the self-denial I have practiced in eating and drinking. I have born my
                            cross, against flesh meats, more than twenty years. Since I came here, I have been as strict
                            a vegetarian as ever before, and am enjoying comfortable health. It is a general time of
                            health here. We, Shakers, have many things to learn of the Jews — and Jews have many things
                            to learn of Shakers. I claim the right to think — to reason — the right of conscience. I
                            claim that Woman is the equal of Man—possessing the same rights —and that the Land belongs,
                            by inalienable right, to the Race — not to individuals. When I first heard of man's taking
                            possession of a tract of land, calling it his own and selling it at a high price, I was
                            surprised. When quite young, I considered it unjust, for a Lawyer, or Doctor, to charge a
                            poor man $5 for five minutes' service. I never have courted opposition, nor persecution. May
                            have been too silent to such wrongs. I have stood still to see the Salvation of God. I may
                            have stood still altogether too long. I perceive there are physical, as well as theological
                            errors, not only in the natural, but in the Spiritual Orders. He, that iterates, and
                            reiterates them, is not an enemy, but a friend — even as Truth is our friend. Elders Abram
                            and Orvil wish me to send their Love. Accept my Love and Blessing, for yourself and all your
                            Family.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hayden, Clark" TEIform="persName"/>Clark Hayden</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Election, temperance, land" TEIform="index"/>ELECTION, TEMPERANCE, LAND</head><p TEIform="p">Eternal, abiding and unchanging law: Truth is the only fore-ordination that ever was or ever
                            will be. We are nominated and drawn by the Father, but our election depends on the Mother,
                            in the tangible form of works; deeds of holiness and righteousness qualified by temperance.
                            Under the law the heirs of temperance are promoted to honor and trust, to office and to the
                            teaching, with grace and truth, gifts of the spirit, healing, speaking in unknown tongues,
                            etc. So far the " Shakers " have done well in fulfilling the law of Moses and the teaching
                            of Christ, relative to marriage, duty to God, duty to our fellow creatures, abstinence from
                            strong drink, swine's flesh, etc. In the primitive, or Father's adopted Church, a wife was
                            permitted. The permission lasted unto the setting up of the Mother Church. The ax hath been
                            used for all advances in progression. It has lopped off, in that Church, husband and wife,
                            strong drink, swine's flesh. The ax will be wielded further. All permissions must run out.
                            Offenses must cease in proportion to Church progress.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Poetic" TEIform="index"/>POETIC</head><p TEIform="p">Wine is a mocker of pleasure and health, Money a mocker of treasure and wealth. Parties for
                            gain are easy to make, But all selfish cords, they are easy to break. The vows of its
                            colleagues it often betrays, Like unto the serpent it hath crooked ways, And however proper
                            the aim for its use, It seems as though doomed to a constant abuse. It, like the future,
                            will bring on a day When bartering will be the unfaltering way. Flesh-meat is a mocker of
                            pure nature's plan, The soil of the clamorous woman and man ; The soil for disquiet, for
                            those not above it, And every base passion, and all who do covet; A soil, void of mercy,
                            where cruelty reigns And bindeth its subjects in pernicious chains. Without good, hand labor
                            to baffle its might, All peace, love and quiet will flee out of sight. As demoniac food, it
                            carries its laws, Demoniac labor, effect of its cause — Tobacco, it mocketh at virtue's
                            promotion, It stifles the voice in heart-pure devotion. The subordinate coffee and tea, with
                            the rest, Are mockers of need, and of comfort at best. Other " parties" of these, below and
                            above, Are mockers in deed of impartial love. The purchase of land for mere love of gain, Is
                            mocking the prudent, the wise and the sane. The monopolizer enjoyeth not worth, The " meek,"
                            it is said " shall inherit the earth." Of what mood or manner of spirit we are, It is good
                            to be mindful in hours of prayer. Our needs they are simple, are cheap and all plain,
                            Requiring no extra of labor or pain. The lusts of the eye make us strive to acquire — The
                            more thatwe gain the more we desire. Let us strive for that food which does satisfy, The
                            food of the Angels that comes from on high.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barnett, J." TEIform="persName"/>J. Barnett, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Aversion to manual labor" TEIform="index"/>AVERSION TO MANUAL LABOR</head><p TEIform="p">The practice of educating boys for the professions, which are already overstocked, or for the
                            mercantile business, in wliich statistics show that ninety-five in a hundred fail of
                            success, is fearfully on the increase In this country. Americans are annually becoming more
                            and more averse to'manual labor; and to get a living by one's wits, even at the cost of
                            independence and self-respect, and a fearfui wear and tear of conscience, is the ambition of
                            a large proportion of our young men. The result is, that the mechanical professions are
                            becoming a monopoly of foreigners, and the ownership of the finest farms, even in New
                            England, is passing from Americans to Irishmen and Germans. Fifty years ago a father was not
                            ashamed to put his children to the plow or to a mechanical trade; but now they are too
                            feeble " for bodily labor, one has a pain in his side, another a slight cough, another " a
                            very delicate constitution," another is nervous, and so poor Bobby, or Billy, or Tommy is
                            sent off to the city to measure tape, weigh coffee, or draw molasses. It seems never to
                            occur to their foolish parents that moderate manual labor in the pure and bracing air of the
                            country is just what these puny, wasp-waisted lads need, and that to send them to the
                            crowded and unhealthy city is to send them to their graves. Let them follow the plow, swing
                            the sledge, or shove the foreplane, and their pinched chests will be expanded, their sunken
                            cheeks plumped out, and their Iung3, now "cabined, cribbed and confined," will have room to
                            play. Their nerves will be invigorated with their muscles; and when they shall have cast off
                            their jackets, instead of being thin, pale, vapid coxcombs, they shall have spread out to
                            the size and configuration of men. A lawyer's office, a counting room, or a grocery is about
                            the last place to which a sickly youth should be sent.—Colorado Republican.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cost of the late war" TEIform="index"/>Cost of the late War.</head><p TEIform="p">Mb. David A. Wells has furnished the Cobden Club of England with an essay upon the expenses,
                            income and taxes of the United States. We copy the following statement of the cost of the
                            Rebellion : The whole cost of the war to the Northern and Southern States from 1861 to 1866
                            is estimated as follows: Lives, $1,000,000; property, by destruction, waste, etc.,
                            $9,000,000,000. The gross expenditures of the United States from June, 1861, to July, 1866,
                            $5,792,257,000. Of this the actual expenses were about $5,342,237,000.</p></div2><pb n="76" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Covetousness" TEIform="index"/>COVETOUSNESS</head><p TEIform="p">Covetousness is idolatry. How men bow down and worship mammon, the god of the world. When
                            this spirit is allowed to grow, and is cultivated, and remains unchecked, how sad, how
                            blighting its effects. Look at the man who has piled up his millions, is he happy ? Is he
                            satisfied ? Nay, nay. The spirit of greed has grown with his growth, and strengthened with
                            his strength ; dried up every spring of benevolence and kindness in his heart, and holds him
                            with an iron grasp. He is blind, foolish, and infatuated with madness. Perhaps he is an old
                            man, just standing upon the edge of the grave, all his hopes, desires, affections and
                            aspirations, buried in a little lump of earth. See him ! bent with age, bent still worse
                            earthward with the spirit of base, sensual, covetous desire. All the rich treasures of
                            Heaven, just above him,but he knows it not. He is a stranger to the Christian's peace, and
                            the delightful ministration of angels. They have no communion with him. When he dies, a dark
                            cloud settles over him, and he takes a " leap in the dark," unattended by any escort, except
                            it be from spirits like himself, whose society will only increase his misery. Well might the
                            poet say : 11 Though a broad stream of golden sands, Through all his meadows roll, He s but
                            a wretch ; with all his lands, Who wears a narrow soul." Let the youth beware of
                            covetousness ; nip this spirit in the bud. Be moderate in all your earthly desires. Be
                            thankful if surrounded with those who are trying by precept and example to inspire in you
                            the beauty of a truly noble, pure and unselfish life. Keep the window of your soul wide open
                            on the sunny side of Heaven. Think how many more blessings you have than many others, and
                            more than you deserve. Rejoice when you see others receiving attention, or enjoying favors
                            which you do not possess. Strive to make others happy, and in this way you will be gathering
                            good to yourself, and sowing seed which will produce a harvest of everlasting joy.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hubbell, Gilbert" TEIform="persName"/>Gilbert Hubbell, Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Old age" TEIform="index"/>OLD AGE</head><p TEIform="p">How rare to see truly happy and venerable old age ! Why is it so ? Life means progress and
                            evolution. If Immortality have sense or meaning, it must mean Advance movement from lower to
                            higher — progress in truth and light — stripping off shackles of ignorance and prejudice —
                            delivering the spiritual nature of man from the bondage of the low animal nature—unveiling
                            new truths — enabling the soul to grow into angelic condition, that it may see God and live
                            in him. Let this course be pursued, and the more we increase in years the better we will
                            learn our lesson, know our duty and do it — the more ready will we be to give up bad habits
                            and learn good ones — the more easy to practice self-denial — to leave behind what is low
                            and earthly, and grow into the Divine and Heavenly. To refuse or neglect this our high
                            vocation, to shrink at a little matter of cross, would be to pawn, with faint hope of
                            redemption, our heavenly birth-right for a most miserable kind of pottage. Do we realize
                            this ? I will labor with all earnestness, that as I advance in years I may advance in true
                            spiritual life and power, that with increase of years the cross against lower law influences
                            will be correspondingly lighter. Would any of you, my dear Gospel Sisiers and Brothers,
                            relinquish your right to personal immortality, to the joys of higher worlds ? I will not.
                            Let us all be nice and clean and sweet, and see to it that neither that which goeth in at
                            the mouth nor that which cometh out defiles the Temple of God. Let us look a little deeper —
                            not neglecting vigilance in meats and drinks, using only such as conduce to purity of body
                            and soul—let us look into the think, and see what is harbored there. Are thoughts admitted
                            there that would not ldok well printed in large capitals and pasted on the outside ? Know we
                            not that we are the Temple of God? Know we not that impure thoughts defile the temple quite
                            as much as superfine flour, alcohol, tea, coffee, drugs, or the dead carcasses of oxen,
                            sheep or swine? What the prospects of such as defile the Temple of God ? Let us drop the
                            curtain.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Assman, Julius" TEIform="persName"/>Julius Assman, Canaan, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Black quakers" TEIform="index"/>BLACK QUAKERS</head><p TEIform="p">We have been permitted to make another extract from an unpublished work of travels in Central
                            Africa. On the north branch of the Gonii river in a secluded country we found a colony of
                            Quakers or friends. They were a very isolated people, having little intercourse with the
                            tribes around them. They used the plain language and never resorted to arms, being
                            non-resistants. In their government they had very admirable police arrangements. The force
                            was composed of strong athletic men and women, who used no weapons but acted the part of
                            care-takers of the insane. These people believed that any one who violated the rights of
                            others or committed any crime was of unsound mind and to a certain extent insane, and it was
                            considered to be a duty to restrain these until they gave evidence of restoration to health.
                            They denied that there was any right to punish any one, the law carrying its penalties with
                            it, and the compunction of conscience being greater where human authority did not interfere
                            and attempt to punish. They claimed the right and the power to restrain any person who acted
                            in a manner that was injurious to themselves or to others. They used just sufficient
                            restraint to prevent this, and in doing this they were always very careful to avoid any
                            appearance of vindictive feelings or punishment toward those on whom it was used. Their
                            police arrangements worked so quietly that one would scarcely know of its existence, great
                            care was taken to avoid any public manifestations, under the belief that they were not
                            beneficial to society, and they kept all such things sacredly quiet, and persons were often
                            restrained for a time, and came forth without its being known to any except those who had
                            kindly cared for them. In their dealings with one another they were strictly honest,
                            preferring each other in all things. Their mode of worship was like that of the friends in
                            civilized countries. They came together every day in a social manner, and sat in silent
                            meditation until some one, either man, or woman, or child, was moved to speak. There was a
                            solemn dignity about their meetings, which was felt by all. The remarks of the young
                            children even, were often very feeling and impressive. Their meeting closed with social
                            greetings, conversation and gymnastic exercises. They claimed to be influenced directly by
                            the Holy Spirit. Their religious views were very plain and simple, always avoiding
                            unpleasant controversies. There was a general feeling of love, and forbearance prevailed.
                            They believed in one God, the great central ruling power of the universe and the Holy Spirit
                            which they believe was sent by God to comfort them and enlighten them in their every-day
                            duties. They carried their religion into all departments of life, and had no observance of
                            days and times; believing all days to be alike holy, they did not set apart one day in seven
                            as is done by most religious denominations. They considered oaths as an abomination, and
                            held that every person was sacredly bound to speak the truth at all times and under all
                            circumstances, and hence had no idea of going through any form to make a person, under
                            special conditions, tell the truth ; for, said they, this would be an admission that they
                            might tell falsehoods all the rest of the time. They were exceedingly plain and exemplary in
                            regard to their dress, while all were left free. The rule generally adopted was economy,
                            utility and comfort. There was no rigid rule confining any one to a particular form or
                            color; each one was left to follow their taste and inclinations. There was a great deal of
                            freedom and sociability among them ; living pure lives, their intercourse was free and
                            without any suspicion, and hence they were a very happy people. Individual conscience was
                            respected always as the real standard, and each one was left free to act according to their
                            highest and best impressions and the dictates of their consciences, with no other restraint
                            than those we have referred to in regard to the rights of others and injury to themselves.
                            Their form of government was very simple. Bach individual being a law unto themselves there
                            was very little need of any external laws. Their education was universal, and by common
                            consent all children were sent to school, the boys and girls together, and they were taught
                            such branches of knowledge as were calculated to strengthen and develop their minds, while
                            the physical was also properly attended to. This spirit of equality, based upon capacity,
                            was carried out in all departments, and woman stood side by side with man, a participant in
                            all things according to capacity. No arbitrary standard of equality was professed, but the
                            divine equality of right measured by capacity alone, was the standard universally accepted.
                            Though they were a simple minded people, they were not devoid of artistic taste in their
                            houses and in the laying out and cultivation of their gardens. The country, being a very
                            fertile one, produced spontaneously almost every thing that was needed for their
                            subsistence. Yet, unlike most persons who live in such countries, they were an industrious
                            people, having an innate sense of the necessity of working in natural things in order to
                            develop their own powers. There were no very wealthy persons and no poor. They were not
                            allowed to hold any more land than they could properly cultivate, and their habits were such
                            that avarice was not at all fostered in any one, and any manifestation of it was considered
                            an evidence of unsoundness of mind and a subject for moral restraint first, and if it did
                            not stop with this, the restraint was carried further. The purity of their lives, the
                            freedom of their intercourse, and the happy relations they sustained to each other in their
                            families and as a community, presented features which we had never witnessed in any other
                            country. We asked some of them why they did not mingle with other tribes; they remarked that
                            they had not found any other people who were willing to live as they did, and therefore it
                            seemed best to them to keep their community isolated, and the tribes around had not yet
                            attained to a position to comprehend and live out the principles which they felt called upon
                            to manifest in their lives to the world. Their idea was, that they were descendants of two
                            families of very good men and women, who settled in that country many years ago.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sow well—reap well" TEIform="index"/>SOW WELL—REAP WELL</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Youth in Zion : There is no greater fallacy than that entertained by many of your
                            class, that they can obtain real happiness in a way suited to their worldly desires. This "
                            Philosopher's stone" can never be found, and all who spend their lives in search of it will
                            be disappointed and ruined. It is folly, 0, youth, to think that you can form vicious
                            habits, and, on arriving at maturity, cast them off as easily as you can change your
                            garments! God never fails to reward good and punish evil deeds, and the law of God is, you
                            shall reap that which you sow; that, and not something else ! If you will sow " wild oats,"
                            depend upon it the result of your folly will be a fearful harvest of vices ! If you give
                            loose rein to sinful practices, deplorable consequences must and will follow! You cannot
                            avert them. If you sow to the flesh, of the flesh you will reap corruption! Loss of peace,
                            loss of happiness, disappointment and shame to yourselves; these are the bitter fruits of a
                            sinful life. Let this truth always be remembered; the prize of salvation is not obtained
                            without personal exertion ; if you desire it, it may be yours, but only by earnest,
                            persevering effort in self-denial, while beset with difficulties of every kind. Hence,
                            should any of you be debating, in your minds, a change of profession, thinking that you may
                            have a " genius " for some other mode of life, hoping to find salvation by " climbing up
                            some other way," dismiss the thought at once, as a temptation of Satan to do evil. If your
                            trials and temptations are great while bearing the cross, do not make them greater by
                            deserting it, but spend all* your energies in clinging to it as the life-boat that sustains
                            you on the ocean of time. If you leave it, it is certain you will go down ; you will be
                            lost! But if you bend every energy to the self-denying work, your love for your profession
                            will increase, and, ultimately, victory will crown your efforts; you will safely outride
                            every storm on the rough sea of nature, and arrive secure in the haven of eternal rest,
                            cheered and directed by " the star of purity."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Anger" TEIform="index"/>Anger.</head><p TEIform="p">Never speak in anger, however much cause you may imagine you have for so doing ; as you not
                            only lower yourself in the esteem of others, but lose your own self-respect, and
                            consequently your confidence; and you cannot hold up your head with that manly or womanly
                            dignity that you might have done had you governed your passion. " He that is slow to anger,
                            is better than the mighty; and he that ruleth his -spirit, than he that taketh a city."</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A pure life is strength from on high, the enactor of it can speak with authority" TEIform="index"/>A pure life is strength from on high, the enactor of it can speak with authority
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A pure life is strength from on high, the enactor of it can speak with authority.</p></div2><pb n="77" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: 'the poor man cried and the lord heard him,' Isa" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: "THE
                            POOR MAN CRIED AND THE LORD HEARD HIM," ISA.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">We live in an age of profound thought and deliberation. In society at large great inequality
                            exists — riches and poverty abound to an alarming extent. The toiling millions who spend
                            their energies in rearing magnificent mansions for the capitalists to luxuriate in, while
                            tliey dwell in rude cottages, and subsist on scanty allowance of food and deficient
                            clothing, feel sorely oppressed; and they dream of a better state of things in a day which
                            they believe will dawn upon them in the future. When they read the avowal of the Founders of
                            the American government, that " All men are created free and equal," they keenly feel the
                            injustice of the state of society as it now exists. Thousands are heard to say that a
                            Christianity that does not take into account, and provide for the physical, as well as the
                            spiritual needs of its subjects, is spurious — wanting in essence and vital energy. The
                            public mind has conceived the idea that somehow, through the communistic principle, a true
                            Brotherhood is the possibility of the race. Although it is divided in opinion as to the most
                            sure method of attaining that desired object, whether to work from a rational, socialistic
                            and benevolent basis, or to combine the material, intellectual and spiritual, in one grand
                            system that represents, comprehends, and supplies, the entire needs of the whole man and
                            woman. The late Horace Greeley, an acknowledged philanthropist, who gave his thoughts and
                            life labors in a large degree to benefit and uplift human society from oppression and want,
                            irrespective of their religious creeds or professions, wrote thus: " Christ never intended
                            that of his disciples a few should enjoy every costly luxury which imagination could
                            suggest, while millions famished and shivered, wanting the veriest necessaries of life.* * *
                            " Man is fallen and is divided ; he must be raised and re-united. Darkened in under
                            standing, and made gross by sensuality, he needs to be taught his first duty to his brother.
                            ' Thou shalt love thy neighbor as thyself.' How read you this, ye upholders of War, Slavery,
                            and that Social Order which leaves millions to grow up in Ignorance, Want and Temptation ;
                            which provides prisons for the guilty, and poor-houses for the helpless and Starving, but
                            makes no provision that the still innocent and nobly striving, shall have Opportunity to
                            earn needful Bread ? " Tell me not this is Christian Society, in which the widow sits
                            toiling from dawn till midnight, consuming her slender remnant of health and vision, to earn
                            of her sister, in the Church, the smallest modicum of food and shelter with which her tender
                            babes can exist. The frightful excess of Social anarchy, misery, and destitution, in the
                            midst of the most abundant wealth and prodigality the world has ever known, is driving
                            millions to inquiry and study with regard to their causes and their cure. Division,
                            Alienation, Isolation, are the bane of our Race." Were truer words ever spoken or written
                            than those ? We honor Horace Greeley for his efforts to roll forward the car of human
                            progress. He was the poor man's friend. He felt the throbbings of the great heart of
                            humanity, and his soul was moved with compassion, while he sought to understand the
                            producing causes of individual and society wrongs, and if possible to find and point out a
                            remedy. He was evidently a man of high culture, possessed strong intellectual powers, and
                            his reason and conscience were in harmony. And we would bestow "honor where honor is due."
                            We highly appreciate, and honor all honest laborers in the field of reform, who give their
                            time and talents, to lessen human woe ; and set up way marks to guide the rising and
                            incoming generations, in paths of virtue and integrity. " All men are created free and
                            equal," says the Declaration of American Independence. That must be accepted in a qualified
                            sense. We cannot say truthfully, that all are equal in physical strength nor in intellectual
                            powers; but all have a right to life, and to sufficient means to sustain life. There is a
                            great variety of intellect and capacity in the human family adapted to meet the varied
                            conditions in society ; and that diversity, if rightly used, and not abused, is a blessing.
                            The head of any body of people, either religious, civil, or social, should never oppress any
                            of the members pertaining to it; not even the least. If this be done, the life fluid which
                            should circulate as freely through the limbs, of the body, as through the head, and trunk,
                            is obstructed, causing pain and disease. Some persons in the pursuit of happiness, would
                            naturally turn to the cultivation of the soil — others to hewing wood and drawing water.
                            Another class would seek to learn and teach the sciences by which those branches of industry
                            can be performed to the greatest profit, with the least amount of labor. Talents thus used
                            are beneficial to society and a blessing to humanity; there is neither wrong nor oppression
                            in it. Those who are leaders, in the order of their creation, by the inherent powers which
                            they possess, will rise to occupy their proper position, as heads in the department to which
                            they belong; and justice demands that the superior talents, which is Nature's gift to them
                            for the benefit of others, should be used to promote the happiness and well-being of every
                            member of the body over which they are called to preside. Leaders should be unselfish
                            workers. As society is now organized, multitudes are seeking to live without labor, to eat
                            and drink without giving an honest equivalent; and they " grind the faces of the poor," and
                            the spoil which they unjustly take from the widow and the fatherless is seen in costly
                            mansions and gaudy equipages. Did God ever design that his noblest gifts to man should be
                            thus used for selfish ends and purposes? That strong and brilliant talents should be
                            employed to enrich the few and impoverish the many? By what law are merchantmen enabled to
                            send out their large vessels, heavily laden with costly wares, until they whiten many waters
                            ? Or those millionaires who store their wealth in vaults and guard it by a strong force,
                            while the poor man who has given his strength to help create those riches, and now dare not
                            put his finger upon them, reaches out his brawny hand and imploringly asks a morsel of bread
                            for himself and children ? Is there no remedy for this state of things ? " No balm in
                            Gilead, no physician there ? " S.urely, we must say with Horace Greeley, " This is not
                            Christianity." We venture to say, that no person has a right to the elements of subsistence
                            without labor. Statesmen, Scientists, and Theologians, are all in duty bound to perform
                            manual labor, more or less; their physical health requires it; and no one should seek to
                            live by wits alone ; and those who do it are not made happy thereby. They may sail over many
                            seas and roam in distant lands, visit the pyramids of Egypt, the cathedrals of Rome, and the
                            fine statuary of Greece, and thus while away the hours; but in the cool of the day, when the
                            shadows of night gather around, conscience speaks, saying, " God is just, and every work
                            will be brought into judgment," and a just recompense be awarded. Dismay fills the mind,
                            when they reflect that the Lord, who placerd them in his vineyard to work, will call for his
                            own with usury.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reflections upon some of the parables of Jesus" TEIform="index"/>REFLECTIONS UPON SOME OF THE
                            PARABLES OF JESUS</head><p TEIform="p">In reading some of the parables put forth by Jesus, I have been led to reflect how much
                            easier it is to make good resolves than to keep them. And how few there are who are really
                            willing to forsake all to follow Christ, when called. Many would gladly grasp the treas ures
                            of immortal life, and possess the goodly pearl, but are not willing to pay the price. Like
                            the young man who addressed Jesus as, " Good Master, what good thing can 1 do to inherit
                            eternal life ? " When Jesus said to him, " Go sell all thou hast and give to the poor, and
                            thou shalt have treasure in heaven," he went away sorrowing. His riches were, in reality,
                            the god he served. Jesus said : " Hardly shall a rich man enter the kingdom of heaven."
                            "Foxes have holes, and the birds of the air have nests, but the son of man hath not where to
                            lay his head." Some, without consideration and mature understanding of the cross and
                            self-denial required to become a true follower of Christ, are ready to say, "Lord,/will
                            follow Thee whithersoever Thou goest;" but as soon as they find that if they " would reign
                            with Him, they must also suffer with Him," their courage fails — there are many idols in the
                            way. One whom Jesus called said, " Suffer me first to go and bury my father." " Let the dead
                            bury their dead," was the reply, which was equivalent to saying they who are dead in
                            trespasses arid sins — who are living the natural generative life, and have not been
                            resurrected therefrom — must attend to the duties of that Order. Let them bury their own
                            dead; " preach thou the kingdom of God ;" •' My kingdom is not of this world," plainly
                            showing there were higher duties to be performed, and that there could be no real fellowship
                            between light and darkness — no blending of flesh and spirit—but that His mission was to
                            draw souls from the worldly life — its affections as well as its lusts — and lead them up to
                            a higher plane. This was plainly demonstrated by the answer that he gave to one who asked
                            permission " first to go and bid farewell to his friends at home in his own house." Jesus
                            said, " He that putteth his hand to the plow and looketh back is not fit for the kingdom of
                            God." Jesus plainly taught, by precept and example, that it is not practicable to serve two
                            masters ; that no one can be grafted into the New heavenly vine, unless cut off from the Old
                            earthly vine, and that it must cause pain and suffering to die — lose the natural carnal
                            life — to find a life that will be eternal.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hillsgrove, Elmira" TEIform="persName"/>Elmira Hillsgrove, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let our haste to bless good equal our earnestness to..." TEIform="index"/>Let our haste to bless good equal our earnestness to...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Let our haste to bless good equal our earnestness to reprove evil. To be fully employed is
                            the best warrant of rapid growth.</p></div2><pb n="78" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is sacrifice?" TEIform="index"/>WHAT IS SACRIFICE?</head><p TEIform="p">At the present time there are comparatively few who call in question the immortality of the
                            human soul; especially since " Spiritualism," the Angel seen by John the evangelist, that
                            descended, "having great power,and lightened the earth with glory," has worked so
                            effectually among the infidel classes, and become a potent agent in removing mysterious
                            doubts which hung over the minds of many, and of unfolding to their vision the realities of
                            the eternal world. The same instrumentality is disenthralling many devotedly religious
                            minds. Though sincere and earnest they were creedhound and held in strong hands of
                            superstition. Through long ages past, Superstition in matters of Religion has dethroned
                            Reason, occupied its place, and ruled with fearful tyranny. Now, Aspiration and its
                            unfailing response, Revelation, are moulded by Reason, while liberated Conscience, with her
                            balances, is active in duty; thus, more rational and just conceptions of Deity — of the soul
                            — and of the effect of the present life upon the future are attained. And the fact that our
                            being is twofold, natural and spiritual, is undisputed. Both have their uses. The natural is
                            first — first developed. It is transient, temporary, and must be superseded by the
                            spiritual, which ia eternal. The general idea of heaven is that of condition rather than
                            place. The narrow limits of private family relations of me and mine, with all the
                            selfishness pertaining thereto, are being exchanged for the expansive relationship of
                            beneficent, harmonious fraternity, where the wealth of virtue that vanisheth not, and the
                            joys of Angels which cannot be borne away on Time's fleet pinions, shall be the soul's
                            treasure to possess in a life that is imperishable. But who would call this exchange
                            Sacrifice ? If we give perverted appetites for the true and good in the natural, that is not
                            sacrifice. So, in leaving the natural for the spiritual — the earthly for the heavenly — we
                            lose nothing of permanent worth, even if this be done while in time. In forsaking the
                            friendships and connections formed by our first birth, we test our sincerity and love of
                            truth, and try the affections upon its fiery altar. The result is, a baptism of pentecostal
                            love, winch is purified, and new relations are formed in a household of Faith, a heavenly
                            parentage and kindred, near and dear, beneath whose sweet ministrations crosses vanish and
                            give place to blessings. The relations we form with such souls unite us to Angel bands and
                            strengthen us to grow in goodness. By leaving the old for the new, the perishable for the
                            eternal, it is not necessary to undervalue the good of the past. There are many in the world
                            at large who do not find an element or sphere in which their interior life can unfold. Such
                            often seek to give expression to their feelings by an artistic mode of dress and external
                            decorations; but the deep longings of the soul cannot be satisfied in that way. There is a
                            home for the soul,where all is truly refined and beautiful. The soul there becomes as a
                            mansion, lighted witli the glory of goodness. The hallowed remembrances of prophetic visions
                            are like beautiful pictures to embellish its walls ; and the heart's virtues will bloom and
                            send forth fragrance like sweet scented flowers, growing perpetually beneath the sunlight of
                            truth. Such is the reward of those whose " lines are hid with Christ in God." Can this be
                            called Sacrifice ? Is not the weight of the Christian's Cross and the Sacrifice
                            overestimated by many, and the blessings received undervalued? What is it but giving the
                            inferior for the superior, the artificial for the real ? And they whose superior
                            intellectual endowments qualify them for Leaders in the van of Reforms or in literary
                            labors, find strong incentives for the development of those powers, for the Gospel opens a
                            broad field for action and offers a reward known only to those who draw the vital elements
                            of support from the great First Cause, the Fountain of their being. Unto such ministering
                            Angels will open the bright portals of revelation, and they will feel impelled by the powers
                            of the spiritual world to give freely of their treasures to-bless humanity, and to yield
                            their lives in unselfish devotion. It has been ascertained by careful investigation that no
                            individual receiving a just remuneration for labor can amass much wealth in excess of life
                            comforts and necessary expenditures. Only through speculation and monopoly, a system that
                            scatters broad-cast the seeds of vice and destruction, destroys the peace of the Community,
                            and preys upon the heart of the Nation, are riches heaped up. Thus toiling millions, often
                            in servile wretchedness, support the few in wanton extravagance, who at their expense are
                            made wealthy. And those highly gifted as financiers, who consecrate that talent to the
                            united interests of a religious community, securing for its inmates the just recompense of
                            honest toil, with the assurance that whatever is accumulated will be dedicated to the
                            diffusion of good, derive therefrom supereminent satisfaction, heaven-high above the toilers
                            for selfish gains whose wealth has been wrung from the toil and sufferings of thousands. We
                            ask again, where is the great Sacrifice ?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/>Catharine Allen, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion" TEIform="index"/>RELIGION</head><p TEIform="p">Religion does not consist merely in the belief that the man Jesus lived a self-denying life,
                            and taught, both by precept and example, that his followers should do the same, neither is
                            it found in wild speculative theories, concerning the doctrines which he taught—while in
                            practice denying them. It is not pure religion which only recognizes God, and asks
                            assistance on occasions of special need; while in general prosperity, the Father's gifts are
                            woven into selfish interests, and his beneficence forgotten. Neither does it consist in
                            formulas, creeds, modes of worship, and particular styles of dress — all of which may be
                            expressions of religious sentiment, but vitally considered, are not spirit power, quickening
                            the soul into resurrection life and producing good fruits, works, which are the evidence of
                            true religion. Throughout all nations there is an innate idea of worship in some form ; and
                            every sect has a corresponding creed, which finds expression in diversified ways. The
                            Shakers profess not to have a creed, to bind and fetter the soul's progress, the effect
                            generally produced, but they believe in God, as a duality — Father and Mother — and in the
                            soul's progression, without bound or limit. As a sequence of this belief, that God is dual,
                            their order of government is represented in dual form. The male and female work, in harmonic
                            relations, together, as brother and sister in Christ — children of a Heavenly Father and
                            Mother, they are co-workers in building up a household of Christrin faith, and promoting the
                            cause of truth. Under the spiritual faith that the true resurrection pertains to the soul,
                            and that whoever comes into Christ, practically, enters the resurrection work. The Shakers
                            give outward expression to their inward feelings, in worship. When they go forth in dances,
                            it is an expression of joy, which they feel, that they are disenthralled — freed from the
                            bondage of sinful passions. In marching they express the idea of traveling home to God —
                            leaving old things of the past for the new — the inferior for the superior. And when they
                            engage in " battles of shaking," it is a sign that all that is false and erroneous must be
                            shaken off, and left behind; and they have found, that shaking is effective, as a means, in
                            disarming the enemies of the soul's peace, and pulling down satan's kingdom. Religion that
                            works by love and purifies the heart, will demand strict self-denial, and lead to an honest
                            confession of sin, and repentance toward God, and thus souls will gain confidence, and be
                            strengthened to pursue their heavenward journey, step by step, until they stand in perfect
                            justification. The question is often asked, Can all minds become religious? We believe that
                            every soul is possessed of a germ of spirituality — of love to God. That germ needs
                            cultivation, growth and the means of education, and the free will of individuals to receive
                            and obey light, greatly determine the results. We believe it is a possibility. It is true
                            that many are blest, through a natural inheritance, with a greater degree of spirituality
                            and intuitive perception, than others; and it is apparently easier for them to comprehend
                            the soul's needs, and to receive divine influences; but there is a greater responsibility
                            resting upon such. If they fill the sphere in which they were created to act, they must be
                            connecting links between the lower and still higher grades of beings. Earnest labor, time
                            and growth, will elevate and progress all. Religion will bring all faculties of mind and
                            body, into harmony of action, in the service of God. It indeed requires great skill, and is
                            a delicate work to guide the heart — turn it away from all its perverse tendencies— to
                            perfect purity; and to guard against pride, vain emulation and self-esteem, and induce
                            humility and love. To learn to prefer and honor others before self, requires constancy and
                            care and battling with worldly temptations. Religion leads from narrow, selfish
                            conservatism, and teaches Christian benevolence, and universal love. Witness how bounteously
                            are the gifts of our Heavenly Father and Mother spread over the universe ; in what variety
                            and profusion; they are sufficient to meet the needs and fill the minds of all. In like
                            manner, finite beings should dispense charity to all who are in need, and from pure motives,
                            give with a liberal hand, as far as consistent. In this way, they become God-like —
                            Christlike— and fulfill the command, "Be ye perfect, even as your Father in Heaven is
                            perfect." True Religion, then, is the outflowing of the principle of love toward God — the
                            source of all goodness and power. It is like a living, growing, fruit-bearing tree, whose
                            roots are deeply imbedded in the soil of truth, and whose branches are ever reaching upward
                            to the spiritual powers above — the elements of divine life — for nourishment, and to be fed
                            by the Christ-spirit. And they who are engrafted thereon, their " leaf shall not wither,"
                            nor their power wane, till eternal life is won — the victory gained. They who toil in
                            earnest, and sow the good seed, then patiently wait for growth, will see the fruition of
                            their hopes and labors.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Martin, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName"/>Elizabeth Martin, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Normal conditions" TEIform="index"/>NORMAL CONDITIONS</head><p TEIform="p">When the marriage institution, under orderly normal conditions, is used to produce a healthy
                            race of beings, who will honor their parents and live according to the laws of their being
                            on the natural plane of existence until they progress beyond that state, and find a growth
                            into the more divine life, the present condition of inharmonies will be changed, and peace,
                            to a great extent, will be established in thg earthly order. If the marriage relation, as
                            claimed, be founded upon love, why is it not more peacefully sustained? Why do the public
                            journals teem with detailed accounts of jealousies, jarring contentions, moroseness of habit
                            and temper, often ending in bloodshed ? It is often said, " There is no effect without a
                            cause." There must be a terrible defect somewhere; a great perversion of physical laws; for
                            what are now sometimes pictured in poetic strains as " Matrimonial heavens," to my mind
                            appear more like a pandemonium! and " Hymen's silken bands" might more appropriately be
                            called hempen cords, which in a wily manner coil around its subjects, then fasten and bind
                            with fetters strong as the chains of chattel slavery, which cost much suffering and many
                            lives to break ! The high and low, rich and poor, priests and laymen fall into the same
                            snare! Ye thinking men and women, prophets and prophetesses of the nineteenth century, will
                            ye point out the cause of all this trouble, and show the remedy ? Let it be written in
                            language so plain, that they who run may read and understand. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Julia" TEIform="persName"/>Julia Johnson, West Pittsfield, Mass.</byline></div2><pb n="79" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Baptism" TEIform="index"/>BAPTISM</head><p TEIform="p">Baptism, in some form, is the door of entrance into the popular churches. How far the
                            ordinance is efficacious in removing sin from the heart, and giving power to abstain
                            therefrom, is a subject worthy of consideration. The tree must be judged by the fruit it
                            produces. There are different kinds of baptisms spoken of in scripture. John's baptism of
                            water, which was for the cleansing of the human body, to prevent disease and keep it in a
                            healthy condition, was symbolical, but as essential as the true Christ baptism of " fire and
                            the Holy Spirit," which is to cleanse and purify the soul, consume all grossness from the
                            heart, and burn the chaff, while it gathers and preserves the wheat. As I take a retrospect
                            of my life's journey, thus far, I can see how kindly I have been dealt with, and how I have
                            been led by unseen hand step by step, in paths that I knew not; and my heart swells with
                            gratitude, as I recount the many blessings which have been dispensed to me; and with the
                            Psalmist of olden time I am led to say, " Goodness and mercy have followed me all the days
                            of my life." In early life, I sought to be a Christian. I was admitted into church communion
                            by passing through the rite of baptism by sprinkling. That was as far as my light then led
                            me. After a time, the spirit again strove with me, and seemed to urge me to take another
                            step. I reflected that Jesus was baptized by immersion ; and in order to follow him, I must
                            also be immersed. I yielded to convictions of duty, and felt blest, for the time being. I
                            searched the Scriptures, and found there were Covenants, as well as Baptisms, spoken of ;
                            and I sought to understand what those Covenants were. I learned that there were Laws and
                            Statutes and Covenants given to the ancient Israelites in the Mosaic Dispensation ; but they
                            were not strong and effective; and " made not the comers thereunto perfect." I also read of
                            a New Covenant that was to be made with the house of Israel, in which the Law was to be
                            written in the hearts of the people ; and Christ would sit as a Refiner in his temple, and
                            old things would be done away, and all in his kingdom would become New, and there would be "
                            one faith, one Lord, and one baptism." Soon after that period, I received a call of the
                            Spirit to come out from the world, its spirit and practice ; and to make a full consecration
                            of my whole being to the service of God. I saw and began to understand the New Covenant, and
                            felt the power of a new baptism — the baptism of fire — even the Spirit of Truth. I became a
                            member of the Church of Christ's Second Appearing, and have been striving for many years to
                            delineate the character of a true Believer in Christian principles, by practical life. The
                            mission of Jesus was not to destroy the Law and Covenants of the past, but to fulfill them,
                            and reveal a higher law — show a more perfect way — while it included all the good. " The
                            law and the prophets were until John ;" and it was his mission to call men and women to
                            repentance for all transgressions of the law of Moses, and th us prepare them to receive the
                            kingdom which Jesus came to inaugurate; showing that repentance must precede the reception
                            of new and divine truth. He taught his disciples to pray for that kingdom to come, in which
                            the will of God would be done by mortals on earth, as it is done by Angels in heaven. That
                            kingdom will manifest itself, not in word only, but in saving powers. It will be constituted
                            of souls whom the love of truth draws together — "a peculiar people who are zealous of good
                            works — whose meat and drink it is to do the work of God." Blessed and happy are they who
                            find an inheritance in that kingdom, and with the saints who possess it, have their names
                            enrolled in the Book of Life. No one can reign with Christ except they be willing to suffer
                            with him. Jesus said to the woman who came to him with a petition for her sons, " Ye know
                            not what ye ask. Are ye able to drink of the cup that I shall drink of, and to be baptized
                            with the baptism that I shall be baptized with 1" He understood full well that few would be
                            willing to be buried with him by baptism into his death, that they might be raised in the
                            likeness of his resurrection. The physical suffering which he endured when he was buffeted,
                            spit upon, forsaken of friends, crowned with thorns, and led as a sheep to the slaughter,
                            were light, compared with the mental suffering and grief of spirit that he felt, when he saw
                            how few were willing to receive the weighty truths which he was sent to confer upon a lost
                            race. When he neared Jerusalem and cast his eyes over the city, and saw how few were willing
                            to accept his teachings, he wept and said, " Oh, Jerusalem, Jerusalem, how oft would I have
                            gathered you, but ye would not! "</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, Ruth" TEIform="persName"/>Ruth Webster, Union Village, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbath" TEIform="index"/>SABBATH</head><p TEIform="p">" Give us this day our daily bread," was the prayer of Jesus. The ancient, typical Israel
                            received their manna fresh every day, and if any, through greediness, gathered more than
                            they needed, it decayed — became corrupt — and availed nothing the ensuing day. Is there not
                            in this fact a significance for pilgrims this later day ? If we are industrious and prudent
                            may we not trust in Israel's God to give us food suited to our wants and necessities, both
                            temporally and spiritually 1 While we are fulfilling the type of the forty years pilgrimage
                            of the children in the Wilderness, if the Lord give us food — manna — from the heavens, will
                            it not be wise for every one to gather for him and herself, in proportion to needs, that
                            thereby we may be nourished and grow? They were instructed to gather, according to their
                            need, but to leave nothing over, except on the sixth day. " To-morrow is the rest of the
                            holy Sabbath unto the Lord. Bake that which ye will to-day, and that which remaineth lay up
                            for the morning, for on the Sabbath day ye shall not find it in the field. Let no man go out
                            of his place on the Sabbath. So the people rested on the Sabbath day." What an admirable
                            plan to destroy avarice, and to teach a lesson of dependence and humility ! We would not be
                            understood that we believe the seventh day was better, and more holy than the six preceding
                            days, other than it was sanctified by the people, and devoted to higher and holier uses. But
                            it was meet that one day in seven should be set apart for spiritual culture and elevation,
                            to refrain from secular business. And who does not believe that the physical, temporal and
                            spiritual conditions of the people were improved by the observance of the Sabbath of rest
                            and devotion, on which day they were cited to study the law and scriptures of that time ?
                            And shall we, of the nineteenth century, of what is called the Christian age of the world,
                            refuse to observe the Sabbath in consonance with its real meaning, or spend the time in
                            idleness and recreation, and thus fritter away the golden moments ? It is said of Napoleon,
                            that while on his marches with his army he observed the seventh day of rest, for not only
                            his men, but his horses needed that rest to retain health and vigor, and that theory has the
                            sanction of scientists. Especially are those who profess to be a "peculiar people, zealous
                            of good works," a " royal priesthood," under the guidance of the Christ-spirit in the male
                            and female order, bound by that profession and by love to God, and duty to our neighbor, to
                            spend the Sabbath as we profess to do, in such a spirit of true consecration, spiritual
                            exercise and devotion, as will be productive of the greatest amount of good to our own
                            souls, and to others, and thus promote the cause of righteousness in the earth. Now, in this
                            day of Christ's second coming, we cannot present ourselves blameless before God if we do not
                            gather the bread of life wherewith to feed the hungry, and living waters to impart to the
                            thirsty. The earth needs saving — purifying elements to-day — salt that has lost none of its
                            savor. The day, and time in which we live, call upon us to be men and women of growth and
                            progress, not to lower the standard of holiness, but to exalt it — raise it still higher. It
                            is our privilege to plunge into the " risen waters " and swim clear of those inferior
                            desires and passions which fetter and bind many souls to earth. May we receive a fullness of
                            the promise made to Israel of old, " To the eunuchs that keep my Sabbaths (and Sabbaths of
                            Sabbaths), and choose the things that please Me, and take hold of My covenants, unto them
                            will I give in Mine house and within My walls, a name and place better than of sons and
                            daughters."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. Webster, Harvard, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Retaliation" TEIform="index"/>RETALIATION</head><p TEIform="p">" Recompense to no man (or woman) evil for evil." " If thine enemy hunger, feed him " (or
                            her). That is good scripture ; it is Christlike. When we are wronged, it is natural to
                            retaliate — to seek revenge — the reverse of the spirit that would lead us to pray for, and
                            forgive those who despitefully use us. It is easier to talk of forgiving an enemy, than to
                            really do it. I ask myself this question : If an incendiary should maliciously, without
                            provocation, put the torch to my dwelling—as was recently done at Mt. Lebanon — would I feel
                            like seeking revenge, and rejoice in the infliction of punishment upon that person ? " I
                            think I can truthfully answer in the negative. I respect the protective laws of our country,
                            and the judiciary which enforce those laws for the safety of the public; but I would gladly
                            commend the erring to the mercy of God, and of the civil magistrates — if they would repent
                            and sin no more. The prayer of Jesus for his enemies was, " Father forgive them ; they know
                            not what they do." Thus we would pray, and forgive. But if they are not brought, through the
                            medium of their own consciences, nor by the moral influence of their friends, to see the
                            great wrong they have done, it were better for the safety of the community, and even for
                            their own happiness in the end, that they be placed by sentence of law where they cannot
                            continue to bring so great suffering and sorrow upon others. 1 am deeply impressed by the
                            recent disastrous fires, with the importance of laying up treasures in that house not made
                            with human hands, beyond the reach of fire or flood.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Danford, Nancy G." TEIform="persName"/>Nancy G. Danford, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oatmeal as food" TEIform="index"/>OATMEAL AS FOOD</head><p TEIform="p">The advantages of oatmeal as an article of food are getting to be tolerably well understood,
                            and all persons who have commenced its regular use will agree that its nutritious and
                            health-giving properties have not been overrated. Chemical analysis shows that oatmeal is
                            richer than wheat in starch and the nitrogenous compounds, the first being fat-forming and
                            the latter flesh-forming constituents. As compared with barley and corn, oatmeal is found to
                            be still richer in these elements. As food, it sits lightly on the stomach, and is
                            exceedingly digestible. It is one of the best articles of food to give to growing children,
                            and is especially valuable, also, to persons who do brain work. A little oatmeal mixed in
                            water 'makes a cool and refreshing drink, and farmers and contractors who supply their
                            laborers with it will find it far better than any form of stimulant, and in the long run
                            more satisfactory to the men themselves. Oats grown in far northern localities have larger
                            and plumper grains than any other, and it is for this reason that Scotch oatmeal ranks so
                            high. Excellent oats for mealing, however, are produced in Canada, the New England States,
                            Central and Northern Michigan and Wisconsin.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unity in diversity" TEIform="index"/>Unity in Diversity.</head><p TEIform="p"> Man is a progressive being, and therefore essentially imperfect. We are not perfect
                            ourselves, and therefore we should not require perfection in others. Our various degrees of
                            development also render each one of us different from the other. It is unwise and unjust for
                            us to condemn others for being different from us, because we are equally different from
                            them. If we will tolerate others in their difference from us as much as we would have others
                            tolerate us in our difference from them, then we may live together in friendship and peace.
                            But if we censure and abuse others because of their faults and failings, then they may treat
                            us the same for like reason, and that would cause contention and separation. Toleration
                            secures unity in diversity, and it will be all the more " good and pleasant" for people to
                            "dwell together" in such unity, because variety is said to be "the spice of life."</p></div2><pb n="80" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Voyage of life" TEIform="index"/>VOYAGE OF LIFE</head><p TEIform="p">Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. 1. Upon the rocky shores of Time Our barques might anchored be, Yet
                            pilot-like our spirits long To cross life's rolling sea. 2.0, youthful mariner beware! Thy
                            vessel frail may strand, Unless 'tis guided on its way By Truth's unerring hand; To sail ...
                            away! . . Upon its changeful tide, To brave the tempest and the storm, And o'er the billows
                            ride Then sail ... away! And leave all phantom fears. Prepare with strength to meet the flow
                            Of the incoming years Though deep and strong the current glides, Far out upon the sea, Yet
                            Faith—thy compass—will direct, And Hope thy light will be ; Still sail away! Nor trust in
                            thine own power, But watch and pray though calm the day, Or dark the midnight hour. 5. Thy
                            finite vision cannot span. Or bound the mighty deep; The secrets of the future years, Within
                            its bosom sleep; But sail away I O voyager on the main! "Within the blessed port of peace,
                            Sure anchorage thou wilt gain. 4. The treasured wealth of patient toil, Within thy spirit
                            hold ; The shining pearls of Wisdom, place Upon life's threads of gold. And sail away! With
                            Love at thy command, To buoy thee up, and cheer the way, To the immortal land.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ" TEIform="index"/>THE CHRIST</head><p TEIform="p">" I will not ask my neighbor of his creed, Nor what he deems of doctrines old or new, Nor
                            what rights his honest soul may need To worship God, the only wise and true; Nor what he
                            thinks of the Anointed Christ, Nor with what baptism he has been baptized. " I ask not what
                            temptations have beset His human .heart, now self-debased and sore, Nor by what way-side
                            well the Lord he met, Nor where was uttered,' Go, and sin no more.' Between his soul and God
                            that business lies, Not mine to cavil, question or despise. " I ask not by which name, among
                            the rest That Christians go by, he is named or known; Whether his faith has ever been
                            professed, Or whether proven by his deeds alone. So there be Christhood in him, all is well,
                            He is my brother, in peace we dwell. " If grace and patience in his actions speak, Or fall
                            in words of kindness from his tongue, Which raise the fallen, fortify the weak, And heal the
                            heart by sorrow rent and wrung. If he give good for ill, and love for hate, Friend of the
                            friendless, poor and desolate, "I find in him discipleship so true, So full that nothing
                            further I demand. He may be bondman, freeman, gentile, Jew, But we are brothers, walking
                            hand in hand. In his true life let me the Christhood see ; It is enough for him, enough for
                            me."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be not moved" TEIform="index"/>BE NOT MOVED</head><p TEIform="p">" Be not moved," we often say. But who discerns the meaning, When pressed by trials of the
                            day, Too small for even naming? But still they cloud us oftentimes, Though light is round us
                            gleaming, We fear the burdens to be borne, Far greater to the seeming. But this is conquest;
                            when we're wronged By incorrect opinion, To simply keep the way of right, And wait for its
                            dominion.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W., Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Condition of man" TEIform="index"/>CONDITION OF MAN</head><p TEIform="p">While pondering upon man's degenerate state, His great responsibility—the ultimate— My spirit
                            groans within me, crying out, alasl Who, or how many, will be saved at last? How many
                            willing to pursue the road That leads to Life, to Heaven, and to God? Who the mighty warfare
                            wage and win, The prize obtain, redemption sing? Almighty Being just, why is it so ? Why so
                            many yield to death, to sin, and woe ? Why turn from Thee away, flinch when trials come, And
                            thus deny the Powers that Be —the Eternal One? Why falter, wane, or stumble at the truth?
                            Why hate the cross of Christ—His life—forsooth? And shun the only path that leads to bliss,
                            And covet woe, or mere transient happiness? Why pleasure seek in pain, and hold the sting of
                            death ? Why fear remorse, yet hug it at each breath ? Why pass along through time,
                            regardless of the past, Of present moment, or, what their doom at last ? Oh ! doleful,
                            doleful sound of Infidelity, Of nothingness, and want of firm reality! Beware of this, the
                            poisoned arrow of despair— The sting of Death—beware of it, O, do beware ! The Tree of Life
                            unfolds its leaves, and teems with love; This seek, 'tis everlasting and from realms above ;
                            'Tis happiness abiding—bliss without alloy, Heaven ever present, which nothing can destroy.
                            It dieth never, fadeth not, nor waxeth old, But renovates our being, redeems the soul; It
                            forms anew, makes angels pure of men, Till Earth and Heaven can together shout, Amen!</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Buckingham, D. A." TEIform="persName"/>D. A. Buckingham, Watervliet, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New stimulant" TEIform="index"/>A NEW STIMULANT</head><p TEIform="p">A new juggernaut, it is said, has been set moving in society, and thousands annually fall
                            beneath its wheels. It is a new stimulant, known as hydrate of chloral—a salt of a burning,
                            pungent taste, having as its basis chloroform, into which it is supposed to be changed in
                            the blood. In small doses it is stimulant and anti-spasmodic ; in larger, narcotic; and in
                            excess it produces death as instantaneously as a flash of lightning. Physicians have been
                            variously divided in the opinion of its ultimate results, some recognizing the fearful
                            consequences of its use, others enthusiastically recommending it for ocean travelers as an
                            antidote for seasickness. In England it has taken the place of opium, and chloral-eating is
                            now as decided a vice as opium-eating, hasheesh-eating and absinthe-drinking. The difference
                            between opium and chloral is that, under the same circumstances, opium is more imaginative,
                            and paints things as they do not really exist; chloral merely increases the power of
                            enjoying the real. A strange, dreamy sense of perfect ease, comfort and happiness takes the
                            place of sorrows and cares; all affection and love are likewise banished, and the eater
                            becomes practically a living, breathing vegetable. An opium-eater has been known to live to
                            a goodly old age. No chloralist can survive three years. The stimulant is imported mostly
                            from Germany, and a high authority asserts, in the London Lancet, that there is positively
                            no antidote for the poison.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kindness" TEIform="index"/>KINDNESS</head><p TEIform="p">Little acts of kindness which we render to each other in every-day life, are like flowers by
                            the way-side to the traveler; they serve to gladden the heart and relieve the tedium of
                            life's journey. Then let us improve each opportunity in performing those deeds of love ; for
                            they will bloom like roses in the memory of those for whom they were performed, which will
                            send forth sweet fragrance long after our departure to spirit spheres.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bathrick, Eunice" TEIform="persName"/>Eunice Bathrick, Ayer, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For youth" TEIform="index"/>FOR YOUTH</head><p TEIform="p">The "evil days (alone) come nigh," When youth has beep in folly spent; For riper years will
                            bring the sigh, Hearts must o'er wasted time repent. Dark clouds will ever be too small To
                            dim the blessed light of God From those who humbly give their all. To walk the path the
                            Saviour trod. As much as fruit exceeds the flower, Maturity is more than youth, In
                            excellence of strength and power, When souls are nurtured in the truth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>Mary Whitcher, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harris, James" TEIform="index"/>James Harris
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Harris, James" TEIform="persName">James Harris</persName>, August 3, 1875, aged 55, Mt.
                                Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>