<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0102" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><date value="18710201" TEIform="date">February 1871</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">9-16</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="9" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">"I WILL SHAKE ALL NATIONS, AXD THE DESIRE OF ALL NATIONS SHALL COME; AND I WILL FILL THIS HOUSE WITH GLORY, SAITH THE
                        LORD." Published Monthly, by, and under the direction of the Mt, Lebanon Bishopric. Vol. I. SHAKERS, ALBANY, N. Y.,
                        FEBRUARY, 1871. No. 2.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Church and state, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>Church and State—No. 2</head><p TEIform="p">In our first issue, we commenced a series of papers, being an inquiry into the foundational principles of the
                            civil and religious governments of the United States, and of the United Societies. Extremes meet. The extreme of
                            skepticism towards theological and religious ideas, when interblended with statutory laws and civil
                            institutions, ultimated itself in the United States Government. This has recently been demonstrated, and ably
                            commented upon, by the " New York Tribune;" showing that the Senate pronounced it a non-sectarian and
                            unreligious government, as follows :— " A Ray of Light from the Past" " The theologians who insist that our
                            government rests upon an implied assumption or recognition of the divine authority of the Christian religion,
                            and who wish to make that recognition palpable, by an amendment of the Constitution, will find a hard nut to
                            crack in the following proTision in the treaty of Tripoli, made under the administration of Washington, in 1796,
                            when the fundamental principles of the government, and the ideas and purposes of its founders were yet fresh in
                            the minds of the people. " ' As the government of the United States is not in any sense founded on the Christian
                            religion; as it has in itself no character of enmity against the laws, religion, or tranquillity of Mussulman's;
                            j and as the said States never have entered j into any war or act of hostility against any Mohammedan nation ;
                            it is declared by the parties, that no pretext arising from religious opinions shall ever produce an
                            interruption of the harmony existing between the two countries.' "To this declaration, which bears the stamp of
                            the Senate's approval, is appended the name of George Washington, who held, that his speculative faith entitled
                            him to no privileges, as a citizen, that were not common to all others, of whatever religious belief or
                            unbelief. The Declaration, moreover, for aught that appears, received the assent of the whole American people,
                            as embodying an essential and fundamental principle of the Government. "Let us not, in the very hour of our
                            rejoicing over the downfall of the civil authority of the Church in the Roman States, countenance the attempt to
                            remove the barriers erected by our fathers against a union of Church and State in this Republic." And this is a
                            principle essential to its own self-preservation. The mental, intellectual, and spiritual freedom of the human
                            mind in all its phases (when not incarnated in acts to the injury of the same rights in others), was what the
                            revolutionary fathers fought for, and germinally embodied in the United States' constitution. The opposite
                            extremes of Spiritualists and religiously-exercised people, like the French Prophets, the Moravians, and Dunkers
                            ; together with New Lights, Breakers, and Quakers, feared God exceedingly, and were mediums of influence from
                            the spirit land. These often spoke and acted as they were moved upon by the invisible souls of disembodied men
                            and women seeking to work the work of God on earth. Out of these arose Mother Ann and her little company of
                            devoted souls; and through their labors the elements became ultimated and organised in the religious Communism
                            of the Shakers—the United Societies From the first there was a deep sympathy between these apparently opposite
                            extremes—the respective founders of two systems in nowise antagonistic,—which became incorporated in a purely
                            civil and a purely religious government. They were nearer together, and more alike, than either of them
                            understood. Both were infidel to the popular orthodoxy of Christendom, as exhibited in the combined church and
                            and state organizations of the civilized world. They disbelieved alike, and both were terribly in earnest. While
                            the skeptical powers were plighting their lives and faith and sacred honor in fighting the battles of humanity
                            against monarchy—the church and state union— the divine right of kings—with its concom- itants, the religious
                            spiritualists were fighting, in " battles of shaking " (often to be heard a mile distant), the anti-Christian
                            theology of a Trinity of masculine Gods ; the vicarious atonement for sin through the material blood of Jesus;
                            the resurrection of physical bodies, ages after death; the eternally-lost condition of all souls, except a few
                            nominal Christians ; the blending together of generation and regeneration, of war and peace, of selfishness and
                            communion of saints. While the Shakers deprecated persecution for conscience' sake, and only to be met with from
                            the priesthood of antiChrist, the skeptics sought, by a constitutional provision, to render it—persecution
                            —legally impossible within the jurisdiction of the United States. Art. 1.—" Congress shall make no law
                            respecting an establishment of religion, or prohibiting the free exercise thereof." Art. 37, First Constitution
                            of the State of New York.—" And whereas we are required, by the benevolent principles of rational liberty, not
                            only to expel civil tyranny, but also to guard against that spiritual oppression and intolerance wherewith the
                            bigotry and ambition of weak and wicked priests and princes have scourged mankind ; the free exercise and
                            enjoyment of religious profession and worship, without discrimination or preference, shall forever hereafter be
                            allowed within this State to all mankind." Art. 39.—"And whereas the ministers of the gospel are, by their
                            profession, dedicated to the service of God and the cure of souls and ought not to be diverted from the great
                            duties of their function ; there- fore, no minister of the gospel, or priest of any denomination whatsoever,
                            shall, at any time hereafter, under any pretense or description whatever, be eligible to, or capable of, holding
                            any civil or military office or place within this State." These enactments plainly indicate the character and
                            design of the men who framed them; and, as burnt childen dread the fire, so did those skeptics go, even over the
                            line of equal rights to discriminate against a class of men—Gospel ministers —who, of all others, ought
                            logically, on the assumption that Christianity is par excellence the religion, to be the safest depositaries of
                            civil power. <pb n="10" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 1O THE SHAKER. It is because worldly, Gentile Christi- anity includes elements
                            that are not in and of the Gospel of Jesus Christ, that its ministers are thus disfranchised, in selfdefence, by
                            the sovereign people. William Pitt, in an essay on superstition speaks of a " certain unnatural passion which we
                            will call religious hatred,— fixed, constant, deep-rooted, and immortal. All other passions rise and fall, die
                            and revive again; but this of religious hatred rises and grows, every day, stronger upon the mind as we grow
                            more religious, because we hate for God's sake, and for the sake of those poor souls, too, who have the
                            misfortune not to believe as we do: and can we, in so good a cause, hate too much ? The more thoroughly we hate,
                            the better we are ; and the more mischief we do to the bodies and estates of those infidels and heretics, the
                            more do we show our love to God. This is religious zeal; and this has been called Divinity. But remember, the
                            only true Divinity is Humanity."—London Journal, 1733. Thomas Paine's "Age of Reason" opens thus :—" I believe
                            in one God, and no more ; and I hope for happiness beyond this life. I believe the equality of man; and I
                            believe that religious duties consist in doing justice, loving mercy, and in endeavoring to make our fellow
                            creatures happy. The world is my country, to do good is my religion," was this unbeliever's motto. Thus was the
                            American Government established, which was in no sense theological ; but a purely civil government, belonging
                            equally to all its citizens, whatever their beliefs or unbeliefs, from the Atheist to the Quaker. Universal
                            suffrage for white ?nen, and universal liberty for white people, was fully and amply secured. Thenceforth rulers
                            were to be the people's choice and the people's servants ; and not, as heretofore the people's masters. And
                            above all in value was the perpetual right of Constitutional amendment. Jefferson says : "At our first
                            legislative session, after the Declaration of Independence we abolished the law of Entails and Primogeniture,
                            and divided the lands of intestates equally among their heirs. These laws, drawn by myself, laid the axe to the
                            root of pseudo-aristocracy." He also proposed a system of free schools, which was too far a-head of the times to
                            be adopted. And, on that account, many forms of evil were reserved to be purged away by succeeding generations,
                            under the power of Constitutional amendments in the good time they saw coming. Prominent among these was slavery
                            and its primal cause, land monopoly, or unlimited landed possessions. There was to be a new heaven, or Church,
                            and a new earth, or civil Govern- ment, wherein should dwell righteousness. We have seen the foundations of both
                            of these laid in the Revolutionary times, and by men and women whose minds were adapted to the work. The removal
                            of the great curse of slavery, so adverse to the genius of the government and to the principles and desires of
                            its real founders, could be accomplished only by a similar class of minds raised up and inspired by those
                            original governmental founders in the spiritual world. And thus was opened the second of the seven degrees in
                            the onward progress of our Government towards a condition of rational and perfect national righteousness. And as
                            Lincoln was the central personage in the great national tragedy which ensued, we will introduce him on the stage
                            and see what is the evidence, and what are the facts. W. H. Herndon says: "One or two preliminary remarks will
                            help us to understand why he (Lincoln) disagreed with the Christian world, in its principles as well as in its
                            theology. In the first place, Mr. Lincoln's was a purely logical mind; and, secondly, Mr. Lincoln was purely a
                            practical man. He had no fancy or imagination, and not much emotion. He was a realist, as opposed to an
                            idealist. As a general rule, it is true, that a purely logical mind has not much hope, if it ever has faith, in
                            the ttnseen and urJknown. He was terribly, vexatiously, skeptical. " I became acquainted with Mr. Lincoln in
                            1834, and I think I knew him to the day of his death. He came to Illinois in 1830, and settled in New Salem,
                            111. It was here that Mr. Lincoln became acquainted with a class of men the world never saw the like of before
                            or since. They were large men; large in body, and large in mind; hard to whip, and never to be fooled. They were
                            a bold, daring, and reckless set of men. They were men of their own minds—believed what was demonstrable ; were
                            men of great common sense. "With these men Mr. Lincoln was thrown; with them he lived, and with them he moved
                            and almost had his being. They were skeptics, all—scoffers, some. These scoffers were good men; and their scoffs
                            were protests against theology,— loud protests against the follies of Christianity. They had never heard of
                            Theism, or the better religious thoughts of this age. They riddled all divines; and not unfrequently made them
                            skeptics—disbelievers like themselves. They were a jovial, healthful, generous, social, true, and manly set of
                            people. "In 1835, he wrote a small work on Infidelity and intended to have it published. The book was an attack
                            upon the whole grounds of Christianity ; and especially was it an attack upon the idea that Jemis was the
                            Christ, the true and onlybegotten Son of God, as the Christian world contends. "His friend Hill, who had an eye
                            to Lincoln's popularity, who saw in him a rising man, and wished him success, and believing that, if the book
                            were published, it would kill Lincoln for ever, snatched it from his hand and put it into a hot stove. " When
                            accused of being an infidel, by his political enemies, during a canvass, he never denied the charge,—' would die
                            first: " Lincoln did not believe in a special creation ; his idea being, that all creation was an evolution
                            under law. He did not believe that the Bible was a special reve- lation from God : did not believe in miracles,
                            as understood by the Christian world. He believed in universal inspiration and miracles, under law. He believed
                            that all things—both matter and mind—were governed by law, universal, absolute and eternal. Law, to Lincoln, was
                            everything. Yet he, like Paine, believed in God and in immortality."—Index. " I maintain that Lincoln was a
                            deeply religious man, at all times, and in all places, in spite of his transient doubts, although not a
                            Christian."—Index. I have reason to know, that Lincoln did not believe largely in God; and that, before his
                            death he became a Spiritualist, and was, like his bosom friend, Stanton, a warm sympathizer with the rational
                            and simple faith of the Shakers. He acted well his part before he left the stage of action. That accounts for
                            the Shakers not being " wiped out " during the late war. Inasmuch as Ann Lee and her compan- ions came by
                            revelation to America, having been spiritually informed and fully assured that the revolution would be
                            successful, and that a Gentile Pentecostal Church would be established upon earth, which, like the Jewish
                            Pentecostal Church, would abjure physical sexuality, selfish rights of property, destructive carnal warfare,
                            wasteful pride, and foolish pomp in dress and equipage, or in vain surroundings in natural things ; and would
                            build up community homes on the basis of personal purity ©f flesh and spirit, and holi- ness—the perfecting of
                            the individual character. Disconnected by a discrete degree from the civil government, it is the Church in its
                            true character and order, destined to shine and operate upon the civil government, as the sun upon the moon and
                            earth —the primal source of all vitality and virility, and the Ruler of day and night. <pb n="11" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHA.KEH. 11 " The law of righteousness shall go forth from Zion, and the word of the Lord from Jerusalem "—the
                            civil government—which will continue to progress until it shall be tke means of securing all the " inalienable
                            rights " to both man and woman, and the necessaries and comforts of life to all the people, each one " sitting
                            under his own vine and fig-tree, with none," moved by spirit of war, " to make them afraid." For wars shall
                            cease to the ends of the earth, in all nations that will accept the reign and rule of the " Prince of Peace !"
                            Reorganisation without Disintegration ! "</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="E., F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. E.</byline></div2><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Biographical: Ann Lee" TEIform="index"/>BIOGRAPHICAL. Ann Lee</head><p TEIform="p">[Continued.) For the greater part of nine years did Ann Lee suffer thus—the severest mental agony— though she
                            experienced seasons of relief, during which she was instructed by heavenly visions and divine revelations why
                            God was thus dealing with her; and with this understanding she bore with fortitude the agonies of preparation,
                            that were fitting her as a receptacle and medium for the Christ Spirit. The revelations made known to her, were
                            the necessity of self-abasement, sorrow for, and departure from sin—the antipodes of that in- struction that
                            provides another to die a physical death, to atone for the millions that continue in and unto sin. , Ann
                            realized the full loss suffered by humanity, but was not yet aware of what the foundation of sin consisted ; nor
                            could she yet see any prospect of relief in the preaching or practices of theological teachers, for the
                            salvation of souls from sin here, or for their redemption hereafter. She agonized to know the cause of human
                            woes, and of their reparation. While lying in the Manchester jail, incarcerated for preaching against " those
                            fleshly lusts that war against the soul," " the mystery of iniquity," as made known to her by directing
                            agencies, she saw, and experienced the man- ifestation of the baptism of the Christ Spirit— the same that made
                            Jesus, the Christ; and the same that will make every man and woman Christ, when prepared; and the manifestations
                            of this' Christ through her, taught many strange things—of the new heavens and earth; of the true Resurrection,
                            consisting of living above the life of generative lusts ; of virgin purity being a component of eternal life,
                            and the impossibility of enjoying the life of the Spirit while engaging in the pleasures of the flesh ! Her
                            testimonies against nature corrupt were the intonations of her directing spirit-agencies, and often brought the
                            deepest embarrassments upon her in their delivery; for she was human, and knew how keenly these testimonies set;
                            but her Christ-duty was superior to human frailties, and she delivered herself "as one having authority."* After
                            her imprisonment in Manchester, she was acknowledged as a leader in spiritual things, and was ever after known
                            as Mother Ann. The religious exercises of her band were singing and dancing, shaking and shouting, speaking in
                            strange tongues, and prophesying after the manner of the Primitive Christian Church. From this time, Mother Ann
                            testified by the Christ Spirit, against all lustful gratifications as the source and foundation of all human
                            misery; that no soul could live in the generative sphere, and practice the regeneration of Christ
                            simultaneously; that naturecorrupt was not only unfit for earthly replenishment, but that reproduction, in its
                            most pure, elevated condition, was positively unchristian and uneternal! She delivered her testimony in the
                            spirit of love, but with such heart-searching power, that many stood convicted of the truth, and acknowledged
                            her gospel as correct. In some, the home-thrust truths kindled the most bitter spirit of persecution,
                            particularly among the professors of theology, in whom the lusts of the world, and the religion that sanctioned,
                            and wedded lusts to lusts, were combined. Of her experiences with some of these persecutors, we purpose treating
                            upon in our next, just a century after their occurrence. * * A woman, of Cleveland, Ohio, occupying an elevated
                            position in society, while under the influence of the Spirit, declared that1'we married women, living in the
                            gratifications of the flesh with our husbands, are nothing but legalized prostitutes ;" and when learning what
                            she had said, nearly crazed with mortification, even after realizing the truth of her words.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Items" TEIform="index"/>Items</head><p TEIform="p">Behold the latter day appears, And things mysterious greet our ears, Which seems to make this wise demand, " Let
                            him that readeth, understand." It has been asserted that the Shaker males hate the females, and vice versa. This
                            is not true; we love each other better than we can express. * It has been said, " The Shakers are the followers
                            of an ' old woman !' " This is not true in any wise: If " old woman " is intended to signify Ann Lee's age, it
                            is false, as she never lived to be aged. As Ann Lee made it the work of her life to crucify the old woman and
                            her deeds of depravity, the Shakers can more consistently be called the followers of the new man (Jesus), and
                            the new woman (Ann). * Right and Wrong.—" If you don't go to school, my son, who will teach you what is right or
                            wrongr" " I don't get teacht, I find it out." " And how do you find it out ?" " By observing that right works
                            for a shilling an hour, while wrong lives on it!'' All persons able to walk should exercise daily in the open
                            air. " Be careful lest a too warm desire for distinction should deceive you into pursuits that may cover you
                            with shame, by setting your incapacity and slender abilities in full light."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Poetry" TEIform="index"/>POETICAL</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit examination" TEIform="index"/>Spirit Examination</head><p TEIform="p">What is in thy heart for God ? Search its depths, and see If them hast a place for Him, Kept in purity. 'Mid
                                the treasures of thy life— Treasures without strife— Hast thou ever for the Lord, A willing sacrifice ? What
                                is iiji thy heart for God ? Are thy joys of earth ? Or hast thou deep happiness Of enduring worth ? And art
                                thou a fruitful branch— Of the living tree, Clothed with innocence, with peace And true humility ? What is
                                in thy heart for God ? Do thy hopes ascend Unto truth, and holiness That shall never end? Is thy love a
                                living fount, Gushing, bright and clear ? Doth the image of the Lord Within its source appear ? All /have I
                                give to God, And his blessed cause ; Praying, that my life may be Guided by his laws. Lead me, holy spirit,
                                down, 'Till I see my loss. Strengthen me, to do the work That cometh by the cross.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="D., C." TEIform="persName"/>C. D., Mt. L., N. H.</byline></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Together we began to tread..." TEIform="index"/>Together we began to tread...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Charlotte" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">During the month of January, 1871, the angels said " Come !" to two interesting young sisters—Marietta Moore
                                and Mary J. Maffit, of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Among the treasures of the latter was found the following tribute
                                from one of her companions—Charlotte—whose affection we here make public, without her knowledge: Together we
                                began to tread The consecrated ground; Together entered here, the home, Where grace and truth abound.
                                Together we have sought for faith, Conviction, power, and light; Together asked for angel's strength, To
                                guide us in the right. Together we have toiled, to earn The love that is so pure, Which clothes the soul
                                with patience true All sorrows to endure. But now doth sickness intervene, To part us for a time ; Still we
                                will struggle to possess The angel-life, divine. True love and friendship shall not cease For you, my sister
                                dear; Though you maj"enter into realms, Beyond this mortal sphere— We still will seek, as one in Christ, For
                                purity and grace; For light and truth, our souls to guide— Our errors to erase. And / will pray, and you
                                will pray, That we may brighter grow ; And, while you toil in yonder home, I'll toil in mine below. Now,
                                dear companion, take my love ; I'll help to bear you through ; And spirit friends will bear you hence, To
                                scenes of fairer view.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A great mind is above doing an unjust act..." TEIform="index"/>A great mind is above doing an unjust act...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"A great mind is above doing an unjust act; above giving away to buffoonery; above giving away to grief; and it
                            would be invulnerable if compassion did not prey upon its sensibility."</p></div2><pb n="12" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian distinction, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>Christian Distinction—No. 1</head><p TEIform="p">cc Brethren, be joint imitators of me, and observe those who conduct themselves as ye have us for an example; for
                            many so conduct, of whom I have told you often, and now tell you even with tears, that they are the enemies of
                            the cross of Christ; whose end is destruction, whose God is sensuality, whose glory is in their shame, and whose
                            mind is devoted to earthly things. For our citizenship is in the heavens, from which we also are expecting the
                            Saviour, the Lord Jesus Christ, who shall transform the body of our humiliation, so as to be conformable to the
                            body of his glory, according to the energy by which he can subject all things to himself." Phil. iii. 17-21.
                            (Original.) These words of the apostle inform us, that connected with the Church of Christ in his da}', were
                            many whose lives were not in accordance with the profession they made, and he considered it necessary to caution
                            those to whom he wrote, against their pernicious example. They were mere sensualists, devoted to the pleasures
                            of the appetites and the passions, and their thoughts engrossed with earthly things. In opposition to such, the
                            apostle exhorted the Philippians to be imitators as one body of him and of those who lived like him. "For," said
                            he, "our citizenship or community is in the heavens, or heavenly world, from which we are looking for the
                            Saviour who shall transform us—the body of Christ, the Church of the faithful, who are now bearing the cross and
                            enduring the various afflictions incident to this state of humiliation—so completely in spirit and in character,
                            that we shall be fitted for intimate and personal association with those who .constitute the church in glory,
                            with whom our names are already enrolled." This, then, is the essential distinction between the genuine
                            followers of Christ, and those who merely adhere to his church without possessing its real life; the former,
                            instead of hating the cross of Christ, cherish it as the means by which they retain an intimate relation to the
                            body of Christ, so that his very life and spirit circulate through them as the life of the tree circulates
                            through e\ery branch; the latter are hostile to this cross, because it interferes with their sensual enjoyments
                            ; its design being as the word implies, to crucify their sensuality, to destroy their very life; not indeed for
                            any real harm to the person, but that the life of Christ, which is the essential life of heaven, and is the
                            opposite of all sensuality, may be substituted for that. They are enemies of the cross, because they are
                            idolaters; and like almost all idolaters, their god is self. Self they worship daily with as much fidelity, as
                            the most zealous devotee who burns incense to his idol ! The class of persons to whom the apostle alludes, may
                            not have been addicted to all kinds of sensuality, yet it is evident they must have been to some of its worst
                            forms, for " their glory was in their shame." They had commenced to follow Christ, perhaps had run well for a
                            season, but from some cause had ceased to bear the cross which was severe against their sensual inclinations,
                            and preferred to be borne down on the current of pleasure, rather than to stem it, so that they became, finally,
                            the enemies of that which was intended for their salvation. The end of this, as the apostle saw, would be their
                            ruin, hence his tears on their account. The forms of sensualism are various, and are vastly different in degree,
                            according to the length of time and intensity with which one gives himself to them. But what is sensualism ? Is
                            it the mere fact of deriving enjoyment through the senses ? That certainly cannot be, for such is the very
                            constitution of man, that the legitimate exercise of the senses is invariably attended with pleasure, and pain
                            is the result of their perverted action. To the eye that dwells upon the various objects of external nature, the
                            mountain and the valley; the ocean, the lake and the river ; the forest clad in its summer dress; the prairie
                            with its vast variety of flowers; the cultivated field with its accompaniment of flocks, herds and dwellings,
                            are a source of exhaustless charm. These enjoyments are in themselves pure as the breath of heaven. So the ear
                            is delighted with sweet sounds that greet it from every side, and the taste with agreeable flavors; and God
                            intended these should be. But the eye may look upon forbidden objects; the ear may listen to sounds that pervert
                            the passions ; the taste may be intoxicated with the excess of delights; and their entire action may become
                            perverted, instead of being normal, or in accordance with the highest physical, mental and moral welfare of the
                            individual. When this is the case the life of the person is mere sensualism. The legitimate exercise of the
                            senses tends to give a healthy tone to the body, sound action to the mental faculties, and a harmonious growth
                            and development to the moral powers; but their perverse action tends to the very reverse of this. In the body,
                            disease is engendered; the mental faculties are confused, and consequently irregular and uncertain in their
                            action; and the moral powers exhibit an insane condition, just in proportion as the senses have become perverted
                            by abuse. With reason, then, may it be said, the end of the sensualist is destruction. Sensualism is a mighty
                            torrent—a flood that sweeps all before it that is really valuable to man. No matter what may be his natural
                            endowments. He may have a physical form that rivals in beauty and majesty that of Apollo; his intellectual
                            endowments may be of the first order; he may have the ability to move multitudes by his eloquence, and influence
                            to action the minds of thousands by the splendor of his diction, and the moral beauty of his thoughts. There
                            have been very many such. In the beginning of their career, they gave promise of a brilliant course through
                            life, and a glorious termination. But oh, the disappointment of cherished hopes, and the despair of trusting
                            hearts! The Apostle Paul is not the only one who has had to weep over the fall of those who had seemingly
                            entered upon a course of usefulness and happiness, and promised so much to the cause of virtue. Thousands of
                            others have wept for a similar cause. Many of the brightest intellects have been completely obscured, by
                            drinking of the cup of sensual pleasure ; at first, sparing!}', but afterwards with the deepest draughts. Men,
                            eminent in political life, and capable of directing the affairs of nations; men filling the desk of the
                            religious teacher, endowed with the rarest gifts of persuasion; men in every condition of life, those occupying
                            the highest places of trust, as well as those pursuing its more common courses—have been swept into the vortex
                            of ruin. Men, too, of every age; those of mature years and large experience, and the youth animated with the
                            freshness and vigor of life's spring-time and the expectation of great enjoyments in the future. I am forcibly
                            reminded of the history of one, who had before him a most hopeful future, and brilliant career; a member of one
                            of our New England colleges. As a scholar, he stood high in the estimation of his instructors, and easily
                            surpassed in scholarship and general talent, all his competitors in the race for distinction. But he had tasted
                            of the inebriating cup, and gradually the sensual gained the ascendancy over the mental. The force of talent
                            enabled him to fill the first place of honor at the finishing up of his academical course, in spite even, of the
                            bewitching and bewildering power of the wine cup; but after that, he went down, down, down,— " his end was
                            destruction." Would that his were a solitary case among the young! but it is not so. The god of sensuality, whom
                            many of them serve, rules them with a terrible power. It may be at first, they do not despise the cross of
                            Christ—their heart and conscience may approve of it, though their lives are in contradiction to it. They respect
                            virtue, and admit its inestimable value; but the seductive power of appetite prevails over their regard for the
                            virtuous, and honor, truth and conscience are wrecked one by one. " Their end is destruction." 0 how many of the
                            young are drawn by the enticing charm of sensuality into the vortex of ruin ! though they never suspected it was
                            taking them thither, nor intended that it should. It presents itself to them, under various disguises, so that
                            they seem not aware of its-true character. Now, it is the nerve-exciting and brain-bewildering drink; and now,
                            it is the excitement of the licentious passion. But it always leads its victims downward to the pit of darkness
                            and death. And what a destruction is theirs ! What ruin of high hopes and glorious promises! what worse than
                            mere waste, what consumption of the physical powers, what desolation of heart and brain, are often beheld while
                            yet life remains to the wretched ones ! What dreadful wreck of intellectual faculties, which were designed for
                            the happiness and glory of the individual, and to contribute to the well-being of others! What wide-spread
                            desolation among the moral powers, that should have allied him so closely to all that is holy ! Is it not
                            destruction indeed, that those capable of attaining to so much that is pure and elevating in every possible
                            sense, should have rendered themselves incapable of it, and have become cniy fit for the opposite? How
                            delightful to the pure <pb n="13" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE 13 heart and sound mind, is the thought of a Supreme
                            Intelligence, possessed of every possible perfection; of the pure occupants of a world of beauty and grandeur,
                            living together in love, peace and perpetual harmony—but characters directly the opposite of these, how dreadful
                            to contemplate ! Yet of the latter, there are multitudes even, upon the earth, who have been led to their
                            deplorable condition through their indulgence in a sensual life. This is a world clothed in beauty for man's
                            sake; and had he lived, and did he still live in accordance with the highest laws of his being, it would be a
                            world of perpetual charm to all, instead of being, as it frequently is to many, a prison, a dungeon, a pest
                            house, physically and morally. The convictions of our reason confirm the opinion that this would be a world of
                            happiness to us all, even though trials and sorrows might be necessary for our perfection, if we were all
                            careful to maintain the eternal laws of rectitude. But now the wail of woe and despair ascends from many a heart
                            that finds no rest. " Their tears are their meat, day and night"— tears of anguish forced from them, because of
                            violated law; and not those of gratitude for blessings daily received and enjoyed, nor those of satisfaction in
                            the way of self-denial, or in the daily discharge of duties that are always attended with pleasure, however
                            exacting of patience and perseverance, and the exercise of every faculty. These faculties lie in ruin; and in
                            the abyss of misery where they are, they bewail their neglect of reproof, from friends and their own conscience.
                            They " have wor- shipped the beast," sensuality. Instead of enduring the cross of Christ, and despising the
                            shame, they have despised the cross, and are now enduring the shame and wretchednoss resulting from perverting
                            the ways of life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., W. H." TEIform="persName"/>W. H. B.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>JUVENILE DEPARTMENT</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dialogue" TEIform="index"/>A Dialogue</head><p TEIform="p">Written for, and rehearsed at an Annual Social Gathering, in Canaan Pine Grove, N. Y., by Ann, Martha, Mary
                                J., Charlotte, Melissa, Margaret, Sarah and Catharine. (Continued.") M.—Tn connection with our subject there
                                are three words I would like to ask the meaning of; they are Agriculture, Horticulture and Aboriculture.
                                Mar.—I should think you would know the meaning of Agriculture, as we have dwelt on that subject some time.
                                M.—I want to know the direct significance of the term in connection with the others. Mar.—Agriculture is the
                                broad term for the cultivation of the farm. It is the art of tilling and manuring the ground; and consisting
                                in sowing, mowing, reaping, &amp;c, also the management of different soils, and the cultivatioi of
                                forest timber. It is said that the highes encomium that could be given to a man o Rome, was, that he
                                cultivated his own spot o ground well! The most illustrious among hem applied themselves to it, and their
                                dictaors were taken from the plow. C.—Horticulture is simply the art ofculti"ating gardens.
                                Mary—Aboriculture is the art of cultivating rees and shrubs. S.—As you have introduced the subject of
                                Aboriculture, I would be pleased to know omething in reference to trees; I could scarcely tell the names of
                                those under whose oroad canopj^ ^e are now so nicely sheltered (looking up), but, I believe I do know the
                                beautiful maple, the stately pine, and a few others. A.—It is necessarj^, not only to know trees by their
                                leaves, but by the formation of their bark, their texture, grain of their wood and ;heir uses. Char.—I think
                                that Sarah will have to ap3ly to Mary for information, as she, unlike ner companions, always lived on
                                woodland, where she undoubtedly acquired a knowledge of trees which we have not. Mary.—'Tis true, that, Away
                                from artificial life— Far from the city's din and strife, I had a home 'mid forests grand, The beauteous
                                works of nature's hand; There 'neath the leafy bower I often strayed, And some acquaintance with the trees
                                have made. Xor is my homeless beautiful now, although more in the region of cultivation ; and I purposely
                                selected some leaves, which I will present to see if any or all could tell the names of the trees from which
                                they were gathered. (They are passed around, the names are all told). S.—I do not know all of them, but
                                recognize the leaves of the fruit trees. M.—I know more of the leaves, than I should of the wood, if you had
                                brought specimens. Mary.—We will no doubt feel an increasing interest in the study of aboriculture, and may
                                pursue it to some extent, in examining trees and shrubs. A.— Very litt'e I know on the subject, but an
                                interest is being awakened in my mind, especially as our home is becoming more and more beautified, by the
                                increase of forest and shade trees, which have been set out within a few years. Our Union Grove seems to be
                                an object of admiration, so rapid is its growth under the care and culture of its guardian. Martha.—It might
                                properly be called an Arboretum ; but we prefer calling it by the simple name of Union Grove. I have been
                                located on the cast side of the dwelling ever since the first saplings were set out (bean poles we called
                                them), so meagre was their appearance, and even thought it would be a good plan to set some scarlet runners
                                around them to relieve the monotony of the scene, anc then it would be a point of economy in saving the
                                gardener's labor ; at the same time using the soil, for we were certain that the trees would never come to
                                anything! But good Elder Frederick Evans never entertained such an idea; he set them out to grow, and grow
                                they did, luxuriantly ! Bathed in the morning sunlight, watered by frequent showers, and under careful
                                cultivation, they have attained a surprising growth, being interspersed with a variety of fruit and forest
                                trees equally thrifty. I almost imagine, sometimes, that a miniature Eden is before me. Contemplating the
                                scene one beautiful Sabbath morning, I penned the following lines, which (if you would like to hear them) I
                                will ask Margaret to read. All.—(We would.) Mar.—I can repeat them— (She repeats)—" I have watched, with
                                interest, the growth of yonder tree, since first transplanted, a sapling, from its native forest. It was set
                                with care in its new abode; down in the soil its fibrous roots struck deeply, and coursed their way around
                                the crevices of rocks and through the fallow ground. Nurtured by frequent showers, the broad, free sunlight
                                and a healthy atmosphere, its branches spread with rapid growth, and each successive year increased to
                                profusion the richest foliage. Oft has the pruning knife, in the hands of the careful cultivator, lopped the
                                surplus twigs, that it might attain symmetr}r of form and strength of limb. Xow, how beautiful to behold !
                                supple in every part, yielding to the gentle zephyrs, each leaf with graceful motion moves; or 'neath the
                                power of the mighty wind, its strongest branches bow submissively. Amid its leafy bowers the songsters of
                                the woods carol their sweetest notes, to cheer the heart and gladden the pathway of life. 0 home of mine!
                                how many joys surround thee. I thank God that my soul has been transplanted from without the wilderness of
                                nature into thy blessed soil, and, as the material elements cause the growth and development of the natural
                                plant, so may the rains of heaven, the sunlight of truth, and the spiritual atmosphere of purity and love,
                                cause my soul to grow and expand in the divine life." Char.—You have portrayed the beauties of the hillside
                                vividly. Its infancy contrasts strangely with that grand old forest above it; I know it presents a most,
                                enchanting, lovely sight. But, Martha, I am astonished—I thought your ideas were more general; but, from
                                your remarks, I conclude that you have confined your observation to one treeonty. I should be glad to see
                                the tree that has called forth such rich effusions as we have been favored to hear." Mar.—I should, too. I
                                have never been able to ascertain which one it was. Martha.—That wras but expressive of the whole scene, and
                                I have gathered leaves of the various trees composing the grove—fifty varieties—and have learned most of
                                their names; these I have brought for our pleasure and instruction. (A folio is now exhibited with leaves
                                arj ranged in order, and names attached. They are examined by the company with remarks on their beauty, the
                                fineness of their texture, the variety of forms, shades of color, &amp;c.; they then are set aside for
                                future examination.)</p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">'he SHAKES is offered to Subscribers at cost price, and only needs to be read to be appreciated.</p></div2><pb n="14" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>MISCELLANEOUS</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker sermon, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Sermon—No. 1</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Eades, H. L." TEIform="persName"/>H. L. EADES, SOUTH UNION, KENTUCKY</byline><p TEIform="p">I begin my discourse to-day with the enunciation of two or three aphorisms; neither of which, I presume, any
                                honest, unbiased mind of ordinary comprehension will have an inclination to gainsay; they consist of a
                                simple declaration of the harmony of truth. 1st. All truths harmonize, spiritual and natural; one truth
                                cannot be opposed to another truth; hence, any two statements or propositions that antagonize or conflict,
                                one or the other, or both must be false. 2d. In the end, nothing but truth will have been or can be
                                advantageous to any soul; hence, it would be wisdom in us to cast off all prejudice and prepossession, and
                                make any required sacrifice to obtain the " knowledge of the truth," especially that sacred truth by which
                                we expect to obtain our redemption and the salvation of the soul. It is necessary that some of our
                                discourses should be mainly argumentative or theological, from the fact, that mere declaration of truth,
                                scriptural or otherwise, does not in this day seem to satisfy the inquisitive mind, and people must learn to
                                think correctly before they can either speak or act correctly. "Well nigh two centuries ago a certain
                                philosopher penned the following: 1st. That a man use no words but such as he makes the sign of a certain
                                determined object in his mind in thinking, which he can make known to another. 2d. That he use the same word
                                steadily for the sign of the same immediate object of his mind in thinking. 3d. That he join those words
                                together in propositions, according to the grammatical rules of the language he speaks in. 4th. That he
                                unites those sentences into a coherent discourse. Thus, and thus only, I humbly conceive, any one may
                                preserve himself from the confines and suspicions of jargon. Were all men to observe this rule, which I most
                                sincerely approve, there would be but little difference among men on any subject; with their terms clearly
                                denned, strictly applied and adhered to, no two really honest men can very widely differ ; each would yield
                                in turn in theology and ethics, just as they are compelled to do in mathematics. Every rational creature
                                will admit that the salvation of the soul is, or should be, paramount to every earthly consideration
                                whatever, and he who fails in the attainment of this, fails in all, and he who is fortunate enough to secure
                                this, lacks in nothing that is worth contending for : " For what is a man profited if he shall gain the
                                whole world and lose his own soul ? or what shall a man give in exchange for his soul?" Matt, xvi: 26.
                                Since, then, from these words of our Saviour, a man's soul is of more value to him than all worlds beside,
                                he ought to be willing to forsake the world, with all its habits, customs, maxims, and practices, for his
                                soul's sake. It appears that this globe now contains over 1,000,000,000 souls, and there are 1,100 dif-
                                ferent religions; one creed, if I may so speak, for every hundred millions, differing from all the rest;
                                and, as there cannot be but one right way, a hollow cry comes up from the " vasty deep," asking which one of
                                the 1,100 is right; because any line diverging in the minutest degree from the right one viust be wrong, and
                                the further it is traveled the more distant the traveler will be from the right way. Hence it becomes a
                                matter of the utmost importance for each one to know he is right—not to guess at it, but know it. You will
                                ask me, then, if there is any possibility of acquiring this knowledge. To which 1 give an affirmative
                                answer. In the words of the Saviour, as to doctrine, he says : " My doctrine is not mine, but his that sent
                                me. If any man will do his will, he shall knoiv of the doctrine whether it be of God," &amp;c. Matt,
                                iii: 8. Not guess at it, but know. As to his true disciples and followers, he has given us one criterion or
                                mark—and one only—by which they are to be known—" Ye shall know them by their fruits. Do men gather grapes
                                of thorns or figs of thistles ?" But after all this, and without troubling yourselves to look into the
                                different sects for the good fruits, which are the only real evidence, you rest in your easy chair, simply
                                saying you know, The Good must merit God's peculiar care, Yet who but God can tell us which they are ? thus
                                giving evidence of one of two conditions, viz: Your own lukewarmness and lack of interest in your soul's
                                salvation, or your infidelity respecting the existence of any religious body where those fruits can be found
                                ; and some of you, when you have found the fruits and acknowledge them, then fault the doctrine —at the same
                                time acknowledge you do not keep the commandments of God; and it is only such that should know of the
                                doctrines or should presume to judge them. Nearly all men agree that among the thousand different forms of
                                religious belief, some one must be right, and as before said, the consequence is, that every other one that
                                essentially differs, must be wrong, and inadequate to the purposes of salvation. Every religious system has
                                for its foundation or formation, some reference to a Supreme Being or Beings, who is, or are, able to reward
                                them for well doing, and punish them for evil doing; and as this seems to be the beginning of religion
                                itself, I propose to offer a few remarks on this subject. I shall try to remember what I said in the
                                beginning, respecting the necessity of having distinct ideas in the mind, defining terms, &amp;c, for I
                                by no means wish to leave the thoughtful part of the audience, especially, in the dark respecting my own
                                position. Leaving, for the present, all others aside, I bring myself to the ground called Christian, whose
                                religious systems have taken form from this book—the old and new Testaments, and so multiplied are the forms
                                derived from the same reading, that it seems almost to justify the remark, that Faith, gospel, all seemed
                                made to be disputed, And none had sense enough to be confuted. I am not so uncharitable as to conclude that
                                this state of things has arisen entirely from the dishonesty of the race, but rather more from education,
                                prepossession, and a want of distinct ideas, clear definition of terms, and their consistent application.
                                Every critical Bible student cannot fail to have taken cognizance of this truth: that throughout sacred
                                writ, God is spoken of in two senses, the infinite and the finite, or subordinate sense. Thus, whenever God
                                is spoken of as coming, going, traveling personally from one place to another, it then must be under- stood
                                in the finite or subordinate sense; because in this sense he is considered as being less than something
                                else. If he travel, there must be some place where he is not, to which, he is going; hence, he must be
                                circumscribed. We cannot help associating with such being, the idea of extension, figure, size,
                                &amp;c.—such as angel or man. Also, when God is represented as having forgotten something, not knowing,
                                or changing his mind or purpose, it is understood as speaking of God subordinate, not infinite. Of the
                                Infinite, or Supreme Being, it is truly said, "His purposes alter not —He is without change or shadow of
                                turning." The same holy writ makes the distinction clear by the saying of Christ, when accused by the Jews
                                of making himself God. He showed them that they were " called gods unto whom the word of God came." Moses
                                was God to the children of Israel in this subordinate sense : " And the Lord said unto Moses, see, I have
                                made thee a God to Pharaoh ; and Aaron, thy brother, shall be thy prophet," &amp;c. Exodus vii: 1.
                                Joshua was called Jehovah— Elijah, God the Lord, &amp;c. To the careful reader, the distinction is
                                clear. But God, when spoken of as " the All and in all," " in whom we live and move and have our being," He
                                is then understood as the " Eternal Unity," the "Infinite Jehovah," and he it is whom we have assembled here
                                to-day to worship, and Him only. Almost without exception, every intelligent, unbiased mind with whom I have
                                come in contact, acknowledges that God, in the supreme sense, is Infinite Spirit—indivisible, immutable,
                                uncaused, selfexistent, omniscient, and omnipresent—filling immensity—the creator and arbiter of the
                                universe, permeating all worlds and all existences at all times, which removes the necessity of his going
                                and coming. But, strange as it must appear, many good-meaning persons, after this admission, stultify
                                themselves by admitting a plurality of supremes or divisibility in the Su- preme, to favor some theological
                                dogma or scheme of redemption they have fixed in their own minds, or others have fixed for them. Tho merest
                                tyro, having taken but his first lesson in inductive philosophy, cannot help realizing the fact that an
                                infinite existence is indivisible. Truth never conflicts. The term infinite signifies without bounds. This
                                seems to be either forgotten or ignored. We say of space that it is infinite, but draw a line through it; we
                                then have two finite spaces, when infinite space disappears. I know it may be argued that a line beginning
                                at a given point and extending in any direction without end, may be called an infinite line, and that this
                                idea might, by parity of reason, be applied to dividing space; 14 <pb n="15" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHA.KER. 15 and
                                even should this be conceded as sound reasoning, which I deny, the same cannot be applied to an infinite
                                being or existence. Thus, I think it clearly demonstrates that such a thing as an infinite plurality, or
                                plurality of infinites, is impossible. I am aware that we are believed to hold to the dogma of duality in in
                                deity, male and female (!) I will try to clear this point. It is admitted by us all that the attributes
                                ascribed to Deity, some are considered masculine, some feminine; and hence comes the idea of father and
                                mother of the universe. We admit the revelation of these attributes of the Eternal Unity by son and
                                daughter; that is to say, God as Father, or the fatherly character of God was revealed by the Son, Christ
                                Jesus, and God us. mother, or the motherly character of God was revealed by the daughter {Ann Lee). Thus,
                                "God manifest in the flesh;" not of man only, but also of woman, male and female, constitute the duality of
                                God, and dual only in this subordinate sense. Being equally manifest in and through finite human beings, who
                                are dual, male and female. Thus the apparently con- flicting ideas of unity and duality are reconciled. In
                                this I can perceive nothing irrational, nothing but what any dispassionate, reasonable mind would readily
                                admit. I will, however, very frankly admit, that for any man to declare that God in the highest sense was
                                the Eternal Unity, and afterwards declare that He was the Eternal Duality, or Eternal Trinity (Eternal
                                Three), that such man would stultify himself because either of the latter would precisely negative the
                                former, and we should not know at last what man did believe. These two ideas of unity and plurality in the
                                supreme and infinite sense, would constitute a formidable and an irreconcilable feature in the theology of
                                any man or sect. I fully concur in the remarks of John Locke on this subject. ** Every deity that men own
                                above one is an infallible evidence of their ignorance of him, and a proof that they have no true notion of
                                God (in the highest sense) where unity, infiniity, and eternity are excluded." But if, as Christ says, "they
                                were called gods, unto whom the word of God came, that the scriptures might not be broken," I have no
                                difficulty in applying this high term in the subordinate sense to the Son of God. Nor would I exclude
                                Jeremiah from among the number of the " prophets of the Lord," for applying the same high title to the
                                daughter. " This is the name whereby she shall be called. The Lord our righteousness." Jer. xxxiii: 16.
                                Perhaps I have drawn too largely on your patience, but I wished to make a fair beginning, to leave no one in
                                the dark, to carp at our doctrines without understanding them We claim that the son and daughter already
                                named now stand at the head of the new creation of God, and we, their children, in the "unity of the spirit
                                and bond of peace," are striving to follow their example, by obeying their teaching and walking as they
                                walked and by so doing have found that peace which this world can neither give nor take away and may become
                                " heirs and joint heirs witl Christ," who has said: " Be of good cheer br I have overcome the world;" the
                                "prince of this world cometh and hath nothing in me; " ' and to him that overcometh will I grant to sit with
                                me in my throne, as I also overcome, and am sit down with my Father in his throne." Rev. iii: 21. These are
                                the great and glorious promises to all who will take up a daily cross and follow Christ in the regeneration
                                ; not generation, but regeneration; not to those who have a blind faith in his atoning blood and still lead
                                a worldly life, but it is to those who 'c walked even as he walked," and have followed him in the
                                regeneration. And the invitation is now extended to every sinsick soul; to everyone who "panteth after
                                righteousness as the hart for the waterbrook " we say come, " without money or without price," and "partake
                                of the waters of life freely," for now has come salvation, and the kingdom of our God and the power of
                                Christ.</p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If all should be shakers" TEIform="index"/>"If All Should be Shakers."</head><p TEIform="p">Are the Shakers running the world out ? The assertion has been made so frequently, that it is a matter of
                                moment to know of its truth. Regardless of the number of population, the Shakers have maintained their
                                testimony of celibacy, since the days of their founder—Ann Lee; with a knowledge, that to " come down from
                                this cross, might cause all men to believe on them," yet with the certain presentation, that to do so, would
                                pull from under the Christian character, its prime virtue—its foundation. We are aware that it is the duty
                                of the followers of the first Adam to replenish the earth; in the fullest meaning of that word—to give glory
                                unto God in the perfect fruits of their bodies. We are as fully aware that duty calls on the disciples of
                                the second Adam—" The Lord from heaven, a quickening spirit," to rise up from the earthly plane of physical
                                production and reproduction, and cultivate a life that has an eternal character. Reproduction is an earthly
                                practice and duty; to those who choose to remain on this low plane, they are welcome to all the pleasure it
                                affords them—the pleasure is earthly, transient, not heavenly, eternal. Connected with the duty of earthly
                                beings, " to replenish and subdue the earth," is the requirement that their reproductions shall be an honor
                                to the father and the mother engaged in this earthly avocation ; to be such, it is necessary that parents
                                present to the earth only " sound minds in healthy bodies;" every chile born and to be born, has this right
                                of demand upon its progenitors. Is tlii demand complied with generally or particularly ? We say not; and if
                                we are right in so judging, the present reproductions of humanity do not replenish the earth, but tend to
                                deteriorate the race— "run the world out!" But were we al able to produce, through our generations,
                                &gt;erfect specimens of humanity, this would &gt;e no argument that we should engage in t as long
                                and as fully as our ability would permit. The child of nature ceases after a time to be a child, and dons
                                the character of naturity. The child of the Spirit grows out of and above the pleasures snd employments of
                                the child of earth, and finds superior joys in the exercise of its eternal affections. What once appeared as
                                duty, repixjduction, ceases to be such ; and a new element being found, regeneration, a degradation is
                                experienced in retreating back to the elements and practices of an earthly being. " He that is down," on the
                                plane of sensuality, " needs fear no fall from it;" but those who, having tasted of the powers of the world
                                to come, who like Jesus have been taught of a superior way, resurrected thereto, and experience eternal
                                life, oh, what a fall is theirs, to return, like a dog to his vomit, to engage in the practices of a being
                                beneath them ! Marriage is honorable, but not Christian. Marriage is believed by multitudes to be
                                God-ordained for the replenishing of the earth. Let its advocates carefully carry out the provision, in all
                                conscience, agreeably to the Mosaic statutes, then are they good Jews. But there is no law that can make
                                them Christians—even . poor Christians ! If the Shakers, by abstaining from marriage *' are running the
                                world out," let it run; we think Christianity a preferable institution—as Jesus is more honorable than Adam;
                                and when the charge of running the world out rises in the mind as an argument against Shakerism, let
                                crusaders think how much more populous the earth would be, if all should live the life of that Christian
                                exemplar, saying naught of the poor, despised Shakers. *</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is no more than bare justice to say, that we are indebted to the Shakers..." TEIform="index"/>It is no more than bare justice to say, that we are indebted to the Shakers...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"It is no more than bare justice to say, that we are indebted to the Shakers, more than any or all other
                                social architects of modern times. Their success has been the ' specie basis' that has upheld all the paper
                                theories, and counteracted the failures of the French and English schools. It is very doubtful, whether
                                Owenism or Fourierism would have ever existed, or if they had, whether they would have moved the practical
                                American mind, if the facts of Shakerism had not existed before them. While we say the Rappites, the
                                Zoarites, the Ebenezers, Owenites, and even the Fourierists are all echoes of the Shakers, we must also say
                                that the Shakers are the far-off echoes of the Primitive Christian Church."</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Noyes, J. H." TEIform="persName"/>J. H. Noyes</byline></div3><pb n="16" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Concise statement" TEIform="index"/>A Concise Statement</head><p TEIform="p">{Concluded.') They that believed in Christ's gospel, and were obedient to that form of doctrine which was
                                taught them ; by denying all ungodliness and worldly lusts; and became entirely dead to the law by the body
                                of Christ, or power of the Holy Ghost, were in the travail of the resurrection from the dead; or the
                                redemption of the body. So that they who took up a full cross against the world, flesh, and devil, and who
                                forsook all for Christ's sake, and followed him in the regeneration, by persevering in that line of
                                obedience to the end, found the resurrection from the dead, and eternal salvation in that dispensation; but
                                as the measure of that dispensation was only as water to the loins, the mystery of God not finished ; but
                                there was another day prophe- sied of, called the second appearance of Christ, or final and last display of
                                God's grace to a lost world: in which the mystery of God should be finished as he has spoken by his prophets
                                since the world began : which day could not come, except there was a falling away from that faith and power
                                that the church then stood in; in which time antichrist was to have his reign, whom Christ should destroy
                                with the spirit of his mouth and brightness of his appearance : which falling away began soon after the
                                apostles, and gradually increased in the church, until about four hundred and fifty-seven years from
                                Christ's birth, or thereabouts, at which time the power of the Holy People, or church of Christ, was
                                scattered or lost by reason of transgression: and antichrist, or false religion became established. Since
                                that time the witnesses of Christ have prophesied in sackloth or under darkness; and altho' many have been
                                faithful to testify against sin, even to the laying down of their lives for the testi- mony which they held,
                                so that God accepted them in their obedience: while they were faithful and just to live or walk up to the
                                measure of light and truth of God, revealed or made known unto them, but as it is written, that all they
                                that will live godly in Christ Jesus, shall suffer persecution : and so it has been, and those faithful
                                witnesses lost their lives by those falsely called the church of Christ: which is antichrist; for the true
                                church of Christ never persecuted any; but were inoffensive, harmless, separate from sin : for the true
                                church of Christ taking up their cross against the world, flesh, and devil, and all sin, living in obedience
                                to God, they earnestly contend for the same. Therefore it may be plainly seen and known, where the true
                                church of Christ is : but as it is written, antichrist or false churches should prevail against the saints
                                and overcome them before Christ's second appearance, 2 Thess. ii, 3. Let no man deceive you by any means,
                                for that day shall not come except there come a falling away first; and that man of sin be revealed, ths son
                                of perdition, Rev. xiii: 7. And it was given unto him to overcome them, and power was given him over all
                                kindreds, tongues, and nations; and this is the state Christ prophesied the world of mankind should be in,
                                at his second appearance, Luke xvii. 26. And as it was in the dayofNoe, so shall it be in the days of the
                                Son of Man, verse 30. Even so shall it be in the day when the Son of Man is revealed : plainly referring to
                                his second appearance to consume or destroy antichrist, and make a final end of sin, and establish his
                                kingdom upon earth: but as the revelation of Christ must be in his people, whom he had chosen to be his
                                body, to give testimony of him and to preach his gospel to a lost world. 4th. The fourth dispensation or day
                                is the second appearance of Christ, or final, or last display of God's grace to a lost world, in which the
                                mystery of God will be finished and a decisive work, to the final salvation, or damnation of all the
                                children of men : which according to the prophecies rightly calculated, and truly understood, began in the
                                year of our Saviour Jesus Christ, 1747. See Daniel and the Revelations. In the manner follow- ing, 1st. To a
                                number, in the manifestation of great light and mighty trembling by the invisible power of God, and visions,
                                and revelations, and prophecies which has progressively increased, with administration of all those
                                spiritual gifts, that were administered to the apostles at the day of pentecost : which is the comforter
                                that has led us into all truth : which was promised to abide with the true church of Christ unto the end of
                                the world, and by which we find baptism into Christ's death; death to all sin, become alive to God, by the
                                power of Christ's resurrection which worketh in us mightily; by which a dispensation of the gospel is
                                committed unto us ; and woe be unto us if we preach not the gospel of Christ. For in finding so great a
                                salvation and deliverance from the law of sin and death in believing and obeying this gospel which is the
                                gospel of Christ, in confessing and forsaking all sin and denying ourselves and bearing the cross of Christ,
                                against the world, flesh, and devil. We have found repentance of all our sins; and are made partakers of the
                                grace of God wherein we now stand : which all others in believing and obeying, have acceptance with God, and
                                find salvation from their sins as well as we; God being no respecter of persons, but willing that all should
                                come to the knowledge of the truth, and be saved. Thus we have given a short information of what we believe
                                of the dispensations of God's grace to mankind, both past and present: and in what manner the people of God
                                have found justifi- cation or acceptance with God, which was and is still in believing and obeying the light
                                and truth of God, revealed or made known in the day or dispensation in which it is revealed: for as the
                                wrath of God is revealed from heaven against all ungodliness, and unrighteousness of men, who hold the truth
                                in unrighteousness or live in any known sin against him; so his mercy and grace is towards all them that
                                truly fear him, and turn from all their sins, by confessing, forsaking, and repenting, which is the way and
                                manner in which all must find the forgiveness of their sins, and acceptance with God thro' our Lord Jesus
                                Christ, or finally fail of the grace of God; and that salvation which is brought to light by the gospel. But
                                to conclude, in short, as we believe, and do testify, that the present gospel of God's grace unto us is the
                                day which in the scripture, is spoken or prophesied of, as the second appearing of Christ to consume or
                                destroy antichrist, or false religion, and to make an end of the reigning power of sin (for he that
                                commiteth sin is the servant of sin and Satan) over the children of men : and to establish his kingdom, and
                                that righteousness that will stand forever: and that the present display of the work and power of God, will
                                increase until it is manifest to all; which it must be in due time: for erery eye shall see him ; and he
                                will reward every man according to his deeds : and none can stand in sin or unrighteousness, but in that
                                righteousness which is pure and holy; even without fault before the throne of God which is obtained by
                                grace, through faith in obedience to the truth of the everlasting gospel of our Lord Jesus Christ, in
                                denying all ungodliness and worldly lusts; by confessing all sin, and taking up the cross of Christ, against
                                the world, flesh, and devil.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M., J." TEIform="persName"/>"J. M., 1798."</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker, monthly journal, devoted to the exposition of religion, acording to Shaker theology" TEIform="index"/>THE
                            SHAKER. MONTHLY JOURNAL, DEVOTED TO THE EXPOSITION OF RELIGION, ACCORDING TO SHAKER THEOLOGY.</head><p TEIform="p">Fifty Cents, Pee Annum, m Advance. Address, G. A. Lomas, Resident Editor. Shakers, Albany, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Members of society" TEIform="index"/>MEMBERS OF SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p">Appointed to answer Correspondents, among whom are the Board of .Editors. Elder F. W. Evans, Mt. Lebanon^
                            Columbia Co., N. Y. " Issachar Bates, Shakers, Albany, N. Y. " C. E. Sears, Mt. Morris, Livingston Co., N. Y. "
                            Simon Mabee, West Pittsfield, Mass. " Stonghton Kellogg, Thompsonville, Conn., Shakers. " Albert Battles,
                            Tyringham, Berkshire Co., Mass. " Wm. Leonard, Groton Junction, Mass., Shakers. " John White!ey, Shirley
                            Village, Middlesex Co., .Mass. " Nehemiah Trull, Shaker "Village, Merrimack Co., N. H. " Henry Cummings,
                            Enfield, Grafton Co., N. H. " John B. Vance, Alfred, Shakers, York Co., Me. " Alonzo Gilman, West Gloucester,
                            Cumberland Co., Me., Shakers. " O. C. Hampton. Union Village, Warren Co.. O., Shakers. " Ezra Sherman, Preston,
                            Hamilton Co., Ohio, Shakers. " Stephen Ball, "Dayton, Shakers, Ohio. " George Kunyon, Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co.,
                            Ky. " J. 11. Eades, South Union, Logan Co., Ky. " J. S. Prescott, Cleveland. Ohio, Shakers.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publications" TEIform="index"/>PUBLICATIONS.</head><p TEIform="p">Christ's First and Second Appearing Dunlavy's Manifesto .... Millennial Church .."¦...« Compendium of Shaker ism
                            Three Discourses on United Interests - Tracts free, where postage is paid. $1 25 1 25 1 00 0 50 0 50</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>