<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2901" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">29</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18990101" TEIform="date">January 1899</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-16</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="29" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                        <pb n="t.p." id="p1"/>
                        THE MANIFESTO 1899. A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE SHAKERS. Just Published. The book is printed with large type and on
                        excellent paper. It contains 130 pages and has ILLUSTRATIONS of the Sbakeks and their The work gives quite an
                        extended account of the Several SOCIETIES, their organization and general management. Price, 50 cts. BRIEF
                        EXPOSITION OF THE Principles and Regulations of the SOCIETY OF BELIEVERS. Price, 10 cts. A SUMMARY VIEW OF THE
                        MILLENNIAL CHURCH, OR "United Society of Believers" It treats of the Rise and Progress of the Society, together with
                        the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony. Price, 50 els. THE ALTRUIST. Is a monthly paper, partly in
                        Phonetic spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and equal rights to all. It is
                        publisht by the Altruist Community, whose members all live and work together, and hold all their property in common,
                        all the men and women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by their majority
                        vote. It now has 5,000 acres of land in Southeast Missouri on which it offers a home and employment for life to all
                        acceptable persons who may wish to join it. 50 cents a year; specimen copy free. Address A. Longley, 19 28 Olive St.
                        St. Louis, Mo. AND SHAKERISM. By Giles B. Avert. Price, 15 cts.
                        --><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><pb n="0" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books &amp; Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cosmopolitan" TEIform="index"/>The Cosmopolitan Magazine
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"What do I fear?" Is a question worth asking by each man or woman. Perhaps without recognizing it the reader
                                of this paragraph is being influenced in his ov her daily life by groundless fears that are ruinous to
                                character. The Cosmopolitan Magazine has taken up this subject and is obtaining the views of a great many
                                prominent people, where they are willing to open their minds frankly. A great ¦many other prominent people
                                have refused The Cosmopolitan's request, being afraid to tell the public what they fear—perhaps even afraid
                                to confess to themselves what they fear. The December issue includes statements from Wm. Dean Howells,
                                Richard Choker, Admiral Ghkrakdi, Chauncey M. Depew, Viola Allen, Mne. Janauechekand Ella Wheeler Wilcox.
                                The second series will, it is promist be even more interesting. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Leavitt's farmer's almanac for 1899" TEIform="index"/>Leavitt's Farmer's Almanac for 1899
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Leavitt's Farmer's Almanac for 1899.
                                Publisht by Edson C. Eastman, Concord, N. H. More than a century has already past since Dudley Leavitt sent
                                out the first copy of his now indispensable Almanac. It has become a household companion, an oracle for
                                consultation by those who travel by land or sea, or by those who remain quietly in their own homes. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kingdom of Heaven is at hand" TEIform="index"/>The
                                Kingdom of Heaven is at Hand
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wooldridge, C. W." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The
                                Kingdom of Heaven is at Hand by C. W. Wooldiiilge, M. D. The book is publisht in the interest of the
                                Cooperative Commonwealth, and as it is very interesting and instructive a great many persons will take
                                pleasure in reading it. Publisht by Charles H. Kerr &amp; Co. 56 Fifth Ave., Chicago, 111.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Uncle Ike's idees" TEIform="index"/>Uncle Ike's
                                Idees
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Miller, George McA." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Uncle Ike's
                                Idees by George McA. Miller. This is in theinterest of the Co-operative Commonwealth but the author has
                                taken the happy view of writing his little book of sixty pages in verse. Uncle Ike reads the Bible and so
                                does Parson Toady, but they do not see eye to eye in regard to it. Publisnt by Charles H. Kerr &amp; Co.
                                Chicago, 111. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Word and works" TEIform="index"/>Word and Works
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Annual Almanac and monthly paper, Word and Works, are now known from sea to sea. We are
                                pleased to call the attention of our readers to the Almanac for 1899, now ready. It is a splendidly printed
                                and illustrated book of 116 pages and the storm forecasts and diagrams and astronomical and scientific
                                matter are Superior to anything that has ever been seen before in a 25 cent book. His monthly journal, Word
                                and Works, is one of the best literary, home and scientific magazines in the country, besides containing his
                                monthly storm forecasts with explanations. The subscription price of Word and works is $1 per year and a
                                copy of the Hicks Almanac is sent as a premium to every yearly subscriber. Single copies of Word and Works,
                                10 cents. Price of Almanac alone, 25 cents. Send your order to Word and Works Pub, Co., 2201 Loctiit Street,
                                St. Louis, Mo. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Popular monthly" TEIform="index"/>Popular Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The complete story of the sinking of the Merrimac and the capture and imprisonment of her
                                crew at Santiago, will be graphically told in an article by Osborn W. Deignan, U. S. Navy, late helmsman of
                                the Merrimac, in the January Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly, now ten cents, and to be publisht December
                                24th. The story will be fully and richly illustrated with authentic portraits of Hobson and all the crew,
                                besides many new drawings specially prepared under Mr. Deignan's personal supervision. Other features
                                promist for the January Frank Leslie's are: Bret Harte's new story. Jack Hamlin's Meditatit n; Joaquin
                                Miller's In a Klondike Cabin; and Thomas B. Dawley's Campaigning with Gomez. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>The Ladies' Home Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mrs. Ballington Booth, of "The
                                American Volunteers," is writing out her experiences in American prisons, and in the slums of New York, for
                                The Ladies' Home Journal. Mrs. Booth has perhaps come closer to the lives and confidences of the men and
                                women in prisons, and to know the poor better, than any woman living. She will not only tell what she has
                                seen, but she will point out wThat her experience has shown her to be the most effective way in dealing with
                                the people of the prisons and the slums.</p></div3></div2><!--
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>WOVUL strange REVELATIONS, -EXPLAINING^ DANIEL'S & STJOHN'S PROPHECIES. 48 page pamphlet. Price 10 cts.
                            13 for $1.00. Address, H. B. Beak, Preston, Ohio. "INTERPRETING PROPHECY" AND THE "Appearing of Christ," is the
                            title of a neat little pamphlet of some forty pages, just sent out by A. G. Hollistee of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. The
                            many at the present time who are interested in the fulfillment of prophecy, and in its mathematical calculation,
                            will find themselves by the side of the good old prophet Daniel, and with him illustrating the Coming of Christ
                            so clearly that no occasion can arise for the least doubt. Price, 10 cts.</p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="1" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><pb n="2" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><pb n="3" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New book" TEIform="index"/>A NEW BOOK</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Evans, Jessie" TEIform="persName"/>Jessie Evans</byline><p TEIform="p">WEARY of the blotted page, the frequent mistakes, the unsatisfactory penmanship and the war of words over irksome
                            subjects, the child in the schoolroom hurries to pen the last word on the last line of the closing page, and
                            with a sigh of relief turns to the teacher that he may receive the promised "new book." How lovingly he fondles
                            it, how especially attractive seem the clean pages in contrast with the soiled ones so willingly hidden from
                            view, and how restfully he settles his little mechanism of brain and body to transcribe upon the first page
                            something "just perfect—my very best, teacher!" Just so, methinks, it is with us in this larger schoolroom of
                            ours. The volumes of our life are handed to us one by one by the great Guide of human destinies, and whether we
                            approach our daily lessons cheerfully or reluctantly, write we must—just so much each day. If the human side
                            revolts in its submission, there is an invisible current within that, tho involuntarily, throbs to the
                            inexorable will of the great Law-giver. So, as the moments slip by, their record glides into place; as thoughts
                            rush through the mind, each registers itself upon the unerring bathometer; tho words take wing, their vibrations
                            touch the life page as they pass and the key-note records its true or false ring; each heart throb takes up a
                            little space in this strange volume —thus our history files itself away where the "angel of the years" stands
                            guard. <pb n="4" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 4 THE MANIFESTO. We have all been at these varied tasks from day to day, the once
                            spotless leaves of the 1898 issue are spotless no longer. Strange events, unlookt-for pleasures, weary trials,
                            sincere resolutions quickly formed and as quickly broken, conclusions unwillingly accepted yet nobly maintained,
                            hopes and fears whose birth and death write themselves side by side, sunshine and long shadows, have crowded
                            into our book linking themselves into language best translated by each author. We are writing our last line, but
                            like the child we can not resist the impulse to turn to the first page whereon we put "our very best." God knows
                            we meant to carry those firm lines all through the book, the heavenly Teacher understands how disappointed we
                            now feel that the blots are so many, the curves so irrelevant as to make us wish to hide it away. But "like as a
                            father pitieth his children, "so the divine Parentage is moved with compassion at our waywardness and weakness
                            now so noticeable as we trace it from page to page, and the New Year book with its stainless pages slips into
                            our eager grasp as a balm and benediction. God's school is beautifully graded, tho, no class work here to force
                            or retard individual development. Instead of many pupils under one teacher, here are rather many teachers
                            molding the character of each pupil. The lessons presented to us for study or recitation are nicely adapted to
                            our needs and abilities. If we found the lessons so recently mastered difficult, the future work will demand
                            greater effort. We can not look forward with certainty to the future, "we know not what is folded there, we know
                            not whether joy or agony, whether life or death is writ within the fearful scroll—but 'tis enough to know the
                            gift is God's." The old book is an excellent landmark. Like the little one let us put the finisht volume out of
                            sight with all its defects for a while, while we pass on buoyed with profitable repentance in the guise of
                            new-born courage and aspiration to engage our minds with the new themes which God has already assigned to each
                            one. Then "some sweet day by and by" when the vital glorious issues of our consecrated life are inscribing
                            themselves in unbroken rhythm upon the unblotted page, we will turn again to the unsightly work of the past and
                            amid our tears of sad remembrance praise God for the New Years that rise so mercifully from the ashes of the
                            old. As a loving greeting to the New Year of 1899, let us say with William H. Channing;— "To bear all
                            cheerfully, do all bravely, Await occasions, never hurry,— In a word to let the spiritual life Grow up, through,
                            and above the common,— This is to be my symphony of life." East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><pb n="5" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peace" TEIform="index"/>PEACE</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>Hamilton DeGraw</byline><p TEIform="p">"Angel of peace thy white wings o'er shadow us, Thy hand scatters blessings around, Thy power hath stilled the
                            whispers of strife, And thy chain in its golden links bound us." WHEN General Sherman was requested to describe
                            war he replied, "War is hell." "Oh Consistency thou art a jewel," but if we have it not in possession how can we
                            estimate its value? The assertion is made, and it can not be successfully contradicted, that there is not a
                            Christian nation on this earth acting in its oflicial capacity. Here are some of the proofs. In time of apparent
                            peace there are in Europe three million armed men, ready at a moment's signal to commence the horrid din of war,
                            maintained at the yearly expense of a billion dollars. When such an eminent statesman as Gladstone expresses his
                            views ou this subject and points to the shoals on which the nations are drifting as the lvsult of these
                            expensive armaments, there must be occasions for thoughtful consideration as to the result. There are
                            individuals among all nations who understand and obey the teaching of Christ when he said, "Put up thy sword,
                            for all they that take the sword, shall perish by the sword." That is the condition of our modern civilization.
                            It is perishing; the result of fostering the war spirit represented by her mighty armies and formidable navies,
                            and profession of peace has become a hollow mockery, an insult upon the name of civilization; and the
                            maintaining of the armed truce is in many respects not any better than open hostilities. The chip which the
                            pugnacious boy places on his shoulder accompanied with 1 be challenge that whoever molests it will get a
                            whipping, illustrates the condition of so-called Christian nations. They stand to-day as instructors in the art
                            of modern warfare. The skill of her inventors is exercised in devising more effective weapons of destruction.
                            But the wrath of man will be made to redound to the glory of that time of which only a few have caught a faint
                            glimpse. General Grant voiced it when he said, "•Let us have peace." There is a growing sentiment which favors
                            the settlement of misunderstandings between nations by arbitration rather than the sword. The desire for peace
                            is gaining a foot-hold and its influence is being felt, but the factor which has been largely instrumental in
                            bringing about the result is the awful destructive power of the modern enginery of war. The intelligence of man
                            has, by perfecting those forces placed a check upon them. The race is not yet ready to plead guilty to the
                            inditement of being fools; both sides are becoming anxious and are calling quit. Let us hope that the limit of
                            those destructive forces has been reacht; certainly before the great nations of the earth have been roused and a
                            conflict precipitated, the result of which would be awful to contemplate. <pb n="6" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 6 THE MANIFESTO.
                            Conmencing the forepart of the present century and continuing to the present, an active interest has been taken
                            to Christianize the Asiatic nations of China and Japan, and to-day Japan has taken her place in the ranks of the
                            modern nations. She has a well-organized army and a navy of modern war vessels, well-equipt with the most
                            perfect implements known for destroying her foes. Remember she has taken these lessons from those nations
                            professing to be followers of the Prince of Peace,—believers in the Christ of the new dispensation. While not as
                            one who is hopeless of better conditions believing that the war demon will forever be the curse of life, resting
                            like an incubus upon human energies, turning the current of life downward ; but that in the good time coming
                            nations will learn war no more and their strength will be used for the upbuilding of the stiucture. Everyone who
                            loves peace and is anxious to see its principles become a permanent factor in human society must be saddened
                            when he realizes how little an incident will stir the war spirit, even with the results so apparent which will
                            follow in its wake. Europe to-day is over a volcano, ready at any moment to burst forth in a continental war.
                            Longfellow in the poem, "The Arsenal at Springfield," asks ; "Is it O man with such discordant noises With such
                            accursed instruments as these, Thou drownest nature's sweet and kindly voices, And jarrest the celestial
                            harmonies?" Rev. C. A. Dickinson spoke words of truth when he said, "The only thing which will settle the
                            turmoils and wars which agitate the world to-day is a proper respect for one another." When the divine Master
                            prayed that his disciples might not be taken out of the world, but be saved from its sins as they had a mission
                            to perform in presenting to the world a better way ; its appropriateness to the present time is apparent,
                            especially to our own Church. The testimony that Believers have held forth has been, first pure, then peaceable.
                            The causes producing war are in their primary origin the results of the violation of the law of divine purity.
                            If any one doubts these statements or thinks them over-drawn, let him peruse the criminal records of our
                            newspapers and he will be con- vinced. The prayer that can with propriety be offered by all who have been shown
                            a better way is that the temple of life may be cleansed from its unrighteousness, and then will be heard the
                            beautiful benediction pronounced by our Lord,—"Peace I leave with you, my peace I give unto you." "Down the dark
                            future through long generations, The echoing sounds of war grow fainter and then cease; And like a bell with
                            solemn, sweet vibrations I hear once more the voice of Christ say peace. Peace! and no longer from its brazen
                            portals The blast of war's great organ shakes the skies! But beautiful as songs of the immortals, The holy
                            melodies of love arise." Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="7" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lay down thy life" TEIform="index"/>LAY DOWN THY LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="M'Kechnie, Frederic" TEIform="persName"/>Frederic M'Kechnie</byline><p TEIform="p">Lay down thy life, if thou wouldst live! I heard a heaven-angel cry, Lay down thy life! and they shall give,
                            God's holy ones who dwell on high, The life that nevermore shall die. Lay down thy life! with all the lust To
                            have, to hold, to fight, to win; And for thou willst, not for thou must, Put far away each darling sin, And let
                            the power of God come in. Lay down thy life ! small is the loss, But large the prize and great the gain; Thou
                            carriest but a passing cross ; And bearest but a little pain, For joys that wax and never wane. Lay down thy
                            life ! they call for thee ; The valiant souls who steadfast stood; Shake off thy fetters and be free, They say,
                            who faced the fire and flood, And gave ungrudged their heart's best blood. Oh heed, my soul, and let the world,
                            The foolish world, drive blindly on, No longer in its eddies whirled, On with thine armor, and be gone ! A
                            kingdom waiteth to be won. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Days of yore" TEIform="index"/>DAYS OF YORE</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>Oliver C. Hampton</byline><p TEIform="p">IN the long ago, when we used to have our good and pleasant Union Meetings, Brother R. W. Pelham and I were
                            sitting one evening in one of them, near a table, on which lay a slate. I wrote on it the following couplet and
                            handed the slate to him, viz. "How fondly clings the mind, To days and scenes of yore," He replied under
                            them,---------------"But we must leave these scenes behind And press to scenes before." O. C.
                            H.------------------------"But what if they were sweet, And pleasant to the mind ?". R. W.
                            P.------------------------"Yet their results they did complete, And must be left behind." 7 <pb n="8" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/>
                            8 THE MANIFESTO. And so we went on for some time, each saying the best he could for his own side. Since that
                            ancient time I have come to think he was not far wrong in his sentiments on the subject. Altho there is no harm
                            in the memory of good that has past, yet it is well to depend upon the good of the present, and the hopes of the
                            future, for our peace and consolation. But to learn this is a great and almost invaluable attainment. What we
                            want to gain, is a com- plete dominance over our environment, so that no vicissitude of the present, can
                            interfere with, or destroy our peace of mind. Let us suppose we were there now. What then? Why it would make no
                            difference how much vituperation might be uttered against us either truly or falsely ;—our tranquillity would
                            not be interrupted at all by any amount of it. All the ordinary vexations and annoyances (and they are legion,
                            to the undisciplined mind,) of this present existence, would flee away forever and leave us in the possession of
                            invulnerable tranquillity. Suppose we had arrived at the condition of mind and spirit, that Jesus declared
                            himself to be in when he said, "I and my Father are one !" This must be possible, for our Savior said,—"Verily
                            verily I say unto you, he that believeth on me, the works that I do, shall he do also; and greater works than
                            these shall he do."—John xiv., 12. . Now we know that the Father is ever tranquil in mind and can not be annoyed
                            or affected with pain, sickness or sorrow. So from this promise we ought to be thoroughly convinced, that this
                            tranquil condition is possible for us ; not only the spiritual perfection, but thaumaturgic element of power, by
                            which he healed all sickness and even raised the dead. This is a most glorious promise set before us and can we
                            do better than to travel into it as soon as possible and really come into the possession of the peace that is in
                            Jesus the Christ? If we shall be so happy as to gain it, then how soon will all the little contemptible silly
                            annoyances of this life, (and all future existence) flee to "the uttermost parts of Egypt,'' never more to
                            return. O let us as one, direct all our efforts and energies to that one point: that is, let us learn to be one
                            with the Father and try to feel just as he does in every vicissitude. I read an article in a little book of
                            religious precepts and admonitions, one chapter of which was headed "God's Chariots." The author called all
                            trials, great and small, and all sufferings so many of God's golden chariots, for our safe and pleasant
                            conveyance away from all sorrow and suffering. And that if we would only get up into them and ride with him,
                            (that is become positive to, and dominate and reign over them,) we should soon dissipate all the sting of their
                            character and feel the same as the Father did toward them. This was setting forth the virtue of resignation in a
                            new and interesting light and since that, I have tried it, and find it a very comfortable policy to pursue under
                            all circumstances. Once more;—if we will take a little trouble to daily retire into the recesses of our Divine
                            Inmost, (where Jesus <pb n="9" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 9 located the kingdom of heaven,) and there concentrate
                            our minds upon the counsels there to be communicated from the Infinite fountain, we may at least seal our peace
                            and trauquility for that day. And our Savior said it was best to take one day at a time. Union Village,
                        Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Visit to East Canterbury, ew Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>A VISIT TO EAST CANTERBURY, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">[The following article was sent to us, by a dear friend, from the far away city of Los Angeles, Cal. but the
                            writer comes only the distance of five miles, from the Village of London. We publish it in part. Ed.] The
                            writer, a poor, sick old Boston musician, whose health has greatly suffered by years of battling with the
                            inconsistent freakiness of the elements, and his purse equally so by speculating in, that is to say, in buying
                            and disposing of many and various medical compounds termed "sure cures," has been summering in the little town
                            of Loudon, N. H , just three miles from the Shakers, at Canterbury. May I hope to entertain a few of the readers
                            of these columns with a brief description of trips numbers 1 and 2 with a small party to Shakerdom? Now here, as
                            did we, is what the visitor rryist do. After hitching your pony, go direct to the trustees1 office. After
                            registering you will probably be met by Brother Arthur Bruce, who is one of the trustees, a kind and courteous
                            gentleman, and, as well, a musician. But do not be surprised should you find him drest, not as your mind had
                            previously pictured all Shakers, in broad-brimmed hat, stiff neckwear, high straight-cut vest, long gray coat
                            and homespun trousers. Oh, no! the younger Shakers do not dress so now; nor do they wear their hair banged in
                            front and long behind; but on the contrary, they just dress as they please, like us world's people. Brother
                            Bruce will kindly procure for your party a guide, who is, I think, always a Sister; who may be a typical
                            Shakeress, sedate and prim, but always the courteous lady. Or it may be a Sister younger in years, intelligent
                            and sprightly, but in any and all cases the Sisters will be found to be kind and faithful guides. Our visit No.
                            1 was what is usually termed a flying one, we having no definite aim. Upon this visit we were taken in charge by
                            Eldress Eliza Stratton, a beautiful woman, rather on the shady side of life, but whose sweet face was plainly
                            indicative of purity and love, and whose soft speech was golden. A grand and noble lady, and patiently and
                            faithfully she performed her duty. Visit No. 2 was more of a business one. Now I could tell of lots of things
                            that we saw, but space in these columns is valuable, as is time to the reader. Moreover, Shakerism is old and
                            its origin dates far back, to France in 1689. To the time of Ann Lee, born 1736 in England, and died in America
                            in 1784; to the time of the first community in America, at New Lebanon, N. Y., 1787, and to the time of the
                            Canterbury, N. H. Community formed in 1792, Shakerism has been much talkt and written about by able minds. I
                            could have much to tell of the great barn, length 250 feet; of the forty splendid cows that give forth sixty to
                            sixty-five gallons of milk daily; of numerous—as the ladies remarkt— darling little bossies; of the three silos,
                            capacity of each one hundred tons. Of the neat and tidy creamery and dairy, with its tiny cream separator, its
                            churn and its butter worker, all run by steam-power. At this point I would remark that every known labor-saving
                            device is in use in the various working departments. I could tell of the lovely opera cloaks made by the
                            Sisters. It does look strange <pb n="10" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 10 THE MANIFESTO. in print. Shakers and opera—but there are
                            many of them that would—mind I only think this—enjoy a fine opera. Of the knitting room, where are made—much
                            Australian wool being used—sweaters of the finest, also golf and bicycle stockings. Of the laundry, with all the
                            latest improvements. Of the printing office where are many presses, both of ancient and modern construction, and
                            where are printed their paper, their magazine and many pamphlets, and even their church music is set up and
                            printed here, the Sisters doing the work. Of the kitchen work, its patent ove.is for baking bread, pies, etc. Oh
                            yes! they eat pies, but not pork apple pie. Of the immense stove, in the oven of which could be stowed away a
                            ten-year-old boy. And such nice bread as they make! We bought some. Of the dining-hall, where one could
                            literally eat from off the floor. We know that'Shaker neatness is proverbial. I could tell of the bright, sunny
                            and cosy little schoolroom and its blackboard sketches in colored chalk, one being our ill-fated ship Maine. Of
                            the sewing and music rooms, where were seen many bits of landscape and flower pieces in oil, the handiwork of
                            the Sisters. Here we come to the crowning feature of our visit. At our special request we were kindly permitted
                            to enjoy the excellent singing by the so highly praised quartet of Sisters, who kindly sang three admirable and
                            pleasing selections. To illustrate their musicianly qualities, I would say that one piece was a beautiful and
                            intricate arrangement by the Sisters themselves. Being a musician, I would, space permitting, like to dwell
                            longer upon this subject, but will close it by saying that one would have to travel far and wide in order to
                            hear better singing than that which afforded our party so much delight, and which was so beautifully and
                            tunefully rendered as a quartet by Sisters Sarle, Fish, Wilson and Evans, and as a quintet with the addition of
                            Brother Arthur Bruce's admirable baritone voice. Thus ended our visit to the Shakers, and all agreed to the fact
                            that it was an instructive and a most enjoyable one. Before parting we were cordially invited to call again.
                            Much has been said and written of these quiet people that is unfair, unjust, and, as well, untrue; still, they
                            plod along in their inoffensive way and say nothing. It is true that in many ways they are peculiar, but not
                            more so than those of various other sects. I would ask, how many of their faith are to be found in our penal or
                            pauper institutions? For all moneys received from the world's people they return a fair equivalent. The rules
                            which govern them are not so inconsistent as many may imagine. Neatness, tidiness and perfect system are
                            forcibly evident at every turn one makes. Now the question is often askt, "What if all the world were Shakers?"
                            Well, all the world are not Shakers, nor ever will be. Yet when we read of the misery, vice and crime, all of
                            which are so common with the world's people in densely populated places, one might be led to think that it
                            w.ould be well if at least one-half of the world could be Shakers.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Duty faithfully performed opens the mind to truth..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Duty faithfully performed opens the mind to truth...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Duty faithfully performed opens the mind to truth, said Dr. Channing. There is nothing which may not
                                    be attained by repeated' effort and continued and diligent application. Attempt nothing until you have
                                    first counted the cost, then having decided, bend every energy to accomplish your purpose, set heart,
                                    mind and every fibre of your being in vibration to respond to the call of duty. Then will the mind be
                                    opened to truth—Truth which is an emanation from the (4od-head itself. The end crowns the work, and "the
                                    truth shall make you free."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="11" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Manifesto, January, 1899. Office of Publication" TEIform="index"/>THE MANIFESTO. JANUARY, 1899. OFFICE OF
                            PUBLICATION.</head><p TEIform="p">The Manifesto is publisht by the "United Society of Believees" on the first of each month, and is the only work
                            issued regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all communications to Henry C. Blinn,
                            East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. TERMS. One copy one year, postage paid. .50 A cross in the margin will show
                            that your subscription lias closed. Remittances for subscription by Money Order should be on the Post Office at
                            Concord, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">November. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Rain. Snow. 1897. 38.13 7.25 8 in. 1898. 39.07
                                3.125 11 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 60 above 0. Lowest " " " " 18 " ' Number of rainy days " " 6 " "
                                snowy " " " 3 " " clear " " " 8 " " cloudy " " " 13 Dec. 1898. The tv heel of time pursues its annual round,
                                Revolving seasons in their order placed, By the Omniscient Ruler of all worlds And systems infinite; and
                                gave to each Its periodic revolution, so Wisely planned, that ne'er a clash occurs in All the circling
                                universe of globes. To earth, First came tloreacent Spring with life replete, Unfolding beauteous germs of
                                flowers and fruit Prophetic of perfected sheaves of golden grain And luscious fruit on plants and bending
                                boughs. Next came the glorious, gladsome Summer Enlivened by the sun's effulgent rays; Crowning the teeming
                                earth with harvest field And gardens robed with plants and fruits To recompense the faithful laborer's toil.
                                Next came fail1 Autumn with perfected stores Of earth's abundant produce, ready to Be safely stored for our
                                support, through all The dreary, cold, inclement winter hours. Yet "Winter has its rightful place in the
                                Great wheel of time's unceasing revolution ; Giving rest for Earth's recuperation. Thus every season acts a
                                part in the Grand circuit of each perfected year, Declaring thus the wisdom, power and skill Of the great
                                Architect Omnipotent. When the wheel of Time has made twenty-seven more revolutions we can bid adieu to the
                                year 1898 with its visitations of storms, cyclones, tornadoes, volcanoes, typhoons, electrical disturbances,
                                floods and destruction of lives and property on land and water. Seldom does a year contain such an amount
                                and variety of sad catastrophies as the year 1898 chronicles. In ages past, when superstition over-awed the
                                human mind, calamities great or small were held to be dispensations of chastise- ment direct from the hand
                                of God as a special punishment for obdurate, sinful humanity. Why these dispensations had no respect for
                                persons but swept all. both good and bad, into the great malevolent abyss of destruction, was a problem they
                                could not solve. Progress has made people wiser and more scientific. 1898 is indelibly stampt upon the
                                memory of millions of earth's inhabitants. Who can fail to give thanks that escaped these terrible
                                convulsions? W7e have a State Road in line of con • struction, that is intended to make our transit over the
                                Berkshire Hills easier than in the past. The road is not where we would like it nor where we would have it.
                                Much of the travel will be out of the village, especially the rougher characters. So far, so good. An
                                improvement is in <pb n="12" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 12 THE MANIFESTO. anticipation in our cemetery by placing honorable
                                head-stones to the graves. Tho multitudes have past from earth to the Spirit world the present year, yet in
                                our ranks we have no deaths to record.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reed, Calvin G." TEIform="persName"/>Calvin G. Reed</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South family" TEIform="index"/>South Family</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1898. The last days of the Old Year are fast approaching and soon we must say our hurried good-byes and
                                pass on to welcome the New Year with its blizzards and showers, its sunshine and flowers. Ofttimes with a
                                flood or a drouth, but we'll welcome it here the happy New Year that smiles on the north and the south. The
                                first snow-storm of the season came this way Thanksgiving morning like a silent benediction, frequent
                                showers of snow have fallen since and many merry sleighing parties have improved the snowy op- portunity for
                                making "music in the air." The skaters too have gone on their wintry travels around the ponds spending many
                                mirthful hours in the healthful pastime, thus each rising son becomes a Knight of the Skate and the ice. We
                                are busy indoors repairing and preparing for the spring-time, for "old things must pass away and all things
                                must become new." We've no time to lose, for we must work while it is day and faithful be to watch and pray.
                                Eepresentatives from the Granite State have added much to the brightness of the fall. Nov. 15th Eldress
                                Emeline Hart of East Canterbury and Eldress Kosetta Cummings of Enfield honored us with their presence for a
                                few hours. Our doors will ever stand ajar for their return when the good time comes.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Genevieve" TEIform="persName">Genevieve DeGraw</persName></byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1898. The year has transmitted to the Accountant of Time a record of its trans- actions. We hope and
                                trust that in the compilation of the balance-sheet, the credit side will have the supremacy; and that the
                                weary and burdened hearts opprestby the antagonistic forces of life have had those blessed angels, hope and
                                courage, enter into the innermost chambers of their soul as loving companions to cause their despondent
                                lives to renew their strength and purpose to grapple with the questions and problems of the coming time
                                which will demand a solution, with earnestness and strength. While the principle of peace, and the
                                arbitration of all disputed questions is the highest and most civilized method of dealing with the affairs
                                of life both at home and abroad, we have seen our beloved country employed as the instrument of ^ higher
                                intelligences to overthrow the adverse conditions that have existed for centuries and proclaim religious and
                                political freedom to those who were in bondage. As Believers in the higher law of peace on earth and
                                good-will unto all of the human family; giving our earnest prayer and labor for its blessed consummation, we
                                can endorse the results that have been accomplisht while deploring the necessity for the arbitrament of war
                                as an instrument used in its consummation, tho recognizing the fact that the seed which nations as well as
                                individual entities have sown must have a harvest-time. Father James Whittaker once remarkt "that the time
                                would come when all wrongs would be righted," and tho the mills of God grind slowly they grind exceeding
                                small. As we are entering upon the burdens and pleasnres of the New Year we wish all of our friends and
                                enemies too, (if it is admissible to recognize the fact of such an existence) a happy and prosperous year.
                                May its close witness the successful advance of human thought and life one step farther toward the desired
                                result, the universal unity of all races in the bonds of a permanent fellowship and an abiding peace. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName">Hamilton DeGraw</persName></byline></div3><pb n="13" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass</head><p TEIform="p">Dec.1898. When this message shall have reacht the members of our Home Circle another year will have opened to
                                us. O that we might pause on its threshold to cast a glance backward at the pathway along which the old year
                                has led us, and forward, into the way which stretches before us—the new. But nay! the pendulum ceases not
                                its endless swinging as each moment passes; nor does the sun pause in its constant journey, all nature
                                pushes onward, and we must join the moving throng. Let "onward" be our motto, throughout the New Year. Even
                                as we journey we extend the hand of fellowship to our comrades on the march, with loving greetings for the
                                Year, for tho our fields may be widely sepai-ated we are following one great leader who has said, "Lo I am
                                with you alway." To friends in northern, pine-scented forests; or beneath southern palms; or on bioad
                                prairies of the west; or verdmt mountains of the east, we send our best wishes for a blessed New Year, and
                                glorious march in the battle of life. We know that victory crowns the efforts of valiant soldiers in the
                                cause of right, and so we press on "for the prize of the high calling in Christ Jesus," trusting in the
                                fulfillment of the promise for "strength according to our day." Thanksgiving morning came, bringing to mind
                                our many blessings, illustrated by the myriads of snow-flakes filling the air. From the next day to the
                                present, sleighing has been quite satisfactory. This snow also drove the live stock from the pastures,
                                indeed they had predicted its arrival and sought shelter about the middle of November. This wise company
                                numbers two hundred cattle including eighty calves that were bought last June. Fifteen horses and colts have
                                also been purchased and commenced the task of emptying our large barns of the immense mows of hay; Our
                                saw-mill has been undergoing rerepairs, preparatory to its winter's work. A new pen-stock 16 ft. long and G
                                ft. in diameter, made of steel, with connecting gates etc., has been erected, and other improvements made.
                                The steam-boiler at the Office, which for years h is faithfully performed its work, of heating the halls and
                                rooms, suddenly collapst and consequently a new one is in process of construction. But while these workers
                                have been so busy out-of-doors, equally as busy have been the active fingers within. The house-work with its
                                necessary details, form the prominent points of each day's picture, but the many corners and empty places
                                are filled with the work upon fancy articles manufactured, and we are now busily sewing the seed for next
                                summer's harvest. Let us determine to make this year, 1899, a glorious, crowning year in the history of our
                                lives, our homes, our cause. Glorious, because filled with the radiance of the "life hid with Christ in
                                God."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Estabrook, Fidella" TEIform="persName"/>Fidella Estabrook</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoosee, Florida" TEIform="index"/>Narcoossee, Fla</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1893. In times of depression or when competition has grown too heavy,—the cultiva- tion of staples may
                                cease to be remuneiative and the unfortunate producer be com- pelled to adopt some other means of
                                livelihood. Such a misfortune may overtake the farmers of the United States. The western farmer who relies
                                on his crop of wheat or corn for a living, is met with an overloaded market and to save the crop from utter
                                ruin, he lets it go at a reduced price. It may barely pay the expenses. Such is competition the world over.
                                The expences in Florida to get the produce into the northern market is exorbitant. This has killed all the
                                courage of the producer. There is but little compared to what ought to be in the fruit and vegetable line,
                                shipt out of the State. The It. It. are <pb n="14" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 14 THE MANIFESTO. held by two
                                monopolists,—Flagler and Plant system. The prices are fixt to meet thfir demands, instead of an encourage-
                                lii'. nt to the labeling people. Some of the leading minds are now wci'kin.'!,1 i(ir ;• change. They see
                                that unless this one ti ing can be changed, Florid i is doomed for another set-back in civilization. All
                                through the state we can seo people tilling the soil for a iiving, and the increase is small compaied with
                                the labor. For that little increase they want some compensation if they keep the wolf from the door. As many
                                are miles away from the market where they would be-glad to dispose of their produce, they are forced to
                                accept the mercy of the railroad Corporations. As the inhabitants are so few and their means so limited but
                                very little can be obtained through that channel. I understand that one of our neighbors sent a car load of
                                melons to some northern city, and when everything was settled he realized twenty-five cents. Many acres of
                                melons are left on the field, just for this reason. Through the goodness of some leading minds of the State,
                                a Bill has been brought before the Legislature and Commissioners have been appointed to correct the error.
                                There is still a hope for the poor man in Florida. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barrett, Andrew" TEIform="persName"/>Andrew Barrett</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1898. The words of the Quaker poet seem in keeping with the present times wherein he says; "Let tlie
                                north wind strong And golden leaves of Autumn, be Thy coronal of victory, And thy triumphal song " Most
                                certainly it seems that the victims of the wreck of the Portland who were destroyed by the furies of the
                                North wind, a short time since, must need some assurance ; some coronal of victory, which no doubt they
                                received after their souls were wafted to a more friendly port, where the furies of such fearful tempests
                                are unknown. While we are enjoying the winter holidays we will not forget to extend greetings over the banks
                                of snow to our precious kindred in other homes, neither will we forget the needy who are always with us. We
                                are deeply interested in the account of the visit of Lafayette to Watervliet, as narrated in the December
                                Manifesto which has just arrived. Sister Genevieve gives a delightful description of her visit to the Church
                                family, which makes us feel envious as we have no other family near us to visit. WTinter has set in
                                uncommonly early and cold; bringing some sickness, but we trust all are convalescing. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cummings, Ada S." TEIform="persName"/>Ada S. Cummings</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1898. "Home sweet home, God's precious gift to me Home sweet home, my life shall honorth.ee." As we look
                                at our home, not viewing especially the lovely picturesqueness of nature's associations, but at the more
                                precious treasure ,—its inmates, we may well waft heart pseans of gratitude to God for the many blessings
                                that are ours. For kindred, as beautiful in character as the flowers we admire, as solid in principle as the
                                rocks of the hills about us and as constantly serving good as the stream that courses down the mountain
                                side. Souls tested by the power of divine truth and affliction, ever self-sacrificing for the good of home's
                                inmates, transmitting influences of pleasantness and bespeaking wisdom's works as genuine as the stars
                                spangling the blue dome of the heaven above. As works advertise our condition and faith, to enrich home, we
                                must blend with the realities of to-day. Dissect, construct and adjust matters in harmony with principles
                                that lead on to victory over sin. The mortal so working has a sacred treasure more beneficial and more
                                worthy of <pb n="15" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 15 adoration than any sacred relic incarcerated in cathedral,
                                palace or institution. Our Thanksgiving Service was "brim full" with soul-inspiring testimonials, which with
                                the hymns, added strength and good cheer. In the evening an hour and a half was given to an entertainment by
                                twenty-eight home folks. A beautiful feature of the event was the numerous pictures of arisen ones of our
                                other Communal homes, decorating wall and piano. The last of the month we had with us, friends, Dr. G.
                                Goding, of Christian Science school and Mr. Galen Fish, of Randolph, Vt. Mr. Fish a student of the Detroit
                                Training School of Elocution and English Literature, gave us an excellent entertainment, rendering many
                                dramatic and humorous recitations. As intermissions, the modern marvel Gramophone afforded pleasure. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Baxter, George H." TEIform="persName"/>George H. Baxter</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Jan. 1899. God bless the survivors of 1898! May they realize a prosperous "Happy New Year" is the fervent
                                wish which sounds through our ideal "Alpine horn," as we seek to communicate with our sister societies east,
                                west, north and south, across the snow-clad Union. Yea, let the message of good cheer reach from New
                                England's hill-tops and vales to the heights and levels of Kentucky. Let it wing its way to New York, thence
                                to far Narcoossee, thus wafting a breeze of comfort to every Christian home between these distant points,
                                and finally reaching out to the "whole, whole world" to which we ever have a duty. The busy old year is
                                gone—its material harvests are stored—but we have many benefits to recount as we reflect upon the past. Were
                                we to try to number the common blessings of a day even, how futile would be the attempt! The blessing of
                                daily association with a large household of true friends, is not of small value. Plenty of honorable
                                employment always at hand precludes the necessity for soliciting work which yields the "daily bread."
                                Toiling at our several tasks by our own pleasant firesides, where are none to "molest or make afraid," is
                                certainly an added mercy. Greater than this is the conscious integrity of striving daily to grow in grace by
                                the unselfish performance of duty in its varied aspects, helping the many rather than the few, thus
                                gradually outgrowing the narrowness of innate selfishness. Let New England, therefore, breathe the "home
                                notes" of musical content, even though the blizzards have come and the summer warblers have flown. We love
                                the birds, the summer breezes, and the flowers, but—listen! A chickadee is singing even while we write his
                                name. Every syllable of his evening hymn is enunciated as clearly as a profest elocutionist could utter
                                them. He seems to say, Chick-a-dee dee-dee-dee, The drifting snows don't trouble me, There's Jots of fun in
                                yonder tree, Chick-a-dee-deedee-dee The bobolink can't rival ine, and so he seems a perfect impersonation of
                                content. Truly, "A contented mind is a continual feast." The storm which proved so disastrous around the
                                coast of the Biy State reacht us on the 27th ult., but no loss of life or property is recorded for this
                                vicinity. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stickney, Asenath C." TEIform="persName"/>Asenath C. Stickney</byline></div3></div2><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I will be what I will to be" TEIform="index"/>I WILL BE WHAT I WILL TO BE.
                            </head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by Ezra J. Stewart ] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> I mean to tread this narrow way, Whatever may betide; I care not
                                        what my flesh may say, In all its lordly pride; I will be what I will to be; From all the chains of
                                        sense set free. I will to be at one with God— And that and nothing less— In everything with full
                                        accord I will in His ways press. E'en tho He say the flesh must die; At once that flesh I" 11
                                        mortify. <pb n="16" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 16 TEE MANIFESTO. If I am weak, what matter that? The Master's leal
                                        and true. His spirit's leadings have begat What can but bringme through. Ne'er as a coward will I
                                        flee The strife which sets my inmost free. I am determined to pursue The course I have begun; And
                                        with abounding life in view All clown that course I'll run. Hinder me not, you fearful crew; To all
                                        that's good I will be true.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Sel.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dream or vision" TEIform="index"/>A DREAM OR VISION</head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by E. B. Gillett.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Over two years ago I dreamed that I saw three beautiful cloudy pillars of pure white. I was so
                                        delighted I turned to call another person to see them, when I lookt again the pillars had assumed
                                        the shape of a most entrancing white city surrounded by a high wall of pure white. Overcome with
                                        delight I dropt to the floor exclaiming "O my God, I love thee." Oft have I grieved as to the
                                        signification of the three pillars. Lately it has come clearly to me. The three pillars are
                                        significant of the three aspects presented in the true spiritual family. First, parent to child.
                                        Second, child to child. Third, child to parent. All was pure white.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Discipline that has life" TEIform="index"/>A Discipline that has life</head><p TEIform="p">—The Catholic University of Notre Dame, at South Bend, Ind. with 1500 students is in Prohibition Territory.
                                "Two students while on a visit to the City, became intoxicated. It came to the ears of the President who
                                expelled them by telephone. They were not permitted to return to the College and their trunks were
                                immediately sent to the depot."—The New York Voice. The Episcopalian bishops are at variance on the subject
                                of Marriages and Divorces. The church tries hard to make it a divine institution, but it still remains in
                                the hands of the civil law. </p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our exchanges" TEIform="index"/>OUR EXCHANGES</head><p TEIform="p">The Student's Journal, is devoted to Graham's Standard Phonography. • Publisht by Andrew J. Graham &amp;
                                Co., 744 Broadway, N. Y. The Student's Journal is the oldest and best phonographic Journal in America. Each
                                number has eight pages of lithographed phonography. News of importance to phonographers, portraits,
                                biographical sketches, and facsimiles of the reporting notes of prominent phonographers are frequently
                                given. One book firm advertises for sale, "A Shaker Bible," and the statement is quite misleading. The
                                Shakers use the same version of the Bible as is used in all the Christian churches. The Book which some are
                                pleased to call a Shaker Bible is largely a history of the Catholic and Protestant churches. "Kind words are
                                the music of the . world, they have a power which seems to be beyond natural causes. It seems as if they
                                could almost do what in reality God alone can do, soften the hard and angry hearts of men. No one has ever
                                been converted by a sarcasm, crusht, perhaps, if the sarcasm was clever enough, but drawn nearer to God,
                                never." Those who write for "Home Notes" should not forget the order of that department, and write an essay
                                on either religion or domestic duties. An article of 350 words will do quite well. The above is from The
                                Manifesto of May 1895, page 119. </p></div3><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mayer, Philip J." TEIform="index"/>Philip J. Mayer
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Mayer, Philip J." TEIform="persName">Philip J. Mayer</persName>, at Ayer, Mass. Dec. 1, 1898. Age 89 years and 9
                                days. Brother Philip has been an active member of the Society at Harvard for thirtyfive years. He was a man
                                of sterling integrity and we mourn the loss. M. E. McL. </p></div3></div2><pb id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><!--
                        advertizements deleted]
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>