<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm1711" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">23</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">17</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><date value="18871101" TEIform="date">November 1887</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">241-264</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="17" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1">
                    <!-- 
<pb id="p1"/>
NOVEMBER,
THE
MANIFESTO.
Published by the United Societies,
"Every plant which my heavenly Father bath not planted shall be rooted
up."- -Matt, xv.,  13.
Canterbury, N. H.
1887.

<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
The Gospel Testimony, No. 20.
Gratitude,     Theology, No. 2.
Letter- -L. R.
"     - -Louis   Basting,
Cathedral,     -          -         -          Perseverance,
Forgiveness,
Our Father,
Notes- -The Church and its Promises
Wants to be a Prophet,
Food Adulterations,
Ardent Spirits,   The Fear of the Lord,
Unrest,     -          -          -         Advice to Youth,    Tobacco,
Spe,ak-no-evil Club,
Now,        -          -          -          A Thought for Others,
Enormous Income,
Books & Papers,
Kind Words,
Deaths,         241
244
247
230
253
254
256
258
259
261
262

NEVER
OUTOF ORDER.
NEW HOME SEWING MACHINE G.ORftNCE,MASS.
Chicago - 30 UNION SQUARE.NX-   DALLAS,
S^OUIS.MO.
SHORT HINTS
- - - -ON- - -SOCIAL ETIQUETTE,
Compiled from the latest and best works
on the subject by "Aunt Matilda."
PRICE, 40 cents,
 book should be in every
 family desirous of knowing  "the proper thing to do."
We all desire to behave properly and to know what is the best
school of manners.   What shall
we teach our children, that they
may go out into the world well
bred men and women?
"SHORT HIJSTTS" contains
the answer and will be mailed
to any address, postage prepaid on receipt of price.
special
Until further notice we wTill
mail each of our friends a copy
of the above valuable book
gratis and free of postage, if
they will mail us 15 wrappers
of Dobbins' Electric Soap.
By folding up the wrappers
as you would a newspaper, the
postage will only be 2cts.
Always put your full name
and address on the out side of
the bundle and write the word
"Etiquette" also, and then
will know who sends it.
I. L. CBAGKCST & Co.,
PHILADELPHIA, PENN'A.
we
Any person who wants paying work as local or traveling agent for warranted nursery
stock should apply at once to James E.
Whitney, Nurseryman, Rochester, N. Y.
No experience is necessary, and complete
outfit is furnished free. Steady work the
year round and all stock warranted to he in
good condition.
263
264
<pb n="" id="p"/>
Vol. XVIII.
NOVEMBER,  1887.
No. 11. --><pb n="241" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the elders, William Lee and James Whittaker no. 20" TEIform="index"/> The Gospel Testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the Elders, William Lee and
                            James Whittaker. No. 20.</head><p TEIform="p"> Published expressly for the several Communities of Believers in 1816. Re-written
                            by Henry C. Blinn. Exhortations, etc. Mother and the Elders spared no pains to instruct the
                            Believers in the things of God, and in the path of their duty. They were employed, day or
                            night, when occasion offered, in giving counsel and instruction, where it was needed,
                            whether in things temporal or spiritual. In all their labors they were careful to impress
                            upon the people the absolute necessity of perfect obedience, in order that they might profit
                            by their privilege and find justification before God. At Watervliet Mother Ann spoke to an
                            assembly and said; "Hear ye my words, and understand. It is but a light thing to speak the
                            word to the souls of men, to what it is really to help them. He that helps souls, must have
                            the spirit of Christ to administer to them, and must take their infirmities upon him, and be
                            able to suffer for, and bear with them." " Be obedient in all things both spiritual and
                            temporal. If you are faithful you will have strength according to your day. Be free, and not
                            be a stranger. A strange feeling never came from heaven.'! "Never give offence to any one,
                            nor take offence from any one." Mother Ann in bidding farewell to a company, said,- -"Go and
                            tell your Brethren these things which you see and hear. The blind receive their sight, the
                            lame walk, the lepers are cleansed, the deaf hear, the dead are raised and the poor have the
                            gospel preached to them, and ble-sed is he whosoever shall not be offended in me." "People
                            see and judge according to the state they are in. When their senses are darkened and their
                            minds under the influence of an evil spirit, they see and judge according to the dictates of
                            that evil spirit; but when they are under the influence of the spirit of Christ, then they
                            see and judge according to the truth." '' If you will take up your crosses against the works
                            of generation and follow Christ in the regeneration, God will cleanse you from all
                                unrighteousness."<pb n="242" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/>"Be faithful to keep the way of God.
                            If you are faithful you will be guarded by good angels." " The head of a wicked man is as
                            full of evil spirits as is a sponge full of water. The head of a good and faithful man is
                            filled with good spirits, and he will be guarded by the Angels of God. They will protect him
                            day by day." "Go and testify to the children of this world that Christ is reigning on earth,
                            and that he has sons and daughters. The world know it not because they do not confess their
                            sins to God." In bidding farewell to the Believers in Littleton, Mass., Mother Ann said, "
                            We will return to our home in Watervliet, N. Y. We have great sufferings to pass through. We
                            will suffer at our own home and not be burdensome to the Brethren and Sisters of this
                            place." " If you should be so persecuted, as to have your houses torn down over your heads,
                            and you cast into the fields, you must not neglect to meet together for the worship of God.
                            We may never meet again, but God has raised up those from your own ranks who are able to
                            guide you in the way of peace and holiness, if you are faithful to obey them." Mother Ann
                            taught the Believers to kneel and pray. " The gift of prayer is with the gift of kneeling."
                            "You should never be idle. It is ali ways good to kneel in prayer to GoJ and ask for that
                            which you may need. You - - should avoid confusion. Never ask for ! i what you do not want,
                            as that is taking God's name in vain. Be fervent in spirit, and Godwill hear and bless you."
                            " Wait on God for the answer ofyour prayer. God has waited many years for you. He will
                            bestow his gifts according to your needs." " Brethren and Sisters you are all the interest i
                            have in this world." Although Mother Ann was a woman of few words, yet her soul was filled
                            with wisdom, and her speaking was a demonstration of that spirit. Many precious words were
                            spoken to the Brethren and Sisters, by Mother Ann and the Elders, which left an indelible
                            impression upon their miuds. God's work upon the earth was not for one day nor for one year,
                            and in answer to a young man who sought advice about the cultivation of fruit, Mother Ann
                            said, "Yea, plant the plum stones, and do all your work as though you had a thousand years
                            to live on earth, and as you would if you knew you must die tomorrow." A young woman
                            solicited the privilege to live with Mother Ann, and received this clear and Christian
                            response. "Live with me, my child. The foxes have holes and the birds of the air have nests,
                            but I have not where to lay my head. Go child, and I will go with you. If you go through the
                            waters, the floods shall not overflow you, and if you go through the fire, it shall not
                            kindle upon you, and if you goto the ends of the earth, I will never leave you nor forsake
                            you." To one who asked Mother Ann if she felt any promise of God for her, she replied, "Yea,
                            God's blessing be with you and rest upon you. God's everlasting grace and salvation be unto
                            your soul, if you will obey. Go to your home and about your duties, and 1 will be present
                            with you.'' To a poor man who complained of his rich brother, Mother replied, "That is<pb n="243" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> the way of the world. The rich are covetous and will not
                            help tha poor, and the poor will envy them for it, therefore they are both wicked. One of
                            the Believers made reference to the faith which he had received, to which Mother Ann
                            replied, "I own your faith. Faith is the anchor of the soul. It is like an anchor to a ship.
                            An anchor will hold a ship when the winds blow and the waves run high. In like manner faith
                            will keep the soul in trials, temptations and bufFetings. Your spirit shall find a resting
                            place with my spirit." After Daniel Wood had accepted the faith of the Believers, the Elders
                            said to him, u Daniel your faith is like the faith of John the Baptist. You must go and
                            prepare the way of the Lord. Go preach the gospel to the ends of the earth. Go first to your
                            own family. Let them confess their sins that you may know what is done in your own house. Go
                            and testify your faith to those you call your Brethren and let them accept the word of God."
                            To one of the young sisters who came to Mother Ann for advice she said, " Elizabeth, I love
                            you. You shall be my sister. I see the glory of God shine all over you, so great that I
                            cannot discern your body with my natural eyes. You must take good care of your little
                            children and bring them up in the love and fear of God." One of the sisters remarked that
                            she could not understand the benefit of some of the gifts and operations that she had
                            witnessed. Mother Ann replied, "You should rather labor for the gift of God in your own
                            soul. Leave such gifts as you do not understand, as they are not for you. Great gifts may be
                            manifested in the Church, and you may love the power of God." One of the Brethren inquired
                            of Mother Ann why some who were lame or sickly were not healed. Mother answered, " We can do
                            nothing of ourselves. It is God that heals the sick, and it is God that makes us whole. We
                            cannot do miracles any more than others. All that we can do, is to be workers together with
                            God." To one of the Sisters Mother Ann said, " Jesus took up his cross against the spirit of
                            the world, and did the will of his heavenly Father. You must take up your cross and live as
                            he lived. Be not unbelieving, but believe and God will make you able. If you obey God, he
                            will send his holy augels to guard you." The Elders in their exhortations were anxious for
                            the protection of souls, and labored faithfully to houor their call. '"Treasure up the gifts
                            of God, and they will wake up in your soul when you need them. Labor to feel the life of God
                            and to make his work, your work and his way, your way. Let it be your inheritance, your
                            treasure, your occupation, your daily calling. Do not fight human beings, you will spoil
                            them. Fight the evil spirit. Fight that spirit that leads mankind into sin." Elizabeth C . .
                            . . became a faithful young sister, and often visited the society at Watervliet, N. Y., to
                            see the Brethren and Sisters. She was very anxious to live with Mother Ann, but the gift was
                            for her to return to her own home. " They need you," said Mother. Elizabeth prayed to be
                            retained, " They need your help," said Mother, "The wicked people are all about them, and it
                            is your duty to go to the family. Go<pb n="244" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> and hold a testimony
                            of light before the wicked and God will be with you. You must not be discouraged, for I see
                            your mission in heaven, and your soul will be released. Go in peace and take my love. You
                            can do more good there, than you can with me." On reaching home Elizabeth retained the gift
                            and fearlessly spoke the testimony of the work of Christ. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gratitude" TEIform="index"/> GRATITUDE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Newton, Agnes E." TEIform="persName"/> AGNES E. NEWTON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> I bless the power that taught my soul Upon the rock to fall; Tho' broken are my
                            selfish hopes And scattered is my all; Wherein I've sought or e'en desired, Aside from
                            Christian gain : To know, to be, to have, or share Without the spotless name. I sing the joy
                            of sins forgiven, Of love that knows no fear; Of truth, that in my inner life Today, is
                            shining clear. And by this truth I know my soul Will be made pure and free; No distant
                            triumph I've in view, Each hour brings victory. And so I've learned to bless the means, And
                            trust the guiding hand, That wisely laid the structure low, When building on the sand. And
                            does the storm or calm surround, I've found a solace sweet; And make the living sacrifice,
                            With gratitude replete. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Full cross and burden..." TEIform="index"/>A Full cross and burden... </head><p TEIform="p"> A full cross and burden Bring solace of life, A promptness in duty 'Mid all
                            earthly strife ; The pattern of meekness Forever our guide, And charity with us Whatever
                            betide.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/> M. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Treatise on theology no. 2" TEIform="index"/> A TREATISE ON THEOLOGY. No. 2.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/> F. W. EVANS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> 26. But when, under the influence of the angels of the third heaven, the earth
                            had brought forth a woman, who fulfilled the righteousness of the third dispensation, Jesus
                            returned, accompanied by his spiritual parents, the true Christ; and, through their
                            conjoined ministrations, Ana was enabled to "- -make herself ready" for the final marriage,
                            or rather betrothment of the Lamb and Bride. 27. The seventh trumpet had sounded, and "the
                            mystery of God was finished," by the revelation of the fourth dispensation itself, and not
                            by the Bible, the mere record of the three preceding generative dispensations, under which,
                            none were children of the kingdom any further than "by adoption," being simply under the
                            promise that "when Jesus should appear, they should see him as he is, and be like him." 28.
                            The Scripture records may be divided into three parts : First. The abstract truths, or
                            higher law- -as, perfect love to God and man, the moral precepts, etc. Second. The types and
                            symbols, and prophecies of coming events. Third. The statutes and laws of expediency, which
                            were "not good ;" the lower law, by which they should always "not live." 29. This was added
                            because of transgression, and was a descent, or adaptation of truth to the "hardness of
                            their hearts." The penalties, sacrifices, washings and carnal ordinances were of this latter
                            class. This additional law comes to an end with all who can say, "Lo, I come to do thy will,
                            O God."<pb n="245" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> By which will the original law itself was
                            fulfilled ; and the old heaven and earth will pass away before that law will come to an end.
                            30. Unless premises, as a basis to reason from, be agreed upon, and some general principles
                            by which to interpret the Scriptures be laid down, I do not see that a oneness can be
                            arrived at. If two men enter into an argument, and quote the Scriptures, should one believe
                            them to be the Word of God- -infallible ; the other, that they are merely the word of man ;
                            their quotations might be as endless as the Jewish genealogies, and equally as unprofitable.
                            31. I do not perceive why Jesus and his apostles should not, in their teaching, have been
                            confined exclusively to the records of the Jewish church, upon the same principle that we
                            are to be compelled to find all the light, the doctrines, and the complete system of the
                            fourth dispensation in the records of the first Christian church ; and so entirely ignore
                            the revelation of the dispensation itself. But it is undeniable that each preceding
                            dispensation brought forth its own revelations, and formed a Scripture record of them. 32.
                            As Jesus and his apostles stood superior to Moses, saying, Moses said thus and so ; but I
                            say unto you, not so ; so do those who stand in the gift of this second Christian church,
                            possess the same authority over all past dispensations, to correct their errors, and to
                            dispense with their laws of expediency, and to explain their parables and dark sayings. 33.
                            The Scriptures are valuable in their place and order; out of it, they "kill," and quench the
                            spirit. 34. Truth is older than the hills. What Jesus uttered was not true because he said
                            it; but, because it was true, he uttered it. 35. Should we not, in reading the Scriptures,
                            seek to know why such and such things are stated by the writers? If we have "life in
                            ourselves," the law and principle will be "in our hearts," as it was in theirs ; and we
                            shall know the thing whereof we affirm, from that ground ; not from the Scriptures alone.
                            36. When the apostles teach me respecting the truths of their church and order, I am all
                            respect; but when I come to our own church and order, to me, Jesus Christ alone is
                            authority. I do not look to Paul for a clear understanding of the cherubim, of which he
                            tells us he could "not speak particularly." The duality of God, who and what was Christ, his
                            powers, office, order, aud his relation to Jesus, were matters entirely beyond his travail
                            and dispensation. 37. As the time had not arrived for the influx from the resurrection
                            heaven to go forth, except to Jesus, no one else could possibly understand the things
                            pertaining to them. 38. The Holy Spirit that ministered to Mary and the Apostles was from
                            the third heaven only ; how then could they comprehend the distinction between Jesus and the
                            spirit who ministered to him?- -when that spirit would not again be fully revealed to any
                            human being until nearly eighteen hundred years afterwards ; at which time, the mother
                            spirit in Deity, and the pre-existence of Christ and his dual order, would both be declared
                            together, by a suitable and appropriate witness- -a woman. "For only a part of God, and a
                            part of Christ were facts to the primitive church."<pb n="246" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 39. I
                            suppose that, in the early ages, men, by nature- -the things that were made- -knew the order
                            of the godhead ; but sin caused them to become gross, so that they held the truth in
                            unrighteousness, and formed sensual ideas of the great supreme, that was idolatry. To
                            destroy this, it was necessary to take from man a knowledge of the personality and order of
                            God, and a law was passed, or given, through Abraham, prohibiting the formation of any
                            likeness or image, of the Divine Being. They must not, even in their minds, form any image ;
                            nor were they allowed to mention the name of God except under certain restrictions. The
                            children of Israel were thus saved from idolatry, by being kept in ignorance of the dual
                            order of God. 40. In the kingdom of Antichrist, the same result has been attained through
                            the Trinity idea of three males. These have done good service as a cloak to cover the dual
                            order of God, until such tim- -. as men cou'd receive and retain it in purity. 41. As male
                            and female in the natural man, Adam is a type of the duality of the '^quickening spirit,"
                            Christ, so is the pre-existence and duality of Christ, a stepping stone to a proper
                            conception of our eternal heavenly father and mother. 42. It is agreed by all that Messiah
                            and Christ mean the Anointed one ; and that the Jews did receive predictions respecting him,
                            and formed their conceptions of him, according to their natural state. They expected he
                            would be a prophet like unto Moses. 43. Jesus did come and inaugurate the third
                            dispensation, as Abraham had done the second. And as Abraham had been ministered to by the
                            second heaven angels ; so was Jesus ministered to by those of the third heavens ; and under
                            their guardianship he was perfected as a Jew. Now comes the question. How is he (Jesus) 'i
                            Jew, to become the Messiah, the Christ, the Anointed? 44. We, standing in the revelation of
                            the fourth dispensation, answer- -Jesus, having the unction of the fourth or Christ heaven
                            poured upon him without measure, by his guardian Christ Spirit (who anointed him at his
                            baptism by John,) became the Messiah, the Christ (or anointed) to us, as to Abraham his
                            ministering spirit was God. 45. Melchisedek, who met Abraham, and anointed or blessed him,
                            and from whom he received tithes, was a type of the primitive Christ, who anointed Jesus.
                            46. All those passages of the Scriptures of the second dispensation, that speak so
                            positively of the then ruling spirit being God, the .Almighty, the great I Am, specifying
                            all the characteristics of a primary Creator, are explained by Elder William Leonard, on the
                            general principle that it was a representative spirit; but that Abraham, Moses, etc., did
                            not see the God that was back of aud beyond the God of Israel; but they saw that, to them,
                            he exercised all the authority and possessed all the power of the great Supreme. So that
                            they would have felt quite as much outraged, on being informed that Israel's God was not the
                            primitive God, as the Samaritan woman, or Peter, or the third heaven angels who presided at
                            the birth of Jesus, would have been indignantly surprised at being told that Jesus was not
                            the primitive Divine Christ. 47. It is highly probable that the<pb n="247" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> Christ who anointed Jesus had himself been anointed by others above him.
                            48. The simple fact, then, as I understand it, is that the first was a god, but not the
                            primitive God, and that Jesus, to us, is the Christ, or the Anointed, which He could not
                            have been had there been no primitive Christ to anoint Him. " 49. Paul, in the latter day of
                            his travail, declared that "though he had known Christ (or Jesus) after the flesh, yet now
                            henceforth knew he Him no more" in that way. He began to be more spiritual. And it may be
                            that, long ere this time, Abraham has seen beyond his former god. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear vegetarian friends, Ernest and Paul: I have received your letter..." TEIform="index"/> Dear vegetarian friends, Ernest and Paul: I have received your
                            letter... </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="California, San Francisco, July 1887" TEIform="index"/> San Francisco, Cal.,
                            July, 1887. </dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear vegetarian friends, Ernest and Paul :- -I have received your letter, also
                            Manifesto. The motives which led you to settle at Mount Lebanon, I cannot understand, at
                            present at least, but since you invite me to do the same you will not deny my request for
                            further information. Before putting direct questions, I would state certain points upon
                            which we perhaps agree. The starting-point of all intellectual activity is the b &gt;dy,
                            beginning with the development and ending with the death of the animal organism. Morality is
                            intellectual activity. The healthier the body is the more perfect will be its intellectual
                            activity. Perfection is an ever eluding object; it may be yearned after, but can never be
                            reached. If morality is an intellectual activity resulting from the development of the
                            animal organism, sensuousness must be a part in the growth of that organism when the human
                            being was yet so imperfect that no intellectual phenomena could be produced. Therefore, a
                            continued development of the body, would make the human race perfect, both intellectually
                            and morally. Since the Shakers believe to have shaken off sexual sensuality they can count
                            only upon the development of single individuals; Shakers are therefore a portion of humanity
                            that disappears with the death of the single individual. Man is the product of the evolution
                            of generations; there is, therefore, a doubt whether single individuals may reach that
                            development the attainment of which has hitherto been the task of his ancestors. If we
                            regard the religious systems of the day as the dogmatic forms of the culture of the
                            different historical periods, we are compelled to come back to our starting-point,
                            recognizing the human body as the material basis of all and every reform. Having become
                            Shakers you accept a religious view which our contemporaries in their progressive march have
                            left behind them long ago. This is about my view of the ethics opposed to the aims of
                            Shakerism. We vegetarians should, according to our individual gifts, stand as high as any of
                            our contemporaries as regards health, morals and economies, because we obey the laws of
                            nature. If you can prove these views to be incorrect I shall be thankful for your
                            instructions, and will act accordingly; if not, let us at least continue to work together in
                            the field of dietetics. With kind regards,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="R., L." TEIform="persName"/> L. R</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="L. R. Respected friend: Since your last letter to our beloved..." TEIform="index"/> L. R. Respected friend: Since your last letter to our beloved... </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, August 1887" TEIform="index"/> Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.,
                            Aug. 1887.</dateline><p TEIform="p">L. R. Respected Friend :- -Since your last letter to our beloved brethren Ernest
                            and Paul contains such severe<pb n="248" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/>strictures upon what you
                            terra "- -Shakerism" I feel justified in taking the liberty to answer your views in their
                            and our behalf. Your arguments culminate in the sweeping assertion that the Church of
                            Christ's Second Appearing is a relic of the dark ages which men of your progressive ideas
                            have long ago left behind. Do you know what you are talking about when you make such an
                            assertion ? Are you so well informed in regard to the aims and endeavors and practical life
                            of Believers, (called Shakers) that you feel competent to condemn them as unworthy of your
                            consideration? But since you ask for further information aod promise to act accordingly, it
                            is clear that your opinions are based upon ignorance ; but I also discover the honest heart
                            of a wellmeaning, enthusiastic young man behind it all. Allow me to enlighten you.
                            "Shakerism" is a narrow, denominational nnd rather disrespectful term for the everlasting
                            gospel of Christ. All "- -isms" savor of bigotry. The gospel is glad tidings of joy, i. e.
                            happiness. What and who is Christ? Not only the man Jesus but every one who possesses his
                            spirit and endeavors to do the will of God according to his light and knowledge. Who and
                            what is God? The etymology of the word explains it sufficiently ; it is good and goodness.
                            All men worship something, either consciously or unconsciously. You worship the human body,
                            and the stomach at that! It is the most ignoble of all worship, even below the fetichism of
                            the poor African. Men grow like unto what is most in their thoughts. If God is their all in
                            all, a sublime ideal, embodying love, justice, mercy and power in perfection, a beautiful
                            character, a peaceable, pure and righteous life will be the result. But what if the stomach
                            is the continual object of contemplation ? Not even physical health, moral stamina and
                            intellectual vigor will thereby be created. You are right when you say that the
                            starting-point of all individual, intellectual activity is with the body ; you are wrong
                            when you say that it euds with the body. Any spiritualist, aod there are millions of them,
                            can tell you that the dead do live without the physical, material body. You are wrong when
                            you declare it to be a fact that the healthier the body the more moral the person will be.
                            Is John L. Sullivan, the prize-fighter, a moral character whose conduct is to be imitated ?
                            Yet he is as healthy as man can be. Are the Apaches of Arizooa, whose physical endurance is
                            undisputed, such a virtuous people as to excite admiration ? Physical health is desirable
                            above all earthly things, but unless it is supplemented by that moral and spiritual health
                            that causes men to leave off sinuiug, even sacrificing health rather than do a positive
                            wrong, they will be but little better than savages. Why talk about perfection when you say
                            it is unattainable? Yet you also say that a continuous development of the human body will
                            make the race perfect in all respects. I leave it to yourself to harmonize the
                            contradiction. But there is to be perfection ; if not in this world then in the next. Man
                            has his roots in the soil of this earth ; he is to grow up into heaven. Of course Shakers
                            are born and die as individuals like all the rest of the race ; but their faith and
                            principles live after them ; oth-<pb n="249" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> er hands will take them
                            up. Je^us was never married, but his words are influencing more lives for good today than
                            ever before. There is a power in moral and spiritual truth that does not perish with the
                            body. How can the race as a whole progress and develop unless individuals, the units
                            composing the whole, arise and advance to higher spheres? Morality and spirituality are
                            acquired chiefly by careful training and education, by correct habits of life and the stern
                            lessons of experience. It is therefore not necessary for Shakers to marry in order to
                            perpetuate their institutions. How mistaken you are to consider the human body as the all
                            that there is of mau ! Again you demonstrate the fallacy of your own doctrine. You yearn for
                            progress, development, advancement. But man cannot lift himself up unless he lays hold of
                            something outside and above himself. No one has ever succeeded in elevating himself by
                            pulling at his boot-straps. Please do give al! the many millions who believe in God and
                            immortality credit for some common sense, honesty and discernment. Do not consider all as
                            being fools or slaves of superstition and bigotry who pass through life trusting upon a
                            heavenly Father for strength to do their duties, hoping to dwell at last in a better land
                            where sin and death are no more. Whatever progress the race has made, whatever is good and
                            desirable in civilization, is the fruit of the genuine religious principle. If all men
                            thought as you profess to think almost every incentive that makes men orderly, law-abiding,
                            self-restrained, moral beings, would be swept away. If the body is all, then the
                            gratification of the bodily senses will become the chief aim of life and corruption the
                            inevitable result. You are a vegetarian, therefore I have hope of you that you may be
                            converted to true Christianity ; not that a supreme importance attaches to a vegetable diet,
                            but my hopes are based upon the fact that a man who can deny himself, in opposition to
                            universal customs, for what he considers a righteous cause, has the stuff and quality in
                            himself to become a righteous man in all respects. As it is, you are clinging to a single
                            frail plank barely able, to keep you afloat. Why not climb on to the mighty Argosy of which
                            Christ is captain ? Perhaps in after years you will discover that your present ism is but
                            one side in the many sided, well-balanced character of the perfect man. Ever since the
                            founding of the Shaker order many of its members have been vegetarians; their wants have
                            been and are today being supplied. We are opposed to the party-spirit that is as death to
                            the delicate organism of a community. We take no part in politics. Democrats and Republicans
                            are unknown, yet we are patriots who love our country and desire its peace and prosperity.
                            Should at any time public sentiment become aroused regarding animal food, that sentiment
                            would find a cordial response in Shaker communities; just as the temperance agitation of
                            forty or fifty years ago resulted in the abolition of all- alcoholic drinks as a beverage.
                            To make vegetarianism a requirement today would be premature ; it would exclude many who
                            i.re willing to live the higher life. Have we a right to deny the privileges of the gospel
                            to those to whom the consumption of animal food is not a sin ?<pb n="250" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/>The tree is known by its fruits. There is abundant evidence that the
                            fruits of the gospel system are the very things hum-duity has longed for so long. Poverty
                            does not exist, because all labor and are satisfied with the necessaries and simple comforts
                            of life ; neither are there great riches to tempt to idleness and dissipation. Drunkenness,
                            gambling, sexual immorality, vice in all its various forms, is unknown. Many useful
                            inventions have originated in Shaker communities. A new system of rational theology has been
                            created. Hell has been abolished; the fear of death is taken away ; the avenues of
                            communication with the other world are opened ; a heavenly Mother has been placed by the
                            side of a heavenly Father ; the hope of final salvation and eternal happiness to all is held
                            out. And we expect to be happy here in this world by getting rid of sin of every name and
                            nature as fast as possible. But those who are merely seeking a temporal home where they can
                            nurse their miserable egotism at the expense of the consecrated labor of others find it
                            about the most uncomfortable place they can get into ; while they who come. in through the
                            open door and by an honest confession of their sins, prove the sincerity of their
                            convictions, a new life is dawning upon them, the kingdom of heaven on earth is opening
                            before them, peace and consolation are theirs, the Father's name is written on their
                            foreheads and his spirit dwel's in their hearts. Brush away the scales that are blinding
                            your vision. Do not think of God as the Jewish war-god or as the triple incongruity of
                            orthodoxy; but rather think of Him as with swelling heart you think of your earthly parents,
                            conceive Him as a being of perfect love and mercy, who will sooner or later, draw all home
                            to Himself. I have written at greater length than I intended, but I never weary telling of
                            the beauty of the spiritual life. We are in the midst of a busy season ; God has blessed us
                            with an abundant harvest of fruit and grain and vegetables, and it requires much labor to
                            take care of everything. Now I must bid you farewell, praying that God's holy spirit may
                            lead you into paths of truth and right and make your life a useful and a happy one. But
                            should at any time the spirit within you struggle mightily to burst the chains that now bind
                            it down, and you feel as if the ends of the world had come upon you, and things once near
                            and dear appear as loss and dross, then think of Mt. Lebanon, as a haven of refuge, think of
                            your friends, those who are watching and praying for you and many others whom the Lord will
                            call in his own good time. Your friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Basting, Louis" TEIform="persName"/>Louis Basting.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="St. Patrick's cathedral" TEIform="index"/> ST. PATRICK'S CATHEDRAL.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/> ANNA WHITE.</byline><p TEIform="p"> It so happened recently that it fell to the lot of the writer, in company with
                            four others of the family, to visit that great modern Babylon of confusion, New York City,
                            and that too, when a tropical sun shed its fiery rays unreservedly from out a clear July
                            sky, threatening to dissolve, if not consume. A releasement of thirty-eight years from
                            confinement within brick walls and stone pavements, out into the green<pb n="251" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> pastures and beside the still waters, made my heart leap for joy at the
                            recollection of so happy an escape. The wickedness existing upon that little island of over
                            one million inhabitants, is undoubtedly sufficient to sink it out of sight; and were it not
                            for a few righteous souls a similar fate might occur which befell Sodom and Gomorrah. It has
                            been prophecied that New York City would be swallowed up by water, and as immigration and
                            crime increase is there not danger? We would readily admit that a spiritual wave, or earth
                            quake might engulf it to advantage. As character is moulded anew by virtuous living, it
                            makes its impress upon the features, and shines forth with a divine radiance that betokens a
                            union with the Christ spirit, so with a character that is selfish, intemperate and
                            licentious, whether arrayed in purple or hcarlet colors, and decked with previous stones and
                            costly pearls, or, in tattered habiliments of poverty and siu- -the moulding is there- -it
                            cannot be hid, not even from mortals, much less from an All-seeing eye. The mark of Cain, of
                            disobedience to moral and divine law, is stamped on the visage. And perhaps nowhere else are
                            all the varied characteristics of life better exemplified, thau in the densely crowded
                            thoroughfares of an over-populated city. But where are all these people going, as they rush
                            to and fro and dash against each other like the angry waves of the sea? Why do they flock
                            together in such multitudes, when acre upon acre of land is lying idle, and suffering for
                            the want of cultivation ? Ah ! this is the great problem that is agitating thousands of
                            minds on both continents ; and who is able to solve it? A mighty struggle between capital
                            and labor is going on in the heart of humanity, a war of ideas, that will eventually put to
                            flight the childish notion, that "might makes right." But anon. Wending our way up the broad
                            avenues lined with palaces on either side, with now and then a "steeple house," we find upon
                            the highest site of ground in that vicinity on Fifth Avenue corner of 50th street, the
                            famous Roman Catholic Church, St. Patrick's Cathedral, "the greatest and most magnificent
                            church in the United States. It was projected in 1850 by Archb'shop Hughes, and dedicated by
                            Cardinal McCloskey. It has cost over $2, 000,000. It is in the thirteenth century decorated
                            Gothic style, and the material is fine white marble. It is a Latin cross, 306 feet long, and
                            120 feet wide (140 at transepts,) and 108 feet high, with a noble clere-story upheld on,
                            long lines of clustered marble columns, and carrying a lofty and richly ornamented ceiling.
                            On each side of the front gable (which is 156 feet high, or taller than most of the steeples
                            of America,) the carved and pinnacled spires are to be carried to a height of 328 feet when
                            this huge marble mountain will be a landmark for leagues. The 70 windows (37 of which are
                            memorial) are of rich stained glass, and were made at Chartres, France, at a cost of $100,
                            000. The main altar is 40 feet high, of Italian marble, inlaid with gems, and bass reliefs
                            of the Passion ; and on one side is the great Gothic throne cf the archbishop. The altar of
                            the Holy Family, of Tennessee marble and Caen stone ; of the Blessed Virgin, of curiously
                            carved French walnut; of the Sacred Heart, of bronze ; &amp;c."<pb n="252" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> Entering this immense chapel, still unfinished, we find a few worshipers
                            kneeling before the altar. One approaches in mourning apparel, and after a few ceremonies of
                            introduction, in painful solemnity announces in the Apostles' Creed, "I believe in the Holy
                            Catholic Church, thank God." Yea, we said, in all due reverence to her sincerity, "and thank
                            God we live in a free country, where all may worship according to the dictates of their own
                            consciences." "Ah! but there is only one Church" continued she, and then repeating the
                            Nicene Creed, "I believe in one Catholic an'"! Apostolic Church," moved on to the vestry
                            room. Here we were escorted by a matron in charge, a noble specimen of womanhood, who kindly
                            and courteously answered our numerous questions and showed much pleasure and interest in
                            taking us around. Here were the sacerdotal garments made of linen that the priest had just
                            laid aside after mass, and something rolled up in a napkin that he held in his hand at the
                            ascension that no woman was allowed to touch; also a silver chalice from which he drank wine
                            upon certain occasions, that likewise whs not to be defiled by the hand of woman. Our
                            womanly instincts revolted at this, and put in their claims that "a woman was as pure as a
                            man, and indeed called to be the redeeming ageut to lift out of the mire and mud of
                            sensuality her brother man, by bruising the serpent's head, which is the lust of the flesh,
                            and living a pure and spotless life here in this present evil world." It was seemingly
                            admitted. She informed us that at the foot of the altar in the church vault lay the bodies
                            of Archbishop Hughes and Cardinal McCloskey. Here we made a remark that greatly shocked her
                            as we related the fact that "the Archbishop was partially converted to Shakerism while on a
                            visit to Mt. Lebanon some years since, and that he then endorsed most of our principles, and
                            undoubtedly had united with our Order in the spirit world long ago." We next attacked the
                            needless labor and lavish use of money expended upon the church, when it would have served a
                            far better purpose in filling the mouths of the hungry with bread and covering their bodies
                            with clothing. This touched a tender spot. "The poor ye have always with you," she quoted,
                            "and earthly temples cannot be too grand and costly reared for the Lord." "Jesus was forced
                            to make that declaration" we remarked, "and would be obliged to do the same today were he to
                            enter a city like this and witness as we are now doing the inequality existing. In Christ
                            there is neither rich nor, poor, high nor low, bond nor free, Jew nor Greek, male nor
                            female. You will find upon examination that the principles which Jesus taught are
                            practically illustrated in our Shaker homes ; and gathering up the crumbs that nothing be
                            lost, is not regarded as among the least of his precepts. But what are you going to do with
                            Father McGlynu ? "Oh! the blessed saint," she ejaculated, "so good, so humble, to think he
                            could commit such an error." "What has he done in violation of the church discipline?" we
                            queried. "That lies between the father and the son- -between Pope Leo xiii and Dr. Edward
                            McGlynn." Farewell my catholic sister, while we admire and reverence your sincerity, we
                            detest your false system. At this instant the entire scene<pb n="253" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> changed, a shudder crept over us as suddenly this splendid cathedral, to our mental
                            vision, was converted into the Inquisition with ail its horrors. You could almost feel the
                            grip of the gibbet, the cruel fangs of the rack, the dismal damps of the dungeon with the
                            faggot and flame. The same spirit was there as existing in the loth century when thirty
                            thousand heretics in the name of God were slain in one day ; and did the same power rule we
                            might expect like results. Xo wonder that men like Dr. McGlynn feel the oppression of the
                            usurper's yoke, and not for themselves only but for thousands of workingmen and women whom
                            they represent. May their influence under the Christ spirit help "loose the bands of
                            wickedness, and undo the hea^y burdens, and let the oppressed go free." Farewell to St.
                            Patrick's Cathedral, thy glitter and luster without, hides not thy deformity within. "Woe
                            unto you Scribes and Pharisees, hypocrites ! for ye are like unto whited sepulchres which
                            indeed appeal' beautiful without, but are within full of dead meu's bones, and of all
                            uncleanness.." Jesus. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Perseverance" TEIform="index"/> PERSEVERANCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnston, Mary" TEIform="persName"/> MARY JOHNSTON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> '' Let us not be weary in well-doing: for in due season we shall reap, if we
                            faint not. " Perseverance is the vital spring that forms our lives and characters and makes
                            it possible to overcome apparently insurmountable obstacles in the pursuit of any great or
                            noble achievement. In reviewing the past, all great enterprises and undertakings have
                            succeeded over the great mountains of discouragemeot, unbelief, and opposition by a firm and
                            steady adherence to this beautiful virtue, Perseverance. So it proves at the present day
                            equally as important towar Js the unfolding of the latent g'M'ins that lie hidden beneath
                            the chaos of the unsettled mind, to persevere onward and upward from the labyrinths that
                            would obstruct our advancement to higher conditions. The beautiful text above promises that
                            if we are faithful we shall reap of the fruits of our labors. Had not our parents of the
                            Gospel persevered in maintaining the testimony of light and truth, where would be their
                            followers to-day? But thank God ! they have paved the way of freedom from the dominion of
                            the adversary. The flood-gates of light are swinging open to the world, and people are
                            beginning to see the light and Power that will aid them to fight the good fight and triumph
                            over all. Although our opportunities for doing good may be small, yet we must remember it is
                            not the great acts, but rather the litile deeds of love that are the truest and the purest.
                            We all have i within our pow7er to contribute towards each other some little attention of
                            kindness ; though small it may appear to us it will not be lost- -therefore " let us not be
                            weary in well-doing : for we shall reap if we faint not." Nothing but perseverance ever
                            accomplished the great reforms which bless our country to-day ; workers whose indefatigable
                            energies sought to alleviate the wounds and bruises of a needy and suffering people- -and as
                            we reflect upon their labors, we will note how all thought of self was left far in the
                            distance. Through this channel of great and successful efforts attained, mighty
                                evolutiots<pb n="254" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> of the mind and soul enforce the
                            practicability of recognizing woman at the standard of equality. Woman is the great emblem
                            of liberty for our beloved land, and why should it not be so in reality? Shall our emblem
                            ever remain a fac-simile of the true and perfect organization of God's law ? I see from
                            various sources outside the pale of Shakerdom that many minds recognize the duality of a
                            Father and Mother in the God-head, and from all appearances the time is not far distant when
                            the Holy Spirit will again visit the children of men, with great power and baptize with the
                            fire that will not be quenched until all the chaff and rubbish of a proud and worldly spirit
                            shall be consumed. May the time hasten when the earth shall be so favored- -for few are the
                            laborers to reap this great and glorious harvest, but " let us commit our way unto the Lord
                            ; trust also in him, and he shall bring it to pass. " Psa. xxxvii., 5. There are two great
                            epochs in the world's history that always rise before our vision with special reverence.
                            First, the life of our Savior and his disciples how they suffered all persecution even unto
                            death- -and second, the life of Mother Ann Lee and her followers. What violent and abusive
                            conduct was their portion as they endeavored to establish the great Millennium that showed
                            the necessity of bearing a full cross in order to be one with Christ in that kingdom where
                            no unclean thing can enter. These two cycles embrace all the conditions that man could wish
                            to attain, and right here, we see a noble banner with the inscription in golden letters that
                            tells us "Our Hope is through Faithfulness and Perseverance." This encomium is awarded our
                            Goapel Parents, and all who make the full sacrifice. Oftentimes when I am called to traverse
                            the field ot test and trial, if I find any lurking foe not rallying round this standard of
                            trust, I ask at once is every motive acceptable to the Holy One? Is his honor and glory the
                            first thought? or is the first thought for the honor and glory of self? It is only through
                            adherence to this divine injunction : "Not to grow weary in well-doing" that we may at last
                            reap the blessed result. Pleasant Hill, Ky. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Forgiveness" TEIform="index"/> FORGIVENESS.</head><p TEIform="p"> Forgiveness and love, go hand in hand. You do not love any one whom you cannot
                            forgive, nor can you freely forgive any one you do not love. So the two are inseparable. We
                            are commanded to "Love our enemies;" we are also commanded to "Forgive our enemies," and if
                            we love and forgive our enemies, God will love and forgive us our sins. If we do not, God
                            will not love and forgive us. God has an altar in Zioa where He meets all who come
                            confessing their evil doings, and there and then, forgives the penitent soul and extends his
                            care and protection, that we may love an:l forgive our enemies. God first loved us, and this
                            love causes our acknowledgement of our sins and He forgives us. Let us be godly and do
                            likewise.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brown, N." TEIform="persName"/> N. Brown. Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our Father" TEIform="index"/> OUR FATHER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, Chauncy" TEIform="persName"/> CHANCY DIBBLE. </byline><p TEIform="p">God dwells in a multitude and works through unnumbered instrumentalities, to whom
                            He imparts life and through whom He makes his character and will<pb n="255" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> known to all his intelligences, so far as is within their comprehension.
                            Truth does not shine in all its luster where ignorance and superstition reigns, hence,
                            inconsistent ideas of the past must fade before the advancing light. Yet there are eternal
                            truths to which every rational mind must concede. Whatever shades of error may cling about
                            us, virtue, peace and love must be respected throughout the realm of intelligences in heaven
                            and earth, aud those who practice these virtues are the light of the world. All our life
                            service, our encomiums upon the loveliness of our Savior, of his death and suffering upon
                            the cross, all the churches and church going, the prayers aud missionary labors will never
                            atone for disobedience to our convictions of right. We look with scorn upon the Jews of old
                            for rejecting Christ. Have we emerged out of that savage condition, sufficiently, to accept
                            practically, the life of the Savior ? Does the pomp and splendor of the churches, the
                            revelry in luxury and ease, manifest the graces of meekness and love? We complain of the
                            spirit of monopoly and fraud that is growing so mightily in society. Are professing
                            Christians a whit behind in these? Does the stupendous preparations now in progress among
                            Christian nations for war, prove them to be followers of the Prince of Peace ? Christian
                            nations have the most destructive war materials, are the bravest, and fear each other most;
                            a compliment indeed for our military heroes ; and are they not most haughty, revengeful and
                            tyrannical? Do ouch endorse the motto, '' Pray for those who despitefully use you. Love your
                            enemies." We look and pray with longing hearts for the Millennium to dawn. Are the people
                            prepared to accept it, in its purity peace aud harmony? We fear if Jesus should come ne
                            would be as of old, without where to lay his head. The self-righteous cannot, will not be
                            baptized with that spirit, for the Gospel is opposed to a lif.- of worldKness We need not
                            expect to see heaven coming down f-om the skies or be wafted to us already prepared, if we
                            neglect to cultivate gospel graces in our own hearts. This consecration of our lives to the
                            good of others ; this dying daily to all our evil habits; is this too expensive? We may yet
                            meet ourselves in a straight place where there will be no turning. and the record of our
                            lives will be plain before us. Then shall. we be thankful for a gospel of mercy. Would it
                            not be wise to commence a reform right here ; to become clothed by degrees with those graces
                            which adorn the angel world ? This requires patient continuance in well-doing, until sin is
                            eradicated and we reign triumphant over self. Such have eternal life abiding in them for
                            they live in the spirit and can never die. When the animal part decays, the spirit lives in
                            all its intelligence, to meet kindred fssociations in a sphere beyond, where our associates
                            will be those of our own choosing. May the kind Father aud Mother of all, aid us through
                            those ministering spirits of light, whose love extends to all the needy. May we feel the
                            warmth of the sun of righteousness which shines equally for all. May Christian equality
                            prevail, aud all be made happy together. Then will heaven come nearer to earth, and angels
                            shed their blessings freely upon us. Watervliet, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="256" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES.</head><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> MANIFESTO. NOVEMBER, 1887. Office of publication. The Manifesto is published
                                at Shaker Village Mer. Co., N. H. All articles for publication should be addressed to
                                Henry C. Blinn, and all letters on financial business to A. Y. Cochran. TERMS. One copy
                                per year, postage paid, " six months, " Send for specimen copy, free. .75 .40 </p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Church and its promises" TEIform="index"/> THE CHURCH AND ITS PROMISES.</head><p TEIform="p"> Although we may differ from the great body of Christ.ans, in our acceptance
                                of the life of Christ, we feel well assured that we have received the spirit of his
                                mission. As imperfectly as-we may represent the order of the work, we know that the
                                foundation principles are sure, and that all who are led by the spirit of God, are the
                                sons and daughters of God. Against this life and testimony of Jesus Christ, "the gates
                                of hell" can never prevail. It may become a matter of convenience for some to throw
                                aside the yoke and the cross which belongs to the work of regeneration, when they learn
                                that there is danger of losing their fellowship with the children of this world. By the
                                law of corresponding necessity, they must have their reward, as a just retribution must
                                follow all the deeds done in the body, whether they are good or evil. To us, it seems
                                hardly consistent to accept a teacher and then show an utter disregard to his special
                                instructions. No order of an earthly government would tolerate such a dereliction of
                                duty, without the infliction of severe penalty on the transgressor. "If you love me,"
                                said Jesus, "you will keep my commandments." This proved to be a correct test, although
                                so kindly and so carefully referred to their own consciences. But the Christian as an
                                individual, the Christian Church and the Christian world, have chosen to modify and to
                                change the order of the primitive or apostolic church, till it would be difficult to
                                recognize it by the name which it assumes. That is, if to be a Christian, means "one
                                whose inward and outward life is conformed to the doctrines of Christ." The simplicity -
                                -f the word that was preached in the wilderness, by Jchn, while calling men to
                                repentance, and subsequently, the deeper and clearer word of Jesus, which made the deaf
                                to hear and the blind to see, has but little in it that moves harmoniously by the side
                                of a creed-bound and world-absorbing Christian church. From the first to the last day,
                                in the advent of Jesus, his whole theme was the coming of the kingdom of God, and the
                                manner in which it was to be established on the earth, among men. In this kingdom, or
                                church, God was to be hallowed; men were to forgive their enemies, as they would ask of
                                God to be forgiven ; and the ruling spirit was to harmonize through all its government,
                                with that in the kingdom of heaven. The selfish relation of the world, which has its
                                foundation in the flesh, and which has ruled, more or less directly every action, must
                                now give THE<pb n="257" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> place to a life of self-abnegation, when
                                those who do the will of God, as Jesus taught, are to be his and our brothers and
                                sisters. He tells us that he had no private inheritance in the world, no place, even, to
                                rest his head, and yet, at the same time, he advised those who would become his
                                disciples, to dispose of their earthly treasures and form, with him, a community of
                                united interest, where they could realize an hundred fold of all the blessings of this
                                world, and an assurance of eternal life. All this was promised to those who would follow
                                him in the regeneration. The lv.',velator, in his beautiful vision, saw those who were
                                redeemed from among men, who stood without fault before the throne of God; and this
                                class "follow the Lamb of God whithersoever he goeth." If Jesus taught his disciples to
                                lay up their treasures in the kingdom of God, we must do and teach the same, or we
                                cannot, in truth, follow him. Every writer of the history of Jesus, understands all
                                this, and also understands equally as well, that the Pentecostal church was built upon
                                this very foundation of obedience to the life of Christ. It was a church where the
                                members were to have a love and a brotherly interest in each other, which should stand
                                in advance of any order to be found among the children of this world. A righteousness
                                that should exceed the righteousness of all religious professors who came before him. It
                                was to be a living church, rising in the resurrection of Christ. Death was to have no
                                part in it, for those who were alive and believed on him, should never die. Jesus, no
                                doubt, gloried in his freedom from the selfishness of the world, when he said, "The
                                foxes have holes, and the birds of the air have nests, but the son of man hath not where
                                to lay his head." Every Christian communist can say the same, and yet, enjoy to a
                                fulness the hundred fold relation. "Seek first the kingdom of God and its
                                righteousness," said he, and not occupy all the time in thinking what we shall eat and
                                drink, and of the garments in which we are to be clothed. Something higher and better
                                should be found upon which to dwell. To the virtuous, rich man he said, "If thou wilt be
                                perfect, go and sell all thou hast, give to the poor, and thou shalt have treasure in
                                heaven ; then come and follow me." Sell all thou hast! It was in this religious
                                brotherhood, this community of united inheritance, that those who possessed property
                                were to sell their houses and lauds and make their consecration to the church. The
                                fearful example that was made of two per.sons, by the disciples at Pentecost, who by
                                deceitfully representing the amount of their property, lost their lives, might,
                                seemingly, be clear to the most obtuse mind, and yet the Christian church by some form
                                of twistificatiou, ignoi*e all these lessons, and rush along among the multitude, hand
                                iu hand with the sons of Belial. There were lessons of value, also, in the days of
                                Moses, bordering very closely upon this same form of discipline, and as he was called a
                                schoolmaster to bring souls to Christ, his work was, in all respects, a much needed
                                preparation. The earthly blessings which God promised the Israelites, through Moses were
                                abundant. "The <pb n="258" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> Lord thy God bringeth thee into a
                                good land, a land of brooks of water, of fountains and depths that spring out of the
                                hills ; a land of wheat and barley, and vines, and fig trees, and pomegrauites, a land
                                of olive oil and honey, a land wherein thou shalt eat bread without scarceness, thou
                                shalt not lack anything in it; a land where stones are iron, and out of the hills thou
                                mayest dig brass." Deut. viii., 9. And this extended promise was made while the
                                Israelites were wanderers in the wilderness, and forced to live on bread and water. But
                                the promise was good to those who were privileged to enter the land of Canaan. Jesus in
                                the same spirit promised to those who love him and keep his commandments, an hundred
                                fold of earthly blessings and spiritually eternal life. And this, when he had no home
                                and no earthly possessions ; yet his words have been and are being fulfilled in those
                                who live as he lived. Everything of this order gives its inspiration to the work in
                                which the " Believers" are engaged. "Blest be that universal love, For which the
                                Christian aims ; Whose source in God, is found above All narrow, human claims. As towers
                                the lofty mountain top Above the distant sea, So stands the merits of this love In its
                                divinity."</p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wants to be a prophet" TEIform="index"/> Wants to be a Prophet.</head><p TEIform="p">An EngRsh clergyman of the Established Church has been delivering prophetic
                                lectures. He says England is to be separated legislatively from Ireland, India and her
                                colonies. Lucien Bonaparte is to become King of Syria and later on Emperor of France.
                                Belgium and the Ehine provinces are to be annexed to France. In 1896 144,000 watchful
                                Christians are to ascend from earth to heaven, and the millennium is to commence on
                                April 11, 1901. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Everyone knows how to find fault" TEIform="index"/>Everyone knows how to find
                            fault </head><p TEIform="p"> Everyone knows how to find fault.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary. </head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Food adulterations" TEIform="index"/>FOOD ADULTERATIONS </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> THE PUBLIC HAS POWER IN ITS HANDS TO EFFECT REFORM. The
                                        chemists of the Department of Agriculture, under direction of the Commissioner,
                                        have, for a year or more, been investigating the matter of food adulteration in
                                        this country, and a report is in process of preparation. That portion relating
                                        to spices and condiments prepared by Mr. Clifford Richardson is already
                                        completed. Mr. Richardson's investigations show that no other kinds of human
                                        food are adulterated to such an extent. Of twenty samples of ground cloves only
                                        two were pure. The others had suffered the extraction of their essential oils,
                                        and had been polluted by the addition of clove stems, all-spice, and husks of
                                        various kinds. Of eight samples of Cayenne pepper only one was pure. Of ten
                                        samples of mustard, none were pare unchanged mustard, though several had only
                                        suffered the loss of their fixed oil: the others contained quantities of wheat
                                        flour, the spurious matter being in some cases two thirds of the compound. This
                                        made it necessary to add tumeric acid (harmless) to restore the mustard color.
                                        Ten samples of allspice were examined, eight of which were pure. Four samples of
                                        cassia were all pure. Of ten samples of ginger four were pure. Only one out of
                                        thirteen samples of black pepper was found to be what it purported to be. A
                                        specimen sent from Baltimore to a man who had an army contract was almost
                                        entirely spurious. Cayenne pepper, black pepper husks, and mustard hulls were
                                        used to give flavor and pungency, while '' body " was supplied by ground beans
                                        and rice, and color by charcoal. Two samples of white pepper out of five were
                                        pure; two samples of mace out of five were pure, and of three samples of nutmeg
                                        examined all were pure. Mr. Richardson's experience leads to the conclusion that
                                        the public has the power in its own hands to effect a reform in the matter of
                                        spice adulteration. The quality of the<pb n="259" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/>
                                        article is usually fixed by the retailer, who names the price he is willing to
                                        pay. The grinder thereupon estimates the amount of pure spice he can afford to
                                        put in, and fills out the order with refuse. Mr. Richardson incidentally
                                        mentions a New York spice grinder who, within a short time worked off 5,000
                                        pounds of cocoanut husks. The ground article, which sells for less than the pure
                                        and unground, needs no test to prove it spurious. Usually when he demanded a
                                        pure article and called upon a first class grocer for it he got it. Considerable
                                        space is given in the report to the operation of laws pt home and abroad
                                        relating to the adulteration of food, while the methods of detection, both
                                        popular and scientific, are treated exhaustively. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/> halFs Journal of
                                        Health.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ardent spirits" TEIform="index"/> ARDENT SPIRITS.</head><p TEIform="p"> We use spirits in tinctures and syrups when we think it necessary, and in no
                                other case whatever unless we think in our best judgment that the stimulus of ardent
                                spirits is indispensable. We find that medicine administered without spirits is far more
                                efficacious than when given in combination with it, in the majority of stomach
                                complaints. In cases where alkalies such as soda or salts of tartar are indicated we add
                                them to syrups, which preserves them from souring without the addition of spirits. No
                                definite rule can be given ; but it is our firm purpose and intention never to let Old
                                Alcohol creep into the church under the cloak of medicine. Sept. 15, 1828. Eliab Harlow,
                                } ri. Garret K. Lawrence, physicians. [At the above early date the temperance cause
                                found able advocates in the good physicians. The position they occupied was in advance
                                of the people generally, whether members or not members of the Society ; and the same
                                care has been maintained to the present date. Ed.] </p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mild in manner, resolute in purpose" TEIform="index"/>Mild in manner,
                            resolute in purpose </head><p TEIform="p"> Mild in manner, resolute in purpose.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fear of the Lord..." TEIform="index"/>Fear of the Lord... </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stickney, Asenath C." TEIform="persName"/>ASENATH C. STICKNEY.</byline><p TEIform="p"> " The fear of ihe Lord is the beginning of wisdom." This saying, though written
                            centuries since, contains a truth, which in my estimation, is as appropriate in its
                            application to us of the present age, as for those to whom it was addressed by the devout
                            Psalmist. "The fear of the Lord is the beginning of wisdom," was the oft repeated lesson in
                            our copy book when a pupil, and although the impress of its certainty has never faded from
                            memory, yet its deeper spiritual meaning recurs to me today, with new force, and so instinct
                            with vitality is it, so freighted with wisdom that to repeat, or transcribe the same in a
                            mechanical way would now seem but a very feeble use of its twofold value. Hoping, therefore,
                            to make it a medium of practical benefit, personally coupled with a deep solicitude for the
                            welfare of youthful mind.- -, I invite the attention of the latter to the meaning of the
                            text quoted, and to bring to their notice also in how many simple ways the same is and ran
                            be actualized by individuals v\ho fear God rather than human opinion. I am happy to realize
                            that there are worthy characters with whom we are daily conversant who are patterns of
                            goodness, and in whose lives the beginning of wisdom is so vividly apparent, in bearing and
                            address that the most morally obtuse, and uncultured in our ranks are compelled to admire,
                            in such, what they cannot imitate, yet are attracted to a better life, through the
                            unassuming, moral dignity and politeness of such. Experience teaches that God-fearing<pb n="260" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> persons are proverbially well-bred and consequently, are
                            invested with a charm which is especially winning to youth and has in itself a power for
                            good. "We invariably find that the genuine Christian, though 'ruthfuland simple in demeanor,
                            is yet courteous in speech, deferential to youth, as well as to age, cordial to equals,
                            charitable to inexperience, and forgiving to the wayward. Such are never boisterous or in
                            any way inconsistent with their profession of practical peace, and oft in their near and
                            prayerful approaches to God, I seem to hear them breathe with the poet, the sentiment of the
                            beautiful lines addressed to Him. " What are ten thousand worlds, compared to Thee? And what
                            am I then? Heaven's unnumbered host, Though multiplied by myriads and arrayed In all the
                            glory of sublimest thought, Is but an atom in the balance weighed Against thy greatness;-
                            -is a cipher brought, Against Infinity! O! what am I then? Naught." Bu1. to return to
                            practical experience I will add that one rarely hears the heavy footfalls of these, in
                            dwellings consecrated to prayer, nor is annoyed by the harsh raising or closing of
                            windowsashes or blinds especially in hours sacred to worship or repose. No reckless opening
                            or slamming of doors heralds their casual entrance or departure from any apartment, or in
                            other words, no echoes reach us indicative of the gross language of uncurbed passion, for
                            the fear and the love of godliness rules the entire being. Still further, no exaggerated
                            statements fall readily from their lips about common occurrences to shock the ear or pain
                            the heart of the truth loving, and thus we might continue to enumerate the excellencies of
                            those whose habits of politeness, resting upon a basis as exalted as is the truth of our
                            chosen text make peace and harmony in the externals of this life. From examples instanced
                            here, I think we may readily discover from whence proceeds the real goodness which we so
                            much admire, and from what principles of honor too real excellence of character is evolved.
                            Hence, we infer that it is no mark of superiority to be loud and boastful in speech, or
                            dictatorial in manner. That truth is never made more conclusive by strong expressions, that
                            falseness of assertion through habitual exaggeration, whether employed in praise or censure,
                            betokens moral weakness, and strictly speaking is the language of ignorance, dictated by
                            passion rather than by superior intelligence. To my dear youthful friends let me extend this
                            cordial invitation, that as you essay to join the ranks of the disciples of the cross, you
                            will unite with us in a renewed covenant to cultivate good manners, and aim to be more
                            select in your choice of words in common conversation. Permit me to instance just a few
                            specimen expressions from the many which you should avoid and which unfortunately too often,
                            find their way into would-be refined circles of the present age, trusting that by so doing,
                            you will see more clearly the errors to which I point, as follows :- -It is horribly cold
                            today. I think this rain is just horrid. I am awful tired. I am tired to death. I believe I
                            shall starve. That is an aw ful, pretty flower. Such a remark was awful cute. Added to the
                            grammatical incorrectness with which the words, awful, horrid and terrible are used, there
                            is such a falseness in the statements thus made when viewed from a moral standpoint, that
                            though used as qualifying adjectives, or adverbs, they are not only misplaced in that sense
                            but in<pb n="261" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> connection with all slang phrases, are as entirely
                            out of place in the social converse of Christian civilization, as are common outlaws and
                            criminals among peaceable citizens. One of our early leaders, Father Job Bishop, often
                            reproved young people for the too common use of the word awful. He said, " There is nothing
                            awful but the judgments of God, and you should not make a free use of this word." Trusting
                            that some youthful mind may be worthily impressed with what is here written I will conclude
                            this appeal by repeating, - -' The fear of tht Lord is the beginning of wisdom, and the
                            knowledge of the holy is understanding." Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unrest" TEIform="index"/> UNREST.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON. </byline><p TEIform="p">Heave, heave ye giand billows on time's cradled sea, Tumultuous toss on its
                            breast! Break, break on its strand ye wild waves and free, Ye are emblems of human unrest!
                            The surging of thought from the depths of the mind Is swaying the nations today, The tides
                            that are rushing, what power can bind? Who, truth's potent forces shall sway? There are
                            prophets arisen as true as of yore, Apostles who hallow no creeds, Who are waking to action
                            as never before, To work for humanity's needs. With new inspiration the people are stirred,
                            How the old wrongs and new wrongs will quail, Till righteousness answers to justice
                            deferred, And the true golden rule will prevail. While the voice of the throng loudly
                            clamors for right, There are many who silently bear, Awaiting God's time, and the arm of his
                            might, To bring a response to their prayer. The strong rule of centuries rise9 to sight, A
                            castle, with battlements high, Which the art, skill and valor of labor's bold knight With
                            courage and patience defy. Not force or blind passion will conquer or win, Nor the red flag,
                            defiant unfurled; Ope your hearts O ye people let Christ enter in, He triumphs o'er sins of
                            the world! The Master was greatest, yet humblest in name, No landed estate did He own, No
                            home, and no title to wealth laid He claim, By love was His mission made known. The friend
                            of the poor, the weak and oppressed, Reprover of folly and sin; The wrongs of the widow and
                            orphan redressed, And strove all the erring to win. Are ye his vicegerents, ye sceptered and
                            crowned, Who rule with the pomp of a state, ' Whom thousands of vassals with splendor
                            surround, And homage receive from the great? Ah nay! the cry passes from door unto door,
                            From the temple whose service He loved, The Savior is found in the " Priest of the Poor,"
                            His mission is blest and approved. God sends through the lowly the means of his grace,
                            Through hearts that are rich in his love, Whose feelings go out to the whole human race, The
                            worth of the gospel to prove. Pride and power hath narrowed redemption's broad The Church
                            would extinguish its lights, [plan, Its prelates deny the true manhood of man, And would
                            wrest from him heaven-born rights. Low arched are its portals, and dim are the rays That
                            fall on high altar and aisle, Or lume the deep transepts where worship and praise, Resound
                            through the time-honored pile. Shall he be disgraced whom the Lord would uphold ? Who loveth
                            like him to do good, Whose teachings to-day, like the precepts of old By the selfish are not
                            understood. Aa multitudes listened in reverent mood To truths which the Savior declared, Nor
                            went from his presence till comfort and food From his bounteous hand they had shared, So the
                            teachers of men must in sympathy blend With hearts that have one common need, Equality,
                            justice and mercy defend, The cause of the lowliest plead. Then, blessings will follow
                            Religion's pure name, Its ministries truly divine Will kindle anew its bright altar flame,
                            And souls will return to its shrine. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Advice to the young no. 1" TEIform="index"/> ADVICE TO THE YOUNG. No. 1.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shepard, Harriet" TEIform="persName"/>HARRIET SHKPARD.</byline><p TEIform="p"> It is better to learn young what difficulties are, and how to meet life's
                            misfortunes. Begin now to share another's ills, aud help to bear the burden under which your
                            neighbor may be sinking. Repress often thy hilarity aud go to the place cf mourning and
                            discipline thy vivacity to speak soothingly to the afflicted.<pb n="262" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 202 the manifp:sto. Life is a reality. Old or young we have always a duty
                            to do and something to bear. Our occupation is here and imploring suffering invites us to
                            it, and the call of good will and charity is, " Come over and help us." Places of service
                            are as many as are the abodes of the needy and distressed. Have you anything to do but to
                            decorate your frail ten. ement and your own surroundings, and cultivate pride which must be
                            wholly eradicated before becoming a truly meek and humble follower of Christ? Have you
                            powers of heart and soul to give to the labor of self-elevation and the improvement of our
                            kind? The pains that have been taken to educate you has accelerated your ability for
                            usefulness, by fertilizing your heart, and illuminating your sensibilities and supplying
                            your intellectual faculty with fresh and aspiring thoughts. Having acquired new impulses to
                            your advancing nature, and expansion of your intellectual and virtuous capability, for which
                            you are accountable : your Heavenly Father will hold you amenable. North Union, Ohio. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Acrostic" TEIform="index"/> ACROSTIC.</head><p TEIform="p">Wisdom from Proverbs. A soft answer turneth away wrath, xv., 1. Let not mercy and
                            truth forsake thee. iii., 3. |n the fear of the Lord is strong confidence, xiv., 27. Commit
                            thy works unto the Lord and thy thoughts shall be established, xvi., 3. ETery purpose is
                            established by counsel, xx., 18. Correction is grievious unto him that forsaketh the way.
                            xv.] 10. A merry heart maketh a cheerful countenance, xv., 13. Righteousness delivereth from
                            death, xi., 3. Yea if thou criest after knowledge and liftest up thy voice for understanding
                            then shalt thou understand the fear of the Lord and find the knowledge of God. ii., 35. Wme
                            is a mocker, strong drink is raging, xx., 1. A merry heart doeth good like a medicine,
                            xviii., 22. Death and Life are in the power of the tongue, xix, 20. Even a child is known by
                            his doings whether Ms work be pure and whether it be right, xx., 11. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Speak no-evil club" TEIform="index"/>THE SPEAK-NO-EVIL CLUB </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A very novel society which has been started in England is called
                                    " The Speak-no-Evil Society." Its members are enjoined before speaking evil of any
                                    one to ask themselves three questions : "Is it true? Is it kind? Is it necessary?"
                                    These simple questions, if answered by all evil-speakers before uttering the remarks
                                    derogatory to others, might result in a new society of most delightful qualities.
                                    Often people speak evil, not from any motives of unkindness, but from vanity. They
                                    think that by pointing out the faults of other people they will cause their own
                                    virtues to shine out in a brighter light. Nothing could be more erroneous. By
                                    speaking evil they create the distrust of those who hear them and lose a position of
                                    dignity which true reserve always brings. When evil speaking is necessary to warn
                                    others against placing confidence in the evil doer, the circumstances of the case
                                    are changed and the necessity of the criticism will cause the critic to be
                                    respected. On a similar basis with the " Speak-no-Evil Club " is a club proposed by
                                    "Good Housekeeping" for a mind cure. Its rules are : Personal ills are not to be
                                    mentioned. Anything like gossip is to be avoided. Nothing depressing or gloomy is to
                                    be allowed. The first rule is a valuable adjunct to the speak-no-evil questions. One
                                    who continually speaks evil of himself is not only selfish but discourteous to
                                    others, but a boor who does not put in practice the first rule of polite society.
                                    His complaints are mistrusted and his criticisms made an object of amusement.
                                    Unselfishness makes the rules which prevent the speaking of evil bright and
                                    attractive. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Boston journal" TEIform="index"/>Boston Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The evangelicals of Hungary..." TEIform="index"/>The evangelicals of
                            Hungary... </head><p TEIform="p"> The evangelicals of Hungary, both Lutheran and Eeformed, have united in the
                            project of revising their translation of the Bible. </p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Baptist church in Ocala, Florida..." TEIform="index"/>A Baptist church in
                            Ocala, Florida... </head><p TEIform="p"> A Baptist church in Ocala, Fla. has expelled all members whose names have
                            appeared on petitions for liquor licences. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Strength is from above" TEIform="index"/>Strength is from above </head><p TEIform="p"> Strength is from above.</p></div2><pb n="263" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Now" TEIform="index"/> NOW </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Akise, for the day is passing While you lie dreaming on; Your
                                    brothers are cased in armor, And forth to the fight are gone; Your place in the
                                    ranks awaits you ; Each man has a part to play; The past and the future are nothing
                                    In the face of the stern to-day. Arise from your dreams of the future- - Of gaining
                                    a hard-fought field, Of storming the airy fortress, Of bidding the giant yield !
                                    Your life may have deeds of glory, Of honor; God grant it may! But your arm will
                                    never be stronger, Or needed as now to-day. Arise ! If the past detain you, Her
                                    sunshine and storms forget, No claims so unworthy to hold you As those of a vain
                                    regret; Sad or bright, she is lifeless ever; Cast her phantom arms away, Nor look
                                    back, save to learn the lesson Of a nobler strife to-day. Arise ! for the hour is
                                    passing; The sound that you dimly hear, Is your enemy marching to battle; Eise !
                                    rise ! for the foe is near. Stay not to brighten your weapons, Or the hour will
                                    strike at last, And from dreams of a coming battle You will wake, and find it past. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Household words" TEIform="index"/>Household Words.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thought for others" TEIform="index"/>A THOUGHT FOR OTHERS </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Life is full of earnest purpose, Noble deeds and worthy care ;
                                    But amid the strife and struggle Let the pleasant word be there. Smooth the brow
                                    from frowns unlovely: Tune the heart to cheerful words; Pause and look at smiling
                                    Nature; Learn a lesson from the birds. High resolves and lofty planning Need not
                                    cloud the dauntless heart; With the hoping and aspiring Let a kindly word have part.
                                    Oh, the world would be the better, If each morn our hearts would say : "Through the
                                    struggle and the warfare I will help some soul to-day ! " Only, mayhap, with a
                                    greeting, Or a passing word of cheer; Yet some downcast heart may brighten, Finding
                                    sympathy so near. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our love for one another should be like the air, pure, healthy..." TEIform="index"/> Our love for one another should be like the air, pure, healthy... </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Our love for one another should be like the air, pure, healthy,
                                    and ever present; through storm and sunshine the life element.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Calver, A. J." TEIform="index"/>A. J. Calver. </bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Claus Spreckels' enormous income" TEIform="index"/>CLAUS SPRECKELS' ENORMOUS
                            INCOME </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fitch, George H." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">When to this is added the fact that he pay? not one cent of duty
                                    on this crude sugar brought from the Islands, some idea of the enormous profits of
                                    the business may be gained. It was estimated three years ago, when the business was
                                    at its height, that Spreckels made six hundred barrels of sugar everjT day, each
                                    barrel worth thirty dollars, thus giving him a daily revenue of eighteen thousand
                                    dollars, or six million five hundred and seventy thousand dollars a year. His
                                    profits were a clear ten dollars on every barrel, making his yearly income two
                                    million one hundred and ninety thousand dollars. Now, however, the profits have
                                    dwindled sadly, as the railroad company can no longer make special contracts with
                                    him, and a rival sugar refining company is competing with him for the control of the
                                    sugar interests on the islands. King Kalakaua, after borrowing three-quarters of a
                                    million from Spreckels, has recently negotiated a loan of two million dollars with
                                    English capitalists, a proceeding that led to a violent quarrel between the monarch
                                    and his money lender. So leng, however, as the Reciprocity Treaty with Hawaii
                                    continues in force, Spreckels will coin money out of his sugar interests. It is
                                    estimated that he is worth twenty-five million dollars, a large part of which is
                                    invested in plantations, machinery, steamships, and sailing vessels.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Cosmopolitan" TEIform="index"/>George H. Fitch in the September
                                    Cosmopolitan.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Loyalty feels not shame" TEIform="index"/>Loyalty feels not shame </head><p TEIform="p"> Loyalty feels not shame.</p></div2><pb n="264" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers </head><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The alpha" TEIform="index"/>The Alpha</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Primary monthly" TEIform="index"/>Primary Monthly</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Intermediate monthly" TEIform="index"/>Intermediate Monthly</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>Phrenological journal and science of health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thirty second annual report" TEIform="index"/>Thirty second annual report</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peter Henderson and Co." TEIform="index"/>Peter Henderson and Co.</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Forest and steam publishing co." TEIform="index"/>Forest and Steam
                                Publishing Co.</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> The Alpha, is published on the first of each month, by the Moral Educational
                                Society of Washington, D. C. The reformitory work which this paper seeks to establish in
                                the world, and the devoted interest which it manifests in calling the attention of all
                                classes to a higher standard of morality, it worthy of much praise. It is quite time
                                that these lessons, so essentially necessary for happiness in this life, should be
                                placed before the public, that this form of " knowledge may cover the land as the waters
                                cover the sea." Edited by Caroline B. Winslow, and published at$l. OOayr. Prim art
                                Monthly. An illustrated Magazine for supplementary reading in primary schools, pp 32. 3
                                cts. pr copy. Interstate Pub. Co. 30 Franklin St. Boston. Intermediate Monthly. An
                                illustrated Magazine of entertaining and instructive stories for boys and girls, pp 32.
                                Price same as " Primary." The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health. Contents:
                                Oct. Luke P. Poland; Observations in Mesmerism forty years ago; Some Notable Characters
                                of the Day; Christian Religion, Its History and Divisions; Evolutionary Problems; Old
                                Time Courtesy; O. S. Fowler; Heredity; Mrs. Smith's Way; Indications of Disease in
                                Infants; Healthy v. s. Injurious Brain Work; Should Women remain in the Medical
                                Profession ? Child Culture; Notes on Science; Poetry, etc. Fowler &amp; Wells Co.
                                775 Broadway, N. Y. $2. a year. Thirty Second Annual Report of the Odd Fellows Lib.
                                Association of city of San Francisco, for 1886- -87. Peter Henderson &amp; Co's
                                Autumn Catalogue of Bulbs, Plants and Seeds, for 1887. 35 Courtland St. N. Y. Hall's
                                Journal of Health. Oct. Contents: Our Prospects and Purposes; Prohibition; Natural Gas;
                                Instinct of Animals; Mesmerism; Damp Cellars ; Treatment of the Hair; Influence of
                                drugs; Dress; Defective Speech; Fish Diet for Children; A Curiosum; Household, etc.,
                                etc. Office 206 Broadway, N. Y. $ 1. a year. The Forest and Steam Publishing Co., (New
                                York) announce for early publication " Uncle Lisha's Shop, or Life in a Corner of
                                Yankeeland," by Rowland E. Robinson. The dialect and faithful portraiture of Green
                                Mountain characters are said to be very felicitous. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is becoming, is honest..." TEIform="index"/>What is becoming, is
                            honest... </head><p TEIform="p"> What is becoming, is honest, and whatever is honest must always be becoming.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cicero" TEIform="persName"/>- Cicero.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Forgiveness is as valuable..." TEIform="index"/>Forgiveness is as valuable... </head><p TEIform="p"> Forgiveness is as valuable to the one who forgives, as to the one forgiven.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W. </byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Judge not from appearances" TEIform="index"/>Judge not from appearances </head><p TEIform="p"> Judge not from appearances. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/> KIND WORDS. </head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="September Manifesto is beautiful..." TEIform="index"/>September Manifesto
                                is beautiful... </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Watervliet, September 1887" TEIform="index"/> Watervliet, N. Y.
                                Sept. 1887.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> The September Manifesto is beautiful, and the gospel truth contained in it,
                                will do good. It must do good in spite of cavil.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, C." TEIform="persName"/>C Dibble. </byline></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Churchman says it is often a source of serious solicitude..." TEIform="index"/> he Churchman says it is often a source of serious solicitude... </head><p TEIform="p"> The Churchman says it is often a source of serious solicitude to thinking men,
                            that discipline seems little more than an empty name in the church to-day. " </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He who the sword of heaven will bear..." TEIform="index"/>He who the sword of
                            heaven will bear... </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">He who the sword of heaven will bear Should be as holy as severe;
                                    Pattern in himself, to know, Grace to stand, and virtue go; More nor less to others
                                    paying, Than by self offences weighing. Shame to him, whose cruel striking Kills for
                                    faults of his own liking! " </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Property" TEIform="index"/> PROPERTY.</head><p TEIform="p"> Nothing I have is rightly called my own, But what I make my own by using well.
                            Those deeds of charity which we have done, Shall stay forever with us : only the wealth
                            Which we have so bestowed we truly keep; The other is not ours.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Middleton" TEIform="persName"/>Middleton.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I have friends in Spirit Land..." TEIform="index"/>I have friends in Spirit
                            Land... </head><p TEIform="p"> I have friends in Spirit Land, Not shadows in a shadowy band, Not others but
                            themselves are they, And still I think of them the same As when the Master's summons came. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whittier" TEIform="persName"/>Whittier.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths. </head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brettenstien, Alice" TEIform="index"/>Alice Brettenstien</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Allard, Roselinda" TEIform="index"/>Roselinda Allard</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Huntington, Eunice" TEIform="index"/>Eunice Huntington</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> Alice Brettenstien, at Union Village, Ohio, Sept. 27, 1887. Age 43 yrs. and
                                1 mo. Roselinda Allard at Enfield, N. H. Oct. 7, 1887. Age 74 yrs. 11 mo. and 19 Eunice
                                Huntington, at Enfield, N. H. Oct. 8, 1887. Age 77 yrs. 6 mo. and 4 days. days.</p></div3></div2><pb n="265" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/>
                    <!--  
Till,   MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
This powder never varies. A marvel of
ptfrity, strength and vrlioli'sninonesw. M<>r<
economical thitn the ordinary kind , sintl
cunnot be sold in competition with the n:intitude of low test, short weight, alum or phosphate powders. Sold only in cons. Uoyai. '
Baking Powder Co., 106 Waii-st., N. Y.
iviciOAL.   MACHINES.
- X srssw ycse stash assis^ltveal W22


1st, Premiums at all Qormetitiv"   Trif/is
Railway, Chain aiiilLcvfrHdix-r- - - -.
ers,Hirvsh- -'i- - and - -Itaiii*i. flir- -.ili 
4k Shakerx, Clover Uullern. feed Cnt>
lem, Wh- - - -l Horse Riiktw. Hor- -f fi- -if- -I- -forkN, 
Nliing-le ,Wa- -liin*- -.- -itriiw S^rj-n^rving- Jtftye Thresh -!- - - -. 8Nsrti- -l- -S  .*s- - - - - - - - - -jh-Fii~
jjpfiif- -. <Jf- -ler *- -iul WiiieJliiU mnl B- -r*!- - - -e- -,
Dog1 .Slid r<mt P- -Hfr- -. BM- -c BSurniivi
& Mpringy Tooth    Harrow*.     "Robinson's Hay Press, of four sizes- Will
work as easy with one horse, as
others with two. Made with Steel
Gearing which can not ba broken."
WHEELER & MELICKCo;,
aibautt, ar. y.
Send stamp for Circular an A report of Centenni J
trial.
$/- -jKAMONTH   and BOARD Guaranteed
OU3 Young Men or Ladies in each  country,
and highest commission paid (often $150
a month')    SEtt   B- -OK already  on
TIDAL WAVE ^^'^l- -r=^lWl^K!PlH^P1T? d
of success \kis3   rf wIMJJJirwS^
in North and South America, at the Ice-BounJ
Poles, over the lands of the Midnight Sun, under the
Equator, through the Dark Continent, among the Old
Temples of India, in the Flowery Kingdoms of China
and Japan, amid the ruins of Incas. Aztecs and Zuni, within Canons, Cliff Buildings, and Gardens of
the Gods, on the Isles of the Sea, and in all parts of
the globe. 300 engravings, Low Price. Quick Sales.
Send for Circular. P. W. Ziegler, & Co., 720 Chestnut St. Philadelphia, Pa.
After Forty years'
experience in the
preparation of more
than One Hundred
Thousand applications for patents in
the United States and Foreign countries, the publishers of the Scientific
American continue to act as solicitors
for patents, caveats, trade-marks, copyrights, etc., for the United States, and
to obtain patents in Canada, England, France,
Germany, and all other countries Their experience is unequaled and their facilities are unsurpassed.
Drawings and specifications prepared and filed
in the Patent Office on short notice. Terms very
reasonable. No charge for examination of models
or drawings     Advice by mail free
Patents obtained through MnnrwfcCo. are noticed
inthe SCIENTIFIC AMTMIICAN,which has
the largest circulation and is the most influential
newspaper of its kind published in the world.
The advantages of such a notice every patentee
understands
This large and splendidly ilniRtrated newspaper
is published WKEF^LYal $3.00 a year, and is
admitted to be the best paper duvoted to science,
mechanics, inventions, engineering works and
other departments of industrial progress, published in any country. It contains the names of
all patentees and title of everj invention patented
each week. Try it four months for one dollar.
Sold by all newsdealers.
If you have an invention  to  patent write to
Munn & Co., publishers of Scientific American,
861 Broadway, New York.
Handbook about patents mailed firea.
manufacturers of
BLACK WRITING INK.
COPYING and MARKING INK
CAEMINE, RED a d BLUE INK,
wsrrara fluid, inkpowdee &o,
Boston HVXaiss.
MAYNARD & N0YES.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
The Cosmopolitan
The handsomest, most entertaining, low price,
illustrated family magazine in the world.
($2.50 per year, with a $2.25 premium
free.) Sixty-four beautifully printed pages in
each number, filled with short stories, sketches,
travels, adventures, bright and brief scientific
and literary articles, by distinguished American
and foreign writers, such as Julian Hawthorne,
Harriet Prescott Spofford, George Parsons
Lathrop, Louise Chandler Moulton, J. Macdonald Oxley, Ella Wheeler Wilcox, H. H.
Boyesen, Catherine Owen, Rev. R. Heber
Newton, Alphonse Daudet, Paul Heyse, Count
Tolstoi, Th. Dostoivsky, William Westall and
many others. Also entertaining JUVENILE
and invaluable HOUSEHOLD departments.
One or more illustrated articles and several fullpage engravings in every number.
A Shannon   Letter and
Bill File or a Shannon
Sheet-Music Binder
Free   to   every
Subscriber.
These premiums sell
everywhere for $2.25
each. The File is the most
perfect device ever invented for the preservation and
classification (alphabetically and according to date)
of all letters, bills, etc.
Any paper can be referred
to, taken out and put back
without disturbing the
others. With the Binder
one can insert or take out
any piece of music without
disturbing any other sheet.
Get SAMPLE COPY at NEWS STAND or
send 20 Cents to publishers.
AGENTS WANTED. BIO COMMISSIONS PAID.
Schlicht & Field Co., Rochester, N. Y.
THE BEST
INVESTMENT
for the Family, the School, or the Professional or Fubiio JLibrary, is a
copy of the latest issued Weoster's Unabridged.
Besides many other valuable features,it contains
A Dictionary
of 118,000 Words, 3000 Engravings,
A Gazetteer of the World
locating and describing 25,000 Places,
A Biographical Dictionary
of nearly 10,000 Noted Persons,
All in One Book.
3000 more Words and nearly 2000 more Illustrar
tions than any other American Dictionary.
Sold by all Booksellers.   Pamphlet free.
G. & C. MERR1AM & CO., Pub'rs, Springfield, Maao.
The Life and  Gospel   Experience  of
VIother Ann Lee.                  Price  10 cts.
Address, Manifesto, Shaker Village, N. H.
Ti(i Phrenological Journal will be sent
to any address, for Oct. Noy and Dec. for
25 cents.
THE USUAL KESULT.
It is not to be denied that a good sewing
machine is one of the most important appurtenances of the modern household.
We thought we had a good machine until
one day the agent of the New Home presented
himself at our door and proceeded to deiver an oration upon its characteristic merits.
" But," we answered, ''our machine suits us
well and we do not care for another."
The agent, however, begged the privilege
of leaving one of his machines with us, "for
the ladies to try."
The request was not unreasonable, so we
granted it- -but more to oblige the agent than
anything else; for we really did not want the
machine, and had not the remotest idea of
buying it.
The machine once in the house, it was natural that the ladies should look it over : they
did so, and as a consequence fell in love with
it. They say that without the slightest wish
to decry or disparage any other machine,
this, all things considered, is, in their opinion, the most desirable one to be had.
This unrivalled machine is manufactured
by the NEW HOME SEWING MACHINE
CO., Orange, Mass., and 30 Union Square,
New York.
THE   ALTRUIST
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property,
united labor, Community homes, and equal
rights to all. It is published by the Mutual
Aid Community, whose members all live and
work together, and hold all their property in
common, all the men and women having
equal rights in electing officers and deciding
all business affairs by their majority vote.
50 cents a year; specimen copy free. Address A. Longley, Editor, 213 N. 8th St.,
St. Louis, Mo.
The Divine Afflatus :    A force in History.                                Price   10 cts.
Address, Manifesto, Shaker Village, N. H.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
 --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>