<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0512" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><date value="18751201" TEIform="date">December 1875</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">89-96</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="89" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">Vol. V. No. 12. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. ' Mt. Lebanon Col. Co. N. Y. December, 1875.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorial change—summary" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL CHANGE—SUMMARY</head><p TEIform="p">The sixth volume of our paper will commence under the direction of its original editor, Q. A.
                            Lomas. With much satisfaction, we vacate the chair3 in behalf of our worthy and able
                            brother, believing he will continue to maintain sound doctrine, have no fellowship with
                            unfruitful works of darkness, and by The Shaker, shake all, in Church and State, that can be
                            shaken. The Shaker and Shakeress has been well sustained by its inside and outside friends.
                            Thanks to all contributors, and to the press for its uniform courtesy. Extracts from its
                            columns and kindly notices attest the urbanity of editors. Without an exception, they have
                            been gentle toward our little waif. As the S. &amp; S. is the first dual paper on
                            record, may we not assume this generous reception and treatment of it as a prophecy of
                            unanimity in adopting the coming Dual Civil Government, to be formed in likeness of the
                            Shaker Order, in which it will be understood that it is no more good for man to be alone, in
                            framing and executing the laws of a government, for people of all nations, kindreds and
                            tongues, holding to 1,000 different theologies, than it is for man to be alone in the
                            construction of a family. As the Union has treed colored people from slavery, so will it
                            free woman from semibondage, and endow her with a citizenship that Rome, in all her glory,
                            never dreamed of. The Shaker is a little body with a great soul. Its means are small—its
                            aims high— nothing less than the destruction of antichristian Babylon—confusion—and the
                            construction of a true Christian order, from whence shall proceed an influence and a law,
                            that will organize, out of the American government, a new millennial earth. It is in this
                            manner that the kingdoms of this world will become the kingdom of our Lord and his Christ
                            Such nations will learn war no more. The organic wrongs of the then existing governments of
                            earth, and the primary, abstract truths, seen in'the light of the Christ-Spirits, by the
                            Prophets of the Ages, caused them to be as pilgrims and strangers, seeking a city having the
                            continued revelation of truth as its foundations. " Cease to do evil" is now in order, for
                            individuals, and for organizations. In the present light of the retiring editor, seven forms
                            of evil are apparent, in individuals and in organizations. INDIVIDUAL EVILS. 1st. Superfine
                            Flour, divested of its bran, causing general derangement of physical functions. 2d. Mesh
                            Meat, necessitating the killing of dumb animals, who cannot plead their own rights. Its use,
                            under the Darwinian law— " struggle for existence and survival of the fittest"—is not
                            spiritual, but muscular force and mental craft—practical deception. Aboriginal races, who
                            fight with and feed upon wild beasts, themselves become wild. 3d. Spirituous Liquors. These
                            madden the brain, leaving the man unmanned—the reason dethroned—the conscience seared. 4th.
                            Narcotics. Opium, tobacco—types of a numerous class of nerve-destroyers, eagerly sought and
                            recklessly used by a large proportion of mankind. 5th. Condiments. These help in the work of
                            physical deterioration, directly and by inheritance, in destroying the natural taste of all
                            articles to which they are applied, and also by creating unnatural appetites and tastes.
                            Salt, pickles, pepper, mustard and vinegar can be applied to the land, without much damage
                            to health. 6th. Teas and Coffee are types of a large class of plants that furnish drinks to
                            the female portion of humanity. They may be vainly used, but are not used in vain. 7th. Foul
                            Air. This is one of the curses that Moses said would cleave to his people, if disobedient to
                            his laws and statutes. How universal this plague, and what dire results follow breathing
                            impure air and drinking impure water are problems that the science of the world is now
                            engaged in solving and devising means of avoiding. The people of God should be as clean in
                            the air they breathe, as in the food they eat, the clothes they wear, or the houses in which
                            they live. SOCIETY EVILS. 1st. Holding land, as property, forever. The accumulation of "
                            broad acres " in the hands of persons holding it from general use. 2d. Poverty, resulting
                            from people being cut off from their inheritance in the earth. The promise is, The saints
                            shall possess the earth, each sitting under his and her own vines—No poor. 3d. Wars. Bread
                            or blood is the cry of the landless always and in all times. The landholders give them both
                            bread and blood. They cause them to earn their bread by. shedding the blood of each other.
                            When the Romans had no national wars, they made the landless kill one another, as
                            gladiators. 4th. Slavery of the conquered is a logical deduction from war. De#ath to the
                            vanquished is its law, unless self finds use for the doomed wretch as a slave to minister to
                            the lusts of the heroic conqueror. Slaves are the highest form of property known to
                            Christian (t) law. 5th. Masculine Domination. This is an organic evil in all old creation
                            organizations. The desire for women modifies the Darwinian law of brute force in man ;
                            otherwise, under that force, man would kill all women. Her lord and master's passions
                            balance each other. 6th. Usury. This eats, as does a canker, into the vitals of the
                            producing classes. " Thou shalt not kill; thou shalt not take usury of any," was Jewish law.
                            7th. Spiritualism, the science of all sciences, being perverted under the operation of the
                            above-named evils, creates a theology that stultifies reason, confounds logic, and attempts
                            the regulation of conscience, by physical force, torturing the body for the benefit of the
                            soul. Thus we have a union of generation and Christianity — Babylon—mixture—producing Church
                            and State organizations, in all nations—except under the to be New Earth Government of these
                            United States.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vicarious atonement" TEIform="index"/>VICARIOUS ATONEMENT</head><p TEIform="p">In the doctrine of vicarious atonement, God is represented, first, as inflexibly just;
                            second, as changeable, his wrath being changed to love by the vicarious sacrifice. His
                            justice and his mercy are arrayed in conflict. God's mercy pleads " spare the culprit; " j
                            ustice is inexorable, and will not yield one iota to the pleadings of mercy. Punishment —
                            vindictive punishment — must and shall be inflicted on the sinner, or on the substitute.
                            God's children are required to imitate him. Here God is represented as having conflicting
                            dispositions. Transfer this state of mind to a human being, and you have drawn the picture
                            of a miserable, unhappy wretch. Again, justice and mercy are attributes of God, and, like
                            him, are unchangeable in their relations one with another, whether they exist in or are
                            exercised by God or man. The moral effect, then, of such a conception of God as this
                            doctrine inculcates is the following, when exhibited in man : His servant, or subject,
                            disobeys him ; the culprit must be vindictively punished. If there be any of the milk of
                            human kin'dness in this lordling's nature — any mercy — it must be crushed out, annihilated.
                            Inexorable justice overrides and quashes all mercy's pleadings. It might as well not exist;
                            it can have no influence. '' There is no room for mercy, none for pardon left." Thus man, in
                            imitating his God, becomes a perfectly remorseless tyrant. If now he undertake to make the
                            dodge attributed to God by this vicarious doctrine, and take his innocent son as a
                            substitute for his erring servant, and pour out the rage of his wrath upon the innocent son
                            in order to satisfy the vindictive demands of his justice, does not every one see that he
                            still more outrages all the principles of eternal justice instead of satisfying them? The
                            doctrine carried out frustrates its own professed end, and is a flagrant exhibition of gross
                            injustice. There is not a civilized nation on earth which would not punish a man, capitally,
                            for immolating his innocent son, because some of his servants had offended him. Yet all the
                            orthodox and evangelical sects of nominal Christians do, in their creeds, charge the God of
                            heaven with the commission of this diabolical crime. <pb n="90" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 9O A modern
                            author, writing of Calvin and Calvinism, says: " Hatred of sin was fixed upon the sinner.
                            The burning indignation of his offended conscience was seldom tempered with mercy. Justice,
                            dark and frowning justice, streaming with implacable vengeance ; justice omnipotent and
                            impatient of execution ; justice, the divinest principle in the constitution of the
                            mysterious trinity; justice, the unchangeable grandeur of God's intellectual character;
                            JUSTICE, the support of heaven and hell; I may add justice, the frigid climate of kingdom
                            come, the savage feature of the Calvinistic theology, the refractory attribute within the
                            heart of destructive combativeness, is the pet principle, the central idea — the
                            indestructible motive power of cruelty in mankind." Again, the same author says: Millions
                            have accepted Jesus, not as an elder brother and member of the human family, but, on the
                            contrary, that Jesus has been apprehended and outrageously martyred as the sacrifice of an
                            infinite mind, a lamb slain on the bloody altar for human benefit; a debt-payer of that
                            which he did not owe, suffering for gigantic and innumerable sins lie never committed,
                            transforming, to angels of heaven, great world-worn sinners, because they merely " believed
                            on Him and were baptized, and have accepted a mountainous mass of other absurdities and
                            heathenish contradictions." CONCLUSION OF A DREAM. A few days after writing the abo.ve, I
                            dreamed of preaching a regular discourse to an audience on the subject of Vicarious
                            Atonement, of which the following is the concluding part: According to this doctrine of
                            imputed sin and vicarious atonement, Adam's original sin was imputed to the whole human
                            race. This sin against God, thus attaching to the race of man, is so stupendous, so heinous,
                            that God cannot extend mercy; cannot forgive without violating eternal justice. Man, thus
                            lying under the guilt of this tremendous criminality, with the sword of offended and
                            implacable justice lowering over him, nothing daunted, audaciously adds to his already
                            unpardonable sin one still more horrible and sacrilegious. He commits Deicide! Seizes and
                            murders God's own innocent Son! the second person in the trinity ! This additional and awful
                            outrage, it is said, satisfied God's eternal justice, and opened his bowels of mercy to man.
                            But really it would seem more as if the Omnipotent was intimidated, his eternal justice
                            conquered, and his mercy extorted, than that he should, for this new offense, now become
                            satisfied and reconciled to the human race.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pelham, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. Pelham, Union Village, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blood of the lamb" TEIform="index"/>"BLOOD OF THE LAMB."</head><p TEIform="p">"And they overcame him by the blood of the Lamb, and by the word of their testimony." Kev.
                            xii, 11. There is a deep significance attached to these words, more so perhaps than the
                            generality are aware of, especially those who expoct to be saved by the blood of the Lamb ;
                            without living his life and overcoming the world in themselves, as he did, and adding to
                            that life the word of their testimony. John, the forerunner, said, after baptizing Jesus, "
                            Behold the Lamb of God which taketh away the sin of the world." John, i. 29. How did he "
                            take away the sin of the world ?" By bearing a daily cross, and overcoming the world in
                            himself, i. e., all that is in the world, the lust of the flesh, the lust of the eye and the
                            pride of life. A trinity, as the apostle Peter said, " leaving us an example, that we should
                            follow his steps." Impossible! says one. Impracticable! says another. He was God, and no
                            mere man, since the fall, can follow the example of a God, nor keep his commandments; but
                            doth daily break them in thought, word and deed. This antichristian idea has long since been
                            exploded. The blood of the Lamb here spoken of, is the life of Christ; the blood is what
                            constitutes the life of every human being, physically, while in the form. " The blood is the
                            life thereof." What constituted him the " Lamb of God," spiritually, was the purity and
                            innocence of the life he lived, and the Baptism of the Holy Spirit, into the work of
                            regeneration, being led by the Spirit of God. " As many as are led by the Spirit of God,
                            they are the sons of God," the same as he was. Nor did he take away the sin of the world by
                            living a life of righteousness himself, and imputing that righteousness to others. In
                            addressing his disciples, he said, " except your righteousness shall exceed the
                            righteousness of the scribes and pharisees, ye shall in no case enter the kingdom of
                            heaven." If a dependence on the righteousness of Christ was sufficient for salvation, why
                            did he not say to his disciples, never mind about your own righteousness, mine is sufficient
                            for you in all cases ? It would be conflicting with God's attribute of justice, to punish
                            the innocent and let the guilty go free. It is an immutable law, " he that doeth wrong must
                            suffer for the wrong he doeth," whether it be moral or physical, and no blood of lambs or
                            goats can make it otherwise. But " he that doeth righteousness is righteous even as he is
                            righteous." But, says one, would it not do as well, to live the life and omit the testimony?
                            We think not. Where the testimony is omitted the life is lived, only in part, as a general
                            thing. They have to go together. " 1 testify of it, that the works thereof are evil," said
                            Jesus ; i. e., the world. Let any try it, and see if they do not find, by experience, an
                            increase of moral power over the world, the flesh, and the devil, if there be one, and I
                            believe there is — not a black personal devil, but that old lying spirit — slanderer. " The
                            accuser of our brethren and sisters is cast down, which accused them falsely before our God
                            day and night," and they overcame him by the blood of the fLamb and by the word of their
                            testimony."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, J. S." TEIform="persName"/>Elder J. S. Prescott, North Union, 0.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Worlds without end" TEIform="index"/>WORLDS WITHOUT END</head><p TEIform="p">Worlds ad infinitum. We like the idea. It opens a field for change ad infinitum — eternal
                            progress. Advent into the first world is not inaptly symbolized by the entered apprentice's
                            degree in masonry — we go it blind. Advent into the second world is like the follow craft
                            degree — we are but half hoodwinked, not half satisfied with the wisdom or knowledge gained.
                            No inconsiderable percentum of the vast amount of raw human material that takes the first
                            degree in the scale of semi-conscious being, would, apparently, be semi-content to linger,
                            and so of those who take the second degree. Not so with aspiring minds. Excelsior is the
                            motto inscribed on their banner. They are not content with human moieties, nor with
                            ill-assorted, vulgar fractions. They want to see humanity in its entireness — in whole
                            numbers — integers. To attain the desideratum, a searching ordeal must be endured. We must
                            be put through the land of shadows — the camera obscura. This is a lengthy process. The soul
                            will be tried to the extent of human endurance. In this crucible we must continue, till no
                            dross remains ; till the Son of Righteousness can shine through us, as clear as crystal,
                            casting no shadow on the canvas. Now are we prepared for an advance movement ; a movement
                            that is a movement. We enter a world where man is found in the likeness of God. A world
                            where the brief Mosaic poetic epitome of the creation of man is, to some extent, actualized.
                            We say, to some extent, for there is really no end to the worlds. Every world we press
                            through will be accompanied with corresponding elevations. To the increase of glory there
                            will be no end. World after world will appear in view,each, in turn, holding out inducements
                            worthy of our loftiest ambition. The time Will come, the condition be reached, in which we
                            can appreciate the justice and the wisdom of God, in conferring on us conscious existence.
                            In the first, and in succeeding worlds, much may be accomplished by earnest minds,
                            preparatory to an early advance movement. We have splendid opportunities here and now —
                            opportunities not to be trifled with. No experience in scenes, no matter how trying, which
                            may not be made available in coming worlds. This should reconcile us to endure the
                            disagreeables of life in the present world, be that life long or short. Glory, honor,
                            immortality, are before us as inducements to endure the cross and despise the shame of our
                            juvenile ignorance. We are living for eternity, for God and humanity.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, Oliver" TEIform="persName"/>Oliver Prentiss, Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Do good" TEIform="index"/>DO GOOD</head><p TEIform="p">What we do is ours, together with the ultimate fruits of the same ; let whoever may receive
                            its immediate effects. How many have been awakened to feel conviction for sin, that have
                            afterward felt they had fallen from grace, or committed the unpardonable sin ! And have not
                            many, through ignorance or false teaching, thrown away hope, and set darkness and the pit
                            before them as their sure doom, and recklessly, plunged headlong into temptation and crime 1
                            This is either making work for many days of repentance, or heaping up fuel for the
                            unquenchable fire. In all the revelation of God there is nothing to discourage doing good at
                            any time or under any circumstances, even by those who may suppose themselves irredeemable,
                            but who are quite the reverse. The following text of the prophet is sometimes misapplied : "
                            When I say to the righteous he shall surely live, if he trust to his own righteousness and
                            commit iniquity, all his righteousness shall not be remembered, but for the iniquity that he
                            hath committed he shall die for it." The simple meaning of this is, his former righteousness
                            shall not save him from punishment as the wages of iniquity, if he consent to practice it.
                            In like manner, if an unrighteous man repent and turn to righteousness, correct his errors
                            and right the wrongs he has committed, his former transgressions shall not prevent his
                            reaping the fruits of his righteousness. Jesus testified that whosoever would give a cup of
                            cold water only, to a little one who followed him, on account of his being a disciple,
                            should in nowise lose his reward. In the judgment work of separating the good from the bad,
                            those who have fed and clothed the least of Christ's brethren and sisters, or visited them
                            in sickness or in prison, unwittingly did it to him, and are invited to an inheritance in
                            the heavenly kingdom. While those who merely prophesied (i. e., taught) in his name, and in
                            his name did many wonderful works, but omitted these deeds of mercy and charity, are
                            commanded to depart. If to every one shall be given " according as his works shall be,
                            whether they be good or whether they be evil," surely none can fail of a recompense for what
                            unselfish good they do, even if they fall under the judgment of condemnation, to expiate
                            their folly and guilt by suffering. But when they are sufficiently broken to acknowledge the
                            justice of the hand that deals with them, they will realize that their deeds of
                            selfsacrifice have mitigated their sufferings and made repentance easier; while every wicked
                            deed, willfully committed, will aggravate their torture. This is according to reason and
                            justice, and is confirmed by the testimony of some who have experienced a measure of the
                            same. If " every idle word" shall meet us in the judgment, or Balance of Justice, Mercy,
                            Reason, Justice, and Revelation, all assure us that every positively good deed will be there
                            also. Truth clearly affords all encouragement to do good, even to the last moment of
                            probation. All discouragement proceeds from falsehood. " Do good and lend (or give), hoping
                            not to receive as much again, and thou shalt be recompensed at the resurrection of the
                            just." But those who are prompted by mercenary or selfish motives in all they do, may look
                            in vain for any future recompense of righteousness. Let those who suppose themselves
                            irretrievably lost set about doing good to their neighbor, whether stranger, friend, or
                            enemy, hoping not for earthly reward, the only way souls can prove their love to God, and if
                            they abstain from all willful and premeditated SHAKER A.1STD <pb n="91" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/>
                            SHAKEEESS. 91 evil, who can say the good will not so far prevail in their day of reckoning,
                            that they may fiaally secure a part in the first resurrection. Certainly such deeds,
                            particularly those done for the household of Christ, will be of more value to the doer,
                            whether saint or sinner, than all earthly pelf and pleasure. The Revelation of this Day
                            teaches " Never throw yourselves away—Though you be fallen never so low, it is not too late
                            to cry to God—A soul in the belly of hell can do no better than cry to God." But some will
                            say " The prayer of the wicked is abomination to God." True! when they do not pray
                            sincerely. Souls cannot pray to God while seeking to save their carnal lusts—or to be
                            sanctified in their sins. Their prayers ascend not above carnal pleasure, and are answered
                            by " the Man of Sin," who sitteth in their temple and showeth himself to such that he is
                            god. Their eyes, blinded by impurity of heart, cannot see the real and living God. So of the
                            proud, whom " God resisteth," and the selfish and self-willed, who pray to be saved in their
                            own ways, and to have their own wills executed; God " beholdeth them afar off." But " In our
                            humiliation our judgment will be taken away, and in no other way." Every honest, humble
                            seeker is indeed blessed ; for the Holy One who inhabits eternity dwells with the humble and
                            contrite heart, to revive the spirit of the contrite ones. " I am come to seek and save that
                            which was lost—the whole need not a physician," is the language of the Good Shepherd.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo" TEIform="persName"/>Alonzo Hollister, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jesus" TEIform="index"/>JESUS</head><p TEIform="p">According to historical accounts, Jesus was a man of symmetrical beauty, in body and mind. He
                            was clothed with wisdom, in harmony with Nature's laws, in sympathy with suffering humanity,
                            and ever ready to forgive the erring, especially his enemies and wicked or ignorant
                            persecutors. He seemed to possess an intuitive knowledge of the ruling elements of the lower
                            world, which bring misery, pain and sorrow upon mankind; also of the laws which rule the
                            heavens, which, if kept unbroken, produce happiness and joy. He was physically and morally
                            sound, well developed, qualified to comprehend the needs of the human family, and the causes
                            of their misery, and was pre-eminently prepared to receive the Christ-Spirit, to show, by
                            example, how to make an end of sin, finish the " mystery of godliness," and the misery which
                            is the fruit of ungodly deeds. He occupied such an elevated position that he comprehended
                            the proper sphere of all inferior creatures, their powers and imperfections. When I compare
                            myself with the standard that Jesus raised, the contrast is great. As I understand, he was
                            born of the best morally cultivated, religious Jewish parents. 1 have no such claims. I was
                            of humble birth ; my parents were Gentile, and I was reared in inharmonious relations and
                            irreligious surroundings. But I am what I am to-day, and hope, by the grace of God, and the
                            aid of good Spirits, to be something more and better in the future, if I persevere in
                            walking the path of purity and doing the works of righteousness. By engaging in the
                            Christian warfare, and fighting all the lusts that war against the welfare of body and soul,
                            I expect to find redemption from sickness and physical disease, as well as spiritual sins,
                            and the effects flowing therefrom. I crave the power that Jesus possessed in body and soul.
                            " The truth made him free, and he was free indeed." He was a pure medium through whom Divine
                            inspiration flowed freely from the inner heaven of heavens. To attain unto the same
                            knowledge and goodness, and in my measure to be as he was in this world, shall be my highest
                            aim.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hayden, Clark" TEIform="persName"/>Clark Hayden, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">E Contributions to, and all Exchanges with The Shaker should be directed to "The Shaker,'
                            Shakers, Albany Co., N. Y." All subscriptions and advertisements must be directed to " N. A.
                            Briggs, Publisher, Shaker Village, N. H." Exchanges please notice.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Resist not evil" TEIform="index"/>RESIST NOT EVIL</head><p TEIform="p">How important to our spiritual welfare and progress, as Believers, that we seriously and
                            carefully consider the true import of the words standing at the head of this article — the
                            beautiful injunction of our Saviour—"Resist not evil, but rather overcome evil with good."
                            This will often give strength to curb and control the angry tide of passion that might
                            otherwise mar the peace, and sever the bonds of gospel union. Though maligned and persecuted
                            by others, we should ever cherish as sacred the blessed precept inculcated by the founder of
                            Christianity, to " return good for evil." Nothing brings a greater cross upon the natural
                            disposition, and costs a greater amount of self-denial, than a true application of this
                            principle. By it we gain a conquest over the lower nature, but it is only accomplished by
                            earnest and continued struggle. If amid the trials and temptations of communistic life, we
                            allow a harsh or unkind word to escape our lips, how easily we may wound the sensitive
                            feelings of a dear brother or sister, and mar the harmony of the social circle, where naught
                            but Christian love, and the spirit of peace should reign. If this be done, much of the
                            highest enjoyment of life would be sacrificed through want of proper and timely
                            consideration, and the wisdom that is from above, that teaches the important lesson : "
                            first pure, then peaceable." We have been called by the spirit of Christ to renounce a
                            worldly life, and unceasingly to pray that we may possess true charity, to " forgive as we
                            would be forgiven," to " be kindly affectioned one toward another;" and to arm ourselves
                            beforehand, that, when temptations assail, we may have the power of resistance, and faith to
                            buoy us up and bear our little bark safely above the waves of discord and strife, where the
                            turbid waters of passion never roll. We shall all prove our sincerity, and evidence, by our
                            daily life-practice, whether our professed, faith and works agree. If we cultivate and grow
                            all the lovely spiritual graces of the gospel, we shall be shining lights to the world, and
                            beautify the fold of Zion. Thus by nobly striving to attain unto the highest perfection of
                            human character, possible in earth life, many will bless our efforts, and we hopefully
                            trust, will be induced to do likewise. What is so beautiful as to see brethren and sisters
                            dwelling and toiling together in bonds of unity, cemented by holy angelic love and
                            affection, striving to promote each other's happiness and welfare in all things temporal and
                            spiritual. I thank God for the priceless knowledge of the way of life and salvation through
                            the medium of Divine revelation, enabling all who will strictly follow the light that
                            shines, to gain power and victory over every vile passion, and bring them into
                            reconciliation with God and his angels, and with their brethren and sisters. Such, whether
                            on earth or in spirit-spheres, will be numbered with those " who have come up through great
                            tribulation, and having washed their robes and made them white in the blood," or by living
                            the life of the Lamb, their names will be exalted, and enrolled in the book of life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Beaver, Orrin" TEIform="persName"/>Orrin Beaver, Watervliet, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Things new and old" TEIform="index"/>"THINGS NEW AND OLD."</head><p TEIform="p">External things are perpetually changing. In the universal laboratory, there are combinations
                            and decompositions of elements constantly succeeding each other, all under the direction of
                            the Supreme chemist, and all tending to one end — the production of the greatest good for
                            the individual man, and the ultimate harmonizing of all minds with the Divine. Why, then, it
                            may be asked, the need of bringing up any thing from the past, since the present must be so
                            much superior to it, and what is to succeed the present, will so much surpass it? Why should
                            the magnificent edifice of to-day be reminded of " the rock from which it was hewn?"
                            Because, the future can only stimulate hope, while the past and the present alone must be
                            our instructors, and can alone prove what the future shall be. All that has been learned has
                            been learned in the past and the present. ''Day uttereth speech unto day, and night showeth
                            knowledge unto night." The products of to-day show us how fertile the past has been. All
                            human beings, whether existing upon the unnumbered spheres of the outward universe or in the
                            spirit realms, differ from each other only as they contain within themselves more or less of
                            the accumulated treasure of the past. "Who hath despised the day of small things 1" or
                            rather, who should despise it ? Without it, there never could be the day of great things.
                            The new things of to-day are but the natural growth of what were planted yesterday. The
                            rains of yesterday fertilized, and the rays of yesterday's sun warmed them; so that we owe
                            to the growth of yesterday, the fruits we are enjoying to day. But are there not productions
                            of the past that are to be avoided ? Most certainly. Not every combination of elements
                            produces what will sustain life. On the contrary, much that is produced will destroy it.
                            There is need, therefore, of discrimination. These are to be classed among the things that
                            are behind which we are to forget, while we press toward the attainable things before us.
                            Past experience is a lesson for to-day and a prophecy of the future. We know from the twig
                            before us what the tree shall be. So we trace back, through centuries, the tree of today to
                            the sapling and the twig of the past. From the ruins lying before us, we judge of the extent
                            of the once existing city, the material of which its buildings were constructed, and, in
                            some degree, of the character of those who once inhabited it, though no record of them
                            remain. That which was once the Church of Christ, though now incumbered with heaps of
                            rubbish, yet has enough to show, aside from the records handed down to us, what was its
                            original foundation, and how much the present superstructure differs from the model
                            exhibited by its Architect. But it is not enough that the past be restored. The second
                            temple, though resembling the first, must surpass that in beauty and glory. The sciences of
                            to-day resemble those of by-gone ages, yet how vastly superior to them! " Truth is truth
                            wherever found," yet to-day we behold the flower in full bloom, where those of other times
                            beheld only the closed bud, the growing stem, or the just expanding seed. Revelation is a
                            perpetual unfolding, both in the individual soul, in the national life, and in the life of
                            the entire race of man. Hence, it is a perpetual necessity. One of olden time has said,"
                            There is nothing new under the sun." Eyes he may have had, but the past was to them a sealed
                            book, and the present shed insufficient light upon his vision. His great kinsman of after
                            ages was far wiser than he—''a scribe perfectly instructed in respect to the Divine
                            government." What patience, what trust in the future he manifested! This was the lesson he
                            had learned from the past, so that though the flesh shrunk from the trials before it, yet
                            the spirit with unbounded confidence in the future, could say, " Thy will be done." The
                            perfect lesson we have to learn from all our experience is, that the Divine Mind is
                            unchangeable. It sees the past and the future with unerring certainty. We need intimate
                            connection with that which cannot err, so as to be assisted in our judgments respecting the
                            past and the present; and a perfect reliance upon him with whom is " no variableness nor
                            shadow of turning," in order to possess that equanimity of soul which ail the changes of
                            earth, whether in its physical elements or the moral condition of its occupants, cannot
                            disturb.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>Wm. H. Bussell, Groveland, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Count the cost" TEIform="index"/>COUNT THE COST</head><p TEIform="p">I marvel, when I contemplate the condition of the present generation of men and women, to see
                            in how many ways they seek happiness — regardless of the future — at the expense of the
                            soul's welfare. How important it is<pb n="92" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> that children and youth should have
                            the right discipline in early life, that they may understand how to form correct habits. And
                            those of mature age should bear in mind that it behooves all who take upon them the
                            Christian name to "depart from iniquity," tor name signifies character. The followers of
                            Christ must be like him; bear his cross, wear his yoke, and walk in his footsteps. For this
                            reason all should count well the cost before they undertake the work ; for, although the
                            land of the redeemed is full of blessing and ineffable joy, fallen humanity can never attain
                            that state of blessedness, except through conflict and struggle. " The kingdom of heaven
                            suffereth violence, and the violent take it by force." The true way to trust in Jesus is to
                            have our life correspond with his life ; if his deeds were meritorious, let ours be
                            meritorious also. If he was a son of God, — "the first-born of many brethren"—"to as many as
                            received him," — in his true name — character—"to them gave he power," also " to become the
                            sons and daughters of God." We read of a large — representative — number of redeemed souls
                            who stood " with the Lamb on Mount Zion," and were the " first fruits unto God." They had
                            gained that redemption through great tribulation, and had washed their robes and made them
                            white. It would appear by this rendering of scripture that they did not rely upon Jesus, or
                            any other person, to wash their robes and do the work for them; but they worked out their
                            own, salvation by following him in the work of selfdenial, and bearing the same cross that
                            he bore. Does not the same power exist now that did then? and the same God who ruled the
                            heavens and communed with mortals and sent mediators — messengers — to aid them in the work
                            of redemption, and enable them to become his sons and daughters then, live to-day ? I
                            believe there is a " Mount Zion" at the present time ; and that the dual-Christ — male and
                            female — the Lamb and Bride with a large company of virgin followers and co-workers ; and
                            that they proclaim as with one voice, "Now has come salvation and strength, the kingdom of
                            our God and the power of his Christ;" the accuser of saints, in all past ages, is now cast
                            out — slain." Having been fully awakened to the truth of St. Paul's declaration, that " The
                            flesh lusteth against the spirit, and is contrary to it," and that Christ's followers must
                            walk in the spirit, and crucify the flesh with all its concomitants, this virgin band, by
                            confession, have cast off the old deeds that were wrought in darkness; their deeds have gone
                            beforehand to judgment, and they stand acquitted ; their consciences are at peace with God
                            and all mankind. This is a treasure that no earthly power can give nor take from its
                            possessor. I rejoice in spirit that I am called to this beautiful inheritance — that I have
                            received the fulfillment of the promise of an hundredfold of fathers, mothers, brothers,
                            sisters, and houses and lands, now in this world, and have felt the power of an endless life
                            in my soul, with an assurance that it will continue and increase, while the ages roll, if I
                            remain faithful. If some who are called into this work, and run well for a season, should
                            turn again into sinful paths — to the weak and beggarly elements of a worldly life,— and
                            thus their light be turned into great darkness, it need not discourage any faithful soul;
                            but rather be a cause of rejoicing, that God sends his angels — messengers — to " gather out
                            of his kingdom all that offends." The plan of salvation was laid in great wisdom ; but it is
                            so plain, just and true, that the wayfarer of .small capacity, if honest, may understand it.
                            " Cease to do evil, and learn to do well" — do right. There is no promise given that any one
                            would be saved from sin, and its consequent miseries while continuing in sin. Neither sin
                            nor sinners belong in Christ's kingdom.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kulp, Jacob S." TEIform="persName"/>Jacob S. Kulp, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fire" TEIform="index"/>FIRE</head><p TEIform="p">At the upper Family, Canaan, ashes emptied into the Leach Tub, close to the Wash House,
                            kindled a fire two days afterward. It was discovered at 9 o'clock at night, otherwise not a
                            building'would have been left on the premises.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Labor" TEIform="index"/>LABOR</head><p TEIform="p">Christ has come to seek and save that which was lost. The Gospel is a work of redemption for
                            poor human souls, willing to give up every thing to obtain its blessings. Persons coming
                            here, seeking salvation, should be informed what they are expected to do. They should learn
                            that we, as a people, are not idle, and that this is not an idle place; that to gain
                            salvation, we have to work for it, both in temporal and spiritual things; not by acting
                            according to the dictates of our own wills, working at this or that thing as long, or as
                            short as we choose, thereby creating confusion generally ; but by being obedient, not merely
                            to our Elders, but also to those who have any business in charge, and by showing
                            faithfulness in whatever we may be called to do. Thus, we not only find satisfaction, but
                            also gain knowledge of what there is within us, which is just what we need. The evil
                            elements in our hearts are touched and stirred up, and we can see where the battle-field is,
                            and what we have to contend against. By confessing our past sins and putting them away,
                            determined not to yield to the tempter any more, we have one point gained. This enables us,
                            in a degree, to break the chains that bind us to earth, and by watching the workings of the
                            enemy within us, and resisting him, we gradually rise out of the lower sphere into the
                            higher — from the natural into the spiritual life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Clark, G. W." TEIform="persName"/>G. W. Clark, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Extraordinary cure" TEIform="index"/>EXTRAORDINARY CURE</head><p TEIform="p">AUSTRALIAN LETTER. Dear Friend and Brother: Like one snatched from the dead, I resume social
                            and business relations with my brethren of humanity. You are aware that I have for upwards
                            of two years been suffering from a chronic disease of the stomach, from which neither
                            Spirits—Media nor Medical men seemed capable of relieving me. This disease culminated about
                            a month ago, in one mass of ulceration from the tip of my tongue to the bottom of my
                            stomach—and like Job of old I preferred death and the grave to the miserable existence I
                            then had. My medical adviser told me my case was utterly hopeless— and the spirits attending
                            me told me they were now waiting to take me home. Three days and nights I was in constant
                            expectation of departing, my wife constantly remained with me; my family, and two or three
                            select friends watched by me in turns. Upwards of a dozen spirits were in almost constant
                            attendance, soothing and comforting me, assuring ms that they would not leave me in my
                            distress and that they were there for the express purpose of mitigating my sufferings to the
                            whole extent of their power, and rendering my passage to the Father's presence as easy as
                            possible. These spirits including my father, mother, paternal and maternal grandfathers and
                            mothers, a brother and sister, father-in-law, and five or six more of my near relatives in
                            the spirit home, manifested day and night, not only to me, but to every person in the house.
                            Copious instructions were given in spirit writing and by other means to every one what to
                            do. When they should go to bed, when and whom to watch with me, whom to admit into the
                            house, whom to invite, and whom to meet at the door without admitting them further. In fact
                            the whole household arrangements were for three days and nights under spirit control. On the
                            third and last night of my severe illness, my spirit friends summoned all my earth friends
                            to bid me good-bye, and allowed only one besides my wife and children to see me die. My
                            hands and face changed color, my feet grew numb —when all at once I was seized hold of by
                            some extraordinary power, and shaken violently in bed, so violently that the bed shook also.
                            I was shaken at the rate of more than two hundred vibrations per minute from side to side,
                            for three or four minutes, the length of vibration across my bowels being about three
                            inches. Somewhat alarmed, I asked the Spirits if this was death, and if it would be a
                            painful struggle for me. The Spirits attending me told me they did not know what this was at
                            all. In all previous death-bed scenes they had never seen any thing like it. They desired me
                            to trust in God with perfect confidence ; I was undoubtedly under the control of a power
                            superior to them at the time, with which it was impossible for them to interfere ; but God
                            assuredly was with me, and I might with great certainty repose perfect confidence in him.
                            Meanwhile they would not leave me till they saw what was determined respecting me, telling
                            me at the same time that though they certainly expected to take me with them that night, yet
                            no Spirit save only those in the immediate presence of the Father, to whom He communicated
                            the intelligence, could absolutely fortell when death would happen to any one, their power
                            of judging was superior to that of mortals, only in proportion to their greater experience
                            and progression, nothing more. The result of this fearful shaking was, that an obstruction
                            which all treatment had failed to disturb was removed, and since that time I have gradually
                            but surely mended in health. The Spirit attendants have all left me but one, as their
                            presence is required elsewhere ; but they assure me of being constantly watched by one
                            attendant at least, who can instantly summon others when I really need their services. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Finlay, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Finlay</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Chittenden, Vermont, October 30, 1875" TEIform="index"/>Chittenden, Vt., Oct. 30,1875</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Father Evans — I saw, in your monthly, a letter from Dr. Miller, stating: " They say the
                            Eddy Brothers are jealous of their Sister, Mrs. Hunter." Please allow me to say, through
                            your beautiful little paper, If there be jealousy, Horatio G. Eddy has no part in it. I have
                            witnessed my sister's seances two evenings only ; I never saw such wonderful manifestations;
                            I will not attempt to describe them. I was disappointed; old Mrs.Eaton, a spirit in
                            William's seances, said Mrs. Hunter was a fraud. There was no fraud the two evenings I was
                            there. I was surprised and glad to know she had so wonderful a gift; I wish there was a good
                            materializing medium in every house, and spirits seen in all places. Good Angels, bless
                            every medium in the land; do all you can to convince the doubting, that they have an
                            immortal spirit. Their prison bars will be broken ; churches rot and decay; lawyers defraud
                            no more for money ; ministers and all will have to do right, for the spirits of the dear
                            ones can tell their own story. Good spirits, do your noble work ; come in every house ; I
                            could beg, in every street, to have your work go on ; I am humble, and ask no praise for
                            what the spirits do through me ; but bless the spirits for doing their work. Such, friend
                            Evans, are my feelings. Publish, if it seem you good.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eddy, Horatio G." TEIform="persName"/>Horatio G. Eddy</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Work" TEIform="index"/>WORK</head><p TEIform="p">"If all the year were playing holidays, To sport would be as tedious as to work ; But when
                            they seldom come, they wish'd for come. And nothing pleaseth but rare accidents." One of the
                            greatest means of assistance to those struggling for redemption from the existing evils of
                            society, is the privilege of daily labor. Our ideas and aspirations are usually far in
                            advance of what we are, in our worldly condition, capable of. Our ideal of a life of purity
                            is, practically, a life of many burdens ; it is only through the " fiery furnace " of trial
                            that we are qualified for that life that has ever been our ideal of what the earth life
                            should be. During these days of regeneration a busy hand is a safety-valve, as it were, to
                            an overcharged brain and heart. Time spent in brooding over our dark thoughts, and in
                            listening to the enticing voices of the sirens of the world, is simply time spent in
                            creating troubles with which we may have to battle months and years before conquering.
                            Humble yourselves with labor— " therefore he brought down their hearts with labor." Work
                            hard, until the physical man is stilled and tired ; and then, in tranquillity and rest,
                            receive the ministrations of the spirit. Our days of rest are enhanced by their becoming a
                            necessity ; the hours devoted to general intellectual enjoyments are made pleasurable by
                            their being the exception and not the rule ; " when they seldom come, they wish'd for come."
                            David, in promising reward to the righteous, says: " Thou shalt eat the labor of thine hands
                            ; happy shalt thou be, and it shall be well with thee." Eat not "the bread of idleness,"
                            either in spiritual or temporal things, for it is while in this open condition of inactivity
                            that our minds are filled with doubtings and wonderings; it is then that evil influences
                            fill our souls, simply because of the dearth of those good influences which are attendant
                            upon constant conscience-eet-isfying labor.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="E." TEIform="persName"/>E., Mount Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Chicago Tribune estimates that getting born costs..." TEIform="index"/>The Chicago Tribune estimates that getting born costs...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The Chicago Tribune estimates that getting born costs the people of the United States
                            $220,095,000 annually; getting married, $250,000,000; getting buried, $73,839,450 ; total,
                            $543,984,450.</p></div2><pb n="93" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Defined thought" TEIform="index"/>DEFINED THOUGHT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">Thoughts are the parents of actions. Action, without profound consideration, is often
                                disastrous in results. Speculative ideas and theories, however good they may be,
                                unsupported by actual works, are like spectral objects, floating in the air, ever
                                eluding the grasp — mere phantasy resembling the fairyland, and at best, a dream life.
                                Good works are the product of ripened thought — the fruit of true desires. If we reason,
                                as God has given us the power to do, our deductions are, that Sin is the cause of all
                                the misery and suffering in the human family. Disease of every kind, pertaining to body
                                or mind, whether inherited, or created through our own volition, is a distinctive mark
                                of violated law! Instead of a beautiful earthly home, where Truth and Justice bear rule,
                                we are now forced to open our vision upon a pandemonium — a stronghold of unclean birds
                                — rapacious vultures—the legitimate progeny of Sin in its varied forms and degrees, and
                                we see through a murky atmosphere, dark specters, casting gloomy shadows over the
                                pathway of life. If we enter into the palaces of kings, the domiciles of the venerated
                                priesthood, the cottages of the lowly, or the huts of savages, we find everywhere the
                                same law existing. The foul breath of sin produces physical disease, moral deformity,
                                and spiritual death. " Wasting and destruction are in the land." Thorns and briars
                                spring up to pierce the feet of those who travel the highway of life, metaphorically
                                speaking, and in the soil from which we derive physical sustenance, they choke the good
                                seed, while the mildew, the locust and the caterpillar, blight and destroy, often
                                causing a stinted harvest of food, inadequate to the needful demands of life. How shall
                                this be remedied 1 The dignitaries, in the popular churches, say, Ignorance is the root
                                of degenerate plants, and point to savage tribes as proof. Again, they direct attention
                                to, and bemoan what they call heathenism in pagan lands, where Christ has not been
                                preached. The apostle Paul, speaking of the worshipers of idols of gold, silver and
                                precious stones, said : " The times of this ignorance God winked at." By this we may
                                judge of the difference between the sin of ignorance and willful transgression. Jesus
                                said : " This is the condemnation, that light has come into the world." Will a salaried
                                priesthood, who eat the fat of the land through the labors of others, ever be found
                                ready and willing to " cry aloud, and spare not the transgressions of the people ? " and
                                to tell them that " there is no peace for the wicked, and that every one will be
                                rewarded according to their works 1 " Let the professed spiritual leaders of the people
                                come forth in the spirit of the Divine Teacher, and, firstly, by example, then by
                                precept, admonish and instruct their flocks, that God will not accept any thing short of
                                honesty, justice and equity ; that all who worship Him to His acceptance must do it in
                                the spirit of sincerity and in the truth ; that all the passions of body and mind, and
                                the individual will must be brought into subjection to the law of right — the law of
                                Christ. Let him or her who has been accustomed to steal, do so no more. Let the
                                incontinent man or woman become chaste in habitude and thought, and the lying tongue and
                                deceitful lips be made to speak truth in lieu of falsehood, and the speculator, who
                                lives upon unjust gains, put his own hands to work, and prove that honest, faithful
                                labor is a blessing — God's boon to humanity — a moral elevator. As a. rule, they who
                                live in idleness upon the labors of others are voluptuous and sensual, spending their
                                time in riotous living, wasting their energies upon perverted appetites, and watching an
                                opportunity to despoil the unwary, and add fuel to the smoldering embers which lurk in
                                the bosoms of the physically and morally degenerate beings, whose spirits, when freed
                                from the shattered clay tenement, will appear like smutty chimneysweeps. Will not waters
                                as effective as those of Damascus and Jordan be requisite to cleanse and fit them for
                                the society of the good and pure ? The good Master said : " Go work in my vineyard." We
                                may weep over the fallen, and strive to alleviate by kind words; we may pity the poor,
                                in word, and bestow charity from our abundant stores, but there are stronger claims,
                                sterner duties resting upon those who occupy the position of advance guards of the
                                public weal. If the sin and disease of the human heart have not gained full dominion,
                                and there is hope yet for humanity, by emancipation from the serfdom of sin and
                                wrong-doing, is it not high time for the loquacious rhetoric of pulpit orators, to give
                                place to sound doctrine ? Educate the masses to know that they will have to atone for
                                their own sins, by repenting and forsaking. Teach them that the virtue which will adorn
                                the chambers of the heart and make it a fit receptacle for angel visitants, is true
                                wealth. Turn the tide of thought, that gold and silver is the wealth that bears upon its
                                breast the strongest power to sway the destinies of nations or individuals. The clergy,
                                who pass through colleges and seminaries of learning, to fit them for the work of the
                                ministry, instead of seeking until they find the baptism of the Holy Spirit — the
                                unction of Divine Power — until the words which they speak really convey spirit and life
                                to the hearers, are fast losing their hold upon the confidence of the people, and will
                                be displaced by the rising spiritual prophets of the present age, who are coming up, all
                                over the land, outside of the churches. True inspirational power will carry an
                                unmistakable force with it, and be its own witness. The lo here's and lo there's will
                                avail little in the sequel. By their fruits — not words — will all spiritual media be
                                known There will not be much doubt in the minds of truthseekers and truth-doers, where
                                the Christ of God is found. Those who are truly inspired — sent of God— will not turn
                                aside from their purpose with fear, lest the leaf shall fade, the fig tree refuse to
                                yield her fruit, and there be no grapes on the vine, knowing, full well, that the same
                                hand that feeds the raven will supply the needs of those who trustingly work, watch and
                                pray. God is the just rewarder of those who diligently seek and serve Him.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="'If I be lifted up I will draw all men unto me'—Jesus" TEIform="index"/>"IF I BE LIFTED
                                DP I WILL DRAW ALL MEN UNTO ME."—JESUS</head><p TEIform="p">To our spiritual understanding, there are three clear, inferential statements in this
                                remarkable and peculiar expression : Firstly, That there was a time when Jesus was not
                                lifted up, or the thoroughly redeemed man he afterward became, else why the "Jf I be
                                lifted up?" Secondly, That by " lifting up " he meant something immeasurably more
                                significant than the manner by which his spirit was to be released from the clay it was
                                sojourning in. Thirdly, The immense magnetic power derived from a life lifted up above
                                the ordinary conditions of materiality, and which induced him to believe, with the eye
                                of faith, that he would eventually " draw all men unto him." That he was " tempted on
                                all points like as we are " we believe, though the high Jewish discipline he had been
                                subjected to had kept him, like Paul, " blameless concerning the law," still we can
                                scarcely find any who have been more severely and continuously tempted. The apostle says
                                a man " is tempted when he is drawn aside by his own lust and enticed." But as Jesus
                                came off conqueror, he knows how to feel for, and " succor those who are tempted, and
                                with the temptation make a way for their escape." The only Archimedian lever which can
                                move the world of mankind, spiritually, and lift them up to the heights where they too
                                may win souls to right doing, is the cross of selfdenial Jesus practiced and taught, and
                                which yields by destroying self-love, disinterested love to God and man.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. Webster, Harvard, Mass.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love token" TEIform="index"/>LOYE TOKEN</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Eldress Antoinette : I would proffer love to you, and grateful acknowledgments for
                                the benefit that I have derived from the perusal of the S. and S. It has been filled
                                with mental instruction and soul-food, which to me have been like sweet manna. I am
                                mindful that it has caused many hours of weariness and toil on your part to make it so
                                good and acceptable. My thanks are due to all who aid the cause By pen, or works, and
                                keeping laws, In building up the good and true In this our Zion home below. I would
                                encourage those who are young to ever bear in mind while they are forming habits of
                                life, that self-denial in the mind is the first requisite for the formation of a true
                                and substantial character; always let pleasureseeding be subservient to duty and
                                principle. Curb vain thoughts, and restrain sinful desires, then it will be easy to
                                bridle the tongue and sow seeds of peace and love, instead of discord and strife. How
                                beautiful it is to see those who are full of youthful vigor arid activity, turning the
                                strength of their minds to self-culture — training themselves to become useful — to
                                honor God, and to bless the race by their existence. To do this, the voice of conscience
                                must be regarded in small things which will lead to the observance of counsels, rules
                                and regulations which are constructed for the wellbeing and protection of society at
                                large, and are way-marks in our consecrated Zion home. In this way, the evils of the
                                human heart are subdued — character is made brilliant and beautiful, and the soul is
                                happified and filled with peace and joy. All such souls are an ornament and strength in
                                Zion, and a blessing to humanity ; their influence is healthful and saving wherever they
                                are.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Eliza R." TEIform="persName"/>Eliza R. Avery, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progression [part 4 of 6]" TEIform="index"/>SOCIAL GATHERING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">Cecelia : I know that you all would be pleased to hear A little acrostic, quaint and
                                clear, That Martha whispered into my ear, About this day of reaping. Now, Martha, will
                                you be so kind as to tell The words that Our Social Gathering spell? They sound to me
                                like a silver bell, Their music my mind is keeping. Martha : Out of the growth of a
                                hundred years, Union with ripened fruit appears ; Righteousness, sown in toil and tears
                                Spreads, like the oak, its leaves, Over the hills and plains of earth. Change to the
                                seeds of good gave birth Increasing harvests of priceless worth ; Angels garnered the
                                sheaves. Light and knowledge, through human law, Gave, as the prophets of old foresaw, A
                                safe retreat from oppression's war, That the ranks of the martyrs swelled. Here, in a
                                land of liberty, Earth has proclaimed her children free ; Rights that they cherished
                                sacredly, In lawful chains are held. Now we behold, while peace bears sway, dad omens of
                                millennial day. Margaret: We bring to our annual gatherings The treasures of life and
                                love, Ami gifts of our spirits mingle With those of the Heavenly Dove. They're a garner
                                for thought, a garner for truth, Kept sacred by holy resolves, Made pure by the faith
                                that unites us as one, The union that never dissolves. Incentives to action, to labor
                                and prayer, We gather from year unto year, While a knowledge of life, its duties and
                                care, Disrobes the dim future of fear. They are like a morning of beauty and light, A
                                morning that never departs, But bears on its wings the promise of life, And the rest
                                that true conquest imparts. And ever anon we hear the glad sound Of blessing from
                                kindred afar, Who long for a share of the pleasure we reap, Which pleasure no evils will
                                mar. With joy in our hearts, we await them each year; United together we say, O! let
                                them continue, they are unto us A light to illumine our way. Ann : Among the peace gifts
                                of my life, Is one that glitters bright; Its glory lingers in my heart Like everlasting
                                light. The thought—I mingle on this spot With those I love most dear — Arises like the
                                morning sun Unto my vision clear. <pb n="94" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER A.ND O! may the gift that
                                here is won, Upon me rest in peace, And may a deeper sacrifice Bring to me truth's
                                increase. And cherished in life's memory Shall be this hour of love, When gifts of holy
                                pleasure come Prom Zion pure above. Er,vAH: When the shadows of evening are gathering
                                'round, And the breath of the rose is hidden or blown; When hushed is the sound of labor
                                and care, And quietude seals the day that is flown,— Then cometh the hour that gladly I
                                meet, The hour for angels to reign in our home, Who breathe o'er the souls my heart
                                fondly loves, And whisper the joy of the future to come. 'Tis then I can view the fair
                                Zion of God, Increasing in glory, in honor and light; 'Tis then I'm inspired to toil to
                                the day When truth will be monarch and right will be might.</p><div4 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We will sing of eternal progression..." TEIform="index"/>We will sing of eternal progression...
                                </head><p TEIform="p">VlGOROSO. echo, four voices. We will sing of eternal progression, Till its joy the
                                    whole earth can fill, earth can fill, We know the gift of our parents, And its
                                    virtues our spirits thrill, spirits thrill. Over mountains and wide rolling rivers
                                    The sound of its glory will roll, glory will roll, The wings of freedom will bear it
                                    onward To meet a response in each soul, in each soul. Till the nations re-echo the
                                    echo. echo. music, Sweet peace and love will reign, will reign, Pure love to welcome
                                    the increase, And peace to hallow its gain, hallow its gain.</p></div4><div4 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progression [part 5 of 6]" TEIform="index"/>Progression [part 5 of 6]
                                </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">Melissa — Heard ye the song of the Angels ? Heard ye its echo sweet. That softly
                                    swells around our home, When the earth and the heavens meet?</p></div4><div4 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Yea, we have heard that glorious song..." TEIform="index"/>Yea, we have heard that glorious song...
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Yea, we have heard that glorious song, 'Tis a burst of music grand, 'Tis vict'ry's
                                    inspiration From the resurrection land. I have caught its echo in my soul, Its
                                    melody has come to me, Oh, let its cadence roll and roll, 'Till earth is glad and
                                    free, Oh, let its cadence roll and roll, Till earth is glad and free.</p></div4></div3><pb n="95" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progression [part 6 of 6]" TEIform="index"/>Progression [part 6 of 6]
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">Cecelia: I thought from Margaret's speaking, A little while ago, There was at least one
                                place on earth Where Sharon's rose could grow ; Where hearts, by consecration, Could
                                draw the angels near; And, since we heard that blessed song, I know that place is here.
                                Margaret: There is no spot on earth so dear As this on which we stand, Made hallowed by
                                the meeting here Of friends from spirit land. Could their material forms be seen, What
                                joy it \yould create. Why not? 'tis just a step between This and the future state, A
                                step that every one must take, For we must leave each earthly scene ; Then, let our
                                faith unbar the gate, And love push back the screen. Charlotte : The great beyond ! 'Tis
                                near our life, I long to see and hear Fulfillment of the promises By prophet and by
                                seer. 'Tis not for sight of spirit forms, This yearning is within, But the uplifting of
                                the race From sickness and from sin. I know that poverty will fall Beneath this mighty
                                flow, And earth no longer reel and toss With her strong weight of woe. For yon bright
                                souls can better find And melt the hearts of ire, Than dwellers here below, who ne'er
                                Have doffed the earth's attire. When mortals know they're really seen By beings up
                                above, The wrongs of life will yet be changed And hearts will grow in love. And, though
                                from me that law is hid That governs this great power, I know 'tis true ! and so I wait
                                The spirit's day and hour. Elvah: Who knows but what this world will blended be With
                                that unseen above ? And hence eternity Will be as dwelling here upon the earth, From
                                birth to death, and thence again to birth. For if, by passing on from sphere to sphere,
                                We understand we die, yet live again, Our life with all creation will combine To show
                                that vital forces will remain. How grand and e'en sublime we view to-day, With eyes of
                                full belief, the spirit forms That come from that dim, vague and wond'rous land, In
                                human shape that life-blood freely warms ! Melissa : There's nothing new, the sage hath
                                said, And growth with this is rife ; The theme that fills the mind to-day, And throbs
                                the pulse of life, Was regnant when the Nazarene Received the spirit birth, While the
                                old corridors of life Portrayed its ancient worth. From Genesis to Revelation, From
                                Revelation on through time, We see its phases, while its truth With our best thoughts
                                can chime. Cecelia: As Catharine claims a long descent From those who dwelt in Israel's
                                tent, It was but right to have her sent To search the book of Moses. The spirit powe^r
                                that there is found Is like the giant race it crowned; It stands, the ages to confound,
                                By all that it discloses. So, Catharine, tell us what you saw, And what the inference
                                you draw, How far you probed the potent law That mystery incloses. Catharine : Adown the
                                vista of the past We see through time's dim mists, That with the human race this soul Of
                                science co-exists. The records of antiquity Are all agleam with stories Of how the
                                spirit power wrought out Its wonders and its glories. The tutelary deity That anciently
                                o'er-ruled ; That in the laws of mundane life The tribes of Israel schooled, With Moses
                                many times communed, As clad in man's attire; And, sometimes, brilliantly appeared
                                Within a bush of fire. "I Am," he simply called his name, When profferintr the mission
                                Through which his chosen ones could find Deliverance and remission. When unto Moses he
                                gave power King Pharaoh's heart to move, In visitations that he sent To punish and
                                reprove, The magic rod, that Moses used, His wonders to perform, When struck upon the
                                ground, received A serpent's life and form. The plagues of flies and frogs were sent,
                                The waters turned to blood, And locusts swarmed upon the earth, Consuming all the food.
                                O'er Egypt sable veils were drawn— Three days were as the nightWhile Israel's children
                                all abode In dwellings filled with light. But Pharaoh's heart was still too hard To let
                                the captives go, Until the Lord, by heavier hand, His judgment strong would show. But
                                when he found in every house A flrst-born struck with death, That e'en his son upon the
                                throne No more had life and breath, He rose in midnight's darksome hour, His servants to
                                command, That Moses with all Israel Might quickly flee the land. All through their
                                dreary exodus, To guide their feet aright, A pillar moved as cloud by day, That brightly
                                glowed at night. They marched through trackless wilderness Until they heard the roar Of
                                waves, that from the Red Sea rolled To wash its pebbly shore. And, then, they heard the
                                marshal tread Of Pharaoh's host draw near; But Moses, filled with faith and hope,
                                Delivered them from fear. The guiding angel, that was clothed In cloud and radiance
                                bright, Cast darkness on the enemy, While giving Israel light; Then Moses stood, with
                                outstretched arm, Commanding the great sea To rise in walls on right and left And clean
                                divided be Till every child in Israel Had passed upon dry ground; But, when its might
                                returned again, The enemy were drowned. Martha: By these great works the people knew
                                Their Lord before them moved, His power to save in danger's hour Unto their hearts was
                                proved. But, when encamped upon the land To which they had been led, Their hunger
                                prompted murmurings For Egypt's meat and bread. The Lord, who always heard their cries,
                                Replied with blessings free, Appearing to them in a cloud Whose glory all could see.
                                With evening shade there fell soft due, Like hoar-frost on the ground. And in the
                                morning everywhere Fresh manna could be found. 'Twas gathered from the atmosphere— We'll
                                say, " materialized "— And thus, for forty years, their bread Was daily improvised. Ann:
                                When journeying o'er the desert waste They found no water-brooks, And bitter murmurings
                                Moses felt Expressed in words and looks. He bade them wait until the Lord Could satisfy
                                their thirst, Then with his rod smote Horeb's rock Till water from it burst. A living
                                spring came bubbling out, A sparkling, flowing tide ; Its source was in the viewless
                                power Which all their needs supplied. Catharine: From types and shadows in the past
                                Comparison we draw To Zion fair, whose growth shall prove Fulfillment of the law. The
                                little ark, before us placed, Brings to our vision clear The ark that was the cabinet
                                Through which the Lord drew near. The principles of righteousness, And testimony pure.
                                Were in the ark of covenant Held sacred and secure. On these, from precious metal
                                wrought, Was placed the Mercy Seat, Whereon the Lord could speak His will, And with His
                                chosen meet. The Cherubs, 'neath Shekinah's light, In beauty there express The dual life
                                of Deity, The Altar of redress. Another type of ancient time In Zion is redeemed. The
                                breast-plate by the high-priest worn, Through which the Lord convened. Its form was of a
                                perfect square ; This meant equality, That all the tribes of Israel Might perfect
                                justice see : Twelve precious stones composed this plate, Twelve tribes thereon were
                                named, Through these, in time of counsel, God's answer was proclaimed. Shekinah's light
                                the letters marked That spelt each needed word, When Prophet, Priest or Ruler, In duty
                                sought the Lord. Ideals of the past give place To grand reality, The substance of those
                                shadows dim, In brightness now we see. We feel and know, by inner sense, Their meaning
                                deep and blest; For with the Lord's Anointed Ones The Ark and treasures rest. And Mfcy
                                Seat, O sacred gift! Its wort I) is more than gold, More purely than could Cherubim
                                Their wings our hearts enfold The breast-plates by their spirits worn Of judgment from
                                above, Metes to our souls God's justice true, Clothed in parental love. In the
                                Shekinah's light they dwell, And by it they can read— Not lettered symbols as of old—
                                But life with all its need. Margaret: This growth of innate spirit power In beauty was
                                displayed, When on the Altar of the Lord Their rods twelve princes laid ; When Aaron's
                                chosen by the will Of overruling powers,—¦ Was caused to yield the bud and fruit Of
                                fragrant almond flowers. Thus far these time-famed miracles, To which we have referred,
                                Through Moses' gift of mediumship Have principally occurred; But, when his days of
                                leadership Were drawing to a close, The mantle rested on the one Whom God in wisdom
                                chose. And, thus, when Joshua led them forth To find the promised land, Like the Red
                                Sea, were Jordan's waves, Divided, caused to stand. Milissa : Still further on, we read
                                of those Who could materialize; Who, having left the earth, again Could wear the mortal
                                guise. With Samuel this was the case; He through the witch of Endor came, Her powers
                                secretly were sought, With safety promised in God's name. He showed himself unto King
                                Saul, And openly conversed, While Saul, who asked his counsel wise His grievances
                                rehearsed. Elvah: And have not all the story read Of Elijah by the ravens fed, And how
                                the widow's oil increased When its supply had almost ceased, And meal that only once
                                could feed Was multiplied as growth of seed? And when Elijah went his way Within the
                                wilderness to stay, Requesting of the Lord to die And with his fathers dwell on high, He
                                laid him 'neath a tree and slept, While angel guards their vigils kept. Their soft touch
                                caused him to awake, And, lo ! beside him was a cake, And water pure within a cruise,
                                Which they had brought there for his use. Charlotte : Those were pleasant incidents,
                                And, though they seem but small, To me they're quite as wonderful As Honto with her
                                shawl; And little yet, at Chittenden, Has been materialized, But that the past, in
                                prototype, Has fully realized. The spirit friends and chariots, seen By all the Eddy
                                brothers, Soon before they had to part With one of their grandmothers, Did not require
                                higher law Or stronger spirit forces, Than those which caught Elijah up With chariot's
                                fiery horses. Margaret: A strange event, of which we read, To us is now made clearer, By
                                one who lived five hundred years Before the Christian era. She who appears as mountain
                                witch, Whose home was in the East, Was present when Belshazzar, king, Held his ungodly
                                feast. And through her influence there came The writing on the wall, Predicting that a
                                judgment hand So soon on him would fall. To mountain clefts she had to flee From
                                persecution's storm ; But now she often comes to earth, Her mission to perform. Ann:
                                With spiritual phenomena The olden times were rife, In several oases written then The
                                dead were raised to life. Daniel, in the lion's den, All night in safety dwelt; The
                                Hebrew sons through fire walked, Its flames by them unfelt. The miracles that Jesus
                                wrought We have not specified ; But that they were realities, I think we coincide. We
                                know that all of them occurred By laws yet unrevealed ; Within the future's treasury,
                                From us they are concealed. Charlotte : We've learned that death is not the end of man;
                                There is an after-life we all must know; A spirit-world, where countless souls abound
                                Who've learned the bearings of a life below. These bible records of the spirit power
                                Confirm the truth within—we live and breathe With friends departed, who our pathway
                                cheer, And joy amid our sorrows gladly wreathe. From fire and storm and fierce
                                destructive powers A Saviour in a dream or warning oft they give : This dawning law will
                                yet become our guide. The shadow with the substance now doth live ; We know that to the
                                substance we are dim or dark, But grasp the shadow with an anxious fear; Our purblind
                                vision can but dimly mark What in the spirit life is full and clear.</p></div3><pb n="96" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Change" TEIform="index"/>CHANGE</head><p TEIform="p">While earthly charms surround us, And all is bright and fair, That beautlfles our
                                dwelling In this terrestrial sphere, For spirit is the power, And each material thing Is
                                subject to the changes That hidden forces bring. Mayhap to search the future,
                                Untraversed fields to roam, Or led by angel guardians, Revisit our earth home. "We know
                                these are but shadows, So, are our mortal dwellings, To mingle with our kindred, That,
                                in the grand beyond, The substance without shadow Will to the soul respond. By spirit
                                here controlled, 'Till silently we leave them For mysteries yet untold, Appear before
                                their eyes, As, when we with them journeyed In earth's material guise.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Respectful manners" TEIform="index"/>RESPECTFUL MANNERS</head><p TEIform="p">To young persons, and to some, not so very young, a correspondent offers the following :
                                In speaking to many, or to few, let your words be chaste, respectful, and distinctly
                                articulated. Common justice requires this — self-respect requires it. As to coming in,
                                salutation, being seated, rising and taking leave, we deem no instructions needful.
                                Well-disposed persons will, intuitively, be well behaved. With such as are so deficient
                                in self-respect as not to be well disposed, we have, at present, no vocation. To
                                correspondents — to contributors — to all, who write, expecting others to read, we
                                respectfully suggest, that you wait till you are quite sure you have an idea— an idea
                                that will interest some body besides your own dear self. When sure you have an idea, put
                                that idea in the fewest possible words. Put the words together mechanically, in
                                pursuance of the laws of language. Let your sentences be short. Don't send your readers
                                away back to hunt for your nominative case, or antecedent. In this fast age, such is the
                                deluge of would be reading matter, that writers, if they would have readers, must write,
                                not wholly for their own edification </p><byline TEIform="byline"> —<persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Ed.</byline></div3><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Parsees" TEIform="index"/>Parsees</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"As a race, the Parsees are intelligent, active and energetic ; with business
                                        capacities far above the average, they are usually successful in amassing
                                        wealth, while they are extremly benevolent in dispensing their gains for both
                                        public and private charities. For private benefaction they have, however, but
                                        little call among themselves, since a Parsee pauper would be an unheard-of
                                        anomaly. They burn upon their sacred altars fire which they brought from Persia,
                                        and which has never been extinguished since it was kindled by Zoroaster from the
                                        sun 4000 years ago. They think it can never go out till it has consumed all evil
                                        from the earth and the good has become universally triumphant. * * * Memory
                                        fails to recall the case of a single fire worshipper who was not strictly
                                        upright in his dealings. * * * Commencing with the worship of the sun and of
                                        fire as his emblem, the Parsee grew into a sort of reverence for the elements of
                                        air, earth and water. The air must not be contaminated by foul odors, and of
                                        necessity no filth could be tolerated anywhere, in houses, street or suburb, and
                                        to this reverence for the purity of the atmosphere may be traced the absolute
                                        cleanliness for which fire worshippers are everywhere noted."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Investigator" TEIform="index"/>Investigator</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sunshine in houses" TEIform="index"/>SUNSHINE IN HOUSES</head><p TEIform="p">The time very n*kely will come when sunshine or sunlight will be so utilized as to be the
                                entire remedy used for very many diseases. That it is a wonderful fertilizer none can
                                doubt who know any thing about it. But how many houses are constructed with a view to
                                getting all the sunshine possible, especially when so much is needed in winter and
                                spring? The living or sitting room, at these seasons of the year at least, should have
                                full Southern exposure, with large windows to let in the sunshine. All sleeping rooms,
                                closets, wardrobes and passage ways should receive the cleansing, vivifying influence of
                                the sun. Sickly persons should court the sunshine as much as possible— sit in it, lie in
                                it, luxuriate in it. It doesn't cost any thing, only appreciation. A room warmed neither
                                by sun nor by fire is unhealthy, and not fit for human habitation. It is a poor theory
                                that sends men, women and children off into a cold room to sleep on healthy principles,
                                when warmth has been excluded for a day or week, or perhaps months. The change in the
                                temperature of a room having both fire and sunshine, after the sun goes down, is
                                exceedingly marked. A perceptible chill is felt. </p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit communication" TEIform="index"/>SPIRIT COMMUNICATION</head><p TEIform="p">To F. W. Evans : A full basket, when presented, gives pleasure to the one presenting it,
                                and to the receiver more than he can express,— hence all the baskets used in such a
                                manner, would tend to liarmonize a multitude, much larger than are assembled around, or
                                in a so-called sacred edifice, where on a Sabbath Day, the so-called Christian world
                                assemble to offer prayers and praises, to a God they know but little of, straining their
                                every nerve to become popular in their utterances. Making long harangues of little
                                import, more than to evoke the ridicule of men, who are good and great from principle,
                                who prefer a respectful silence to the blarney of a proud and ostentatious priest, who
                                seeks the applause of men without a single aspiration to become approved of God and the
                                "Invisibles."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lawrence, James" TEIform="persName"/>James Lawrence, Cleveland, Ohio. March 3,1873</byline></div3><div3 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The opinion is quite general..." TEIform="index"/>The opinion is quite general...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The opinion is quite general that Thomas Paine was an atheist, but this extract from his
                                last will seems to leave no room for doubt that, in spite of his skepticism on other
                                points, he was a believer in God: " Reposing confidence in my Creator, God, and in no
                                other Being, for I know of no other, nor believe in any other, I, Thomas Paine, of the
                                city of New York, author of the work entitled ' Common Sense,' written in Philadelphia,
                                in January, 1776, which awakened America to a Declaration of Independence on the 4th of
                                July," etc., etc. Communications in future, to be addressed, "THE SHAKER," Shakers,
                                Albany Co., N. Y. " There is nothing covered which shall not be revealed " Is now being
                                fulfilled. The almost incredible revealments of " Satan in Society " are fully sustained
                                by Women and Men, who claim to speak from sorrowful experience, and observations — fully
                                establishing the scandalous fact, that worst prostitution — most outrageous abuse of
                                reproductive powers — of humanity — is perpetrated under sanction of law — cloaked under
                                the sacred (?) ordinance of Matrimony.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="As Christianity is gradually compelled to give up civil government..." TEIform="index"/>As Christianity is gradually compelled to give up civil government...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">As Christianity is gradually compelled to give up civil government, so it will gradually
                                be compelled to give up associations with metaphysics, with long creeds, and with
                                apostolic succession, and chorals and candles, and betake itself into the soul, and find
                                its ejnpire to be bounded by faith in Christ, and an fipright life. In that day, and may
                                it hasten its coining, all the hearts that love Christ and do the will of God will be
                                one.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Swing, David" TEIform="persName"/>David Swing</byline></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The expenses of States, counties, cities and towns..." TEIform="index"/>The expenses of States, counties, cities and towns...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The expenses of States, counties, cities and towns in the Northern States, not
                                represented by funded debts, have been estimated at $500,000,000. The increase of State
                                debts on the war account was $123,000,000. The increase of city, town and county debts
                                is estimated at $200,000,000. Total war expenses of the loyal States and the National
                                Government, $6,165,237,000. The estimated direct expenditures of the Confederate States
                                on account of the war were $2,000,000,000. Aggregate expenses of the war to the country,
                                North and South, $8,165,237,000. The total receipts of all sources during the second
                                year of the war were less than $42,000,000. The expenditures were $60,000,000 per month
                                — at the rate of $700,000,000 a year. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Questions" TEIform="index"/>Questions
                            </head><p TEIform="p">QUESTIONS. As a people, why do we shave — cut off
                                our beards? Why do the Chinese shave their heads, as they do their faces? Why do Chinese
                                females cripple their feet, and some females their waists? Why does not Nature give up
                                the struggle of centuries, and let Anglo-Saxon and Chinese men be born minus surplus
                                hair, and their females be born with wasplike waists, high heels, club-feet, and humps
                                on their * * * * s, and on the back, of their heads? Does nature expect her children to
                                become so sane that they can leave off a bad habit, without dropping a good one to
                                balance it —progression without retrogression ?</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute" TEIform="index"/>TRIBUTE</head><p TEIform="p">Weed, Parsons &amp; Co., Publishing House, 39 &amp; 41 Columbia St., Albany. Our
                                Brother, Wm. Offord, was from England, where he was Master Printer and Methodist
                                Minister. After going through the above named Printing House, he remarked, " I have
                                never seen an office where the system was so perfect, the order so complete." I indorse
                                that opinion. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>