<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2504" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">25</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><date value="18950401" TEIform="date">April 1895</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">73-96</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="25" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
APRIL.
MANIFESTO
PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES.
VOL. XXV.
 Cast thy bread upon the waters ; for thou shalt find it after many days.'\
Eccl. XI: i.
East Canterbury, N. H.
1895.
THE
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.	
	Page
History of South Union, No. 18,	73
True Spiritualism,	77
"Letter,Sinion Emery,	80
New Year's Thoughts,	82
Righteousness,      ....	84
MusicBest Gifts,	- '    -           86
Notes About Home,	87
Tribute,Eldress Sarah Small,	93
Reception at Harvard, Mass.   -	"
Exchanges,          ....	94
Acrostic,.....	95
Deaths,         .....	96
Books & Papers,   -      -      -	"
cMATSJRADE Marks
COPYRIGHTS.
WANTED
RELIABLE MEN to sell
our choice and complete
line of Nursery Stock_
'Highest salary and commis!
sion paid weekly, paying permanent position
guaranteed and success assured to good men.
Special inducements to beginners, experience
not necessary. Exclusive territory and your
own choice of same given.   Do not delay.
 ALLEN NURSERY CO.
ROCHESTER, N. Y.
THE SHAKER COVSNANf.
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS    OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES  and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION    AND    CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
the same time, afford instruction to all inquiring  minds.    Price 5  cts. each,   postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
Agent to sell our new book, Dictionary of
United States History, by Prof. J. Franklin Jameson. Needed by every teacher, pu"
pil, and family; indorsed. Agents selling fif"
ty books per week. Successful agents will
be made general agents.   Big- pay.
PURITAN PUBLISHING CO., Boston. Mays.
CAN I OBTAIN A PATENT? Fora
prompt answer and an honest opinion, write to
MUNN &; CO., who have had nearly fif ty years'
experience in the patent business. Communications strictly confidential. A Handbook of Information concerning Patents and bow to obtain them sent free. Also a catalogue of mechanical and scientific books sent free.
Patents taken thronch Muim & Co. receive
special notice in the Scientific American, and
thus are brought widely before the public without cost to the inventor. This splendid paper,
issued weekly, elegantly illustrated, has by far the
largest circulation of any scientific work in the
world.  $3 a year.   Sample copies sent free.
Building Edition, monthly, $2.50 a year. Single
copies, 25 cents. Every number contains beautiful plates, in colors, and photographs of new
bouses, with plana, enabling Builders to show the
latest designs and secure contracts.  Address
MUNN & CO., New Yokk, 361 BROADWAY.
THE  ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley,
2 N. Fourth St.,  St. Louis, Mo.
A Visit to tpie
of EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
LLOYD IT. CHANDLER.U. S.M.
Liberally Illustrated with half tone
pictures of peksons and places.
The Village of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the lovliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price 15 cts.
WANTED!
Apply to--><pb n="73" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="History of South Union, Kentucky, no. 18" TEIform="index"/>HISTORY OF SOUTH UNION, KY. NO.
                            18.</head><p TEIform="p">MAY 19, 186.3. A company of two Brethren and six Sisters ride to Bowling Green a distance of
                            fourteen miles. While ascending a hill for the purpose of seeing the fortifications, a bolt
                            broke under the carriage, and the company were all thrown to the ground. Six of the company
                            were quite severely wounded. One Sister had her hand crushed, another a wrist broken and
                            another was badly cut on the head and face. One Sister was brought home on a bed on account
                            of serious injuries. May 24, Sunday. Not less than thirty persons are seen in our field of
                            strawberries. They come armed and so can not be driven away. May "27. General Judah and
                            family with a staff of twenty-five soldiers, and others, in all numbering about fifty
                            persons, are treated to a very excellent, free dinner. A visit from a general of the regular
                            army brings a measure of relief in these perilous times. Companies of lawless creatures are
                            prowling around day and night, and are ready to commit any depredation for their selfish
                            interest. Hardly a day passes that either the Federal or Confederate soldiers are not
                            passing through our village. Some of these ask for or demand whatever they may want, while
                            some are very kind to pay for all they receive. It is difficult to tell who are our friends
                            or our foes by their military dress, as the Confederates are quite often to be seen in the
                            uniform of the Federals. As food is very scarce the whites or blacks will steal whatever may
                            be found and the chicken house is quite a center of attraction. The slaves are now learning
                            a new lesson, and as the masters or overseers are unable to keep a APRIL, <pb n="74" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 74 THE MANIFESTO. close watch over them, these irresponsible chattels in human form are
                            taking liberties with any property they may find and under cover of the night, make their
                            way, a score at a time, into the free states or where they can be protected by the Northern
                            soldiers. Aug. 8. Two hundred soldiers pass through our village to-day on their way to East
                            Tennessee. A company of some forty men and women leave the train at our station and come to
                            the village on purpose to obtain some food which they understand we keep ready for any who
                            may call. We told them the report was not correct and that we are not able to dispose of our
                            property in that manner. As a deed of charity however, we give this large, disappointed
                            company a free lunch, for which they express many thanks and then leave for their homes.
                            Sept. The government authorities have again taken charge of the railroad that passes by our
                            village and are using it for military purposes. The lawless classes that dare to do as they
                            may wish with the property of others, are patting the Officers to a great deal of trouble.
                            Although they go about in small companies they are difficult to conquer. As strange as this
                            may seem, two of the Brethren have been on a journey of two hundred miles into the southern
                            country, with a span of horses and a carriage and return without the least harm. For this
                            preservation we render thanks. Several of the Brethren have been drafted into the United
                            States' service, but have not yet been ordered into camp. Dec. 31. A Brother goes to Bowling
                            Green to inform the Provost Marshall that the Brethren will not report without further
                            orders. The Marshall said they need not report, as he had just received a dispatch from
                            Washington, as follows: To the Provost Marshall, Bowling Green. Sir ;If there is any
                            religious Community within your district, whose conscientious scruples abjure war, or the
                            payment of commutation fee, you will parole them indefinitely, still holding them subject to
                            any demand from the authority here. (signed) E. M. Stanton, Secretary of War. Washington, D.
                            C. Dec. 30, 1863. This is "good news and glad tidings" to all in our Community, as our call
                            to follow Christ forbids our Brethren entering the army as soldiers, and we are anxious that
                            the government should recognize the fact and give them an honorable release. 1864. This year
                            opens very much as have passed the last months. Soldiers are constantly passing through our
                            village, but do not make us much trouble. The country is still infested with sneak thieves
                            and robbers and it requires a <pb n="75" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 75 constant watch day and
                            night to protect our property. Our neighbors are treated much worse than we are. Their
                            houses are broken into, their lives threatened and their money all taken from them. These
                            lawless characters do not seem to discriminate between Unionists and Confederates. It is
                            money they want and they will risk their lives to obtain it. The negroes are still giving
                            anxiety to their masters. Freedom sounds a little better than slavery, and the negroes are
                            doing their best to find it. One southern woman came to our village in search of her slave.
                            She had been very kind to him and gave him permits to hire out. This time he wanted to work
                            for the Shakers and she came to the village to find him. The Brethren said they had not seen
                            him. He was evidently looking for freedom. One of our neighbors, a rich planter, informs us
                            that two of his slaves left him last Sabbath while he was at Church, and have entered the U.
                            S. army. One of them is very valuable and trusty and the man had no thought that he would
                            leave him. "My farm," he said, "must be idle for want of hands to till it." [Indeed and this
                            farm had better remain untilled, than that it should be tilled by human beings who will be
                            treated like the brute beasts. Ed.] In March, one of the Brethren made a trip into the state
                            of Tennessee to sell garden seeds. On his return he related the following incident. It was
                            in the early evening and I was driving slowly through a section of woods, when a
                            fierce-looking fellow presented a revolver and ordered me to halt. As I was powerless, I
                            obeyed and the following conversation took place. Guerrilla.Where are you going? Shaker.To
                            Latham's a few miles distant. Guer.What is in your wagon ? Shaker.Garden seeds. Guer.Where
                            do you sell them? Shaker.We have a market for them in the South. Guer.Where do you live?
                            Shaker.In South Union, Ky. Guer.I don't know where that is. Shaker.In Shakertown. Guer.I
                            don't know where that is. Shaker.It is on the State road fourteen miles west of Bowling
                            Green. Guer.That'll do. You have a large mule in your team and a good-looking horse.
                            Shaker.It is an indifferent team and the horse is lame. The fellow then examined the horse's
                            mouth. Guer.He is about eight years old. Shaker.The horse is nearer fifteen. Guer.This mule
                            is a fine animal. <pb n="76" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 76 THE MANIFESTO. Shaker.His leg has been injured.
                            Guer.Yes, it may have been broken, but he is a good animal and some of these jay hawkers may
                            gobble him up. Shaker.I can travel slowly but I should hate to lose them. Guer.You are going
                            to Latham's to stay over night? Shaker.I am. Guer.Well, go on then. I called at Latham's,
                            but he was from home. A negro boy told me to drive in and stop ; but he said the Yankees
                            might take my horse. They were stealing all round here, they had just stolen two barrels of
                            whiskey and a bale of cotton from his master. Shaker.I fear the guerrillas more than I do
                            the Yankees. Negro.O da'll come ter-night an' steal der hosses. Shaker.Is there any place to
                            hide the horse? Negro.Sometimes Massa hide dem, but dars de wagon an' den da'll break in der
                            house an' make yer tell. I concluded to put them into the stable and when Latham returned he
                            would advise me. After waiting more than an hour the host arrived, and I told him of my
                            trouble. He called the negro boy and told him to take the horse and mule and hide them in
                            one of the negro huts and if any body came and asked where they were, he was to say he did
                            not know, or he might say they were put into the stable and fed. I soon retired for the
                            night, but was suddenly aroused about midnight by the boisterous noises of some one or ones
                            who had called for the master of the house. They were admitted and conducted up stairs to a
                            room. They talked very loud, and I believed tney were robbers and w^ould demand my horses. I
                            slept but little, and was out at the dawn of day, and as soon as the animals had been fed
                            preparations were made to continue the journey. Fortunately I left the place without
                            molestation and started for Dresden, Tenn. When within three miles of the village, I called
                            at a house to see if I could stop till Monday. The man of the place was away from home and
                            the woman was in trouble. She said that the guerrillas and Yankees had robbed them of their
                            horses and of nearly all they had to live on. She said it was of no use to buy seed as they
                            were unable to cultivate the land. I concluded to drive a little nearer to the village and
                            try again. I called at a nice-looking residence, and the story of my last stopping-place was
                            repeated. The man said they had been robbed of everything and had not a thing left on which
                            to feed a horse, but if I could stay on such conditions I should be welcome. However, I
                            concluded to drive on as the horses must have something to eat. When near Dresden I asked a
                            negro if the soldiers were yet in town. He said the soldiers had just gone away. At the
                            hotel I met an old friend and he provided a safe place for both my horse and wagon. I
                            subsequently <pb n="77" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 77 learned that both houses where I had
                            called were broken into and robbed that same night. After disposing of my garden seeds, I
                            was fortunate enough to reach home in safety. Through the whole of this year there was but
                            little rest to be found. Although the Southern army did not march through the state as
                            formerly, yet hardly a day passed that the Shakers were not obliged to provide food for
                            Union soldiers and for those who fiercely demanded if. On some accounts the country was in a
                            much worse state and the people suffered more than they did during the invasion of either
                            the Confederate or Union army. There was no hour of safety, day or night. To forcibly enter
                            a house and demand your money, or whatever they might choose, was of daily occurrence.
                            Breaking into the houses at night was so common that it deprived many of their much needed
                            rest. Many years will be required in this part of the country before the ruinous results of
                            the war will have passed away. It has been an ordeal that one would not care to pass through
                            more than once in a life time. Yet South Union with all its suffering has been especially
                            protected. The civil government has kindly recognized the religious principle that governed
                            the lives of the people, and acted accordingly, and it was through the care of an overruling
                            Providence that we were protected from harm during this furious storm of the worst passions
                            of the human mind. (The End.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True spiritualism" TEIform="index"/>TRUE SPIRITUALISM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>By Anna White.</byline><p TEIform="p">[This essay was read at a recent meeting at Unity
                            Church, Pittsjield, Mass.] IN a recent issue of "The Banner of Light" we read of spiritual manifestations in an
                            Episcopalian home a few miles from this city ; the medium being a girl twelve years of age
                            who is living with this Episcopalian minister's family. It is reported that she evidently
                            possesses the gifts of clairvoyance and clairaudience to a remarkable degree, and as is
                            frequently the case in the experience of the Spiritualists her descriptions of the
                            manifestations taking place in her presence is substantiated by an absent medium, thus
                            making assurance doubly sure. To us among whom spirit manifestions occurred some years
                            before the Rochester rappings, this phenomenal phase of spiritualism is very interesting. It
                            is one among many prophesies given at that time, which are being fulfilled to the letter.
                            Modern spiritualism originated in the Shaker Order, in 1842 and it continued to work a most
                            marvelous work for seven years. Then the ruling spirit informed us that the class of spirits
                            that had been with us, were going out into the wide world and there was not a palace or
                            cottage that they would not <pb n="78" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 78 THE MANIFESTO. visit. It was four years
                            before they commenced operations at Hydesville, N. Y. How their predictions have been and
                            are being actualized, through the nations of the earth, you need no information. Phenomena
                            is to the unbeliever the foundation of spiritualism, without it there would be nothing upon
                            which to construct its philosophy, and he who attacks phenomena, strikes at the cause
                            itself. One good "test" is worth more in convincing the skeptic of the truth of spirit
                            return and the soul's continued existence after the death change, than all philosophy and
                            theories ever preached or taught by man. True phenomena first, then the grand philosophy.
                            That is for the unbeliever, mind, not for the believer. John the Revelator says, "I saw an
                            angel come down from heaven, having great power (from the Spirit world,) and the earth was
                            lighted with his glory." Now although this angel "had great power," the earth though lighted
                            was not saved. Is not that Spiritualism? Look at the exhibition of weakness and wickedness
                            among the various mediums ; many, like the priests, "preach for hire and divine for money."
                            Like leaders, like followers; yet, where is the theologythe creed and dogma in Christendom
                            that can stand before Spiritualism? And again John says I heard another voice from heaventhe
                            Spirit world, saying "Come out of her my people that ye be not partakers of her sins, and
                            receive not of her plagues; for her sins have reached unto heaven"the churchesand God hath
                            remembered her iniquities, the Inquisitions of the great Catholic Church, and her
                            persecutions of the Protestant Church her daughter, and man is remembering them too ; we
                            hope Americans will never forget them and let Christianity into their secular constitution.
                            The only people who obey that voice are the Shakers ; though we are in the world we are not
                            of the world, even as Jesus, his disciples and the pentecostal Church, were not of the
                            world. We constitute a new ordera new heavensand the light shining upon the new heavens,
                            like the sun upon the moon,is creating a new earthly order or state, "wherein shall dwell
                            righteousness" in earthly things. A right to be born right; where marriage will be used only
                            for propagation and not abused by the indulgence of inordinate desires, resulting in acts of
                            lust, followed by infanticide. Where woman will be man's peer in all things, ruling by
                            right, and not by consent. Where land will be nationalized, each man and woman having a
                            homestead of their own. Where education will be national, all childi'en be equally educated
                            in industrial schools and the schools be self-supporting. Where peaceable arbitration will
                            take the place of the sword. The "swords will be beaten into plowshares, and the spears into
                            pruning-hooks, and the nations will learn war no more," and "man to man the world over will
                            brothers be." That condition you will say is Utopian, that will be the long looked-for
                            Millennium. Even so ; "Behold I stand at the door and knock ; if any man hear my voice and
                            open the door, I will come in to him and will sup with him, and he with me." <pb n="79" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 79 There needs to be an opening for the Christ to enter; and
                            what if he should enter your city to-night? Are there not some who would feel like calling
                            upon "the rocks and the mountains to hide them from the face of him that sitteth upon the
                            throne and from the wrath of the Lamb ? " Would not the tables of the money-changers be
                            overturned and those cast out that bought and sold? "Make not my Father's house an house of
                            merchandise." Look at your saloonsgreat giant tempters of the youth, the youth that are to
                            be our future presidents to enact our laws and control our government: Prohibition does not
                            remedy the evil. The front doors may be closed and the protest on, still intemperance runs
                            riot. And what of those other dens, those horrible dens, not only found in the city slums
                            but on the wide streets, where fine carriages roll with their miserable inmates to palaces,
                            magnificent without, but within are full of corruption and full of crimehot-beds of lust.
                            "The social evil strikes at the fountain head of true progress; it paralyzes the conscience
                            and demoralizes the soul. Rend this veil of the flesh assunder as the Shakers have done for
                            nearly two hundred years and are doing at the present and there is no retreat for the
                            accused or the accuser only in the light, in the truth. Spiritualism with us is as a means
                            of salvation from the gigantic sins of the world, and from "the little foxes that spoil the
                            vines," the virtues. Therefore we hail every movement of this kind wherever we see it, as a
                            preparatory step toward the consummation of the Kingdom of Heaven in earth. I wish to call
                            your attention to an article in the Dec. No. of "The Arena," published by B. 0. Flower of
                            Boston, entitled "The Well-Springs and Feeders of Immorality." That opens up a chapter of
                            events which aie daily occurring in private and in public life that are alike disgusting and
                            alarming. Were it not for the prophets and prophetesses and the Witnesses of Truth that
                            raise their voices as a protest against the hideous monsters of vice grown bold in infamy
                            and crime, we might hang our heads as bulrushes with no hope of the morrow. But hear the
                            clear bugle notes as they follow one after another from the inspired poet, James G. Clark. I
                            have come, and the world shall be shaken Like a reed, at the touch of my rod, And the
                            kingdoms of time shall awaken To the voice and the summons of God; No more through the din
                            of the ages Shall warnings and chidings divine, From the lips of my prophets and sages, Be
                            trampled like pearls before swine. Ye have stolen my lands and my cattle; Ye have kept back
                            from labor its meed; Ye have challenged the outcasts to battle, When they plead at your feet
                            in their need; <pb n="80" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 80 THE MANIFESTO. And when clamors of hunger grew
                            louder And the multitude prayed to be fed, Ye have answered with prisons or powder The cries
                            of your brothers for bread. I turn from your altars and arches, And the mocking of steeples
                            and domes, To join in the long, weary marches Of the ones ye have robbed of their homes; I
                            share in the sorrow and crosses Of the naked, the hungry and cold; And dearer to me are
                            their losses Than your gains and your idols of gold. I will wither the might of the spoiler,
                            I will laugh at your dungeons and locks, The tyrant shall yield to the toiler, And your
                            judges eat grass like the ox; For the prayers of the poor have ascended To be written in
                            lightnings on high; And the wails of your captives have blended With the bolts that must
                            leap from the sky. The thrones of your kings shall be shattered And the prisoner and serf
                            shall go free; I will harvest from seed that I scattered On the borders of blue Galilee; For
                            I come not alone, and a stranger Lo! my reapers will sing through the night Till the star
                            that stood over the manger Shall cover the world with its might. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder Henry;--I was thinking to-night..." TEIform="index"/>Elder Henry;--I was thinking to-night...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Maine, Bangor, December 28, 1894" TEIform="index"/>Bangor, Me. Dec. 28, 1894.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Elder Henry ;I was thinking to-night perhaps you might imagine I had forgotten to send my
                                yearly subscription for The Manifesto, but I have been very busy in various ways since I
                                wrote you last so I could not seem to get around to it. To-morrow, I am going to send
                                you seventy-five cents in postage stamps, nothing preventing. A most eventful year has
                                nearly closed it3 evolution and its revolution and we are about to enter a new year in
                                which, according to all signs, there will be no less startling events than there have
                                been in the one just passing out at this present time. All mankind and all nature seems
                                to be in a terrible ferment. May it continue to ferment until it ferments all error,
                                injustice, wickedness and wrong-doing from the human family. Let the righteous raise the
                                banner of liberty high in the heavens that all <pb n="81" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 81
                                may read its beautiful inscription; Freedom, Freedom to all those that are bound in
                                chains of darkness and superstition. It seems to me that all the Heavenly host are
                                working earnestly to liberate the children of earth from all the errors of past ages.
                                The old car-wheels of progression that have so longbeen trigged by ministers and
                                priests, have finally been removed and the old progressive car once more has begun to
                                move on, and will finally grind all error to powder beneath its wheels and be blown away
                                by the four winds of heaven. In the Dec. Manifesto, Hamilton DeGraw, said I spoke the
                                gospel truth, (not all are as frank to acknowledge it as he) the plain truth is what is
                                needed in times like these let it strike where it may; he thinks I am entitled to some
                                kind of a reward for what I said, but I am not, for ni}T reward is always with me
                                whenever I can say anything that Avill give another an impetus to go to work for the
                                truth and the uplifting of humanity to a better condition. If the Shakers had used half
                                of the money in spreading the gospel truth that some of their defaulting Trustees have
                                absconded with and what has been lost in wildcat investments in the west to draw big
                                interest on, in my opinion there would not be such a dearth among them as there is now.
                                Stop trying to hoard and use your money freely for the spread of the light of truth, and
                                it will return to you four fold after many days. Follow your motto, on The Manifesto
                                "Cast thy bread upon the waters" or else remove it, substitute, "we have been weighed
                                and found wanting;" which would be more appropriate unless you follow it to the letter.
                                I would suggest that the Brothers and Sisters among the Shakers contribute their
                                thoughts to The Manifesto, if only a few words it will show they have a living interest
                                in the gospel cause. It is the littles that make the sum of life ; there are many
                                persons in the Societies that are hardly ever heard from, that could write something of
                                interest, if they would, that would be an impetus to some poor one of God's unfortunates
                                of earth and perhaps lift him from the slough of degradation and misery to a higher and
                                better condition. Do not be too much absorbed in the cares of this life; so much so that
                                you can not give a few moments of time once a month for the elevation of your brother
                                and sister that has not been as fortunate as you, in the knowledge of the truth. Let
                                your light shine, do not keep it hid under a bushel. ISow is the time to sow the good
                                seed, much of the ground is ready to receive it and if you withhold the sowing you
                                surely ought not expect to reap the harvest, if you do, you will be disappointed as you
                                have been these many years. The Shakers as a body, come nearer the teachings of Christ
                                in practice than any other society that pretends to be his followers, they are inlklel
                                to all other religions; once they were a very progressive people, but after a while they
                                became somewhat bigoted like other sects, thought they had all the truth there was to be
                                had and became fossilized in this belief, It acted like a nar- <pb n="82" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 82
                                THE MANIFESTO. cotic that stupifies, and as it is one of the laws of nature that nothing
                                can stand still, it has either to progress or go back from whence it came, so naturally
                                the Shakers began to retrograde. Each and every one has to fight his own battle and be
                                responsible for all his short comings ; there is no escaping it, so it behooves us all
                                that have started in the true and heavenly way to ever be loyal to this beautiful
                                spiritual cause. All that are strong in this blessed way of truth and justice can, from
                                time to time, say some kindly word to those who are more easily discouraged ; we can not
                                conceive what good it will do. There is a wonderful power in a word kindly expressed.
                                Let every one who has the good cause of truth and righteousness in heart make it
                                manifest in his own way, not in some one's else way, for if you attempt to, you will
                                invariably make a failure. Let all strive to make heaven here and now, while on earth,
                                not put it off for some future imaginary heaven. My motto is, to be good and to do good,
                                not under fear of a future punishment by a revengeful God, or any expectation of a
                                future reward by the same God for my good deeds done here, but because it is right to be
                                good and to do good, for the happiness it gives now, and the reward which is always with
                                me when I am being and doing good. This happiness and reward no one can take from me. If
                                I am faithful and true to my honest conviction to the end, my reward will be with me
                                through all eternity. With these few scattering remarks I remain your brother in the
                                cause of righteousness, truth and justice.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Emery, Simon" TEIform="persName"/>Simon Emery.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New year's thoughts" TEIform="index"/>NEW YEAR'S THOUGHTS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Baxter, George H." TEIform="persName"/>By George H. Baxter.</byline><p TEIform="p">HT IKE the sweet hosannas of the merry chimes that fill the air with meloI J dy so are the
                            pleasant New Year's salutations, cheering weary hearts and making many a home circle
                            brighter by its advent. What a powerful influence is born with the sincere heart salute of
                            good cheer my sister, my brother or my friend. What a simple gift, yet how fraught with glad
                            meaning when uttered to the weary, faltering soul wavering between the former resolution to
                            patiently continue in well-doing, or sacrifice upon the altar of that innate natural craving
                            for ease and self-aggrandizement. Let each annual season herald its cheery signals. Let the
                            cold philosophy capped with egotism that would criticise its beneficial results, pass
                            beneath the sod of forgetfulness, while the lives of all mankind are brightened by the sunny
                            ray of Christian kindness and brotherly love. This year, like all that have preceded it,
                            will no doubt bring its train of victories and failures, each day being rife with its joys
                            and its sorrows; and <pb n="83" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 83 we must walk in life's path as
                            we find it, resolved to "stand as the oak midst the tempest and storm ;" sacrificing at no
                            shrine save that of honor and truth. Oh, for the heart that is pure and free, daring all
                            things, bearing all things for the truth's sake. Well may we ask at the opening of the
                            present year, what has the past yielded? Have not the unselfish acts of kindness borne the
                            legitimate fruits of blessedness and soul justification ? Do we not value the increasing
                            wisdom that gives power to resist evil and rise superior to every temptation of the
                            adversary that beckons us to partake of those pleasures that detract from the spirit the
                            priceless gem of self-respect? Great must be the joy of that soul who is able to truthfully
                            exclaim, "I know that Christ my Savior lives, I feel his power to-day." This assurance gives
                            renewed strength of purpose, making every duty to yield profitable results, while the mind
                            is filled with that peace which passes human understanding. Who shall say there is nothing
                            new under the sun when we are constantly receiving new inspirations, new truths and new
                            light to guide our souls heavenward. Shall the good old story of God's great love to man be
                            forgotten? Shall we cherish less our brother's happiness and soul growth than we do our pet
                            ideas and theories, that to the progressed mind and unprejudiced thinker may be even marked
                            in their unreasonableness and inefficiency to meet the demands of the present generation ?
                            Is it in accordance with the life of Christ to become merely as echoes of the religion of
                            past ages, trusting for salvation in the merits of those who gave their lives and all they
                            possessed to lay the foundation of our Church of to-day ? or shall we join hands with those
                            whose motto is "onward and upward" and whose voices unite in singing, "Ever changing, ever
                            aiming toward a higher, better life, Ever learning, ever earning is the good Believer's
                            strife." Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I looked above, beyond, around..." TEIform="index"/>
                            I looked above, beyond, around...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">I looked above, beyond, around To find love's blossoms sweet, I looked again, when lo, I
                            found Them lying at my feet. I stooped to gather when I thought How oft we look afar For
                            blessings that are nearest home, For joys that dearest are.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., S. J." TEIform="persName"/>S. J. B.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="As the sculptor chisels..." TEIform="index"/>
                            As the sculptor chisels...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">As the sculptor chisels and polishes the marble in order to express his ideal; and the poet
                            gives the beauty of his dreams in word pictures ; so we must labor to express to others, the
                            dignity of our inner self.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="L., A." TEIform="persName"/>A. L.</byline></div2><pb n="84" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Righteousness" TEIform="index"/>RIGHTEOUSNESS. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">THE necessity of great and constant care is apparent in the continuance of any system that
                            may have been inaugurated through the labors of interested and active minds for the
                            promulgation of peace and prosperity of any of the family of man. Too much direct interest
                            can not be exercised in holding all these temporal and spiritual blessings to an honorable
                            standard, as it is a work that has already been planned for successful consummation. One
                            writer in illustrating this very vital subject presents the case in a light so clearly that
                            no doubts need be entertained. "It only takes a few years to change the character of a
                            church. If the converted men and women die off, and unconverted persons come in, or grow up,
                            in a little while new methods and means are used, new results are sought, and the old paths
                            of peace and blessing are neglected." Whatever the treasure may be that has been obtained by
                            earnest and consecrated labors, it becomes of corresponding value to the effort that has
                            been made in reaching it. Treasures on earth or in heaven are held securely only by constant
                            vigilance. If worldly riches have been obtained and the possessor fails to place them behind
                            bars of iron or within walls of stone, they may at any moment "take to themselves wings and
                            fly away," while the inestimable treasures of the kingdom of righteousness, which the hand
                            of a heavenly Father so kindly bestows upon his children, may through neglect of care become
                            motheaten, or ruinously consumed by rust. For the obtaining of only an earthly interest we
                            are told that a man will sell all that he own?, that he may buy a field in which to dig, and
                            possibly in which he anticipates the finding of a precious pearl, and should he be as
                            determined in securing the promise of everlasting life, he will as a resolute soldier of the
                            cross of Christ, valiantly fight the "good fight of faith." Neither the earthly nor the
                            spiritual man can be assured of final success unless he works with untiring zeal to build
                            and to hold what may be acquired. For us the foundation has been laid, and "other foundation
                            can no man lay, than that is laid, which is Jesus the Christ."1 Cor. iii., 11. The master
                            workman was baptized into the divine spirit of his holy mission, and sacrificed his whole
                            life that his followers might be led into paths of righteousness and peace. Our Mother Ann
                            Lee did no less. She gave herself no rest, day nor <pb n="85" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 85
                            night till she became assured that her mission of the love of God was in the ascendency, and
                            that her life work was under the direct blessing of our heavenly Father and Mother. The
                            Elders who were engaged in the same work of regeneration with Mother Ann, and were baptized
                            into the same spirit of practical righteousness, as was Jesus the Christ, worked with
                            untiring energy to establish the gospel work in the hearts of the children of men. Like the
                            disciples of Jesus, they had left all and entered into the narrow way that they might be
                            able to attain unto eternal life. Their testimony was against the sins of the world, and
                            clothed as they were with the "whole armor of God," they were assured of a full victory over
                            all that was wrong. These pioneers of the gospel work made the divine life as preached by
                            the Christ, their life, and a power accompanied their word which carried conviction to the
                            soul. Let your light shine, said Jesus, and these anointed workers in the cause of truth did
                            let their light shine, and they were abundantly blessed of God in their temporal prosperity.
                            Their faithful labors in the house and on the farm not only afforded them a sufficiency for
                            all their daily needs, but enabled them to help those who were less fortunate. Agreeably to
                            the advice of Mother Ann, they gave their hands to honest and industrious toil, and at the
                            same time consecrated their souls and all that they possessed to the work into which God had
                            called them. A practical righteousness was their theme for inspiration, whether engaged in
                            their daily avocations or assembled for the worship of God, the same spirit of devotion was
                            manifested, which secured to them a fullness of all the blessings which God had promised to
                            the faithful soul. Through this a beautiful inheritance was obtained in the land, and the
                            same has passed into our charge for faithful care and protection. If a continual
                            consecration is the life of the gospel work ; then there is in this a bright hope for the
                            future. Shall we say there is now less need of constant care in the bearing of the cross of
                            Christ ? less need of a full consecration before God? less need of a baptism into the holy
                            spirit, then we may as well say that we have gone from the "middle of the King's highway,"
                            and have left the path of uprightness for conditions that are more congenial to the spirit
                            of the world. The same warning that was given to the Churches by the Revelator, may with
                            equal propriety be given to the churches of to-day, and a careful inspection may readily
                            determine the position that each one occupies.</p></div2><pb n="86" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Best gifts" TEIform="index"/>BEST GIFTS.</head><p TEIform="p">ilThey that turn many to righteousness shall shine as the stars forever and ever."Dan. xii.,
                            3. Canterbury, N. H. 1892. Fairer than rubies and richer than gold, Are the gems of Christ's
                            kingdom I see, Wisdom for service, and pow'r to uphold Are gifts most attractive to me.
                            Clothe and bedeck me with beauty and grace To win precious souls to God's way; To lead in
                            the light of his glorious face, His will all my life shall bear sway.</p></div2><pb n="87" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. APRIL, 1895. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All communications should
                            be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. TERMS. One copy per year,
                            postage paid .75 " " six months, " " .40</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. - February. Thermometer. Rain. Snow. 1894. 23.30 &gt;4
                                in. 25 in. 1895. 20.18 0 " 24 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 52 above 0 Lowest " " " "
                                18 below Number of rainy days " " 0 " " snowy " " " 8 " " clear " " " 11 " " cloudy " "
                                " 9 C. G. Heed. March, 1895. Surely we need but a short measure to encircle the years.
                                The months pass by so rapidly, that unless some important event is inscribed thereon, we
                                hardly note their passage. Would it not be a grand idea to have every month dedicated to
                                some particular virtue; we could thereby note our prog ress in each as the years go by.
                                In November we are called each year to measure our blessings and our corresponding
                                gratitude. December is imbued with an intuitive desire to surprise some one into
                                happiness. Then the finer elements of true Christianity seek to be forgiving and
                                forgiven, if anything has created a dissonance where harps should play only the tunes of
                                that sacred love which characterizes the true disciple of the Prince of Peace. And again
                                December being the close of the year, every progressive mind seeks to square their
                                accounts with God, and man, that the New Year may have no debts carried over to mar its
                                pages. January comes with its earnest appeal to make a better record than ever before,
                                and each year we earnestly hope that our. pathway is in spiral form around the mound of
                                time, that at every round we may find ourselves a little nearer the goal of perfection
                                which we hope to find at its summit. We have thus a distinctive aim for three months,
                                and when the other nine are equally blest we shall more readily mark our progress. At
                                our present writing old Father Winter's white wig still covers his head, nor does it
                                seem likely to be suddenly remov ed, since it is added thereto every few days. Last year
                                at this date the bluebirds and robins were with us; but we shall not look for an early
                                spring this year as the excessive and extensive cold has so frozen the Northern lakes
                                and rivers, that the winds blowing over them will for some time yet keep our temperature
                                wintry like. But the tedium of a long cold winter is enlivened by pleasant tidings from
                                "The Land of Flowers," which some of our Brethren have visited and where some still
                                remain. It is pleasant to know that we are peeping over the horizon into something new,
                                even if it is a venture. "Nothing venture, nothing have." It is also pleasant to realize
                                as we do in our Society, that the foundation principles of our spiritual home are so
                                firmly built upon, that when authorized by the <pb n="88" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                                leading powers, we can change either in dress or location, and our faith and works
                                remain the same. Plainness and neatness in dress become us as a modest spiritual people,
                                and we have long since learned that when we all move in unison, and work for the highest
                                good, we shall conscientiously measure our time and strength, that we rob not ourselves
                                of mental and spiritual growth, for custom's sake; then we shall as surely drop all that
                                is useless and cumbersome, either in dress or habit, as the beautiful plant drops its
                                old leaves for a new growth when placed in richer soil. Amelia J. Culver. North Family.
                                March, 1895. Theee seems to be little that is newsy to communicate at present, for all
                                through the winter season we of necessity keep the even tenor of our way, at peace with
                                the righteous. According to arrangement, the missionary meeting was held Feb. ltth at
                                Unity Church, Pittsfield, and was largely attended. It was reported that those who
                                sought admission, and found none, far exceeded those in the edifice. The speaking was
                                according to the gospel of Christ, and the singing pleased the audience, what more could
                                be asked? After the service the Pastor invited us to a lunch in the Church parlors; and
                                then came the long, midnight ride through valley and over mountain to our home and
                                cherished friends who waited to bid us good morning. Such was the sowing, what will the
                                harvest be? We have made very few converts this season but those who come seem to desire
                                the Christ life; it is better to gradually build up our homes with prepared souls than
                                to receive large numbers who steal the children's bread and go away unthankful. The
                                Florida fever has not yet reached the North family and we hope it will not, for we would
                                not know where to find a physican to cure it. There is a majesty in Mt. Lebanon not to
                                be found in the sand beds of the south; and our lovely village is truly a city set on a
                                hill that will not be hidden when the next spiritual revelation comes to humanity, then
                                should the call reach us to go and found homes for souls in distant climes how gladly
                                would the humblest worker in the Cause respond to the summons. In the outer order, that
                                which is natural is first, and if there is anything spiritual it follows, but we must
                                "seek first the Kingdom of God and his righteousness" and all blessings will follow as a
                                consequence. It is but reasonable that where the Jewish law is disregarded, as it
                                certainly is in most Gentile countries, the land must become exhausted as it has to a
                                great extent in our. northern homes, and the expense of fertilization is enormous; we
                                also venture to think that where any organization long abides; the tendency is toward
                                conservatism and inertia, which conditions are the cause of many spiritual deaths; but
                                as a people there is more to keep us alive than there is to kill us, and more to
                                encourage than to make afraid. We believe that new homes will be founded, but spiritual
                                life will alone make them secure. The trend of progressive thought is westward, and with
                                prophetic vision we see that souls will be gathered there who will desire the
                                ministrations of the gospel. In the mean time we will watch and pray, fervently trusting
                                in God, that he will give unto us the work of the future. The health of our family has
                                been remarkably good, in fact we have not had time to be sick, for with shirts and fine
                                lawn and calico waists to make, the sewing machines are kept buzzing. The work is clean
                                and light, but like all who stuggle under the competitive system, we must work hard.
                                Besides the sale work which is done by the Sisters, the kitchen and dairy must be tended
                                with willing hands, and the tailoring and dressmaking must be carried on, for while we
                                work we wear. The Brethren find plenty to do in making the home comfortable, and spare
                                no service in their power to render, Breth88 <pb n="89" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 89 ren
                                and Sisters living together in honesty and purity, sharing all the burdens of life
                                equally is certainly a household to be wondered at, and amid the wranglings of people in
                                office and out we live }n undisputed happiness. The behavior of the last Congress was
                                enough to disgust any sensible person. The shaking work is needed and if any one is in
                                doubt on this subject a few books like "Progress and Poverty," "Wealth Against
                                Commonwealth," or "Civilization's Inferno," will soon place them in the light of truth.
                                The world is sorely in need of salvation. It is very pleasing to read the Home Notes
                                from our loved ones far away, for we become acquainted with those whom we may never meet
                                yet are 'dear to us through bonds of faith. We need to encourage one another for the
                                times are growing troubled; still the masses do the bidding of the classes, and the
                                mills of toil grind hard, but the new time is approaching when all shall brothers be.
                                Cora C. Vinneo.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Maxell, 1895. The open winter that wejthought might be probable from the indications in
                                the early past of the season, was just a "little ways off." We have had our share of
                                snow, and blizzards that have piled it up in promiscuous heaps, and in other places left
                                the ground bare and exposed, but at present date, the 8th inst. there does not seem to
                                be much visible indication of balmy spring; but we will wait with hope, knowing full
                                well that it will come, that the promise of seed time and harvest can not fail. It
                                should move a heart even of stone with sympathy, in reading of the awful destitution in
                                some parts of the west; and many times in partaking of our bountiful repasts we feel
                                rebuked for not having that deep sense of gratitude for these blessings that we should.
                                When we read testimonies from such veterans as Elder John Whiteley, it gives us courage;
                                but, "as the Ancients of the City pass away, who will keep the testimony burning
                                bright?" Whatever the temporal circumstances or what the tribulation we past through,
                                every one who loves the cause and gives" it support, can lift up their heads and
                                rejoice, and sing praises to the God of their salvation; for the testimony of the higher
                                life has gone forth, and is being received in honest hearts by those who are weary of
                                the elements of the world, and are yearning in spirit for the ministrations of the
                                higher life. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">March, 1895. We have been favored this winter with an abundance of snow. As we look
                                around we behold large drifts, small drifts and medium sized drifts; to the right of us,
                                to the left of us, before and behind; but between the banks of snow, and off on the
                                hillsides, the brown earth is struggling for supremacy. The crows are occasionally seen,
                                and are heard giving hoarse messages to each other; soon we shall have the robins and
                                bluebirds with us. Other signs of returning spring are evident. The children who have so
                                enjoyed the snow the past cold months, are even now planning for the little plot of
                                ground they call their garden, and which if we may judge by their confident talk, will
                                by and by shine with wonders of the floral kingdom. Though it will be some time before
                                their little fingers can even plant the seeds, why dampen the ardor of their innocent
                                hearts. Our homes would be dull without their bright faces and cheerful voices, and much
                                would we miss their willing hands and feet. We had the pleasure of a short call from
                                Elder George Wilcox, of Shaker Station, on the 27th ult. We are always glad to welcome
                                our gospel kindred, especially the aged fathers and mothers, of whom we have so few in
                                our own home. The value of those who have grown to old age among Believers, allowing the
                                gospel to <pb n="90" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 90 THE MANIFESTO. exert full influence over their lives,
                                can hardly be estimated, but they are honored by many who are not willing to go and do
                                likewise. Emoretta Belden.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct.</head><p TEIform="p">March, 1895. "Work while the day lasts." This is wise counsel. Nothing truly noble is
                                gained without work; persistent, patient, per. severing work. In the race for eternal
                                life self-denying work is sure to win and good efforts will not go unrewarded. Cross,
                                bearing yields good results. Time is always on the wing, and it is a sad mistake to let
                                it pass without wisely improving the golden opportunities. We should discipline, train
                                and develop the moral and spiritual faculties. "Let us so number our days that we may
                                apply our hearts unto wisdom." Conscience bids vis be watchful and wary. A good way to
                                remove discourage" ment is to belittle our troubles. A virtuous character is the "one
                                thing needful." Let us do better than we have ever done before; accomplish more for the
                                benefit of lost humanity and grow to a fuller, spiritual stature, that when our earthly
                                pilgrimage is ended, we may be able to say in the language of our great Exemplar, "I
                                have finished the work thou gavest me to do." "The first Thanksgiving proclamation that
                                was ever printed was issued in 1677, and a copy of it is in the collection of the
                                Massachusetts State Historical Society." "In China the hands of the clock stand still
                                while the dials are made to move round." "The Chinese read from the bottom of the page
                                up." "The first newspaper advertisement appeared in 1652." "The first steel pen was made
                                in 1830.'' ******* Poultry should not be fed, day after day, on the same food. They will
                                eat nearly all kinds of food and there is no reason why their tastes should not be
                                consulted, especially as they thrive best on a varied diet. While chickens are young and
                                growing, the albuminoids and nitrogenous foods should be fed largely to promote the
                                growth of flesh, muscle, bone and feathers. Three weeks before marketing, cracked corn
                                and corn meal are best. All soft feed given to poultry should be salted about as much as
                                the same amount would be for human use, and if this is done they will not eat salt to
                                excess if they are allowed to run where they can get it. It is a common mistake that
                                salt is fatal to poultry. Daniel Orcutt. South Family. March, 1895. Winter is beginning
                                to weaken, and the glad spring-time is giving signs of awakening, and gladdens our
                                hearts with promise, after a cold and severe winter, to which we cheerfully bid adieu.
                                The snow has been so plentiful as to obstruct the roads and delay traveling in this
                                section as elsewhere. Now lumbering and repairing are going on. A barn for straw has
                                been removed from an out-lot and is being re-erected at home. An additional amount of
                                ice has been secured this season for the creamery; 3668 spaces of cream in January.
                                Colds and coughs prevail in our vicinity. Where premises are infested with rats, get one
                                of the improved wire cage rat traps. They do thorough work. One morning we found the
                                cage full, eleven having been caught and nearly all large ones. They have been very
                                distructive in our home this winter and we trie,d every known means to exterminate them
                                without, avail, until we found this trap. The past four months a school has been kept at
                                home for our girls and they are improving with constant teaching for we strive to give
                                them an education that will be sufficient to meet the burdens of life. They are often
                                admonished that time and youth, are going, never to return. We can not be too earnest to
                                improve the <pb n="91" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 91 present, and gain those treasures
                                which are lasting for "Time, time is passing, my work is not clone, A nd I must be
                                hastening to my future home. My comfort and glory, my happiness there, Depend on my
                                labor, my faithfulness here." Maria Witham.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">March, 1895. Another month has fled, with its record of good or ill, its duties done or
                                unfulfilled. But one thing is certain, Feb. has very nearly fulfilled its forecast for
                                it gave us the severest storm of the seaon. It compares very unfavorably with a year
                                ago. Then we were making maple sugar and honey. Now the snow is deep, and more is
                                falling; the mercury low and no signs of spring. Such inclemency is enough to make one
                                dream of Florida, or some other genial climate. Br. Andrew gives us glowing accounts of
                                their Florida place. We hope it will prove as disirable as he anticipates, and may
                                prosperity attend the movement. Accounts of Florida are as varied as the people who go
                                there. Those who have prospected the state say some parts are fine, others worthless.
                                Feb. 24th our good Br. Ezra B. Newton celebrated his centennial birthday. He had many
                                relatives come to see him, also five reporters. In the afternoon we had a spiritual
                                service, attended by about forty of the towns-people. Wood is being housed as fast as
                                weather permits, that all may be in readiness for spring work. According to an old
                                saying the prospect for a fruit crop is small. "A snowy March, no fruit; but a dry,
                                dusty March, plenty of fruit." We hope for a bountiful harvest from the farm to
                                replenish our loss of last fall. When we hear reports from Newfoundland and Nebraska, we
                                feel our hearts overflow with sympathy for the sufferers with thanksgiving that our
                                condition is no worse. Marcia M. Bullard.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>-Alfred., Me.</head><p TEIform="p">March, 1895. "The stormy March has come at last," and with it bacteria which affects the
                                head and lungs of our people. I wonder if we should be troubled with bacteria down in
                                Florida. The zero weather we have does not freeze them, and I do not think the torrid
                                weather of Florida would roast them. By an article in the last Manifesto I learn they
                                have mosquitoes, flies and fleas, there. We have flies, and a few mosquitoes but no
                                fleas. I think we will be content awhile longer to live in Maine. The few warm days of
                                the past week remind us that spring will soon be with us, and gladly will we welcome it,
                                for the winter has been a cold and disagreeable one. The busy hum of the saw tells us
                                that next year's supply of wood is beingprepared, and so the seasons come and go, taking
                                our lives with them. Do we so live that we have no desire to recall the days that are
                                past, that we may improve them better? If so it is well with us. We have pledged our
                                lives to perfect consecration to God. Soul and body, time and talents, all that we have,
                                and all that we are to his service. What a great and noble work Do we daily and hourly
                                live to this pledge, or do we let self and self-interests govern? May we remember the
                                great profession we make and live according thereto. Fannie Casey.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant Hill, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hill, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">March, 1895. Beloved Elder Henry;Though we have been hovering about the frigid zone for
                                the last two months, we would not have you think that we are wholly lost in the
                                icebergs. Nay, dear friends, your little paper coming to us each month, so charged and
                                recharged with glowing messages of divine love, intelligence, and progressive ideas,
                                that our mental faculties are sharing the blessings of life. Until the 25th of last Dec.
                                we had very pleasant weather, with no snow. From <pb n="92" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                                that day uutil the 8th of March we had twenty-two days that snow fell in our village.
                                Some days from half an inch to nine inches, and the mercury fell once to sixteen deg.
                                below zero, and once to ten deg. Such continued cold weather was never before known. The
                                past ten days have raised our hopes and we are at last enjoying the sunshine and showers
                                of the incoming spring. The bursting buds and verdant fields proclaim our freedom from
                                freeze-land. How we enjoy the inspirational talks in The Manifesto. Such a vast
                                relationship of one faith, one spirit and one interest in the glorious work of soul
                                elevation. Such a confidence in the Lord, such a faith of purity, and charity for the
                                weak and fallen. How vividly do the testimonies of the present writers for The Manifesto
                                bring the first Believers before us. Oh those were halcyon days, the effect of obedience
                                to the pure gospel of Christ. We prize the Monthly messenger, so fraught with truth,
                                love and unselfishness. "O selfishness, thou deadly foe to union and progress. Thou
                                destroyest long tried friends and makest desolate many homes." We congratulate the
                                beloved friends of Mt. Lebanon, in their progressive move. To leave the barren hills and
                                mountains, and enter a land of sunshine and flowers, where fruits and vegetation abound.
                                What if they do find some flies, fleas, mosquitoes and snakes, have we not some of them
                                here with us? And are they not found at the north? Life is too short to remain idle. We
                                are not placed upon the earth simply to earn our daily bread and clothe our bodies, but
                                to make the earth a little better for having been on it. Something seems to be
                                saying,"Up and be doing, morally, mentally, physically and spiritually. Our life battles
                                will soon be ended. May we leave some little token or foot-print be. hind us, that will
                                give courage to a poor faltering pilgrim, if no more. May heaven's blessing go with the
                                prospectors who have gone south, and to those who may go to meet them. Nancy L.
                            Roupee.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes from Florida" TEIform="index"/>Notes from Florida.</head><p TEIform="p">March, 1895. Beloved Elder Henry;Yours of Feb. 21st at hand. You request me to write a
                                letter about the "Land of Promise." It is a hard task for the reason that I have been
                                here but a short time, so I shall attempt to give you a description of the land as I see
                                it. First in regard to Florida. Like all other places it has its advantages and
                                disadvantages. To decide upon these, they must be placed in the balance. The soil is
                                mostly sandy although there are large muck beds along the lakes. The muck is from one to
                                ten feet deep. The timber is mostly yellow pine, or Georgia pine, as some call it. The
                                lakes are not covered with green scum but are as clear as ours in the North and abound
                                with fish, with a sprinkling now and then of alligators. The grass is not like that of
                                the North but rather a coarser quality, and is found in the woodlands, but the palmetto
                                also abounds in timber lands. What will grow in Florida? All vegetables that grow in the
                                North. Corn does grow here though not much has ever been planted. Sugar-cane, oranges,
                                lemons, pine-apples, irish and sweet potatoes. Wheat, oats and rye, I can say but little
                                about, although I saw a field of rye sown for green fodder. Cattle run the whole season
                                and take care of themselves, but better attention would pay inj better results. We have
                                selected a tract of land on which are several lakes, consequently, much muck soil. The
                                rail-road station is about one mile from where we are building a small dwelling, and a
                                proposed rail-road will run on the northern boundary of our land if not through it. We
                                are about seventeen miles from Kissimmee. Our tract is the highest land in this section.
                                As the water from lake Alligator runs north into the Gulf of Mexico and south into the
                                Ocean. You ask about the heat in summer, and of the insects both great and small. As I
                                92 <pb n="93" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 93 have not passed a summer here I am unable to
                                make a statement, but one thing I can say I have not found and that is a snow-bank. I
                                learn while the weather is warm there is always a breeze or most of time. The nights are
                                cool so that there is comfort in having a good rest at night. But just what can be done
                                in Florida time and energy alone can tell. While I am not anticipating a universal move
                                to the "promised land," it might be well to test all locations and hold fast to the
                                best. All things should be well considered and the only way to find out is to try on a
                                small scale, before a rush is made. It would require a little if not a good deal of
                                pioneer work before a large move could be made. But human nature runs to extremes, and
                                some might expect all the benefits of soil, climate and location, in one state, and that
                                state,Florida, without any disadvantages. This would be asking too much. But there are
                                many things in favor of Florida in my humble belief. The Brethren are building a house
                                20x30 for present convenience. Br. Andrew Barrett is an excellent gardener and is taking
                                charge of that department and of the fruit trees, while Br. Henry Hollister who is a
                                carpenter is at work on the cottage. The alligators and snakes have not yet been seen
                                and possibly have faded away. Isaac Anstatt.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Small, Sarah" TEIform="index"/>TRIBUTE To Eldress Sarah Small.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cowen, Jane" TEIform="persName"/>By Jane Cowen.</byline><p TEIform="p">Eldkess Sarah spent seventy-two years of noble service in this Society, being twelve years of
                            age when her mother with several children, embraced the testimony of Christ's Second
                            Appearing, and she remained a faithful pillar in the temple of our God. The mother received
                            faith through the first missionaries who came to this state in the year 1809. Joseph Small
                            who received faith at the same time embraced the gospel and was a faithful member. For
                            nearly half a century Eldress Sarah was engaged in the care and educating of children, for
                            which she showed a marked capacity and fitness, but during the last twenty years of her life
                            she officiated in the capacity of an Eldress. She was tireless in her efforts to support the
                            cause of righteousness and truth, and to implant a living faith in the minds of those who
                            had less experience than herself. She ardently desired above all things that they might come
                            up to the help of the Lord and sustain the cause of truth. She willingly passed to the
                            summer shore to join with kindred spirits. We now bid our dear mother, a loving farewell,
                            with a desire to meet her in the heavenly home, where her purified spirit has gone. When our
                            summons comes to quit all terrestrial scenes we may be prepared for her association. In the
                            language of the prophet, we can but exclaim,"Let me die the death of the righteous, and may
                            my last days be like his." South Union, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reception, at Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>RECEPTION, AT HARVARD, MASS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Greene, Louisa E." TEIform="persName"/>By Louisa E. Greene.</byline><p TEIform="p">Sunday, Feb. 24th, was the one hundredth birthday of Ezra B. Newton, of the Harvard Society
                            of United Believers. He was born in Paxton, Mass. Feb. 24th, 1795. The occasion was
                            celebrated by an assembly of members at the South family of Harvard, of which the aged
                            Brother is a member. The friends from the Society at Shirley attended, also many from the
                            Church family at Harvard. Elder John Whitely of Shirley, presided. Twenty-six of the nearest
                            kindred of Br. Ezra were present, and a large number of friends and neighbors from Ayer,
                            Harvard and Shirley. Many called upon Br. Ezra during the day who were much pleased to see
                            him. Flowers were sent by kindly neighbors and added cheer to the <pb n="94" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 94
                            THE MANIFESTO. reception room by their spiritual influence. Br. Ezra B. Newton is quite a
                            progressive character, and is of Revolutionary lineage. He has lived a progressive life, and
                            labored industriously. He married Sallie Turner, of Holden, Mass. Two children were the
                            fruit of the union, who died many years ago. Ezra, was a kind and affectionate father. He
                            was a consistent Christian and a member of the Baptist Church until the rise of Adventist
                            ideas of the expected coming of the Christ in person, and the speedy dissolution of the
                            material world. This awakened his sensibilities and he saw that he was not living to the
                            highest light, unfolding within his spirit. He soon became conscious of an inward leading
                            toward a people who, forsaking all worldly things, professed to "Take up the cross against
                            the sins of the world." He became convinced that there was no other way for him, and was
                            anxious to induce his com" panion to see and feel as he did. After a long struggle, when he
                            almost seemed on the verge of despair, he became conscious of an audible voice which said,
                            "This is the way walk ye in it." From that moment all hesitation disappeared and he saw
                            clearly the sacrifice that was demanded. He prayed long and earnestly for guidance in the
                            way and his companion seeing his distress and evident sincerity placed no obstacles in his
                            path, and only stipulated that the children should not be taken from her. He entered the
                            Shaker Order in Oct. 1848. According to the rule of the Order in such cases, his property
                            was placed in trust for the support of his family. From that time forth, he never doubted
                            that he had received a direct call from the invisible world, to renounce the worldly
                            generative life, and come into a spiritual and regenerate life of body and spirit. From the
                            beginning of his union with the Order, his whole mind and strength has been given to the
                            support of its tenets His conscientiousness is excessive, often convicting him of sin when
                            his Brethren and Sisters could see no fault. He has had the sense of ministration and
                            guidance from unseen helpers and he has ever held in mind the ruling axiom of the founder of
                            our Society "Hands at work, and heart toward God." This he has always faithfully acted upon,
                            tlrus having had no time for useless regrets for past sacrifices, while many who joined the
                            faith with him, on the same impulsion, fell away from what they had deemed their
                            convictions. He has been true to his sense of an unseen, divine power and secure in the
                            promise that for all sacrifice of earthly things, he would receive an hundred-fold in
                            spiritual attainment. When advanced age rendered it necessary, Sister Catherine Walker cared
                            for him; but after many years, her summons came to "come home," causing him great grief. At
                            almost his last interview with her, she said, "Now be patient and wait until you have passed
                            your one hundredth birthday and then if it be possible I will come for you." This comforted
                            him; and he awaits the fulfillment of that promise with serene hope, yet his health is quite
                            good and he shows no evidence of near dissolution. His life has been well spent and a
                            principle of right maintained in harmony with his highest aspiration. Harvard, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>EXCHANGES.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Teacher's journal" TEIform="index"/>The Teacher's Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Teacher's Journal is published by Rev. J. P. Anstaclt of York, Pa. No 1. of Vol. 22
                                is wholly devoted to the International Sunday School. The Blackboard illustrations are
                                very interesting and instructive, and liberally used in explanation of the lessons. This
                                work is published in the interest of the Lutheran church. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Icarian community" TEIform="index"/>The Icarian Community
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Icarian Community, which
                                is four miles from Corning, Iowa, after an eventful life of forty-seven years will now
                                pass into history. The brotherhood of man is certainly on the ascending scale. On the
                                6th of October last was published No 1. of Vol. I. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Altrurian" TEIform="index"/>The Altrurian
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> "The Altrurian," at Berkeley, Cal.
                                This informs us that on the 16th of Oct. "eighteen adult travelers and eight hopeful
                                younglings" entered their land of promise. To be able to enter this haven of rest a fee
                                    <pb n="95" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFES TO. 95 of $50.00 is demanded, and having an eye to
                                the worldly prosperity of the community makes this initiation fee quite necessary. At
                                present they have the control of 200 acres wellwooded and some rich land for
                                cultivation. The reader of Win. D. Howell's very interesting articles in the
                                Cosmopolitan, of the traveler from Altruria can now he informed of the address of that
                                wonderful man who lived among n, class of people who were interested in the welfare of
                                each other. We shall wish the best of success to this new class of interested laborers,
                                for the good of humanity.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Souvenir" TEIform="index"/>The Souvenir
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Souvenir comes from the Scarritt, Coif legiate Institute, at Neosho, Mo. The whole of
                                the Souvenir is a treasure-house of good gifts, and many carry an appreciative influence
                                for the prosperity of humanity. Moral worth stands in advance of earthly pleasures or
                                Measures. While an interest is being taken in the lands and climate of Florida, it may
                                he interesting to read of the Koreshans who have purchased a large tract of land in Lee,
                                Co., which is about 26 deg. north latitude. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ploughshare and pruning hook" TEIform="index"/>Ploughshare and Pruning
                                Hook
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The writer in the "Ploughshare and Pruning
                                Hook," states that it is the most beautiful climate in the worldIt is some forty miles
                                from a rail-road, but only a few miles from the gulf of Mexico. We hope this new home
                                may prove to be "the promised land," to all who make the pilgrimage, and we shall take a
                                deep interest in their spiritual and temporal prosperity.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religious telescope" TEIform="index"/>The Religious Telescope
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> "The Religious Telescope," is
                                an expo, nent of the faith of the "United Brethren in Christ." It is edited by J. L.
                                Kephart and published in Cincinnati, O. An article in the paper of Feb. 27th, "The
                                Gospel for the Rich,1' is well worthy of close investigation by every Christian.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Acrostic" TEIform="index"/>ACROSTIC.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Elkins, Almira" TEIform="persName"/>By Almira Elklns.</byline><p TEIform="p">Blessed are the pure in heart.Matt, v., 8. JLay not up for yourselves treasures upon
                            earth.Matt, vii., 9. Enter ye in at the strait gate.Matt, vii., 13. Seek ye first the
                            kingdom of God and his righteousness.Matt, vii., 33. Save me, O God, by thy name and judge
                            me by thy strength.Psa. liv., I. Even'so it is not the will of your Father which is in
                            heaven, that one of these little ones should perish.Matt, xviii., 14. 1&gt;raw nigh to God and
                            he will draw nigh to you.James, iv., 8. And this is the promise that he hath promised us
                            even eternal life.John, ii., 25. Return unto thy rest, O my soul: for God hath dealt
                            bountifully withthee.Psa.cxvi., 7. Every good gift and every perfect gift is from
                            above.James, i., 17. Through faith we understand that the worlds were framed by the word of
                            God.Heb: xi. How excellent is thy loving kindness, O God. Psu. xxxvi., 7. Except the Lord
                            build the house,they labor in vain that build it.Psa. exxvii., 1. Poverty and shame be to
                            him that refuseth instruction.Prov. xiii., 18. Understanding is a well-spring of life unto
                            him that hath itiProv. xvi., 22. Rejoice not when thine enemy falleth.Prov. xxiv., 17.
                            Enlarge the place of thy tent, and stretch forth the curtains of thine habitations. Isaiah,
                            liv., 2. En Jewry is God known; his name is great in Israel.Psalms, lxxvi., 1. IVot unto us,
                            O Lord, but unto thy name give glory.Psalms, cxv., 1. Hear my prayer O God, give ear to my
                            supj&gt;lications.Psalms, cxliii., 1. Envy not the oppressor and choose none of his ways.Prov.
                            iii., 31. JL faithful man shall abound with blessings. Prov. xxviii., 20. Righteous art thou
                            Lord when I plead with thee.Jer., xii. 1 The hoary head is a crown of glory if found in the
                            way of righteousness.Prov. xvi., 31 Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The very act of confiding..." TEIform="index"/>
                            The very act of confiding...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"T.He very act of confiding in another takes the poison out of many an offense, enables a man
                            to see his act as others see it, and to take those steps which, if another were concerned,
                            he would at once discern to be the only wise, right, and hopeful method of escape from his
                            offense or his difficulty. He who confides in a faithful friend divides his troubles and
                            doubles his power of resistance and his chances of deliverance."</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The very difficulties of life..." TEIform="index"/>
                            The very difficulties of life...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"The very difficulties of life, of which we are so apt to complain, are converted into the
                            means of that discipline, that self-improvement, which is the great end of life. Let a man's
                            present desires be met and satisfied without any exertion on his part, and he will be
                            content to remain as he is. Progress is the child of struggle, and struggle is the child of
                            difficulty."</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good examples will do more..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Good examples will do more...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Good examples will do more toward the reformation of humanity, than any amount of
                            sermonizing. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="R., B." TEIform="persName"/>B. R.</byline></div2><pb n="96" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>The Ladies' Home Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Dr. Parkhurst's first article to women in The Ladies' Home Journal has proved so popular
                                that the entire huge edition of the magazine was exhausted within ten days, and a second
                                edition of 45,000 copies has heen printed. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of Hygeio-Therapy" TEIform="index"/>
                                Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Journal of Hygeio-Therapy. March. Contents.
                                Medical Science; Phrenology; The Journal; The School; The Law of Cure; Reply of Dr.
                                Murphy; Fomentations; A Sermon by a Layman; Letters from Friends, etc., etc. Dr. T. V.
                                Gifford, Kokomo, Ind. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sunday magazine and day of rest" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Sunday Magazine and Day of Rest
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Through the courtesy of the "International News Company" of New
                                York, we have received a copy of "The Sunday Magazine and Day' of Rest," which is under
                                the Editorial management of Rev. Benjamin Waugh. This number for January 1895 has an
                                interesting and liberal page of contents from many contributors of high standing in the
                                religious world. Many of the articles are liberally and pleasantly illustrated. No one
                                will regret the perusal of this interesting work. Price 10 cts. per copy, or $1.00 per
                                year. Address, The International News Co., 83 and 85 Duane St., N. Y. Borax,200 Best
                                Borax Recipes from 250 different Publications. Pacific Coast Borax Co. San Francisco,
                                Cal. From the Anti-Infidel Library, Edited by II. L. Hastings, 47 Cornhill, Boston,
                                Mass. Spirit Workings in Various Lands; Familiar Spirits; Spiritual Manifestations
                                Explained; The Depths of Satan; Trying the Spirits; Modern Spiritualism; Primitive
                                Christianity. As these little books are in defence of the Gospel, and only cost five
                                cents each, all who love the Gospel should obtain them and be armed in the day of
                                temptation. Success in raising the earliest vegetables or flowers depends in a great
                                measure on planting seeds grown in our own climate here in New England; having become
                                acclimated to our soils and seasons, they are far better for us to plant than seeds
                                obtained from the Southern or Middle States. New England seeds have implanted in them
                                that same rugged, hardy constitution which has so characterized the sons and daughters
                                of New England from the first landing of the pilgrims to the present day. If you will
                                send your address on a postal to O. M. Richardson &amp; Co., Canton, Me., they will
                                send you by return mail a copy of their beautifully illustrated catalogue of seeds,
                                plants, bulbs, seed potatoes etc. FREE. Each catalogue contains a 25c. premium coupon.
                                If you send the names of four of your friends who are the jnost interested in flowers or
                                gardening, they will send you FREE in addition to the catalogue and coupon, a tine
                                novelty in flower seeds. Don't buy seeds that have lain in stores and been carted from
                                place to place for years, but send for the above catalogue, don't put it off, send
                                to-day. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological Journal and Science of Health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health for March, with an interesting
                                phrenograph of the well-known reformer, MrsElizabeth B. Grannis, editor and proprietor
                                of the Christian Union, and president of the National Christian League for the Promotion
                                of Social Purity. It is from a personal examination by the editor, Dr. Beall, and is
                                illustrated by several portraits. Her leading characteristics are carefully analyzed and
                                the elements pointed out which have rendered her influential. "Do Men Gossip? " is an
                                entertaining peep into club life, by Mrs. Jessie M.Holland. Mrs. Charlotte Fowler Wells
                                sketches the life of the Rev. Joel Wakeman, D. D,, a pioneer friend of phrenology. An
                                especially attractive feature is a symposium on "Phrenology and Unfortunate Marriages,"
                                by Otto B. Falme, Mrs Margarette Allen Fitch, and Ward B. Stevens, Ph. D., with comments
                                by the editor. Prof. Nelson Sizer contributes several illustrated pages on "Children,
                                Hard and Easy to Manage," in his vigorous and sprightly style. In the Science of Health
                                department Dr. H. S. Drayton gives timely and instructive opinions on'"Anti-toxine, and
                                the Bacillus of Diphtheria." Dr. A. G. Humphrey writes well on "Mental Diseases." In the
                                editoi'ial columns portrait of the Count de Castellane and Miss. Anna Gould are given,
                                with remarks concerning their conjugal fltness, and the editor expresses some radical
                                views on the relations of the State to the production and prevention of crime. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cosmopolitan" TEIform="index"/>The Cosmopolitan
                            </head><p TEIform="p">TO OUR
                                READERSAny reader of The Cosmopolitan who will do us the favor of securing three yearly
                                subscriptions to the Magazine, at 1.50 each, will receive a copy for one year, free; or,
                                instead! he can have a copy sent to any friend, free, for one year.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Standish, Sarah A." TEIform="index"/>Sarah A. Standish
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Sarah A. Standish at the Church family, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., Feb. 17, 1895. Age 85
                                years, 8 mo. and 17 days. Sister Sarah was a lineal descendant of Miles Standish of
                                Puritanic Mayflower note, and her long and useful life has been characterized by the
                                stui'dy will of her brave ancestors At J. C, 96</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p27"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
with large type  and  on excellent paper.
It contains  130 pages and has
ILLUSTRATIONS
of the Suakees and their
The work gives quite an extended account of the Several SOCIETIES, their
organization and general management.
Price in cloth 75  cts;   in boards 50 cts.
Address   H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
AUTHORIZED RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   0OMMUNITY.
The religious basis of the Order must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individ
ual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
sell our choice and
" " hardy Nursery Stock, and Seed Potatoes, full and complete line. Many varieties can only be obtained through us.
Commission or salary paid weekly, and
promptly. Exclusive and choice of territory given. Don't delay, write at once
for terms.
ALLEN NURSERY CO.
Rochester, N. Y.
Should have the beautiful 3ft-pag:8 Monthly
= XX>USTaATOI> EOM3 JOURS'AX =
BOets. a year.   Sample free.   Agents wanted.
THOBEAS O. HSWVllsr ft SOS.
CHICAGO, ILL.
SOMPQUND CONCENTEATED
SYRUP of SARSAPARILLA,
With 1 oz. Hydeiodatb or Potassa to 12 Bottlei.
PREPARED AT
Sbafcsr Tillage, Merrimach $o., B. $.
This medicine has proved to be most
valuable in the following diseases:
Chronic Inflammation of the Digestive
Organs; Dyspepsia, or Indigestion; Weakness and Sourness of the Stomach; Bheumatism ; Salt Bheum ; Secondary Syphilis ;
Functional Disorders of the Liver ; Chronic
Eruptions of the Skin, and all Scrofulous 
diseases and disorders arising from impurities of the blood. It is also an excelled remedy for the Ei-ysipelas, Asthma,
Dropsy, Dysentery, and Diarrhoea, and
for the complicated diseases of females,
so apt to end in consumption.
Dose.For an adult, a teaspoonful
four or live times a day, with or without
a little water, which may be increased to
a tablespoonful, as best suits the patient.
To guard against counterfeits, observe
the signature of the inventor on each
label and on each wrapper.
HUMAN NATURE
is an illustrated Monthly, now only 50 cts.
per    year,   devoted   to   PHEEN0L0GY,
PHYSIOGNOMY, HEALTH, MEDICAL
& SOCIAL EEPOEM.
Would you like a copy?
Send 5 cts. for Sample to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Francisco, Cal.
Reliable  men   to
WANTED.
<pb n="" id="p28"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
Absolutely Pure.
A cream of tartar  baking  powder
Highest of  all in  leavening strength.
Latest   United States   Government
Food Report.
Royal Bakikg Powder Co.,
106 Wall St., N. Y.
HOW 1 CAME
TO  BK
 SHAKER.
Price 5 cts.
This is a genuine American watch. It is
made for service, and is the best, low priced
watch for the rich man or poor man, or for
their sons or for any one who wants a good
time keeper. It is a work day as well as a
Sunday watch. It has a patent, winding attachment and weighs i)4 oz. It is open face,
with heavy, polished, bevel crystal. For $1.50
we will send the watch, and also a copy of
"The Manifesto" for one year to any address
in theU. S.   Address,
The Manifesto,
East Canterbury, N. H.
I American Bee Journal,
/*
(Established 1861.)
IS Oldest, Largest, Best,
Cheapest and the Only
weekly Bee-Paper in all
America.  32 ppgos. $1.00
& year.   Send for Free Sample.
SI.00 BEE-BOOK FRE3
S, YT. YOKE & CO., 159 Randolph St., Chicago, 111,
SHAKER'S   ANSWER
To THE OFT REPEATED QUESTION,
I "What   will   become   of  the
World, if all become Shakers?"
Price, 10 cts.
A.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>