<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2610" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">26</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><date value="18961001" TEIform="date">October 1896</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">153-168</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="26" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
1896.
A Visit to the
of EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
LLOYD H. CHANDLER. U. S. N
Liberally   Illustrated   with   half   tone
pictures of persons and places.
The Tillage of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the lovliest spots of
w Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price,   15 cts.
Address   H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF TEE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OB1   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
AND
SHAKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the United   Society   of   Believers   in   Christ's
Second Appearing.    Illustrated.
By Giles B. Avery.
Price,  15 cts.
THE SHAKER COVENANT.
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS   OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION    AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
the same time, afford instruction to all inquiring minds.    Price 5  cts. each,  postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
OCTOBER,
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
The September number of Frank Leslie's
Popular Monthly, just out, is a brilliant one.
It is impossible to even mention all of its
special features. A few of these are: "Colonial Dames and their Daughters," by Sally
Nelson Robins, of the Virginia Historical Society, illustrated with many old portraits; the
second paper of Colonel Garnett's description
of General Lee's part in the battle of Gettysburg, forming the eighth article in the Popular Monthly's great Lee Series; "A staff
Officer's Recollections of General Lee," by
Colonel M. V. Moore; "The U. S. Lighthouse
Establishment," by Joanna R. Nicholls, describing the buildings, vessels and buoys in
our waters, and their maintenance, liberally
illustrated; "The Nuremberg of the Mastersingers," by George Willis Bardwell, with
seventeen pictures; "The War in Cuba," by
Frederick A. Ober, giving an account of the
battles and progress of the struggle for independence' with portraits, battle scenes, etc.;
'Signaling on the Battle-field," showing how
messages are transmitted during an engagement. 'Then there are a number of short stories and poems, the conclusion of a serial, an
attractive young folks' department, and oth.
er features.Frank Leslie's Publishing House,
New York.
The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy for August has the seventh chapter of "The Science
of Life," by Dr. Gifford and this treats of the
wonderful state of sleep which is termed the
third ability in life. "The Science of Phrenology," by Ella Young M. D. "Anti Vaccination" receives the attention of A.J.Clausen,
1'h. D. "Phrenological Sketches of Major
Wm. McKinley and Wm. J. Bryan," by Ella
Young, M. D. will be studied with interest.
Other articles will also claim attention. Published by Dr. T. V. Gifford & Co., Kokomo, Ind.
The Pulpit for August has "The Effects of
Atheism and Agnosticism" bv Rev. J. B. Hawthorne, "The Fool" by Rev. Frank DeWitt Tal.
mage. "Praise vs. Flattery" by Rev. S. L.
Krebs. "Christian Position of Women" by
Rev. Wm. H. Leavell. "The Influence of Jesas
Christ in Civilization," by Rev. X. D. Hillis.
"The Parable of the Impossible." by Rev.
George M. Stone," Published by G. Holzapfel,
Fredericksburg, Pa.
The Outlook for August 29th has several
articles beautifully illustrated. The first
written by Col. Frederick D. Grant, has interesting references to Li Hung Chang and
General Grant with some six illustrations.
"Mr. Moody and Nortlrfteld" by H. W. Webb
Peploe of St. Paul's London has nine illustrations. "The Higher Life of St Louis," by Rev.
John   Snyder  has   twenty-five   illustrations.
"The Institutional Church" by Rufus R- Wilson has eleven illustrations. (3. a year.) The
Outlook Co. 13 Astor Place, New York.
The Phrenological Journal for Sept. pub.
lishes the Photographs of Hon. Win. .1. Bryan
and Hon. Arthur Sewall whom Prof. Sizer
has kindly and carefully presented to the
readers of the Journal. "Phrenotypes and side
views" is a lesson of instruction and no less
"Phrenology and Psychology" by John W.
Shull. From the study of uch articles, comes
an appreciation of their value. An interesting reminiscence of Bayard Taylor. Then we
have "Temperament in Hand Writing;" by IT.
S. Drayton M. D. Several other articles w ill
claim the attention of the reader but the illustrated article on '-Child Culture" will rind
many interested readers and thoughtful examiners, Following this comes Table Manners, for Children; The Science of Health, &c,
&c. Fowler & Wells Co., 27 East 21st St. New
York City, N. Y.
Ian Maclaren's new short story, the last he
will write until after his American visit, has
been secured by The Ladies' Home Journal,
for publication in the October and November
issues. It is called "The Minister of St.
Bede's" is said to be in the brightest and
cleverest Maclarenesciue vein. Besides its
charm as a delightful romance, the htory is
said to be notable for the admirable character
that the author has created for the chief personagethe minister of St. Bede's, as a loyal
lover of an hnmble Scotch lassie.
Every one knows of the Young Men's Christian A ssociation; few know the circumstances
of its origin and the magnitude of its work today. The Sunday School Times is enlightening its readers in this matter, from authoritative sources. First, an article by Sir George
Williams, the English founder of the Y. M. C. A told of its inception in the world: another article, by the secretary of Foreign Department,
told of the Association's work around the
world. Subsequent articles will take up other
branches of t)ie ever-spreading work, including the progress it is making among railroad
men.
JOHN 1). WATTLES & CO.
1031 Walnut St.   PhiladelpMa., Pa.
The Pentateuch, its origin and authorship
by IT. L. Hastings, editor of The Christian.
This little work of eighty-four pages abounds
in useful information. Those interested in
the study of the Bible will be much better informed byr a careful perusal of tnis pointed investigation on the Higher criticism. It is
sometimes amusing to see how nice these
worldly wise men are illustrating the Scriptures. "The claims of these critics," sayrs Br.
Hastings, "are astounding, but the testimony
of these experts needs to be tested before we
can believe in their ability."
Published at 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass.--><pb n="153" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes referring to the early history of the shakers in the United States, no. 4" TEIform="index"/>Notes Referring to the Early History of the Shakers in the United States. No. 4.</head><p TEIform="p">SUBSEQUENTLY Father James said, "It is my desire that whenever you are in a room or open a
                            door where people ate kneeling that you kneel with them and not wait for them to rise.
                            Mother Ann taught us to be devoted while in the worship of God. "Labor, when you have a
                            privilege to worship God, to gather of the substance and power of the gospel. When I set out
                            to seek the Lord I gave my whole soul and body to labor for the saving power of God." Mother
                            and the Elders would often repeat, "Holiness becometh God's house forever." I never saw a
                            spirit gift pass unnoticed by Mother. She taught us to look cheerful and be pleasant, that
                            it was not good to be of a sad countenance. She would say, "Be solemn, yet joyful; as having
                            nothing, yet possessing all things." Mother always looked pleasant, and when administering a
                            reproof she wore a sweet and heavenly smile. On one of my visits to the Square House, Mother
                            met me at the door and taking hold of my hand walked with me into several of the rooms, and
                            then into the one where the family was assembled in worship. She spoke not a word, but went
                            to the south door of the Square House and extending her arms to the the south west, she
                            said, "The next opening of the gospel will be in the south west." OCTOBER, <pb n="154" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 154 THE MANIFESTO. Father James who was present said, "I hear the angels
                            singing." Mother asked, "Where do you hear it?" Father James replied, "I hear it in the
                            south west and sometimes it seems very near." At one time when on my way home with one of my
                            companions, we stopped to pick some whortle berries. Mother sent word to us not to pick them
                            on land not owned by Believers, unless we asked permission. When any one presented Mother,
                            or any of the Elders with any gift, tliey would manifest great respect and gratitude. Father
                            James would sometimes pray aloud, when young believers were present, and I supposed it was
                            to teach them to pray and give thanks to God. He seemed to take great delight in the way of
                            God, especially when he could see those who were young growing in spiritual grace. I never
                            saw Mother Ann under any violent operations of the power of God ; she seemed to possess
                            within herself an inexhaustible fountain of that power which she would often communicate to
                            a whole assembly, by singing and gently speaking a few words. Fathers, William and James
                            used to labor in the worship with great power and zeal and administer gifts to others, but
                            Mother Ann's presence, the sound of her voice, or the movement of her hands when under the
                            immediate influence of the Spirit of God, was far more poweiful than the united gifts of all
                            others. She was the supporter of their gifts and the center of their influence. By Jonathan
                            Clark. The first year that I lived at Watervliet, N. Y., we suffered for the want of food as
                            money was very scarce, and the Believers were counselled not to run in debt. Our subsistence
                            was largely on rice and milk. Sometimes we would go to the river and catch some fish and for
                            several months this was the only kind of meat we^were able to procure. Flour was very
                            expensive and we used but little for the making of bread. Our work of planting, haying and
                            sowing of grain was very laborious and through the scarcity of food we became very much
                            emaciated. On the Sabbath our meals were extremely light. Sometimes it was only a bowl of
                            thin porridge and a small piece of cake. When our potatoes had matured sufficiently for the
                            table they were roasted and eaten with milk, and we began to fare better. In this same year
                            there was a famine near Lake George, and the citizens of Albany sent a large donation of
                            flour, grain, beef, pork and other articles of food to the sufferers. Myself and another
                            brother were hired to transport the food to Crown Point. While on the way we called at a
                            small house to obtain some refreshments. We soon learned that a lady and;three children were
                            the occupants, and on making known our business, she told us she had not a mouthful of
                            bread, or meat, or potatoes in her house aijd had not seen any for some months. When we
                            asked her what she lived upon she replied, that when the brier- <pb n="155" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 155 vines began to grow in the spring she gathered the leaves and boiled them and
                            then ate them with milk. We passed on and soon reached our destination. On our return we
                            purchased some grain and some flour for the Believers which was the first that had been
                            purchased during the season. So soon as our crops were harvested we were able to make sales
                            and purchase articles for our own use. God smiled on our labor and the Society began to
                            prosper in temporal and spiritual blessings. Father Joseph Meacham encouraged the Believers
                            to bear their sufferings patiently and to remember that they were engaged in a work for the
                            redemption of souls. ?; (To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Emancipation" TEIform="index"/>THE EMANCIPATION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>By Oliver C. Hampton.</byline><p TEIform="p">IF you find thai fear, sorrow, sickness or pain is standing in your path, and your peace has
                            departed,then seek some retired place, and try to gain perfect silence of spirit, soul and
                            body. Endeavor to consider yoiii'self in the presence of the Father. Do not ruminate,
                            speculate, or evefn reason, only think that you are waiting for restful relieving. Try to
                            penetrate more into the inmost recesses of your being. While you do this try to remain in
                            perfectly passive resignation, without excitement of any kind. Leave for the time, all
                            emotions of sorrow, joy, hope or despair. When you have reached this Divine Inmost of your
                            being, yon will gradually discover the Kingdom of Heaven within you, that Jesus referred to
                            and which he said consisted of righteousness, peace and joy in the Holy Spirit. You will
                            find that the windows of this silent kingdom, open to the Infinite and Eternal; not lovely,
                            but Love itself; not peaceful, but Peace itself. You will find that you have discovered the
                            celestial solitude spoken of by the Judean Shepherd, when he sang,"He that dwelleth in the
                            secret place of the Most High, shall abide under the shadow of the Almighty." You will also
                            find that "Because thou hast made the Lord, (which is my refuge) thy habitation, there shall
                            no evil befall thee, neither shall any plague come nigh thy dwelling. For he shall give his
                            angels charge over thee to keep thee in all thy ways." Whereas you may have been driven this
                            way and that, by effects, and the fluctuations of your environment, here you will find
                            yourself in the calm region of causes, and for the moment, you will find that your troubles
                            have departed and a serene peace has come over you. You will exclaim with the poet, "I will
                            abide in this region serene, With Christ to commune by the rivers of Peace, <pb n="156" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 156 THE MANIFESTO. Where bloom the rich flowers of loveliest sheen, And sorrow
                            forever shall cease." While you can maintain this sweet communion, you shall bid all sorrow,
                            sickness and fear to depart and they will obey yoi. You shall speak the word and it is done;
                            you shall command, and it shall stand fast. But now you will ask, can all this be done at
                            one sitting?I tell you nay, nor by a hundred. But by faith and perseverance, it all can be
                            effectually accomplished. If it be possible to attain, is that not enough? Give it a trial.
                            But you must bring every desire into passive resignation to the All Good. To indulge in
                            anything that contradicts your sense of propriety or reason, in thought word or deed, will
                            be fatal to success All day and all night, must your intentions be to subserve your
                            interest, elevation and betterment. To drink whiskey, take morphine, or indulge in lustful
                            pleasure, will destroy every possible chance of reaching that rest in God, which in the days
                            of adversity you so much long for. Gluttony, anger, jealousy, revenge or impatience, will
                            effectually close the door into this Divine Inmost which Jesus exhorted us to seek. But if
                            you persevere, these will all gradually drop out of your life and depart, leaving you in
                            possession of everlasting peace. Go into this holy Silence and pure stillness say twice a
                            day and remain under the Divine afflatus, say half an hour at one time. Keep it up, do not
                            flinch nor yield to discouragement on account of poor, or slow results, and in process of
                            time you will surely reap if you faint not. I have thus written from the sincerest sympathy
                            with any and all of my fellow-beings, whether friends or foes, and I shall be glad if it may
                            do any of them good. Union Village, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rest in peace" TEIform="index"/>REST IN PEACE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Staples, Florence A." TEIform="persName"/>By Florence A. Staples.</byline><p TEIform="p">[In memory of Sister Emily Offord.] ' Struggling ? ah the strife is ended, And there rests a radiant bow O'er the spirit that has
                            found a glad release; And upon the breath of stillness, Floats there an enchanting song;
                            'Tis the rich enrapturing melody of peace. Through the bright and pearly portals, Leading
                            from death unto life; Golden gates by God's great mercy set ajar; Through the valley dimmed
                            with shadows, Hath a risen spirit passed, To the land of souls which lieth not afar. <pb n="157" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 157 Not afar, our eyes now blinded By the scenes of
                            time and sense, Soon the glory of that blissful land shall see; And our ears dulled by the
                            discords, Of inharmony and strife, There shall list the chords of angel harmony. As the
                            flowers upturn to sunlight, In expectant attitude; Or the lifting of the mists from hill and
                            lea, As the rushing of the streamlets, Coursing towards their native source, There to mingle
                            with the waters of the sea, Turns the spirit ever homeward, Towards its origin divine;
                            Homeward from conflicting scenes of earth below, Where the vision in the valley, And the
                            faith is turned to sight; There far grander possibilities to know. In a life of endless
                            progress, Will the souls unfoldment be ; Love divine the vital energy supplies, While
                            material forms uprising, Reach their Zenith, yield to death, Still the spirit hath a growth
                            which never dies. Deathless sing the rolling ages, In their ceaseless, ceaseless rounds ;
                            Spirit force the vast immensity infills, And the grasses, and the leaflets, And the rocks
                            attest the truth, Graven on the brow of the eternal hills. Life immortal is crowned victor ;
                            By the gate of pearls she stands With the trophies of her conquests nobly won, Though the
                            perishing is smitten, Yet the grave hath brought no sting, For the strife is ended and the
                            race well run. Light, O loved one, greets thy vision Of a fair eternal day, Nearer, nearer
                            drew the bright angelic band ; And, as round the night damps settled, And we bade thee a
                            good night, Angels bade thee welcome in the Morning Land. Canaan, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="158" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our mother is coming" TEIform="index"/>OUR MOTHER IS COMING.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, Julia" TEIform="persName"/>By Julia Russell.</byline><p TEIform="p">Hark ! list to music in the distance now pealing ; All hail! comes the echo in accents most
                            sweet; Be glad 0 ye people, 'tis your day of rejoicing, A Mother is coming her children to
                            greet With the soul-cheering message, not one is forgotten, Your prayers have been heard by
                            our Father above; And your names are enrolled in tae Archives of Heaven As Daughters and
                            Sons of my favor and love. Stand ye fast in the faith which will finally anchor Your souls
                            beyond doubting, earth's trial and pain; You remember through suffering I purchased my
                            freedom From bands more oppressive than slavery's chain. Though the struggle was long, yet I
                            fully determined The foes of my household to conquer and slay; Incessant in prayer through
                            the fiercest of conflict, Sought only the courage my faith to obey. Despised and forsaken of
                            friends once the dearest; I drank my lone cup, meekly blessing the rod; E'en when life was
                            endangered by cruel designers, I feared not their anger, my trust was in God Who had thus
                            far been leading me safe through the mazes ; At times filled my soul with a glory divine;
                            Which ope'd to my vision a grandeur supernal; An earnest of Heaven when the triumph was
                            mine. Thus my work well accomplished; and true to my mission ; Ordained as a Savior, my
                            purpose should be To herald the truth that on earth, had been given The power of salvation
                            all souls to set free. This day bear me witness, who know the full blessing Of the pure
                            testimony I sought for and gained ; Unfurl the bright banner where all may behold it That no
                            longer in darkness and error they reign. Pray often for those in the broad fields of labor
                            Attacking the strongholds of misery and sin; Their cause is all worthy their efforts most
                            blessed, Unyielding their purpose they surely shall win. Then instead of the bramble shall
                            spring up the fir-tree, The waste places smile in their beauty and mirth And the nations
                            shall turn unto God their Creator His house be an honor and praise in the earth. Enfield, N.
                            H.</p></div2><pb n="159" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life in the light" TEIform="index"/>LIFE IN THE LIGHT.</head><p TEIform="p">TT OW very little is correctly known concerning us or our CommuXI nity." We take this remark
                            from the letter of a gospel friend who is in another state on a mission of peace. Shall we
                            not with equal propriety add,How very little we do to extend this much needed correct
                            knowledge of our order. More than one hundred years have already passed since the revelation
                            of the word of God was delegated t-6 mortals by which our Christian order was called out
                            from the elements of the world. Although the publications of the Society in the past, have
                            been very limited, still the record has been sufficiently full to render us ample
                            information in regard to the trials and perils through which our gospel pioneers passed in
                            order to establish our religious home. This has proved to be in the fullness of the term, a
                            haven of rest for soul and body, to many thousands since that day. Indeed, one among the
                            many great blessings is that of a good Christian home, surrounded by the necessary comforts
                            of life and by the daily association of friends who have proved themselves faithful by the
                            cross of Christ. As excellent as this may be it is a greater blessing, by far, to be able to
                            publish the gospel of glad tidings and to verify the truth of our statement by a practical
                            demonstration. If most of the information existing among the masses represents our order in
                            an obscure or false light,then the information in many cases proves very injurious to our
                            Society. Should we not study to modify or wholly change this order of things ? We may be
                            ignorantly and maliciously represented. The effect of these representations upon society is
                            often the same and the influence of the ignoramus or the vile traducer is magical. Our
                            gospel fathers and mothers who have passed on before us were firm and fearless in their
                            testimony against every phase of wrong doing, and yet when their enemies sought to injure
                            them by slanderous reports, it was their custom to bear the stigma in silence. Perhaps it
                            was the most judicious course they could have accepted. At any rate it was their way. As the
                            population of the country increases, so in proportion do silly and designing stories
                            increase in the minds of men and women of corresponding conditions. The age of the Church
                            has thrown into the world many disappointed, disaffected and may be unprincipled persons
                            whose exaggerated reports are often heralded from city to city. All this needs a
                            counteracting influence and an invitation for a closer inspection into the <pb n="160" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 160 THE MANIFESTO. principles which underlie the gospel work, and into the
                            practical lives of those who form the order. To-day we live in a land of publications.
                            Thousands and thousands of printing presses are running day and night, while from ten to
                            twenty thousand impressions of books, pamphlets or papers are thrown out upon the world in
                            one hour. It is emphatically a printing and reading age. Every form of trade, every phase of
                            professional life, and no less every order of religious organization must publish their
                            programme if they wish to be known. Religious bodies, like dealers in merchandise must place
                            before the world what they wish to have accepted, and this should be done from day to day so
                            long as the world stands. This needs an illustration of their forms and ceremonies and the
                            order of the cross under which they live, whether it be of Adam, Moses, Jesus or Paul; and
                            then in all kindness allow the children of this world the privilege of accepting or
                            refusing. To neglect this is to neglect the education of the public mind in those truths
                            which we think so essential to salvation. Those who neglect to make use of this privilege as
                            time passes, may as well fold their arms and brace themselves securely in the corner, as to
                            think of either progress or prosperity. Spurious representations of the cross of Christ may
                            be multiplied and the testimony of eternal life most shamefully adulterated by ambitious and
                            worldly-loving churches. There may be instances where those who know the truth will prefer
                            from sinister motives to speak that which is false, and yet all this does not prove that
                            every person must become unprincipled, or a teacher of error. Indeed it does not. As there
                            ever has been, so we trust there ever may be witnesses for the truth who will fearlessly
                            testify against the sins of the world. If we are in any wise commissioned to this work, does
                            it not follow that our prosperity will be commensurate with our religious interest. The
                            religious and social life of the Shakers should be better known. The rules and regulations
                            which govern their families from day to day; the care which they exercise over each other,
                            and that which is proffered to the children they receive into the Society, and above all,
                            the discipline of the cross of Christ which is the light of life to the order, should be
                            sown broadcast in the world. No rules should be adopted nor any practice admitted of which
                            the Community need be ashamed. As individuals and as Societies we may do. wrong; may fail of
                            reaching that standard of excellence or spiritual growth which becomes the true diciples of
                            Christ, and yet we may and indeed should be willing to <pb n="161" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                            161 be the subjects for a just criticism. Saint Paul said of his brethren, that they even
                            gloried in some things of which honorable men among the Gentiles would be ashamed, and as
                            strange as it may seem the Corinthians as yet, are not all dead. The Christian work is
                            directly and emphatically an individual work. However much men may assist each other by
                            associations in their multiplied business or domestic arrangements, when it comes to the
                            consecrated life of a Christian it must be that of an individual, even to the forsaking of
                            his own life. In this we should be clearly known through our publications ; through the
                            influence of those who have seen and heard the testimony, and through the manifestation of
                            the spirit of God in the moulding of our lives as vessels of honor unto Him.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Blinn.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Day lilies" TEIform="index"/>DAY LILIES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vinneo, Cora" TEIform="persName"/>By Cora Vinneo.</byline><p TEIform="p">Born for a day! and yet so sweet and fair That day seems brighter just to see thee Isloom,
                            And night seems holy just to be thy tomb. God said "exist," and from the virgin air He spun
                            for thee a robe, with matchless care, And in the under darkness and the gloom He struck the
                            wells supplied with rich perfume, And filled thy incense cup with nectar rare. Born for a
                            day! and yet the thoughts that come Stay with us when thy snowy forms are gone, And find a
                            voice when day's harsh voice is dumb. But when the golden sun announces dawn, We look to see
                            thy lovely sisters greet The new-born day with forms and perfume sweet. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We are all prone to keep the level..." TEIform="index"/>We are all prone to keep the level...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">We are all prone to keep the level of those we live with, to repeat their words, and dress
                            our minds, and often our bodies, after their fashion, and hence the spiritless lameness of
                            our character. Our greatest danger is not from the gross, the vulgar, or the licentious, but
                            from the common class of humanity who claim to live a moral life. The mind grows by what it
                            feeds upon, therefore a mental scavenger is, like the scavengers of the earth, low in
                            aspiration, and led and governed by the lower passions.</p></div2><pb n="162" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. OCTOBER, 1896. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the
                            "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all
                            communications to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. One copy one year,
                            postage paid. .50</p></div2><div2 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Muggletonians" TEIform="index"/>THE MUGGLETONIANS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Basting, Louis" TEIform="persName"/>By Louis Basting.</byline><p TEIform="p">When Henry YIII became King of England in 1509 the Catholic church was in complete and almost
                            unquestioned possession of the ecclesiastical establishment. He was himself a devoted
                            member, going so far as to write a book in opposition to some of Luther's doctrines, for
                            which performance the Pope bestowed upon him the title of Defender of the Faith. But later
                            on, dissensions of a personal and a political nature arose between him and Eome, and because
                            he could not have his way in matters and things, he broke with the ancient church. The
                            process of breaking up the old establishment extended over a long period of years, and
                            successful as he was in that enterprise, accomplished almost wholly by brutal force, he
                            failed of supplanting it with a generally accepted system. If he, the former devoted
                            catholic, could deny time-honored doctrines and pronounce new articles of belief, many of
                            his subjects claimed the same right for themselves; if he almost extirpated the catholic
                            form of religion out of England, he and his successors found it impossible to prevent the
                            discussion and debate of points of theology, and the formation of societies based thereupon.
                            Theology and religion was the common topic of controversy everywhere. The great mass of
                            pointed matter related to arguments and disputations of that nature. Very little was there
                            in it of love and duty, of charity and true religion; it was a stormy period of political,
                            social and religious upheaval. It was not at all strange that at that time, when the old
                            landmarks had been swept away, men of much egotism and strong will should make claims for
                            themselves that only wild fanaticism could make and childish credulity would accept. During
                            Oliver Cromwell's rule there were men who claimed to be divinely inspired prophets; who
                            assumed to bless and to curse, to judge and to condemn at will, and asserted that their
                            decisions would stand forever; but they were divided amongst themselves as to who should be
                            the greatest. One Robert Tannye announced himself to be the Lord's High Priest, called to
                            gather the Jews together out of all nations. He also claimed to be able to materialize
                            spirits, saying he often had eight or ten of them at his house, Jeremiah the prophet among
                            them. His pretensions were resisted by Ludovco Muggleton, who gave him thirty days to repent
                            in, at the expiration of which he wrote a sentence of eternal damnation against him as a
                            false prophet. This Tannye and his followers had built a small vessel in which they started
                            for Jerusalem, but as they were all lost at sea it was considered to be a fulfillment of
                            Muggleton's curse, whose fame was therefore much increased. Then there was John Bobbins who
                            posed as the Almighty himself, and was worshipped as such by his followers. Him, Cromwell
                            had imprisoned for blasphemy and Muggleton went to the Bridewell, called him to the window
                            and pronounced a sentence upon him of which the following is a part: ' 'Many have been thy
                            162 TERMS. <pb n="163" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 163 o'rimes, John Robbins; many hast thou
                            deceived and ruined in a multitude of ways; thou gavest them leave to abstain by degrees
                            from all kinds of food; thou didst feed them on windy things, as apples, and other fruit
                            that was windy, and they drank nothing but water; therefore look, what measure thou hast
                            measured unto others we will measure again to thee." Robbins was utterly mastered; he said:
                            "It is finished; the Lord's will be done." He wrote a letter of recantation, was released
                            from prison, and disappeared from public notice. Muggleton and his party were triumphant
                            over the lesser prophets, and they published a book, A Transcendent Spiritual Treatise. He
                            formed no regular congregation; indeed he spoke slightingly of public worship, prayer and
                            praise; he thought it might do for the little men, he had no use for it. He continued to
                            work at the tailor's trade, but was ever ready to meet inquirers, and if he could not subdue
                            them by agreement he would curse them. One Penson engaged in disputation with him, with the
                            result that Muggleton "did pronounce this Penson cursed to all Eternity." The latter, not
                            liking to be treated in this manner "arose and smote the prophet upon his head with both his
                            fists. But it came to pass that this Penson was taken sick immediately after and died within
                            a week, much troubled and tormented in his mind. Then began the children in the streets to
                            cry after Muggleton: "There goes the prophet that d**** people." A motley crowd gathered
                            around him, monomaniacs, astrologers, pranters, scoffers, atheists; all talking, preaching,
                            haranguing, about religion, visions and revelations. The chief article of the Muggletonian
                            theology was that: "God hath a body of his own, as man hath a body of his own; only God's
                            body is spiritual and heavenly, clear as crystal, brighter than the sun, swifter than
                            thought, yet a body." It was also held that the Trinity was composed of God, man and the
                            devil. This brought about a collision with the Quakers, whose conception of the Deity was
                            pantheistic. Fox and five of his ministers held a public discussion in London with Muggleton
                            and his assistant prophet Reeves; it ended in the usual way, Fox and his company were
                            consigned to eternal perdition. Some time afterward the same fate was denounced against a
                            Quaker named Josiah Coles, who was soon removed by death. This aroused the l wrath of young
                            William Penn who thundered out defiance. "Boast not," he says, "thou enemy of God, thou son
                            of perdition, and confederate with the unclean croaking spirits reserved under chains to
                            eternal darkness. I boldly challenge thee with thy six-foot God and all the host of
                            Luciferian spirits, with all your commissions, curses and sentences, to touch and hurt me.
                            And this know, O Muggleton, on you I trample, and to the bottomless pit are you sentenced,
                            from whence you came, and where the endless worm shall gnaw and torture your imaginary
                            soul." Surely, in violence of denunciation the Quakers had nothing to learn from Muggleton,
                            who of course hastened to retaliate to the best of his ability; but it is evident that the
                            former were much worried by the doings of the latter, and many of their publications of that
                            period are directed against him. The prophets were arrested, fined, imprisoned and pilloried
                            quite a number of times. Once when on trial before the Lord Mayor he was told by Muggleton
                            to hold his peace and be silent as became ad* * * * man in the presence of the Lord's
                            prophets. It is stated that the mayor obeyed and said nothing more. Muggleton is described
                            to have been a man of much natural shrewdness, but without sentiment or sympathy, without
                            nerves, staid, stern, fearless, insensible to pain. He worked as a taylor till late in life,
                            and derived a competence from the sale of his books. He never preached, never tried to make
                            converts, never spoke except when spoken to; but when applied to as an oracle then he
                            answered as a god. He was certain that he knew; he knew he <pb n="164" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 164 THE
                            MANIFESTO. was the light. Pleasure! He did not know the meaning of the word. Riches? He had
                            no use for them. Content to pass his days in stubborn rapture he has left it on record that
                            he did not so much mind to be saved as he did to escape being d* * * * He thought that if he
                            could but lie still in the earth it would be as well with him as if he were in eternal
                            happiness ; nor did he care whether he was happy so he was not miserable, whether he went to
                            heaven so he did not go to hellHe died at an old age, and his funeral was attended by two
                            hundred and fifty of his followers. His last words were: "Now hath God sent death unto me."
                            The sect still exists; their latest work, Divine Songs of the Muggletonians, is a book of
                            six hundred and twenty-one pages. West Pittsfield, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. August. Thermometer. Bain. 1895. 68.36 ' 3.875 in.
                                1896. 68.58 4.375 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 92 above 0 Lowest " " " " 44 " "
                                Number of rainy days " " 8 " clear " " " 15 " cloudy" " " 8 C. G. Meed. North Eamily.
                                Sept. 1896. Eldeb Henry :The rolls of Manifes tos, "Brief Exposition," and kind letter
                                in which was the generous offer of a hundred more, were all duly received. Many thanks
                                for the same. "We think with you, the pamphlet excellent for general circulation and
                                shall be very glad to have our missionary fund renewed by such a valuable addition. Have
                                just made up a package of more than a hundred tracts to send to our absent Sister Ada
                                Brown, who has already distributed many among interested friends to whom a more correct
                                and fuller knowledge concerning Believers seems like an unexpected revelation. They
                                censure us as a body of people for not making ourselves better known. We are in receipt
                                of many letters of inquiry from different parts of the country and occasionally from
                                England and Scotland. All of these are answered in part by printed matter which is sent
                                through nearly every mail, in addition to that which visiting friends take with them.
                                Some Manifestos are always in the packages, but when asked to subscribe the usual answer
                                is; "We have already more papers than we can read, what we want is not more reading
                                matter, but an epitome of your rules, customs and general principles." Aside from
                                callers, our visitors' rooms have been occupied most of the summer. We have with us now
                                a Dane, a teacher in a western college, a writer, lecturer and really deep thinker. He
                                says that his intellect is convinced but his heart not sufficiently convicted for him to
                                leave the work in which he is engaged, to become one of our number. He believes he is
                                receiving light which will make his life more useful to others and more acceptable to
                                God. With many thanks for your kind and helpful remembrance of us and with true
                                appreciation of your labors for our precious cause, I remain your gospel Sister.
                                Catherine Allen..</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New york" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">^ortli Family. Sept. 1896. We render thanks to the writer, for the inspiring words of,
                                "When to speak and when to keep silent" in Sept. Manifesto, Such gifts ministered to the
                                soul causes it to feel that life is more than the mere seeking for wealth and social
                                position. Above all of those sordid influences that <pb n="165" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                MANIFESTO. 165 appear to dominate human life there are gifts that minister to the
                                spiritual desires and cause the soul to strive for that passport which will give
                                admittance to that temple where "nothing that defileth or maketh a lie" can enter. We
                                have received leaflets from our Brother Arthur W. Dowe, 948 Mission St. San Francisco,
                                Cal., dealing with the much discussed and long expected "Day of Judgment." The subject
                                is well handled and an intelligent view taken of that important event. They are in a
                                form suitable to circulate in missionary work and all who desire can by application
                                receive them. While reviewing the past season with its hopes and labors, our
                                anticipations in some respects have not been realized; but nevertheless we have many
                                things for which we can render thanksgiving. To those who are lovers of that tropical
                                fruit water melons, we would ask them to try Cole's Early. Of all the varieties that we
                                have tested this has proved the most satisfactory in quality and early growth. The 5th
                                of August we had ripe fruit. We waited very patiently with the hope that the Editor
                                would call around and share with us, but we will be ready when the time comes. Hope we
                                will not be disappointed. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1896. Litekattjre, divested of vulgarity and moral insipidity, is one of the potent
                                factors that inspire mortals to right living. Well may we be led to reflect that human
                                beings are much like novels, being lined with elevating or degrading influences. But
                                should the dots of evil and dashes of greed be left uncorrected? How valuable to society
                                are those "living epistles of righteousness," whose examples intelligently show why
                                virtue pays. Whose life chapters sMne with a godly light; Teaching lessons of truth o'er
                                might; Lessons which tell of the Infinite plan, Heaven, not gained by faith in man; But
                                from the force of spiritual strife, Is found the bliss of Heaven's life. On the evening
                                of August 24th we were entertained by our friend Hon. Thomas Savage of Maplewood, First
                                Lieutenant of the Ancient and Honorable Artillery Co. of Mass. He gave an interesting
                                recital of his trip to England with his fellow company. During the past two months,
                                parties of two and four have been making occasional berry excursions; the results of
                                which have been the securing of twelve bushels of blueberries and about eighteen bushels
                                of blackberries. Twenty barrels of pickles and one ton of beet seed have been prepared
                                for market. Artist Autumn has commenced his grand work of tinting the foliage which
                                helps to make our locality, "Beautiful indeed for habitation." George II. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1896. Months have come and gone since the readers of The Manifesto have heard from
                                us; but do not think we have forgotten the magazine by any means. We welcome its arrival
                                every month and it is more interesting each time. Our flowers have been a source of
                                pleasure and profit this summer. Such lovely sweet peas and asters as have bloomed
                                continually, and even now the vines are full of the beautiful blossoms; and what is
                                better the Poland Spring House is full of guests who admire and purchase our flowers as
                                often as we have time to carry them to the Hotel. This has been a great blessing to us
                                and as a people we are greatly favored. Our fancy work has also found a ready sale. Two
                                very pleasant Sisters from Shirley, Mass., Eldress Lucy Mitchell and Sr. Mary Ann
                                Whiteley are with us on a short visit. We enjoy their company and find the sterling
                                worth that marks the genuine Shaker everywhere. These, Father James <pb n="166" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFES1 0. said, "would shine brighter than the stars in the firmament when
                                called into eternity." We are having an abundance of apples and the evenings at present
                                are occupied by the Brethren and Sisters in cutting the apples and drying them. Plenty
                                of fruit and vegetables but a scarcity of hay, therefore the stock will have to be
                                lessoned before cold weather. Ada S. Cummings.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1896. As we look upon the mountains surrounding our house and note the change of
                                color in the foliage of trees and shrubs, listen to the moaning of the wind, we are
                                reminded that summer will not always last and our thoughts find expression in the poem
                                of Bryant, when he says, "The melancholy days are come, the saddest of the year."
                                Harvest time brings to us its usual round of duties and learning from nature the
                                prudence of storing for necessity, we wisely conclude to be unlike the cricket of whom
                                the school children tell us, who foolishly danced away the summer hours, finding when
                                winter came nothing but an empty store. The crop of hay was secured about the middle of
                                August. After this work was commenced in removing the old palisade, which lay a little
                                south of the Office. Nearly two thousand yards of rock and earth have been taken from
                                this section to a much more desirable place. The ledge of rock was broken by blasting
                                powder and dynamite and then taken to protect fine high embankment at our grain and
                                cattle barn. This makes a good drainage west of the Office, south, through this section.
                                We have often heard of "removing mountains," and this has been accomplished, if by a
                                slower method. Where formerly only a peek from the Office sitting room window only found
                                a mound of earth, now may be seen a broad landscape view extending from the large
                                expanse of meadow land to the railroad and Richmond Lake, a mile and a half in the
                                distance. FiiieHa Estabrook.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">South Family. Sept. 1896. By kind invitation of the Church some of our members spent four
                                days last week gathering cranberries in company with them. All report a great harvest,
                                so we judge from the beautiful clusters brought home as trophies of their work on the
                                mountain. Sunday August 30th Sister Sarah A. Collins and the writer spent at Ocean
                                Grove, a most beautiful and inviting summer resort where are held each day during the
                                summer months revival meetings. Thousands of Gospel workers come here to hold divine
                                communion by the ocean. We attended the Methodist Love Feast in the morning at the Ocean
                                Grove Auditorium. Twelve thousand persons were present to listen to Bishop Mallalieu and
                                Rev. E. H. Stokes earnest and eloquent sermon. The Bishop said, "we will not have the
                                usual passing of bread and wine but we will have something more soulfully profitable;
                                let the whole congregation shake hands one with another and encourage each other to more
                                faithfulness in the service of our Lord." This wras followed by the singing of "Beulah
                                Land" the mammoth assembly waving their handkerchiefs in harmony with the grand and
                                heavenly tune. The scene was strikingly impressive. We were present at the "Salvation
                                Army" or "American Volunteers" meeting held at Asbury Park in the afternoon; Patti
                                Watkins a leader in the army and known as the "Nightingale singer" and a devoted worker
                                in the cause of humanity said to the large audience while the collection was being taken
                                up, "X have never called for a selfish offering; those who give must give freely as
                                giving unto the Lord. Though some of my friends 166 <pb n="167" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                MANIFESTO. 167 pronounce me a beggar I have never ; ; begged for selfish purposes and
                                some say when I die it will be said, "and behold it came to pass the beggar died," but
                                remember "the angels carried her away." Genevieve DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1896. The breath of the Lord has again touched the forests of New England and they
                                are being arrayed in "new robes of beauty." The song birds have all flown to their
                                southern home for the winter, and we sorrow for their departure. The frost line has
                                reached central New Hampshire, and many of the fruits and flowers tell the sad story.
                                The apple crop, although not abundant is much better than last year. The building of
                                another silo, to contain some seventy-five tons speaks favorably of that form of
                                securing food for the stock, during the winter months. Beautiful fields of corn are now
                                being cut down, with a machine, drawn by two or three horses, and taken to the barns to
                                be passed through the "ensilage cutter" before entering the silo. Portions of these
                                beautiful fields of corn had reached the height of fifteen feet, and the ears of corn
                                were higher than the ordinary man could reach. The fairs in the several towns, have been
                                visited by some of our Sisters, with their fancy work, and the sales have been quite
                                satisfactory. Many blessings still rest upon tis. Henry C. Minn.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Physiology of digestion" TEIform="index"/> THE PHYSIOLOGY OF DIGESTION.</head><p TEIform="p">It would seem to any one of common mental caliber, that at the advanced stage of
                                scientific research and investigation that all true scientists and physiologists should
                                have ere this arrived at a perfect agreement and understanding regarding this most
                                important function of human economy. Yet it seems the more investigation and experiment
                                is pushed, the '.; more diversified their opinions and be- /, liefs become regarding the
                                physiological, function of digestion. Nevertheless, however diversified their opinion
                                may be regarding other phases of this function, all practically agree as to the
                                important part the teeth have to perform in triturating and properly masticating the
                                food before deglutition conducts it to the stomach for digestion. Most authors and
                                writers holding that the thorough salivation of nutriment should be had to insure rapid
                                digestion and assimilation. While others equally learned and able in scientific
                                research, holding the antipode of opinion, farther that the greater quantity of fluids
                                taken to rinse down the food the more favorable for rapid digestion and assimilation.
                                Just here the "old saw" comes to one's relief. "When Doctors disagree who shall decide?"
                                I aver that each individual must in this case be the umpire for self, aided by research,
                                experiment and practical experience (one of the best of teachers), though ofttimes at
                                fearful cost! There can be no general or set rule, for all are not constituted alike, as
                                to temperament, constitutional tendency and physical capacity, hence the failure of any
                                such general rule nine cases out of ten. I admit to being a specialist in dental
                                practice for the past thirty-five years. Many and varied have been the cases I have had
                                under hand for diagnosis and treatment; necessarily, hence I can speak advisedly on the
                                paramount importance of properly treating and caring for the human teeth. Without good
                                teeth there can not be thorough mastication. Without thorough mastication there can not
                                be goad digestion. Without perfect digestion there can not be proper assimilation.
                                Without proper assimilation there can not be nutrition. Without nutrition there can not
                                be health. Without health, what is life? Hence the importance of good teeth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hudson, R. N." TEIform="persName"/>R. N. Hudson, D. B. S.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-centered thought and will..." TEIform="index"/>Self-centered thought and will...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Self-centebed thought and will are detrimental to soul expansion.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><pb n="168" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fruits of different kinds..." TEIform="index"/>Fruits of different kinds...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Fruits of different kinds have been used from time immemorial as a desert, but might be
                            better used as a principal dish, and this would do away with many of the condiments. It
                            would be slow progress to learn to relish apples or strawberries or peaches when well
                            besprinkled with mustard or cayenne or showered with salt. I am a firm believer in personal
                            idiosyncracies and individuality. Variety as well as diversity seems to be the order of
                            creation, hence "every one is a law unto himself" and must conform to his environments and
                            climatic efforts as well as personal characteristics to obtain the most advantageous and
                            best results.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Acrostic" TEIform="index"/>AN ACROSTIC.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName"/>By Watson Andrews.</byline><p TEIform="p">Elder Napoleon Brown; what are all king? ILords, dukes, ladies, nay, all earthly things:
                            Dynasties and powers, compared with one Enjoying God's high favor to his Son? Robed in the
                            panoply of righteousness, Weeding no motive but to love and bless. _A_11 in their proper lot
                            and proper sphere, I*rinee, priest, nor potentate can claim him Only the "pure in heart"
                            thus see God, [peer ILove Him alike in nature and his word; Even in all things see God
                            manifestObserves his blessing as he hears him "blest. None but one "horn again" thus sees or
                            hears; IBorn out of self; born out of sordid cares; DEleleased alike from sin and passion's
                            thrall; Onward and upward still his royal call. "What guards of time his interest can claim?
                            None, surely none; nor wealth nor place nor fame. Union Village, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good temper" TEIform="index"/>GOOD TEMPER.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">There, s not a cheaper thing on earth, Nor yet one half so dear; 'Tis worth more
                                    than distinguished birth. Or thousands gained a year. It lends the day a new
                                    delight, 'Tis virtue's firmest shield; And adds more beauty to the night Than all
                                    the stars can yield. It maketh Poverty content, To Sorrow whispers peace; It is a
                                    gift, from heaven sent, For mortals to increase. It meets you with a smile at morn,
                                    It lulls you to repose; A flower for peer and peasant born An everlasting rose. A
                                    charm to banish grief away To snatch the brow from care; Turn tears to smiles, make
                                    dullness gay, Spread gladness everywhere. And yet 'tis sweet as summer dew That gems
                                    the lily's breast; A talisman for love is true As ever man possessed. What may this
                                    wondrous sprit be, With power unheard of before This charm, this bright amenity?
                                    Good Tempernothing more!. Good Temper'tis the choicest gift, That woman homeward
                                    brings, And can the poorest peasant lift To bliss unknown to kings.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Chatterbox" TEIform="index"/>Chatterbox.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The dying words of Albert the Good..." TEIform="index"/>The dying words of Albert the Good...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The dying words of Albert the Good, the husband of Queen Victoria, were "Thank you," for a
                            cup of water he received from his nuise.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="That great friend of humanity..." TEIform="index"/>That great friend of humanity...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">That great friend of humanity Annie Besant always says please or thank you to her hired help
                            when requiring or receiving service.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, A. E." TEIform="persName"/>A. E. Lomas.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A cultured mind..." TEIform="index"/>A cultured mind...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A cultured mind is like a cultivated garden,the result of fine taste, rare skill and careful
                            training.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dunn, William" TEIform="index"/>William Dunn
                            </head><p TEIform="p">William Dunn, at Watervliet, Ohio. Sept. 3, 1896. Age 74 years. He was born in Lester,
                                England, in 1822. United with the Society at North Union, Ohio, in 1875. He moved to
                                Watervliet, Ohio, in 1889. A faithful, worthy member for twenty-one years. J. O. T.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE    MA NIFES TO.
Word and Works for September.The first
chapter is on storms and stars, and the story
of the month is one filled with conditions not
at all inviting. The Rev. Editor might have
taken a rest for a few days as we all know
quite well that September is a month, more or
less of storms. Hut we are advised to look for
"Hurricanes and equatorial cyclones, especially along our southern coasts." In the
north we must look out for "frosts and not
less for storms attended by th mder and
lightning." Word and Works, however, is
not wholly about hurricanes and cyclones.
There is an abundance of good and profitable
reading, on subjects that are in the best interest of humanity. Published by Word and
Worsk  Pub. Co.   2201 Locust St., St. Louis, Mo.
Mount Lebanw Cedar Boughs. Original
Poems by the Xorth Family of Shakers. Cloth,
pp. 31(5. Buffalo; The Peter Paul Book Company. This collection of poems is the product
of a dozen writers, whose names are attached.
It is the easiest of all things to discern glimpses of the inner life of the Shakers, and in the
unfolding one catches the sweetness of :i life
that is incomprehensible to the world at large.
A careful rending of the book will give a bet
ter idea of the integrity and industry, the
peace and plenty, the contentment and the
happiness of the home life than almost any
sketch of modern days. The- spiritual and
mental clearness of their perception, the genial warmth of their lives, the ripples of mirth
that give those lives variety, are all shown in
the choice grouping of these beautiful ex.
presskms. If the three hundred and fifty
poems are to be taken as an inde\, the Shakers in Mount Lebanon are blessed with higher
conditions of happiness to each other, a liner
intellect, more affectionate hearts and clearer
views of truth than sects generally promulgate or enjoy. The verse while it is marked
by simplicity, is far above the average in
merit   in   many   instances.lUnuier   of Litjht.
Humanity is a magazine of Social Ethics.
The publisher says there is no other paper
like it on earth, and I gue.ss he is correct. "It
knows no sect, sex, ism or creed." Some of
the articles are illustrated and this feature
alone would induce any one to purchase a
copy. Published by \Vr. B. Putnam, Kansas
City, Mo.
What is Communism? a narrative of the
Relief Community. This is a book of 424 pages, giving a lull and entertaining explanation
of the principles, organization and practical
details of Community homes, with common
property, united labor, mutual .support, and
equal rights to all, so as to secure much greater wealth, comfort and enjoyment in all the
affairs of life to all the members than can possibly be obtained, in the  ordinary   separate
way of living. It also contains a simple and
practical plan by which Communities may be
established all over the country and consolidated so as to finally and speedily secure the
adoption of common property and united labor by our government, in which every citizen
will be required to work according to his ability for the Community of which he is a member and be supplied thereby with everything
it can afford according to his wants. All who
are interested in improving society in any
way, or who might wish to secure the great
riches and pleasures of a Community home,
for tliemselves, should read it. It will be sent
by mail to any ad.dress, for 50 cts.. by the publisher.A. Longley, 1719 Franklin av., St. Louis,,
Mo.
A SUMMARY VIEW
 CHURCH,
"United   Society   of   Believers,"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price, 50 els.
"INTERPRETING PROPHECY"
"Appearing of Christ,"
is the title of a neat little pamphlet of
some forty pages, just sent out by A. G.
Hollister of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
The many at the present time who are
interested in the fulfillment of prophecy
and in its mathematical calculation, will
find themselves by the side of the good
old prophet Daniel, and with him illustrating the Coming of Christ so clearly
that no occasion can arise for the least
doubt.                             Price, 10 cts.
OF   THE
MILLENNIAL
OR
AND   THE
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
AUTHORISED   RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY.
The religious basis of the Order must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
For Information and free Handbook write to
MUNN & CO., 361 Broadway, New York.
Oldest bureau for securing patents in America.
Every patent taken out by us is brought before
the public by a notice given free of charge in the
Largest circulation of any scientific paper In the
world. Splendidly illustrated. No intelligent
man should be without it. Weekly, jft3 CO a
year; $1.50 six nionths. Address, MUNN & CO,,
Publishers, 361 Broadway, New York City.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cream of  tartar  baking   powder.
Highest of all in leavening strength.
Latest   United   States   Government
Food report.
Eoyal Baking Powder Co., New York.
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
with large type  and on excellent paper.
It contains  130 pages and has
ILLUSTRATI0N8
of the Shakers and their
The work gives quite an extended account of the Several SOCIETIES, their
organization and general management.
Price,  50 cts.
The New York
Dispatch.....
Oldest      and      Best     Recognized
Weekly     Paper     in   the    United
States.
Improved        Management,        and
Methods up to date.
A   Family   Journal
Of Morals and Public Interests,
Newsy, Literary, Scientific,
Humorous, Useful, Entertaining.     Also   G.    A.    B,.,     Masonic
and Society News.
One Copy,  One   Year,   $2.50.
Post yourself on what is going
on in New York.     Address
The  New York  Dispatch
150 Nassau Street, N. Y.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>