<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1304" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">13</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><date value="18830401" TEIform="date">April 1883</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">73-96</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="13" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb n="t.p." id="p1"/>
                    <p> VOL. XIII. APRIL. NO. 4. SHAKER MANIFESTO Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT
                        HARVARD, Mass. "Blessed are those that hear the word of God and keep it." SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H.
                        1883. </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>
                        </head>
                        <p> [Advertisements deleted.] </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="73" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><!--
                    <div2 type="none">
                        <p> The Testimony of Jesus, 73 Supplication, - - - - 75 Dialogue, Xo. 2, - - -  " Needy but Believing, .... - 77
                            Letter of E. Martin. - " The Bible, -..- - - 78 Guard well thy Heart, •- - - 70 Higher Life , - - - - - - "
                            Letter of D. Oucttt, - - - 80 Puhity of Life, - .-.." Life's Object, - - - . - - - 81 Pleasant Recollections, -
                            - - - 82 l8 IT WORTH IT ALL? - - - " "What is Man? - - - - - - - S'S Page. Peacemakers, ...... 84 Our Home,
                            -.- - - " Nothing New, - - -  86 Letter Box, - -..... 87 Kind Words for 1882, - ... " Notes,......... 88
                            Sanitary, -..-..- 89 House and Farm, - - -  80 A Lesson in Law, - - -  92 Nothing to do, - - - School Days,
                            - - - - 93 Music, - - ,- - - - - - 94 Books and I'ai'B', .-.-.. 96 Deaths, - - - Vol. XIII. APRIL, 1883. No. 4.
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Testimony of Jesus" TEIform="index"/> THE TESTIMONY OF JESUS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/> ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "Ye are my friends, if ye do whatsoever I command you." Jesus. Human nature is the same in
                            all ages, and never changes except by culture. Civil, and religious progress is requisite,
                            to up-lift humanity from crude graceless conditions, into higher spheres of thought and
                            action. Hence we see that "history repeats itself." Barbarism exists in many countries at
                            the present time, as really as it ever existed, notwithstanding the world in which we live,
                            has grown olde since the days of yore, if not wiser. Tyranny and oppression, master and
                            slave, are seen wherever the power to execute exists, differing only in form and degree. The
                            cruel war spirit, with all its direful effects, rules in all nations today, in what are
                            called civilized and religious, as well as among the savage tribes of earth. War is wrong,
                            either invasive, or repellent, and the more enlightened and cultivated people become, the
                            more inglorious it is : if more subtle, and carried on under the sanction of what passes by
                            the name of "a Christian Priesthood," the more malevolent and reprehensible it is, because
                            light has dawned upon the world, at least, that portion of it in which they dwell. By the
                            march of civilization, public sentiment is changing in regard to war, capital punishment,
                            and religious persecution. Freedom of conscience is the boast of the nineteenth century. No
                            people have greater cause of thankfulness for religious toleration that exists in America at
                            the present time, than the Shakers ; to it, we owe our existence as a religious organized
                            Body. CONTENTS. <pb n="74" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. The secular arm is outstretched to
                            protect all its law abiding citizens, irrespective of caste, or color, foreign, or home
                            born. Pulpit orators are lenient toward those who hold views differing from their own, on
                            minor points. Civil power may restrain, bind and hold in check ; but the testimony of the
                            baptized Jesus was: "I kill and make alive." Certainly he did not "wound and heal, kill and
                            make alive by the use of carnal weapons, but by spiritual power given him by the Father,
                            which was "the sword"—the testimony of truth, that proceeded out of the mouth of Him who
                            held the seven stars in his right hand." The spirit of persecution, may slumber, and its
                            fires die down for a time ; but unless that "Wicked" is revealed, exposed, by the Christ
                            spirit and is consumed by the testimony of truth, which always accompanies that Spirit, and
                            is "destroyed by the brightness of that coming," there is no permanent safety. When Jesus,
                            the lowly Nazarene, walked among the Jews, he saw and felt that the hearts of the children
                            of men were not changed, that the spirit of persecution was still rife; and that they would
                            "kill and stone the prophets that were sent unto them ;" pile up faggots, light the flame,
                            prepare the rack upon which to torture the saints of that day ; and what they could not
                            otherwise accomplish, would employ wild beasts, a little more savage than themselves, to do
                            for them. xxxx Jesus, feeling all those conditions, among the Jews who stood so stiffly for
                            their Master Moses, and his code of laws, rebuked the Pharisees and pronounced a woe upon
                            them ; while he charged upon them the blood of all the prophets, from Abel to Zacharias ;
                            saying it would be required of that generation : Their fathers killed the prophets, and they
                            built their sepulchres, and were of the same spirit. "Like causes produce like effects" from
                            age to age. Was it a sign that the full testimony that Jesus was sent to bear, was
                            unnecessary, because it was distasteful to the learned Jews ? Or did he flinch from the
                            cross by which he was crucified unto the world, and the world unto him, until he could
                            truthfully say: "The prince of this world cometh, and hath no part in me ?" We know full
                            well, that the natural mind that craves indulgence and pleasure, at the expense of rigid
                            duty, will always reason against the cross of selfdenial that crucifies, instead of
                            gratifying the selfishness and pride of the unregenerate human heart. If we sacrifice in
                            part, our reward will be in part. Did Jesus in his time appeal to the learned men of Greece
                            and Home to follow him? A few humble fishermen were his first disciples. And even the highly
                            cultured Paul, when met in the way by the Holy Spirit was first felled to the ground, and
                            taught a lesson of humility. Not many rich, learned and wise of this world have as yet
                            received the full gospel testimony. In the first, and second appearing of Christ, the call
                            has been to prepared souls. The Spirit and Bride say "Come whosoever will, and are ready." I
                            cannot agree with the Author of the Article headed "Consistency," in the February No. of the
                            "Manifesto" (whoever he or she may be,) "that perfect purity of life is impossible apart
                            from courteous manners, and refined intellect." If purity of life is dependent upon the fine
                            arts, music, painting and flowers, however desirable, and admissi74 <pb n="75" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 75 ble they may be in their time and place, as adjuncts, then were the first
                            founders of our Institution and Order, very deficient in Purity, the foundational principle
                            which they taught, and the basis upon which the structure rests. I must still be allowed to
                            believe, that they were quite as pure in life and character, and possessed as much real
                            integrity and stability, as any of their professed followers in our time, who have a better
                            opportunity for intellectual culture, and less manual labor to perform. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Supplication" TEIform="index"/>SUPPLICATION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Goodrich, Hannah" TEIform="persName"/>BY MOTHER, HANNAH GOODRICH.</byline><p TEIform="p"> [The following hymn was contributed to the Manifesto, by Eldress Anna Ervin, of Enfield, Ct.
                            who has preserv ed it for many years, in loving remembrance of the author.] O Lord of
                            everlasting light, Thy mercy I implore, Protect my spirit in its flight, When time shall be
                            no more. Support me while I drink the cup, With patience clothe my mind; To meekly fill the
                            measure up, Our Parents left behind. In Thee my confidence I trust, In Thee my hope I place,
                            And though a feeble worm of dust, I feel thy power and grace. And while I suffer here on
                            earth, I feel an inward joy, That I can walk the narrow path, Which will all sin destroy.
                            Let murm'rings and all complaints, Escape me never more, But meekly with thy precious
                            saints, This valley I'll explore. Give :ne the patience of a lamb, The meekness of a dove,
                            In resignation meek and calm, I feel our Mother's love. In thisfpoor tenement of clay, The
                            love of God has dwelt, The purest light of gospel day, This feeble heart has felt. I've seen
                            the glory and increase, The gospel spread abroad, The church arise in power and grace, The
                            glorious work of God. I've seen the glory of the lamb, In female form arrayed, Crowned with
                            a royal diadem, By Christ in wisdom led. Who on the Mount of Zion stands, Redeemed from
                            nature's fall, Ordained to keep the sheep and lambs, That God by faith shall call. The
                            gospel path of purity, The Father now has shown, The righteous Prophets could not see, To
                            angels 'twas unknown. What glorious things I have beheld, Beneath the gospel sun, Now let my
                            soul with thanks abound, When time shall cease to run. With Simeon I now can say, Let me
                            depart in peace, Because mine eyes have seen this day, Redemption's work increase. Thy
                            blessed sin-destroying power Through every nerve has run, Now let me in this trying hour,
                            Say, "Lord, thy will be done." Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dialogue no.2" TEIform="index"/> DIALOGUE-NO. 2.</head><p TEIform="p"> B. I wonder why you selected that. It is the very essence of simplicity. I think I could
                            write a much better recipe but I have something that will suit your case just as well.
                            "Believe as I believe, no more no less, That I am right and no one else confess; Feel as I
                            feel; think the same as I think, Eat what I eat; drink only what I drink : Look as I look;
                            do always as I do, Then, only then, I'll fellowship with you. That I am right and always
                            right I know, Because my own convictions tell me so; And to be right is simply this : to be
                            Entirely, in all respects just like me. To deviate one hair's breadth or eyen begin To
                            question, doubt, or hesitate, is sin. Let sink the drowning, if he will not swim Upon the
                            plank, that I throw out to him; Let starve the hungry, if he will not eat <pb n="76" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 76 THE MANIFESTO. My kind and quantity of bread and meat; Let freeze the naked, if he
                            will not be Clothed in such garments as are cut for me. 'Twere better that the sick should
                            die than live, Unless they take the medicine I give; 'Twere better sinners perish, than
                            refuse, To be conformed to my peculiar views. 'Twere better that the world stand still, than
                            move Any other way, then that which I approve. C. I never was so narrow and bigoted as that;
                            I always admired individuality. There is not one sentiment in your remarks that I endorse.
                            Radicals always go to extremes; this is the reason they have no more influence on the minds
                            of the people. B. Why, really, I thought that would be just what you would like. I did not
                            think of offending you. C Do you wish to convey the idea that I want every one to think,
                            act, and breathe as I do? Who would keep the wheel of progress moving, if there were no
                            pioneers? B. Then you are willing to admit that you have conservative ideas? C. Certainly, I
                            am. B. Well, that is more than some persons are willing to admit; but I did not know that
                            you were at all intei ested in progression. C. It was always a theme of thought with me, and
                            yet to progress I do not think that we should lay aside all that tends to spiritual growth
                            and activity of mind because it may have been done by our ancestors. I have watched this
                            matter closely, and think great harm lias come from it. A. I do not think we should ridicule
                            what we might term past conservative notions. If we view things intelligently, I think we
                            shall see that they served a purpose in their day. Our day demands different things, which
                            may to our successors a hundred years hence appear ridiculous. C. I would guard against all
                            despotism and bigotry; all that binds free thought and speech. The advancement of a more
                            liberal and progresssive religion has been marvelously rapid, and of course as truth
                            advances error must die, while the truths of the past, are as dear to me as those of the
                            present. B. You still cling to the dear old past. C. Indeed, I do, and may always do it. I
                            cannot put off a certainty for an uncertainty; at least, not until I find something better.
                            B. You are not so liberal as I had supposed. You would not pretend to say that the present,
                            with all its light and intelligence has not brought anything superior to the past? C. Who is
                            to be the judge in regard to the superiority of these things? B. All intelligent minds may
                            be the judges regardless of persons or position. A. It often occurs that those who think
                            they possess superior minds, labor under very narrow ideas. 0. My conception of the matter
                            is this :—We shoTild embrace all that offers an opportunity to lead us to a better life. All
                            that prompts us to forsake the bad and accept the good, are constituents of true religion,
                            while mere theology remains a dead letter; and I think that some persons have much more
                            theory than practice. B. All of this conversation comes just because I was trying to
                            distinguish the difference between creed and religion ; and now I am charged with having
                            more theory than practice. That is a nice way of changing the burden from your own shoulders
                            to that of another. The theory of religion I have nothing to do with; but have contended
                            only for the practical part. A. It seems to be a difficult matter to arrive at a medium in
                            any thing, even in our ideas of religion. B. Why so? Religion to be worth any thing must aid
                            in moulding its adherents into a more noble humanity. It must enter into all the departments
                            of life; into the business of the tradesman as well as into the sermon of the Minister.
                            Those who will be honest in all their dealings, just in all their measures, kind to foe as
                            well as friend, such persons have religion whether they make a profession or not. A. It
                            seems to be the practical part of religion for which we are all contending, the very essence
                            being a renewed order that passes through the whole of one's life. C That is certainly what
                            I have been anxious to maintain. I do not see that we differ, so much, after all. Perhaps,
                            it is well that we are not all alike. While some minds are preservative, and hesitate at the
                            changes which time forces upon us, others accept the same as a growth and a new light, or a
                            reve- <pb n="77" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 77 lation from God. In the union of the two
                            classes conies the blessing. A. An interchange of ideas is often produe" tive of good, and
                            it may be so in this case. A difference of opinions need not cause disunion, if we possess
                            liberal Christian minds, we shall study to prove the worth of. all things before condemning
                            them. We will not complain of the deficiency of light, till we have lived more faithfully by
                            what we have received. Shirley, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Needy but believing" TEIform="index"/> NEEDY BUT BELIEVING.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witham, Maria" TEIform="persName"/> MARIA WITHAM.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Weak and helpless, yet believing, In the living power of God, Poor and needy yet receiving,
                            From the promises of God. Weak and helpless, yet relying, On the arm none can withstand ;
                            Poor and needy, yet supplying, All my wants from His full hand. Faint and weary, yet
                            pursuing, Still the promis'd boon of rest; Fill'd with hope I now am longing, For a union
                            with the blest. Sometimes weary, yet unwilling, In the Christian race to fail; Here would
                            ever be fulfilling; Duties crown'd within the vail. Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, New Hampshire, February 1883" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Village, N. H. Feb.
                            1883.</head><p TEIform="p">My Dear J;—Something whispers to me this morning, that J.—has several times asked me for a
                            letter to be addressed to herself "full of sweet tilings." Well, my dear young friend if I
                            could fill this sheet with words the sweetest, and sentiments the most choice in portraying
                            the spiritual glories of the beautiful "Garden of God" into which you have been, by his
                            spirit transplanted, and over whose growth his angels keep charge; if I could awaken in your
                            mind new and stronger resolves to consecrate, in youthful days your life fully to God,—how
                            gladly I would write them. For would not this result be the best and ¦'sweetest" of all
                            things? Jesus said, "No man cometh unto me except the Father draw him." Have you not my dear
                            J,—felt amid the conflicts of your short experience; in the secret chambers of your heart,
                            down in the hidden depths of its purest and most hallowed desires, these strong cords of
                            God's infinite Love drawing you into his presence, and holding you with a firm grasp? Ah my
                            dear sister, may it still hold, till you shall be so fully imbued with its power, and
                            impressed with its beauty, that all other loves shall be merged in this and all other
                            pleasures seem turbulent and unsatisfactory, without this joy to give the peace, the
                            fullness and freshness of life. Did you think that Mother Ann was called from England to
                            America that she might establish in a free country a "school of Christ,"—a system of
                            education wherein all pupils who "would" should be taught how to preserve themselves
                            unspotted from the world, and should attain unto the fullness of knowledge in godliness? We
                            know that practical lessons are above all the most reliable, and now one hundred years later
                            J,—our J; in the providence of God, is called from the same section of the Globe to be a
                            learner in this school whose students are to be renewed "after the likeness of Christ"—a
                            Savior in her generation, a vessel prepared for the indwelling of the Holy Spirit, the
                            perfection of beauty ! May you be safely guided by the hand of that wisdom whose "ways are
                            ways of pleasantness and all her paths are peace," until you reach the gates of the golden
                            city, and are fully persuaded of your rightful heirship to an inheritance there with the
                            redeemed. You must be aware ere this that you are an object of love and prayerful interest
                            in the hearts of all the good Brethren and Sisters; and we shall continue to love and pray
                            for you and yours, until we are fully persuaded that you are the Lord's. Most Lovingly Your
                            Friend.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Martin, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. Martin.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We should often have reason to be ashamed of our most brilliant actions if the world could see the motives from which they spring" TEIform="index"/>
                            We should often have reason to be ashamed of our most brilliant actions if the world could see the motives from which they spring
                        </head><p TEIform="p">We should often have reason to be ashamed of our most brilliant actions if the world could
                            see the motives from which they spring.</p></div2><pb n="78" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible" TEIform="index"/> THE BIBLE.</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY C. BLINN.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The growing liberality of the day often brings to us the fruits of investigation which are
                            very satisfactory. At the same time it cannot be other than the growth of intelligence which
                            is advancing on lines that only a few years in the past would not have been admissible. To
                            doubt, was to be more than condemned, while to give an expression to advanced thought, on
                            the infallibility of the Bible would have been hazardous in the extreme. But that day like
                            all others of corresponding darkness i is gradually giving place to light and truth, and the
                            world is not wanting for brave minds to speak it. The Rev. Henry Ward Beecher, says that we
                            have been brought up largely "to found our notions of creation upon the poetic expressions
                            of the sacred Scriptures. We felt as if God came to the fore front on the day of creation,
                            and said, 'Let there be light, and there was light.'" "This," he says, "wasthe prevalent
                            impression." To have questioned the matter at all would have been very presuming, as much as
                            it would to have suggested that the days of creation might have been just a little longer
                            than of twenty four hours duration. Br. Beecher tells us, very humorously, of the manner in
                            which the Christians have used the good book as a weapon ; having reference to the battle
                            which Joshua fought with the five kings of the Amorites, (see Joshua x.) "They" the
                            Christians "threw the Bible at the sun and moon once, and it came back on their own heads,
                            and astronomy stands. They threw it at geology, and geology stands." As the Bible is a
                            historical record of the creation and growth of man, his journey from a wild and savage
                            state to a responsible being, and also one extended record of the Hebrew nation, through all
                            their desert wanderings and their subsequent national prosperity and adversity, we see no
                            reason for using it as authority in determining the correctness of geology, astronomy or
                            physiology. That the writers of the Bible were guided by plenary inspiration, has been a
                            forced teaching of the church, and on this account, no word nor sentence could be
                            questioned. Instances have arisen where the converted have over stepped their bounds, and
                            where the unconverted and infidel class have expressed themselves quite clearly in regard to
                            the propriety of some passages, and a mountain of unkindness and even bitter feelings have
                            grown up between the church party and those who wished to exercise a more liberal thought.
                            The Eev. K. H. Newton of the Episcopal church has now expressed his mind on the subject, and
                            he says that "the old view of the Bible is fading upon the vision of the age. It is a wrong
                            use of the Bible to set it, in its entirety before all classes and all ages. The horrible
                            atrocities and brutal lusts of the early Hebrews, and the coarseness of their latter days,
                            are as unbearable to modern ears, as the rough talk of Shakespeare's ladies. It is wrong to
                            consult it as a heathen oracle for the determining of our judgments and the decision of our
                            actions." St. Paul writes to Timothy that "All scripture is given by inspiration of God, and
                            is profitable for doctrine, for reproof, for correction, for instruction in righteousness."
                            and this has determined <pb n="79" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. the case so clearly that the
                            whole Bible is a full and perfect inspiration of God, that sermons have been preached upon
                            the subject proving that every word from the first of Genesis to the last of Revelations was
                            an inspired word of God. But the revision of the New Testament spoils the chance for another
                            acceptable sermon on this point. It now reads;—"Every scripture inspired by God, is also
                            profitable for teaching, for reproof, for instruction which is in righteousness." Indeed it
                            is; whatever is done in righteousness must certainly be good, and especially so if inspired
                            of God. The revision has pruned many passages and also blotted out many others which have
                            been decided tu be errors, and the result has been to make the New Testament a much better
                            book. Search the scriptures, cannot be too thoroughly impressed upon the mind, as the Bible
                            is a vast repository of historical information and of moral instruction, and if better known
                            might be better appreciated. If many who profess to hold it in such reverential regard,
                            could only be persuaded to accept the teachings of Jesus and his disciples as a guide in the
                            walks of life, we might with more confidence look forward to the anticipated millennium. The
                            Rev. Stopford A. Bro )ke of England, says, that—"The yoke bound upoj our souls by an
                            infallible church was bound over again when it put over us an infallible book, and imposed
                            upon our consciences the fulfillment of every word of the Bible as a law. Many did not dare
                            to inquire into anything which seemed to conflict with the letter of scripture, lest they
                            should lose confidence in that book which they had turned into the foundation of their
                            eternal life. 'Touch one letter of it and all was lost.' " It is well that England moves on
                            in its love of liberty or Br. Brooke would have been fastened to a stake and a bundle of
                            faggots burning at his feet. But that day has gone—forever, and the pastor dares to say,
                            that "The Bible then is not infallible as regards history, nor infallible as regards
                            science, nor, indeed is it infallible as regards morality." St. Paul very well understood
                            all this and told his brethren that God had made him a "minister of the New Testament, not
                            of the letter, but of the spirit, for the letter killeth, but the spirit giveth life."
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Guard well thy heart" TEIform="index"/> WRITTEN FOR THE MANIFESTO. GUARD WELL THY HEART.</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="B., H. G." TEIform="persName"/>H. G. B.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Guard well thy heart in youth's bright sunny hour, When sin's tempt atious come with force
                            and power, And fain would load thee from the path of right, And blast thy prospects now so
                            clear and bright. Guard well thy heart, and let not pleasure's charm Ensnare thy soul and
                            lead thee on to harm; But seek the guidance of that Spirit pure Which leads to Him whose
                            promises are sure. Guard well thy heart whene'er the Cros.4 appears, And be not influenced
                            by groundless fears, But take it up and bear it meekly on, Over that path that many a saint
                            hath gone. Guard well thy heart, and ne'er forsake the way That leads to peace, and
                            never-ending day, Seek not for rest while o'er earth's path you run; True rest awaits you
                            when your work is done. Guard well thy heart in every hour of life; Trust thou in God
                            through all thine earthly strife; Let love impel thee in that glorious way, That leads to
                            God and ends in nightless day. Shirley, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Higher life" TEIform="index"/> HIGHER LIFE.</head><p TEIform="p"> Born for a higher life ; And how shall we obtain it, If not through daily strife With
                            anxious heart t6 gain it? The justice of our God Requires our labor given To full ensure his
                            love, Or find a home in heaven.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><pb n="80" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Connecticut, March 1883" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, Conn. Mar. 1883.</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Children ;—No education is worth anything that does not include honesty. You had "better
                            not learn to read, better not know a letter in the alphabet, and be strictly honest, rather
                            than being learned in all languages, and in all sciences, to be at the same time deceitful
                            in heart and counterfeit in life." Be honest. Be pure in thought, word and deed. Impure
                            persons, poisoning their associates with sinful examples, are plague spots, moral ulcers.
                            Shun the malaria of vice, as a pestilence. Oh ! the misery and woe of an impure life. Be
                            masters of your passions, rulers of your appetites. "Blessed are the pure in heart." Purity
                            is very essential in forming a true Christian character. Be virtuous, and heavenly joys will
                            flow into your spirits. Grow wiser and better ; develop pure hearts, strong minds, healthy
                            bodies. Forget not the duties pertaining to a holy life ; their faithful performance will
                            insure you real happiness, while their failure will bring death to your souls. Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/> Daniel Orcutt.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Purity of life" TEIform="index"/> PURITY OF LIFE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fields, Floyd C." TEIform="persName"/>FLOYD C. FIELDS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> What a grand and noble characteristic, it is in man to live a pure life ! It is not only a
                            virtue but it is a combination, the sum total or aggregate of all virtues. In looking over
                            humanity, scrutinizing with a critic's eye and a philosopher's observation, it would
                            certainly be difficult for us to pass any specimen of mankind and truthfully say he is
                            totally depraved or that he has not a particle of good in his nature. But when we take man
                            as a whole and view him as he appears to us, we see so much that is inconsistent, and
                            impure, and those characteristics predominate so much in that direction that it detracts
                            largely from the lustre of his good qualities, and a close observer would have to strain
                            every nerve of his perceptive faculties to find any element worthy of emulation. To diagnose
                            some characters and separate the good from the evil would surely require a person well
                            developed in human nature, but notwithstanding all this there is a spark of divine goodness
                            in the inner recesses of the most depraved natures. But how few men, in ages past, have
                            lived according to their highest ideal of perfection, and what a small number, in this
                            present generation, live according to their God-nature, following the dictates of the
                            divinity which dwells within. How many there are who trample under foot their higher nature,
                            and try with the utmost vehemence to drive out the last vestige of the divine instinct! Thus
                            the spiritual sensibilities are so benumbed by the constant abuse received from the grosser
                            nature, that it becomes almost impossible for the monitor of the soul to be felt, or its
                            existence realized. Begotten in lust, by parents whose aspirations trail the earth; is it a
                            wonder that man continues in sin, and the light of progression does not reach his soul? How
                            true it is, and how forcibly it is illustrated in our day, that the sins and follies of the
                            parents are transmitted to the children, from generation to generation, both spiritual and
                            physical; but there have been those in all ages, that have had the will power to live
                            according to the laws of their higher nature, yet, how such have been persecuted, suffering
                            the most excruciating pain and agony; even unto death in consequence ! Now it is different;
                            all can worship God according to the dictates of their own conscience, without fear or
                            molestation, for it is a Constitutional right, yet how many abuse that privilege. Instead of
                            using the talents of their higher nature, for their own elevation, and for that of mankind,
                            they revel in sensuality and bring ruin to themselves, and all others who have been guided
                            by their influence. There is truly a great responsibility resting upon those who misapply
                            their abilities for they not only deaden their own spiritual <pb n="81" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 81 growth, but retard the progress of others. Observe the multitudes in our great
                            cities; what wrecks to behold;—bent forms, palsied limbs, sunken cheeks and sallow
                            countenances.—What do they indicate? They are the fruits of sensuality. When we study and
                            reflect upon the assertions of eminent physicians, who state that nearly all diseases
                            originate in sexual indulgence, it is about time for some to rebel against the injurious
                            influences to which this vice leads. How many perfectly healthy persons can we find,
                            untainted with disease or unencumbered by infirmity? Alas! the only reply is the echo of my
                            words ! Is it not time to maintain principles of purity and Godliness? The harvest is truly
                            great but how few the laborers. Where will you find a class of people at the present time
                            that are unfolding the banner of truth, wisdom and purity more than the Shakers ? Yea, those
                            who are willing to live the Christ-life, forsake the ways of the world, and let pure
                            Christ-like love be the fruit that proceeds from the heart. Then man can realize of what
                            true happiness consists; then he is prepared to enter the resurrection heaven, where he can
                            receive the flow of divine truth as it proceeds from the great fountain of Spirit; and his
                            soul can then grow in the sunshine of God's eternal love. He can then experience the
                            heart-rest that is only known to the people of God; they can daily realize, what it is to be
                            fed on the rich manna, that is showered by the bounteous hand of the Infinite; they can
                            comprehend the glory and grandeur of being clothed in the resurrection robe of immortality;
                            and they can dwell so near the angelic realms of the blest, that their souls can hold sweet
                            communion with the saints that have passed on to the summer land. The vail seems to be
                            severed, and the aroma to be wafted from Eden's fair bowers to their presence, upon the
                            gentle zephyrs of love. This is happiness that none but the pure can realize. May we all
                            strive to live in the higher temple of our nature, and when the summons conies for us to
                            pass over, may we hear those blessed words "Come up higher." "The pure in heart shall see
                            God!" Come where the fields are ever green, And blooming flowers by angels seen— Kiss
                            crystal dew-drops, falliug there, And with sweet fragrance fill the air. Where streams of
                            life forever flow, Scattering mists on all below Like loving tears, from angel's eyes, They
                            help our drooping souls to rise. The tree of life is standing there Ambrosial fruits so rich
                            and fair, Enchanting spirits as they rise To run the race and win the prize Soutti Union,
                            Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life's object" TEIform="index"/> LIFE'S OBJECT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Collins, Elvah F." TEIform="persName"/>ELVAH F. COLLINS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Live, for higher ends and aims Than the sons of earth aspire to, Live, to render God His
                            claims, Though the effort oft may tire you. Live,—as blest for having lived, Doing good,
                            though good oft fail you, Give, though you have not received, Though in giving, wrongs
                            assail you. Live a spiritual life, Though the tempter bid you falter, Be a martyr in the
                            strife Rather than your purpose alter. Firmness in the path of truth, Nerves the heart and
                            hand for action, Weakness, levels to the earth Every plan for good transaction. Bigotry, and
                            cowardice, Bar the way of true progression, Hold the spirit in a vise, Turning gain, to
                            retrogression. But a firm and steadfast mind, Holds its own through opposition, Looking
                            upward, there to find Only heavenly transition. Calm, mid persecution's wrath, Stayed in
                            virtue's holy power, Strewing in another's path, Some lowly and sweet scented flower. Happy
                            in a consciousness, Of having blest the world in living, Such bear the fruit of
                            righteousness, Bright memories to the future giving. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="82" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reading, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Reading, Massachusetts</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hanaford, J. H." TEIform="persName"/>Dr. J. H. Hanaford</byline><p TEIform="p"> [A Letter from Dr. J. II. Hanuford, Rending, Mass.] PLEASANT RECOLLECTIONS. Mr.
                            Editor;—Having met Abraham Perkins, of Enfield, in the cars a few days, since, I was not
                            only pleased with the interview, but recalled the past, when I was a young man, just
                            starting out in life, "seeking my fortune." More than forty years ago I was teaching in
                            Loudon, near your place, and, during the Winter, made several calls to the Village,
                            attending the meetings—as we did not go to "Church" then. Of course, the services were novel
                            to me, unaccustomed to any such exercises, but they were solemn and impressive, and I had no
                            disposition to regard them in a mirthful spirit—as the thoughtless do, it may he, but then,
                            as now, I felt it a duty to be respectful and gentlemanly, so long as I deemed it well to
                            remain, as I hold that there is no religion in treating any class of worshipers with
                            rudeness, even, with disrespect, however much they may differ from ordinary customs. I then
                            looked with a boy's eyes, and thought with a boy's brain. Though just from the school, I
                            might have cherished the views of the young generally, that great progress then had been
                            made,—from which delusion, since, I have been wonderfully emancipated, or I should have made
                            but little progress, as an idea of personal ignorance seems to be the basis of true
                            progress. As I have since given many years to the study of sanitary science—in which I am
                            more than ever interested, with advancing years—I am more and more disposed to regard that
                            religion as relatively worthless winch does not recognize the duty of making the great
                            principles taught by the meek and lowly Nazarene, the rule of moral life, taking them with
                            us to the table, to all parts of the dwelling, to our work shops, on the farm, into our
                            places of worship, everywhere, as the basis of active duty. As God is the Author of all of
                            the laws of the hody, mind and soul, to violate any of them, willfully, is to sin! But, I
                            know too well that the prevalent idea is that our great duty—and nearly our only ones—relate
                            to the soul, almost wholly ignoring the body, which I cannot accept as the Gospel of Christ.
                            Of course, as the mind and soul are higher than the body, the care of them involves higher
                            ideas of duty, and yet God made all, placing them under law. While the soul is superior to
                            the body, it is manifest that the body was made to be subservient to the higher, the mind
                            and soul, and yet, too often, the mental and spiritual natures are the slaves of the animal,
                            the propensities "warring against the soul." While the mental brain is placed uppermost and
                            foremost, and the propensities at the base of the brain—indicating that it should be the
                            guide, the superior, it is manifest that men too often reverse this order, turning around,
                            placing the lower brain in a conspicuous place, "backing into marriage," as one has
                            expressed it, walking backward all of the time, practically, allowing the propensities, the
                            sensual to lead, bringing the superior into a slavish relation to the superior—the mind and
                            the soul. Such, of course, disregard the divine injunction, "Whether ye eat or drink, or
                            whatsoever ye do, do all to the glory of God." They do not recognize the idea and duty of
                            "bringing the body under,"' but glorify the stomach, the propensities, the animal nature. Of
                            course such sins are followed by the inevitable penalties, pain, sickness, suffering and a
                            premature death! 1 learned from A. P. that there is less sickness in your societies, and
                            that your people attain a greater longevity than others, as do the Jews. I am anxious to
                            learn more of the facts.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Is it worth it all" TEIform="index"/> WRITTEN FOR THE MANIFESTO. IS IT WORTH IT ALL?</head><p TEIform="p">Life is not without its shadows, Smiles are not without their tears, And the one who mounts
                            to glory Climbeth up through patient years. Tender are the threads, and tangled, In the warp
                            and woof of heart, But the best of webs are woven From the many mingled parts. Ours is such
                            a strange existence Such a chance of joy or woe, But small wonder that we ponder That we
                            question, Why 'tis so? But small wonder that the query From the lips should sometimes fall
                                <pb n="83" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 83 "What will all the gain amount to? Is the profit
                            worth it all ?" Fate's and Fortune's wheels keep turning And whichever one controls Makes
                            small matter in the final Summing up of human souls. Circumstance may lend a trifle, And
                            surroundings form a part; But condition is the sought for By the fingers of the heart. We
                            may fret awhile and worry Over ills we might well cure, And we learn in time with patience,
                            Those we cannot, to endure. Could we see the sum in total, Cipher at a glance, the whole, We
                            would count the cost more kindly Of this commerce of the soul. Younger scholars must
                            remember Page by page, to con the book, Learn to take on trust and credit, Forward, more
                            than backward, look. Learn that life is worth the living, Golden hours are not all past,
                            God, in writing out His poem Leaves a sweet verse for the last.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is man" TEIform="index"/> WHAT IS MAN?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Annie" TEIform="persName"/>ANNIE STEPHENS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> What is man ? was asked by one of old ; and we repeat the question. As we cast our eyes over
                            hill, valley and plain, on every hand we see monuments of his power, strength and
                            intellective genius. Every element of earth, has been applied to his ends and purposes ; and
                            the busy world thrills with the products of his ever active mind. Steam, that ever powerful
                            but subtle agent, almost as ethereal as air, he holds within an iron grasp, and makes it
                            perform the mandates of his will, as the myriad industries of life attest. He chains the
                            imponderable fluid that sometimes flashes on our sight from dark forbidding clouds ; and
                            'through this subtle electric current, made subservient to the all controlling power of
                            mind, he sends ; his thoughts from continent to continent in the twinkling of an eye. But,
                            not on land alone has man portrayed his skill; the oc^an teems with the wonders of his
                            creative genius. The little fragile barques of by-gone days, plied by oars and propelled by
                            muscular strength, are as child's toys compared with the floating palaces of the present
                            time. How gracefully these mighty vessels plow the waves, ride the billows, and defy the
                            roughest storms ; bearing their ponderous burdens to every clime, and waving their
                            triumphant flags in the breezes of every zone. The astronomer, wise and reverential in the
                            pursuit of his exalted study, holds the keys that unlock the occult mysteries of yon stellar
                            dome, where countless systems of created worlds revolve in perfect harmony; and could he
                            lead you through his midnight walks, he would show you the limitless fields of his
                            observation, and the exhaustless resources of his knowledge. But, again we ask, "What is
                            man?" These masked beings we view with an external eye, are but the perishable bodies, that
                            are to subserve a purpose in this material sphere for a season, and then return to the
                            elements that shall change it into other forms. Earth does not claim the man, neither can
                            earthly knowledge satisfy his needs. However great his intellectual development the soul in
                            its higher, spiritual unfoldment, is vastly superior. The immortal part is the crowning
                            glory of man's being. Stamped with the impress of Divinity, adorned with reason, and an
                            aspiring sentient spkit; who can disavow his immortality? Not he who reads the <pb n="84" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 84 THE MANIFESTO. thoughts of God written on the visible Universe, and
                            expressed in the various operations of nature. In all his eye sees, his mind observes, and
                            his soul feels, he traces the infinite love and power of God, and, as man is created in his
                            image, he reasonably accepts a belief in his eternal destiny, and progression in the life
                            beyond. Mt. Lebanon N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peacemakers" TEIform="index"/> PEACEMAKERS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Spooner, Emma" TEIform="persName"/>EMMA SPOONER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> [Written for, and read before the Bible Class.] We have abundant reason to thar.k God for
                            that beautiful and instructive discourse so carefully recorded by the sacred historian, and
                            found in the fifth chapter of Matthew. Our Lord spake as never man spake before. It was a
                            mission of Divine blessings to those who would become meek and merciful; who would become
                            pure in heart, and peacemakers among men. It was an especial blessing to those who should
                            hunger and thirst after righteousness, and to those who should suffer persecution for the
                            maintenance of the principles of truth. How carefully we should strive to cultivate all
                            these Christian virtues, so wisely recommended to us ; this humility and meekness ; this
                            penitence for wrongdoing; this earnest desire after righteousness; this universal goodness
                            which so becomes us if we would sustain those worthy names which were conferred upon the
                            disciples. The "light of the world," and the "salt of the earth." Are we worthy? or shall we
                            exclaim as did a good man in former times, "Blessed Lord, these are not thy words or we are
                            not Christians !" All the predictions of the ancient prophets concerning the nature of
                            Christ's Kingdom have represented it as a kingdom of peace, and that Jesus was to be known,
                            in the fullness of the term, as "Prince of Peace." His people are also represented as a
                            peaceable people, and were to be denominated "the children of God," because they are
                            peacemakers in righteousness. When about to leave his disciples he commended them to his
                            Father in the same spirit which he had manifested during his mission. "My peace I give unto
                            you, not as the world giveth, give I unto you. Let not your heart be troubled, neither let
                            it be afraid " It is evident that the disciples, and also that the primitive church, so long
                            as it was guided by the testimony of Jesus, carefully maintained the principles of peace.
                            Again we find that saviors have come up on Mount Zion and they renew the testimony of
                            "Blessed are the peacemakers; for they shall be called the children of God." Enfield, N.
                        II.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our home" TEIform="index"/> OUR HOME.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Elkins, Odillon B." TEIform="persName"/>ODILLON B. ELKINS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> A home where purity reigns is of all places the most beautiful. It seems a plain fact that
                            in no other spot does that absolute purity obtain which marks our Shaker home. Of course,
                            for a Shaker to say this, has the appearance of boasting ; but many a good thing would be
                            left unsaid if we should always stop to think whether it be liable to any objection. Our
                            home may not be, and is not, all that we wish it to be, in regard to our relations and
                            intercourse together, but these we may mould to our liking. Each one may live in a peaceful,
                            Christian element, or in a state of discord and inharmony. We may pass and repass each other
                            like angels, as we are exhorted to do by one of our early parents, or we may grate past each
                            other very unpleasantly ; or again, we may not so much as grate,—we may pass coldly, as
                            strangers pass. While the external conditions of our home may be shaped by us, and improved
                            upon, the divine plan upon which this home is built, is perfect and unchangea- <pb n="85" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 85 ble, and adapted to every soil and climate. The waiting may
                            seem long to us, impatient, short sighted mortals, and none of us may live to see any great
                            increase or spread of those truths which we have espoused, but in the unerring course of
                            Providence this is sure to transpire in God's own time. To make our home relation complete,
                            all ages are necessary, the same as in any home., and a thorough good will and fellowship
                            must subsist between all the members. There is always something lacking if there are no aged
                            ones moving slowly about, with cane in one, or in each hand. The same if there are no little
                            ones to do the capering. The peaceful blending in one accord, of such a diversity of
                            talents, sentiments, and tastes, as there must always be in a community, is a consummation
                            the difficultuess of which, the incidents of every day may convince any one. "With man,
                            tills is impossible; but with God all things are possible." But there are so many things
                            discarded in a Shaker home, which are gratifying to the native tastes and instincts, that it
                            seems a wonder that any one who lives for present and mundane joys, with no especial desire
                            for the coming of the Kingdom, should find any attraction sufficiently strong to hold him.
                            It is not half a home, it is a mere shell of a home, to the soul who hungers for spiritual
                            food, unless it has more to offer than the mere external advantages of a co-operative
                            association, and it has more than these. It has more of blessedness, and genuine soul
                            life,—th-? true felicity, than the finite mind can comprehend. To the meek, the poor in
                            spirit, and to those who do hunger and thirst after righteousness, our :ome affords an ever
                            present hope and prospect of inexhaustible riches. None but the riches of a consecrated
                            spirit are worth the efforts of a life time, and the true Shaker life is a life of
                            consecration to the Lord. It is, no doubt more acceptable to Him than any other course,
                            however perfect, can possibly be. It is more like the example, it accords more with the
                            precepts of our Master whom, it is written, the Father sent into the world to show to all
                            mankind what manner of life is most approved of Him, and the one true way. So here in our
                            quiet home are the true riches to be sought and found. And this home was founded for the
                            sole purpose, that all who will may seek and find the the gifts of the spirit. These in
                            their fullness are not to be had at less cost, than to give our whole life, and our own dear
                            selves a free will offering to God. And whatever our natural parts maybe, they are meagre
                            enough in contrast with the fruits of self-denial. But to make it the all absorbing theme of
                            existence, that all our words, and acts are to the Lord, we must make up our minds to meet
                            the scoffs and taunts of the carnally minded, with such epithets as fanatic, strained,
                            partially insane, aud such. If we are to secure the prize we must disregard these dastardly
                            flings. To some it is very distasteful to mingle religious topics with temporal, every day
                            pursuits, or with our letter writing ; but in a purely religious home this view seems
                            inconsistent. As for me I would have every part of life,—every employment so tinctured, and
                            so mixed with pious impulses, that to draw a line of division between them would be
                            impossible. And to me the sentiments and motives of a true piety cannot seem mis- <pb n="86" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 86 THE MANIFESTO. placed under any circumstances in a community like ours ;
                            the words of eternal life are ever too scarce. We are too prone to depreciate good words as
                            compared with good works. The latter, it is true, cannot be so easily counterfeited, but the
                            former, when genuine and sincere, as they are in most cases, are not a whit less important
                            than the latter, and with some persons, ofttimes they cost more eifort by far. Enfield, N.
                            II.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nothing new" TEIform="index"/> NOTHING NEW.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/>CATHARINE ALLEN.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Can I attempt to indict any new thought? "There is nothing new under the sun." So declared
                            the wise men of the East many centuries ago. History repeats the fact, and nature, the
                            oldest and truest of all teachers, bears this truth through all her treasure volumes. Even
                            the fresh bright robes of Spring, are woven of tissues as old as eternity. The same water
                            that supplied rivers and oceans in ages past and then blessed the earth with gentle showers
                            or copious rainfalls, or burst from its bosom in bubbling springs, still continues its
                            beneficent mission. Each individual inherits the germ of every faculty possessed by the
                            human race, and these are developed in every one by the same changeless laws of progress.
                            The inventor works out, what to him seems a new idea; but, before he can offer the product
                            of his toil to the public, A, B and C are ready to bring forth similar improvements, each
                            attesting that he was the originator of the invention; while history bears record that some
                            ancient nations far excelled in the practical application of the same principles, and showed
                            great skill and constructive ability in the science of mechanics. Excavations in our own new
                            country, (so called) reveal ruins of cities and empires of great antiquity, which bear
                            evidence of high civilization and culture in the arts and sciences, many of which, are as
                            yet unknown to the now existing races. And what of literary and spiritual attainments? It
                            has been said, that "a new verse in literature, is as rare as a new star in the
                            constellations of heaven." And it must be apparent to those acquainted with ancient
                            writings, that the product of modern authors—with rare exceptions—only reflects the light
                            which turned the pages of the past. Media of long ago were gifted with prophetic vision, and
                            clearly foretold the Millennial day that lias so gloriously dawned upon many souls, and from
                            whose blessed increase the saviors now risen on Mount Zion are toiling. Many beautiful
                            chapters in our own Bible, and in the sacred writings of other people, although transcribed
                            by different nations, and at various periods of time, prove the unity and antiquity of
                            truth, and how actively it circulates through the universe of soul, vitalizing and supplying
                            the elements of growth to the immortal being, as do the pure waters that intersect the land,
                            giving it fertility and growth. Again while studying the history of individuals, we see that
                            the same religious element, has in all climes and ages, run like a golden thread through
                            human life, producing in those who followed the higher light within, a similarity of
                            spiritual experience, revealing the fact that one common cross and the same rugged highway
                            awaits every or.e who would reach the celestial heights of conquered self-hood. This echoing
                            of the past must ever continue ; no one can hope for new thought or experience: until,
                            having advanced beyond that which has been attained by those who have preceded us in earth's
                            existence; and even then, it will be in part an emanation shadowed from intelligences still
                            beyond, in higher spiritual spheres ; for God alters not, and human nature remains the same
                            from age to age. But the mind is a germ of God; it is endowed with a capacity for limitless
                            unfoldment, and expansion; and religion, the vitalizing principle of the soul, ever operates
                            to refine, elevate and liberate it from chains of error and death. It is this undying spirit
                            within, that prompts the deep yearning and ceaseless struggling of the spirit, to reach the
                            Divinity which gave it birth; where aspiration mingles with inspira- <pb n="87" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE MANIFESTO. tion from the deep fountains of truth, whose waters impart new life
                            continually. Thus, Truth, although the most ancient and all comprehending reality, is also
                            the newest, because it is the force of activity which keeps all things within its power,
                            ever new. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New Hampshire, Shaker Village, March 1883" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Village. N. H. Mar
                                1883.</head><p TEIform="p">"Watch and pray that ye enter not into temptation." Matt, xxvi, 41. By continually
                                watching and praying, we are kept from a great deal of wrong that we would not otherwise
                                be able to resist; because it would keep us always on guard. I was taught from early
                                childhood to pray before retiring to rest at night, and on rising in the morning; but
                                the first time I ever was impressed with prayer, was a short time after I came among the
                                Shakers. My teacher took me into her room one morning, before going to school, and
                                prayed in my behalf. I then for the first time felt and saw the necessity of prayer to
                                God I saw where I had neglected it, and for what I needed to pray most. Mother Ann Lee
                                said that she could say in truth, "My every breath is continual prayer to God." May I
                                cultivate this spirit.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="K., M. E." TEIform="persName"/>M. E. K. 14 yrs.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watch and pray, lest ye enter into temptation..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Watch and pray, lest ye enter into temptation...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Shaker Village, New Hampshire, March 1883" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Village, N. H. Mar.
                                1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p">"Watch and pray, lest ye enter into temptation." These are the words of our Savior to his
                                disciples on the memorable occasion of his betrayal by Judas, when he prayed in the
                                garden of Gethsemane. Watch and pray! Watch! How many times do we sleep, when we should
                                be doing our duty. Whenever I think of the word "watch," I also think of the enchanted
                                ground mentioned in the Pilgrim's Progress. Hopeful did not "watch,'' and, but for his
                                brother's advice, he would have slept and thus fallen into temptation. Prayer is the
                                earnest desire of the heart, or, as the Bible tells us, the "breath of God."
                                Watchfulness and prayer go hand in hand. We need to watch to become prayerful, and it is
                                necessary to pray to be watchful. When we fall into temptation, we attribute tile cause
                                to our lack of these two virtues. To pray, we do not always need to kneel down and fold
                                our hands, although there are times when it is necessary to take this form; we may pray
                                while engaged in our common duties. The fulfillment of this little text embraces a whole
                                life of devotion. "Pray without ceasing" is another little text. By this our Savior did
                                not mean for us to neglect our temporal duties for the sake of taking the form of prayer
                                to make known to Him our desires. Nor does it mean for us to be so enveloped in our
                                daily employment, that we have no time to think of our spiritual growth, but it is
                                clearly illustrated in the precept: "Put your hands at work, and give vour heart to
                                God."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="E., J." TEIform="persName"/>J. E. age 15 yrs.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind Words for the Year 1882" TEIform="index"/>
                            Kind Words for the Year 1882
                        </head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Manifesto is very neat in appearance and..." TEIform="index"/>
                                The Manifesto is very neat in appearance and...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Harvard, February 1882" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass. Feb. 1882 </dateline><p TEIform="p">"The Manifesto" is very neat in appearance and contents good. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, E. " TEIform="persName"/>E. Myrick. From, the "Yoittli's Mirror." </byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Shaker Manifesto comes to us now from Shaker Village, N. H...." TEIform="index"/>
                                The Shaker Manifesto comes to us now from Shaker Village, N. H....
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Pennsylvania, Altoona, February 1882" TEIform="index"/>Altoona, Pa. Feb. 1882. </dateline><p TEIform="p">"The Shaker Manifesto" comes to us now from Shaker Village, N. H. It ably sets forth the
                                doctrine and faith of the Shakers and has been a great help to us in forming an
                                enlightened opinion of their religion. </p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Manifesto continues to pour excellent treasures of wisdom..." TEIform="index"/>
                                The Manifesto continues to pour excellent treasures of wisdom...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, November 1882" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Nov.
                                1882. </dateline><p TEIform="p">"The Manifesto" continues to pour excellent treasures of wisdom and experience into the
                                mind. I do not see that the contributions abate in interest. Prayerfulness in the July
                                No. is worth the price of the paper for a whole year. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, A. G." TEIform="persName"/> A. G. Hollister</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I am glad your publication is still alive..." TEIform="index"/>
                                I am glad your publication is still alive...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Jersey, Berlin, September 1882. " TEIform="index"/>Berlin, N. J., Sep. 1882. </dateline><p TEIform="p">I am glad your publication is still alive, when there is so many wild gourds, poisonous
                                vines and death in the pot. It needs some meat to correct the pottage, so go on. The
                                world is gaining slowly. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hacker, J." TEIform="persName"/>J. Hacker.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life is disciplinary, and those who are ground in the mill of adversity..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Life is disciplinary, and those who are ground in the mill of adversity...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Life is disciplinary, and those who are ground in the mill of adversity make better spiritual
                            material than those who are disciplined only by plenty and success.</p></div2><pb n="88" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES.</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every person who puts his conscience..." TEIform="index"/>Every person who puts his
                                conscience</head><p TEIform="p"> Every person who puts his conscience and heart, honestly to work for good receives
                                invisible aid, and none ought to claim and appropriate it to himself. I received the
                                spirit and faith from the founders of the Institution ; but it is a two edged sword and
                                cuts back as well as forward, and is as binding on me as on you. It is written. "They
                                shall flock to your windows, like doves ;" but there must be some cooing inside of the
                                windows or the doves will not come in. We must not forget that we had to be cooed in. I
                                find no difficulty in showing to persons that tribulation dire has to be endured in
                                raising natural children, but they think that spiritual children should be begotten,
                                born and reared without any trouble at all! Well the spiritual being the most important
                                we should calculate on more trouble, more pain and suffering than in the natural order.
                                Many think if we forego the pleasure of the natural man and woman, then we should enjoy
                                eveiy thing else in the world. Foolish virgins ! who seem not to know that we are not
                                called to see how much we can enjoy for our redemption, and that of the world, but to
                                see how much we are willing to suffer for them.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eads, H. L." TEIform="persName"/>Elder H. L. Eads.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Last year we gave all our attention to..." TEIform="index"/>Last year we gave all our
                                attention to</head><p TEIform="p"> Last year we gave all our attention to putting things into good shape for the
                                sisterhood. It :s the sisters who make the homo, and they need the wherewith to do it
                                effectually. The Dutch farmers first build a log house for the family and then bu good
                                barn for the farm. The barn is the leading feature until he is able to build a frame
                                house. N. E. settlers put up a great frame house first and paint it white, and then
                                follow, in good time, barns and sheds. Believers by reason of numbers must have large
                                dwellings immediately afterwards improvements on the farm are in order.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/> Elder F. W. Evans.</byline></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It seems to us that Believers should..." TEIform="index"/>It seems to us that Believers
                                should</head><p TEIform="p"> It seems to us that •'Believers" should take heed and not go into partnership with the
                                children of this world. If we do not respect and maintain the laws and regulations of
                                our own Institution, we need not calculate on receiving much sympathy from those not of
                                our order.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Carter, M. B." TEIform="persName"/> Elder M. B. Carter.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gratitude to God" TEIform="index"/> GRATITUDE TO GOD.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/> MARY WHITCHER.</byline><p TEIform="p">Grateful to God for what is given; 'Tis not enough for home and heaven. How shall we meet the
                            debt we owe And for thy mercy when bestow? Thou needest not my humble gift; And naught is
                            mine thy joy to lift; Or to enhance thy peace serene Or fullness of thy glory seen.— But by
                            the light Thou givest me Thy will, my God, I'm blest to see; And in the language of thy Son,
                            Unto the least true kindness done Shall reach thy throne, O God above, By whom we're known
                            and blessed through love. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><pb n="89" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reception of pure atomspheric air into..." TEIform="index"/>The reception of pure
                                atomospheric air into</head><p TEIform="p"> The reception of pure atmospheric air into the lungs vitalizes the blood, and fits it to
                                subserve various purposes in the animal economy. The vitality of the external tissues,
                                however, are dependent, not immediately and directly on the lungs, but on the air which
                                is taken up by the capillaries. No matter how large a man's lungs might be, if his skin
                                were varnished he would suffer very much and soon die. If we were constituted like the
                                feathered songsters, who breathe through every plume, we should have a voice equal to
                                *hat of fifty songsters.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Guilmette, C. A." TEIform="persName"/>C. A. Guilmette.</byline></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Teeth" TEIform="index"/> THE TEETH.</head><p TEIform="p"> The teeth should always, if possible, be thoroughly cleansed by means of pure, soft
                                water and a brush, immediately after each meal. Tooth powders of a very fine and
                                mechanical nature are allowable. Quill tooth picks are the only ones that should be
                                used. Tea and coffee blacken the teeth. All hot substances are injurious. Everything
                                that deteriorates the general health, injures the teeth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shew" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Shew.</byline></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Position in sleeping" TEIform="index"/> POSITION IN SLEEPING.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">It is better to go to sleep on the right side, for then the stomach is very
                                        much in the position of a bottle turned upside down, and the contents are aided
                                        in passing out by gravitation. If one goes to sleep on the left side, the
                                        operation of emptying the stomach of its contents is more like drawing from a
                                        well. After going to sleep, let the body take its own position. If you sleep on
                                        your back, especially soon after a hearty meal, the weight of the digestive
                                        organs, and that of the food, resting, on the great vein of the body near the
                                        back bone, compress it, and arrest the flow of the blood more or less. If the
                                        arrest is partial, the sleep is disturbed, and there are unpleasant dreams. If
                                        the meal has been recent or hearty, the arrest is more decided, and the various
                                        sensations, such as falling over a precipice or the pursuit of a wild beast, or
                                        impending danger, and the desperate effort to get rid of it arouses us; that
                                        sends on the stagnating blood, and we wake in a fright, or trembling, or
                                        perspiration, or feeling of exhaustion, according to the degree of stagnation
                                        and the strength of the effort made to escape the danger. But when we are not
                                        able to escape the danger, when we do fall over the precipice, when the tumbling
                                        building crushes us, what then? That is death! That is the death of those of
                                        whom it is said, when found lifeless in their bed in the morning, "They were as
                                        well as they ever were the day before," and often it is added, "and ate heartier
                                        than common!" This last, as a frequent cause of death to those who have gone to
                                        bed well, to wake no more, we give merely as a private opinion. The possibility
                                        of its truth is enough to deter any rational man from a late and hearty meal.
                                        This we do know with certainty, that waking up in the night with painful
                                        diarrhoea, or cholera, or bilious colic, ending in death in a very short time,
                                        is properly traceable to a late large meal. The truly wise will take the safer
                                        side. For persons who eat three times, it is simply sufficient to make the last
                                        meal of cold bread and butter and a cup of some warm drink. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Milk" TEIform="index"/>MILK.</head><p TEIform="p"> The article contains all of the elements needed to sustain life, in the young, and is
                                one of the simplest in use—wholesome, if it is pure. Its purity depends vipon the health
                                of the producer, and that largely on the quality of the food eaten. If at first pure, it
                                may become otherwise by carelessness. To keep it in tins, made of lead and arsenic, if
                                it becomes sour, especially, is to endanger the life of the family. If uncovered or in
                                any way exposed to fresh paint, or to filth or poison in any form, it soon becomes
                                affected by absorption, since water and all liquids containing it are grand purifiers of
                                the air, these impurities being retained in the liquids. Never keep milk in a newly
                                painted pantry—only water, and that to be thrown out.</p></div3></div2><pb n="90" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>House and Farm</head><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Milch cows" TEIform="index"/> MILCH COWS.</head><p TEIform="p">The Church family at Enfield, New Hampshire, have a herd of some twenty six milch cows.
                                The stock is Durham, full blooded and registered, which the herdsman of this place, Br.
                                Thomas Steadman, thinks is good enough for our northern climate. The success in stock
                                raising as well as in that of the dairy comes largely from the care which is extended
                                through the year and particularly the care for their protection during the winter
                                season, as well as the regularity in feeding and the quality of the food which is
                                provided for them from day to day. The herdsman also positively asserts that he can
                                determine, at the early age of a calf, the percentage of value that the future cow will
                                be for giving milk. This he thinks is one essential degree toward success. This obviates
                                the necessity of keeping a number of animals that are of no especial value to the dairy.
                                We have seen herdsmen who would base all their calculations on the color and beauty of
                                form of the animal, and make the milking quality of secondary importance. Beautifully
                                shaped horns and a dark red body were essential to insure lite. Others would have the
                                animal white and not a red or black spot would be allowed on the surface of the whole
                                body. But Br. Thomas has none of these whims Horns are at a discount, whether one, two
                                or three, strait or curved, as would be the color or general form of the animal. The
                                milk qualities determine whether the creature comes to the stalls for a future
                                residence, or goes to the shambles. The barn is one hundred feet long and fifty feet
                                wide. A cellar is made under the whole building, the walls of which are laid with large
                                blocks of granite. The first floor of the barn has its stalls for the cows, and between
                                these there is^a large passage way which gives ample room for a small reservoir of
                                water, the cooking tank, and for the storing of the herdsman's tools. In the rear of the
                                cows are fixed small pens for the calves. Several of these places are made in each
                                stable and are considered to be very convenient. The boiler room and the root cellar are
                                both entered from this floor. The second loft is used as a feeding floor where the hay
                                is passed easily to the cows which are fastened in their stalls on the floor below. The
                                third loft is the "drive way." An abutment at one end of the barn helps to form a
                                passage for the loads of hay to pass up and into this floor where all the teams are
                                driven to unload. The hay is stored on either side of the barn, after which the teams
                                pass the whole length of the building and out over an abutment into the fields. The
                                building has a gable roof and is covered with slate that was brought from the State of
                                Vermont. The date of the building, 1854, is marked on the south side of the roof with
                                slate of a light shade. As we entered the barn when the Mercury without indicated 10
                                degrees below zero, we soon found that there was a comfortable degree of warmth in the
                                stalls where the cattle stood. These are arranged on the north and south sides of the
                                building, for the accomodation of some thirteen cows each. In a room made fire proof is
                                an upright boiler which is used for the generating of steam. A pipe conducts the steam
                                to a large iron tank, in which are placed the roots that are to be fed out during the
                                day. This process of cooking goes on with a systematic regularity as does the feeding of
                                it to the stock. Seven quarts of this cooked food with the addition of one quart of meal
                                is given to each milch cow at one time, and they are treated to this twice during the
                                day. A pipe also conveys the steam to the trough in the barn yard where the cattle are
                                to get their drink. The water is kept several degrees above the freezing point. In the
                                A.M. some six cows are allowed to leave the barn at one time. These go immediately to
                                the trough and drink all they wish and then return to the barn in less than fifteen
                                minutes, of their own choice, and are fastened in their places till the same hour
                                arrives the next day. Six more are sent into the yard to drink and they soon return to
                                their places. In the P. M. the cows belonging to the other stall are treated in the same
                                manner. <pb n="91" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 91 Another steam pipe enters the water tank
                                that is in the barn and from which a large supply of warm water can be obtained at any
                                hour of the day. This water is used for cooking the roots. It is also used by the
                                milkers who are provided with a pail and cloth for the purpose of washing the udders,
                                for its cleanliness and for sanitary benefits, preliminary to every milking. The water
                                is also ready for use. if an animal should be sick and confined to the barn, and for the
                                general domestic uses of the place. A line of steam pipes are laid the whole length of
                                both stalls, where the cows are tethered, which keeps that part of the barn at a
                                temperature of about 60 degrees Fahr. even in the coldest of weather. Br. Thomas insists
                                that the cows should be kept warm. A warm room to live in; warm food to eat; warm water
                                to drink, and the supply of milk will fully compensate for all the extra care. We find
                                at this date, Feb. 10th, that they were milking seven new milch cows and two farrow
                                cows. From these they obtained some thirty four gallons per day. These cows, as yet,
                                have had no English hay, but are fed with the rations before mentioned, and three times
                                each day with meadow hay and straw. The first feeding is at five o'clock in the morning,
                                at ten o'clock, A. M. and at three o'clock, P. M. From these twenty six cows in the
                                summer season they obtain some sixty seven gallons per day. The best cow in the herd
                                gives twenty six quarts. The calves, except those which they intend to raise for stock,
                                are sold to the butcher, so soon as age admits. The bull is a full blooded, red Durham,
                                bearing the name of "Pea's Blossom," bred by Hon. C. Dunklin, and will be five years
                                old, Apr. 18, 1883. Registered in the Canada Short Horn Stock Register, Vol. 5th. Henry
                                C. Blinn.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>Henry C. Blinn</byline></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Substitute for short fall pasture" TEIform="index"/> Substitute For Short Fall Pasture.</head><p TEIform="p">— If the pastures are short of grass there is but one proper remedy—stall-feed the stock.
                                It is not necessary to draw upon the hay-mow to do this. Every farmer ought to plant a
                                large piece of corn for fodder. Sow a piece of ground with oats, to be cut early for the
                                same purpose, and use them to help out the poor pasture rather than to feed your cattle
                                in the mowing-field. But if the farmer has not provided for such fodder, then top the
                                corn and feed that out; gather the deformed pumpkins, or those lying too thick together;
                                use some of the early clover, or cut what rowen you can. And rather than feed the
                                mowing-field, use some grain or hay, or buy a few hundred pounds of shorts. The stock
                                must not suffer for food, and the farmer cannot afford the injury to his mowing lands
                                that feeding will do.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Virtues of borax" TEIform="index"/> The Virtues of Borax.</head><p TEIform="p">—The excellent washerwomen in Holland and Belgium, who "get up" their linen so
                                beautifully white, use refined borax as a fine washing powder instead of soda, in the
                                proportion of one large handful of powder to about ten gallons of boiling water. They
                                save in spap nearly one-half. All the large washing establishments adopt the same mode.
                                For laces, cambrics, etc., an extra quantity of the powder is used; for crinolines,
                                requiring to be made stiff, a strong solution is necessary. Borax being a neutral salt,
                                does not in the slightest degree injure the texture of the linen. Its effect is to
                                soften the hardest water, and, therefore, it should be kept on every toilet table. To
                                the taste it is rather sweet; it is used for cleaning the hair, is an excellent
                                dentifrice and in hot countries it is used, in combination with tartaric acid and
                                bi-carbonate of soda, as a cooling beverage. Good tea cannot be made with hard water.
                                All water may be made soft by adding a teaspoonful of borax powder to an ordinary sized
                                kettle of water, in which it should boil. The saving in the quantity of tea used will be
                                at least one-fifth.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Those farmers who take the most pains..." TEIform="index"/>Those farmers who take the
                                most pains</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Those farmers who take the most pains to have all the maple sugar utensils
                                        sweet and clean, and who do work in the best manner, are the ones who always
                                        find the readiest sale and the best prices. There is a good deal of interest now
                                        taken in the manufacture of sugar from beets and sorghum, but where the maple
                                        thrives and farmers have the leisure they will be slow to give up sugar making
                                        from the sap of the maple trees. Maple sugar making comes at a season when
                                        little other work may be done to advantage, and, besides, the fuel is often just
                                        where it is needed, or requires hauling but a short distance.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Exchange" TEIform="index"/>Ex*</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><pb n="92" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Select</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lesson in law" TEIform="index"/>A LESSON IN LAW
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brittle, Gath" TEIform="persName"/>BY GATH BRITTLE
                            </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Sire and son, for many a year, The Browns
                                        had owned the mill On the bank of the limpid stream that flews By the foot of
                                        yonder hill. Hard by is the farm the Whites had tilled For three score years or
                                        more ; Success had blessed their peaceful toil, And thrift had heaped their
                                        store. For all these years the neighbors lived With naught to mar their peace;
                                        Their friendship grew, and as time sped Each saw his wealth increase. There came
                                        a change. Not long ago A hot dispute arose. About a narrow strip of land; And
                                        now the friends were foes. Neither would yield ; and White and Brown Forgot
                                        their former ties. To law they went, nor would they brook One hint at
                                        compromise. As climbing birds pick fattest grubs From rotten parts of trees, So
                                        from our faults the men of law Extract their richest fees. The farm belongs to
                                        Lawyer Green, Old Farmer White is dead. His sons and daughters, scattered wide,
                                        With strangers toil for bread. The mill, the miller's homestead, all Belong to
                                        Lawyer Gray; But Brown works as a miller's man At ninety cents a day. When
                                        friends fall out, they should not go To law ; it is not best. Of what they have
                                        they'll little save.The lawyers get the rest.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York weekly" TEIform="index"/>N. Y. Weekly.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Locomotive of 1881-1891" TEIform="index"/>THE LOCOMOTIVE OF 1881-1891
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">1881. Axles groaning, pistons hissing, Tearing,
                                        wearing, bolts all missing, Bushing hideous thro' night air, Always wanting some
                                        repair, Boisterous, blustering, screaming, sooty, That's the way he does his
                                        duty. 1891. Silent, voiceless, quickly speeding, Coal or water never needing, As
                                        he rushes thro' the dark, Showing but a single spark; Like glow-worm or
                                        fire-fly, Or star twinkling in the sky, Soundless all his work will be, Moved by
                                        electricity!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Railroad world" TEIform="index"/>Railroad World.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nothing to do" TEIform="index"/> NOTHING TO DO.</head><p TEIform="p"> Nothing to do ! O folded hands ! Why will ye lie so white and fair? When the busy world
                                on every side Calls for thy labor, thy earnest care. Nothing to do ! there are tired
                                feet Walking with thee life's weary road; Show them the way in path so sweet That leads
                                to Heaven, that leads to God. Nothing to do, but live in ease When thousands fall on
                                every side, You might have helped to bear the pain, And breast the swift and rushing
                                tide. Nothing to do ! thy days are light, With golden eves and sunny morns You gather
                                flowers, fresh and bright, Some are tortured with cruel thorns. Nothing to do ! what
                                will you say When the Lord of the harvest asks of you "What gleanest thou in my field
                                to-day?" "Lord, there was nothing for me to do!"</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Chapman, Ella D." TEIform="persName"/>Ella D. Chapman</byline></div3><!--                         <div3 type="advertizement">
                            <p>The Livermore Company, which originally introduced the Stylographic Pen, have recently made great
                                improvements in their pen, and have reduced the price so that eveybody can have a chance to purchase the
                                best article of the kind. By sending $2 to Louis E. Dunlap, Manager Stylographic Pen Co., 290 Washington
                                St., Boston, you will receive by return mail one of these famous pens, and also a sufficient quantity of
                                superior ink for six months' use. Full particulars as to different styles and prices can be obtained by
                                sending for circular.</p>
                        </div3>
--></div2><pb n="93" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reminiscences of school days" TEIform="index"/> REMINISCENCES OF SCHOOL DAYS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Danforth, Nancy G." TEIform="persName"/>NANCY G. DANFORTH.</byline><p TEIform="p">As we see the advantages for education enjoyed at the present time we can but contrast them
                            with those which we enjoyed in early life. Shall we relate a little of our experience? Well,
                            that part of the country where we then lived was quite new, the people sometimes attended
                            church in school houses; often in winter being conveyed there in ox teams. When in our fifth
                            year we were introduced to a school, the road was merely a foot-path for nearly three
                            quarters of a mile through the woods. The school-house was built of logs and not more than
                            twelve or fifteen feet square. A small window was on each of three sides, the door being on
                            the fourth. The furniture of the room consisted of a stove, the pipe of which passed through
                            one of the windows into a wooden box, depriving us of nearly half its light; one chair, four
                            slabs, with legs driven into the round side, to serve for benches were placed one on each
                            side of the room. These were of different heights to suit the various ages of the pupils.
                            Across one end of the house a plank was fastened to the wall in a slanting position to serve
                            for a writing desk ; a water pail and tin dipper fill out the list. Here we attended two
                            seasons, when the district, which was very large, was divided, and the part to which we
                            belonged was left without a school-house. To remedy this deficiency, a man offered a room in
                            his house. This was also a log house with but two rooms. The family dwelt in one and the
                            other contained a bed and bureau, to which were added two or three benches, a chair and a
                            plank fixed like the former "for a desk. In this room was a stone fire place. Here our
                            school was held for two winters. During the summer we went into the same man's barn. The
                            doors were on the rear side, opening into a field. From the ground to the entrance door on
                            the side next to the road was some six feet. Placing a plank against the wall we ascended a
                            part of the distance anc then used the underpining stones for steps the remaining distance.
                            In this place we stayec ill time to commence haying when we removed to the stable, the floor
                            of which covered only about one half of the room; on his floor we were located without
                            window or door, save a small aperture in one side hrough which we entered. Our furniture
                            consisted of a chair and table, and two or hree benches. Our teachers must have had lard
                            work to cause the young ideas to shoot in a literary direction, while the loads of hay were
                            being driven into the building within a few feet of us. In this place we spent one session
                            and part of the second. When the farmers commenced their haying we were removed to a vacant
                            log house, where we closed ur session. At this time there were no beautiful school tickets
                            printed, for good boys and girls, and our teacher to supply this lack, would, with ;he
                            assistance of the pupils, manufacture inks of various colors, from different herhs and
                            flowers. For our "Rewards of Merit" she would cut small pieces of paper and sketch as a
                            border in colored inks, some species of vine plant, and then after writing our names, passed
                            them to the pupils. Thus were spent the most of our school days. We have attended school in
                            four different log dwellings beside the log schoolhouse and the barn. All this has
                            transpired within the last half century. Now those days have passed away, and we find nice
                            houses furnished with all needful apparatus to facilitate the progress of education, for
                            which we are grateful to all public spirited persons who have done anything to promote this
                            good cause; being unwilling that their posterity should remain in ignorance, or suffer the
                            privations which they have endured, they have toiled night and day for their prosperity. We
                            hope the rising generation may appreciate the privileges that they enjoy, and strive to
                            become not only useful but worthy members of society; remembering that their parents have
                            labored for their good in this respect. Let them show becoming gratitude by striving to
                            assist others, thus ever be advancing to a higher state of existence. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Never to old, too learn" TEIform="index"/>Never to old, too learn
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> "Never to old, too learn."</p></div2><pb n="94" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ of the ages" TEIform="index"/> CHRIST OF THE AGES.</head><p TEIform="p"> Ad Libitum. Mount Lebanon, N. Y. Thou uplifting spirit, Thou Christ of the ages! Draw near
                            to us now, be our comforting friend. Thou hast lighted the pathway of prophets and sages ;
                            In times of affliction, a helper did send. Now, in Zion's great need we ask thy assistance;
                            94 <pb n="95" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 95 We ask it in faith, may we not ask in vain; Give
                            us living bread, a spiritual substance; Give us strength the cause of truth to maintain.
                            Thine shall the honor and glory be, While the eternal years roll on! Thou uplifting spirit!
                            Thou Christ of the ages ! Hear, O hear our prayer. </p></div2><pb n="96" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Phrenological Journal and Science op Health, March; Contents, Sir, John Lubbock, with
                                portrait, A Fall on the Head and a bad Temper, On Language, Leon Gambetta, with
                                portrait, The Four Windows of Character, Brain Weight, The Olive Tree, Wm. E. Dodge,
                                with portrait. A sensible preacher, Alexander the Great, March and Its Lessons,
                                Education and Health, Hygiene of Walking, etc. etc. Published by Fowler &amp; Wells,
                                75.'! Broadway, N. Y. $2.00 per year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>Herald of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Herald op Health. March. Contents : The Future
                                Education, Fashions and Physiology, Treatment of Constipation, Medical Testimony on
                                Alcohol, Study in Hygiene for Women, etc. Pub. by M. L. Ilolbrook, M. D. 13 * 15 Laight
                                St. N. Y. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Homiletic monthly" TEIform="index"/>The Homiletic Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Homiletic Monthly for March contains sermons from : Dr. Thos. Armitage, of
                                N. Y.; Dean Bradley; (the successor of Dean Stanley); Dr. A. J. F. Behrends, Brooklyn;
                                Rev. Geo. E. Reed, of Brooklyn; Canon Liddon, of England; and Rev. E. P. Williams of
                                Cincinnati. The installation sermon of Dr. Edward P. Ingersoll, and suggestive sketches
                                of sermons by Dr U M. Hatfield, of Chicago; Dr. E. B. Coe. Btv.JJos.. Elliot, Dr.
                                Barrows? and Dr. Joseph Parker. Among the articles are : "Saving Tramps." "Changes in
                                Methodist preaching," "Light on Important Texts." A new series of interviews is begun in
                                this number, on "The Best Methods of Preaching and Sermonizing." The March number gives
                                "The Episcopalian view." Other denominations will be represented in future numbers. The
                                series will give the most recent views of extempore and manuscript preaching. The
                                editorial departments maintain their interest. "Hints at the Meaning of Texts," and
                                "Sermonic Criticism," are full of meat for pastors. "Equality before the Law," and
                                "Inequalities of Society," are strongly handled, under the head of "Living Issues.'
                                $2.50 a year. Funk &amp; Wagnalls, 10 and 12 Dey Street, N. Y. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Hall's Journal op
                                Health. February, Contents; Pneumonia, Care of Children, Health Capacity, Scientific
                                notes, Pure water, The Teeth, Practical Knowledge, Spring Diseases, Finger nails,
                                Health, etc. etc. The Feb. number is well worth the perusal by all who have an
                                appreciation of health, E. II. Gibbs. A. M. Editor. Terms, $2.00 per year, 135 Eighth
                                St. N. Y. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elzevir library" TEIform="index"/>Elzevir Library
                            </head><p TEIform="p">LITERARY CURIOSITIES. The poet, Richard Henry Stoddard's brilliant narrative of the "Life
                                of Washington Irving" forms No. 4 in the elegant little Elzevir Library, and is sold for
                                the price of only 6 cents! After all cheap and handsome books are not limited to the
                                so-called "piratical reprints," as this illustrates : the publishers paid Mr. Stoddard
                                $500 for the Manuscript of this sketch—which is a tax of only a half-cent each, when
                                charged over to one hundred thousand of their customers. Number 5 of the Library, also
                                just issued, contains Andrew Wilson's "The Sea Serpents of Science," price 2 cents, and
                                Number 6, Tennyson's famous "Enoch Arden," price 2 cents—in iormer years sold in large
                                editions for $1.00, or more, per copy. And yet, these numbers are in beautiful type,
                                handsomely printed on excellent paper. Sold by all dealers. John B, Alden, Publisher, 18
                                Vesey St., New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker's descriptive and illustrated catalogue to the flower and vegetable garden" TEIform="index"/>
                                Shaker's descriptive and illustrated catalogue to the flower and vegetable garden
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Shaker's Descriptive and Illustrated Catalogue to the Flower and
                                Vegetable Garden. A beautiful work of eighty four pages, containing an extended list of
                                choice Flower Seeds, annuals, biennials and perennials. The part devoted to vegetable
                                sec Is, is full of good and fresh varieties. Rules for sowing and planting, as well as
                                for cultivation are given so that success is sure to attend the faithful laborer. Both
                                departments are fully illustrated. For farther information address Wm. Anderson. Mount
                                Lebanon, Columbia Co., N. Y.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Houghton, Laura" TEIform="index"/>Laura Houghton</head><p TEIform="p"> Laura Houghton, Feb. 14, at East Family, North Union, Ohio. Age 81 yrs. and 10 mo.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Patterson, Peggy" TEIform="index"/>Peggy Patterson</head><p TEIform="p">Peggy Patterson, Jan. 13, at Watervliet, Ohio. Age 82 yrs. 5 mo. and 2G days. She
                                received the faith when a mere child, and kept it through her zeal and faithfulness, and
                                did much to build up this branch of our Zion. She was a woman of singularly bright
                                intellect and almost prophetic discernment. She exercised a remarkable self-control and
                                through a long and severe illness her thoughts were centered on the welfare and comfort
                                of others. For many years she officiated as our Eldress in the Society, loved and
                                respected by all who knew her.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dayle, A. E." TEIform="persName"/>A. E. Dayle.</byline></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Merrick, Isabel" TEIform="index"/>Isabel Merrick</head><p TEIform="p"> Isabel Merrick, Feb. 11, at White Water, Ohio. Age, 58 yrs. and 9 mo</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Williams, Hannah" TEIform="index"/>Hannah Williams</head><p TEIform="p"> Hannah Williams, Feb. 2C&gt;, at the east family' Hancock, Mass. Age, 87 yrs. 7
                                days. Uniting with the Believers when thirteen years of age, she has spent a long and
                                faithful life, a true and devoted soul and a beloved sister. Her spotless character
                                doubly endeared her as a gospel friend.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., W. B." TEIform="persName"/>W. B. P.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To understand the world is wiser than to condemn it..." TEIform="index"/>
                            To understand the world is wiser than to condemn it...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">To understand the world is wiser than to condemn it. To study the world is better than to
                            shun it. To use the world is nobler than to abuse it. To make the world better, lovelier,
                            and happier, is the noblest work of man or woman.</p></div2><!--
                    <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]<pb id="p30"/>
                            <pb id="p31"/>
                            <pb id="p32"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>