<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2803" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">28</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><date value="18980301" TEIform="date">March 1898</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">33-48</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="28" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
 1898.
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
 Just Published.     The book is printed
with large type  and  on  excellent  paper.
It  contains   130 pages and has
ILLUSTRATIONS
of the Shakers and their
The  work  gives  quite an extended account  of  the  Several SOCIETIES,  their
organization and general management.
Price,  50 cts.
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF   THE
MILLENNIAL   CHURCH,
OR
"United   Society   of   Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price, 50 els.
THE ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly "paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all their
property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley, 1719 Franklin Ave, St. Louis, Mo.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF   THE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
AND
SH AKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the United   Society  of   Believers   in   Christ's
Second Appearing.    Illustrated.
By Giles B. Avery.
Price,  15 cts.
MARCH,
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
THE SHAKER COVENANT.
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS    OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES  and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION     AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
the same time, afford instruction to all inquiring minds. Price 5 cts. each, postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
HUMAN NATURE
is an illustrated Monthly, now only 50 cts.
per    year,    devoted   to   PHEEN0L0GY.
PHYSIOGNOMY, HEALTH, MEDICAL
& SOCIAL REFORM.
Would you like a copy?
Send 5 cts. for Sample to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Francisco, Cal.
A Visit to the
of EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
LLOYD IT. CHANDIiER.U. S. N
Liberally Illustrated with half tone
pictures of persons and places.
The Village of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the loveliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price,  15 cts.
Address   H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
WITHOUT   DOUBT
THE BEST FAMILY PAPE PUBLISHED
IS   THE
NEW   YORK   WEEKLY   WITNESS.
16 Pages,   Only   $1 a year.
Has a very wide scope, comprising as it
does the following departments:
Editorials,
Spirit of the Press,
Scientific and Instructive.
Tin' Odd and Uncommon.
Our CounlrjN Hope.
Foreign News,
A Talk With the Doctor.
Around tlie Hearth,
Iiittle Men and Women,
Weekly Articles l.v dieorjc R. Scott
Xalmag'e's Sermon,
Money anil JBusiness,
World-Wide Field,
Our Family Story,
farm and Garden,
Market Reports,
SABBATH
16 Pages.   Only 50 cents a Year.
An Inter-denominational Weekly Paper.
Sabbath Reading is solely religious.
]STo news; no politics. A grand paper
for the truth-seeker.    It contains:
Editorial.
Christian  Endeavor Topic.
Epworth League Topic,
Saul>atn-School Iipsson,
Choice Poetry,
Crood Stories,
Reports of Missions,
Mothers' Sabitath Afternoon
With the  Children.
And a mass of matter   Carefully  selected.
Send for free sample copies of Witness
and Sabbath Reading. And send for
free sample pages of our Bagster's Bible.
Address
JOHN DOUG ALL & CO., 150 Nassau Street, New York.
WONDERFUL strange REVELATIONS,
EXPL AINING
DANIEL'S & ST JOHN'S
48 page pamphlet.     Price 10 cts.
13 for $1.00.
Address,    H. B. Bear, Preston, Ohio,
READING.--><pb n="33" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progress of shakerism, no. 3" TEIform="index"/>THE PROGRESS OF SHAKERISM. NO. 3</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>Elder Henry C. Blinn</byline><p TEIform="p">MOSES gave rules, what should and what should not be eaten, and the wisdom of his inspired
                            judgment is an honor to his name and age. Jesus and the Jewish Christians must, no doubt,
                            have maintained these rules with the utmost precision, and they should have been kept in
                            full force by all Christians. On the introduction, however, of the Gentile Christians, into
                            the Church of Christ, who did not believe in Moses, nor in Mosaic discipline, they retained
                            all their former habits and customs, and these finally became the rule of government for the
                            modern Christian church. The God-inspired example of Abraham with the laws that Moses had
                            promulgated, and no less, the discipline of Jesus and his disciples, were all thrown to the
                            winds, and the savage and warlike Christians, ate the fat and blood of animals, and used for
                            food nearly every living, creeping thing. As the Shaker Societies receive all their
                            accessions from the ranks of the world, they must be subjected to many of these varying
                            influences that arise from the generative order, whether through heredity or through broken
                            laws. As the ruling spirit of the age, is generation without law, and appetites and passions
                            without discipline, the order of ascendency into the life of Christ, must be very gradual,
                            if it is made at all. This forces all reformations, whether of the mind or of the body to be
                            more or less spasmodic. The thought that enters into the life of one person, and induces a
                            growth MARCH <pb n="34" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 34 THE MANIFESTO. for higher and better qualifications, in
                            everything that makes man more of a man, may pass by the next mind without even causing so
                            much as a ripple of thought on this important subject. The next general reformatory wave
                            that past over the Shakers, was in 1842, when they decided to abandon the use of swine's
                            flesh as an article of diet. Up to this date pork had been universally used and as one
                            writer says, "Nothing was left of the beast but the bristles, which were sent to the
                            shoemaker. This creature's scrofulous ears, and feet and snout and even his tail were placed
                            upon the table, for good people to pray over, and then to eat with profound thanksgiving."
                            The presentation of the roasted swine's head (as repellent as it must have been to a
                            sensitive mind) was made the high honor of the feast, at which sat the dignitaries of the
                            so-called Christian Church, and over which they probably uttered a special Christian grace.
                            Dr. Foote says, "I am firmly convinced that mankind are injured by eating swine's flesh, and
                            I am disposed to believe that the hog, if a healthly animal to-day, would in time become
                            diseased by eating man." "Swine are addicted to filthy habits, and one of the causes of
                            blood impurities is the use of pork." "As an article of diet, pork exerts a most pernicious
                            influence on the blood, overloading it with carbonic acid gas and filling it with scrofula."
                            It was a god-sent revelation to the Shakers to discontinue the use of swine's flesh as an
                            article of food. In this revelation they-had the most implicit faith. Intelligent minds, at
                            once, accepted the advanced step and anticipated the beneficial results that must arise in
                            their favor. The predisposition of so many persons to scrofulous taints, warrants particular
                            care on this subject, as health of body is one of the great blessings of God. Altho the
                            drinking of drams had been largely discontinued so early as 1828, the universal
                            discontinuance of drinking cider was not brought about till the year 1842. The old
                            time-honored cider mill suddenly became of less value and cider, for vinegar only, was made.
                            As there was no manufacturing of this article, the interest in drinking it became less and
                            less, till the Communities well earned the name of Christian temperance societies. In the
                            dismissal of cider drinking and pork eating may be included that also of tobacco chewing and
                            smoking. Early in the century it was one of the special customs in nearly every private
                            family, to receive an invitation to smoke a pipe of tobacco. It was to the Americans about
                            the same as was the mug of beer to the Germans. Almost every room you entered, whether in a
                            public or private house, you found the air strongly impregnated with the fumes of the
                            noisome weed and quite often the floor befouled with a quantity of tobacco juice. The pipe
                            became the daily companion of both men and women, and when two or three of these worshipers
                            of the weed were earnestly engaged, it was with difficulty that one could see distinctly
                            across the room. "Dr. Woodward after presenting a long array of facts, showing the tend- <pb n="35" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 35 ency of tobacco to produce diseaseapoplexy,
                            consumption, headache, dyspepsia, cancer and insanity, concludes with the following
                            inquiry;"Who can doubt that tobacco has destroyed more lives and broken down the health of
                            more useful members of society than have been sufferers from the complaint of bronchitis ?"
                            In many cases tobacco fumes poison the air that we breathe, while the clothes and breath of
                            those who use it beloul the an- with a very disagreeable stench. The foregoing, of course,
                            have been radical measures for the moral and spiritual advancement of the Communities, as
                            well as for the general health of the body. The agitation of these necessary subjects has by
                            no means been useless labor. Like the leaven, so aptly illustrated in the parable, it has
                            changed the lives of a large number of persons, and brought about conditions more congenial
                            and more in harmony with the age in which we live. It has enabled many persons to make a
                            practical application of the advice of the Apostle,"To live soberly, righteously and godly
                            in this present world." It has had a salutary influence on the use of correct language and
                            in the manifestation of care and kindness in the general interest of each other and, indeed,
                            for all humanity. In the growth of these reformatory movements that have gone through the
                            land, there are many examples of heroic characters who have wrought out their freedom from
                            the slavery of perverted appetites and become the victorious conquerors. To hold this
                            position for so many years, and with such signal success, is indeed, a great victory.
                            Sometimes the quandary arises;Shall we be able to maintain this Christian position against
                            the strong influences that are around us? With the general intelligence and the practical
                            knowledge that is abroad in the world to-day, it does not seem as tho it could be possible
                            to return to those things which we have so wisely abandoned. We are assured that it was for
                            the best good of all concerned, and neither as a matter of personal taste, nor in conformity
                            to the custom of a special class in Society, should we deviate from a matter of right. "Down
                            to the third and fourth generation of those that hate me," says the word of the Scriptures,
                            and that hate is a departure from knowledge, and from the laws of God for the safe going of
                            man. While all the animal tendencies are born with man, they have their legitimate use, but
                            a perverted appetite and an unbridled passion is quite below that which we designate as
                            animal. With this class there may be neither thought nor desire for any change. An hundred
                            years have come and gone, and the Shakers have moved carefully along the way, accepting the
                            many lessons that have been proffered for the temporal and spiritual prosperity of the
                            Community. <pb n="36" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 36 THE MANIFESTO. It is the mission of the disciple of
                            Christ to become a new creature. To be* made anew, and that in the likeness of the anointed,
                            spiritual Teacher. With this newness comes a new language, such as may be spoken in the
                            kingdom of our God. Well might we live in the prayer, "Leave us not in temptation," as the
                            language and the influences of a low estate surround us. We go abroad in the world, and as a
                            guest we may be invited to drink;at the table we are served with swine's flesh, and so soon
                            as this is over comes the invitation to smoke. These are the leeks and garlicks of our own
                            land of Egypt, toward which we may be tempted. Under the influence of a weak conscience we
                            find it hard to turn away. Little by little the protective barriers are taken from around us
                            and we find ourselves heavily laden with those very things from which we had covenanted to
                            abstain. When a point has been gained that can be shown to have accomplisht beneficial
                            results, for the best good of Society, it would be a sad mistake, to neglect, carelessly,
                            our advantages and allow them to pass from us. "Hold fast that which thou hast gained" is
                            the admonition of the Scripture, and for our present and future prosperity we may do well to
                            bear this in mind. (The End.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="March" TEIform="index"/>MARCH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>By Martha J. Anderson.</byline><p TEIform="p">The March winds are soughing and sighing Like the roar of the murmuring sea, And the
                            icy-armed kings of the forest Engage in a harmless melee. While flashing and dashing, and
                            clashing Like steeds that are heard from afar; Loud the trump of the wind god is blowing The
                            blast of the last wintry war. Like billows the dark clouds are rising Far south of the
                            mist-shrouded sun, Whose halo crowned disk is apprising That Vulcan's storm reign has begun.
                            The chains of the frost king are breaking, And icy gorged river tides swell, While mighty
                            floods compass the lowlands Where many in peaceful homes dwell. As we list to the surging of
                            waters That rush through the rocky ravine, And gaze with delight on the frost work That
                            forms a most beautiful sheen, <pb n="37" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. Wl 'Where the spray molds
                            in stalactite crystals The stone hedged and turreted glen, We think not that sorrow is
                            shading The flood destroyed dwellings of men. The tempest so fitful and wrathful That sweeps
                            like a besom of war O'er woodless expanse of the prairies 'That stretch to the westward afar
                            ; Is broken by bulwark of mountains That circle our hill-side retreat, And so the strong
                            force of the wind god Is subject to hopeless defeat. The weather wise prophets well argued
                            And true their predictions have proved, For winter all stern and relentless Along a strange
                            pathway has moved. There are snows piled where skies are the warmest, And blizzards on
                            Britain's fair strand, While earthquake and tide-wave upheaving Have past o'er the sea and
                            the laud. There are sleet storms and rain storms with thunder And lightning's electric
                            display Then mercury far below zero, Such changes are markt day by day. But March, bitter
                            March is now dying, His requiem gladly we'll sing, When drops the dark pall o'er his
                            presence And bright April heralds the spring. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Remarks made at the funeral of sister Hannah P. Shepard" TEIform="index"/>Remarks Made at
                            the Funeral of Sister HANNAH P. SHEPARD.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kaime, Joanna J." TEIform="persName"/>By Elderess, Joanna J. Kaime.</byline><p TEIform="p">ONE of the most prominent traits in the life and character of our dear Elderess Hannah was
                            fidelity to principle, especially conspicuous where, her religious convictions were
                            involved; so singularly genuine in regard to truth, that many times I have thought that no
                            alloy could be detected in her instructions to the young, while in the exercise of her
                            duties in the Eldership. Her rebukes were so tempered with a loving sympathy, that no erring
                            one 'could mistake the kindly feeling from her true Mother's heart, tho no covering from the
                            light, or daubing with untempered mortar was allowed. <pb n="38" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 38 THE MANIFESTO.
                            Well has the poet exprest it,"Death loves a shining mark, a signal blow," and we have been
                            conscious for a long time that the grim Destroyer had so aimed the blow, that time, tho
                            freighted with the prayers and earnest entreaties of loving friends, could not stay the
                            poisonous dart. We humbly pray that those who have shared her beautiful ministrations, may
                            treasure them in clean and honest hearts and from the pure seed so richly sown, we shall
                            reap a bountiful harvest, which will redound to the honor and glory of God. Methinks, now
                            freed from earth's burdens, that our Sister will exultingly sing,"I know that my Redeemer
                            liveth, because He lives I shall live also." And when we look for her in her accustomed
                            places in earth-life, the Spirit voice will gently whisper,"She whom thou seekest, is not
                            here," she has risen to die no more. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plea for the helpless" TEIform="index"/>A PLEA FOR THE HELPLESS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catherine" TEIform="persName"/>By Catherine Allen.</byline><p TEIform="p">THE Antivivisection Societies of Europe and America represent a movement which can not fail
                            to call forth the blessing of every one of just and humane sentiments, who has knowledge of
                            the terrible facts which make such organizations necessary. The experience of those who
                            undertake to forward the work proves how very few, even of those who suppose themselves
                            informed on the subject, begin to know to what extent needless cruelties are being practiced
                            on animals in hundreds of colleges and lesser schools, or who would believe for a moment
                            that friendless hospital patients and criminals are in some places being experimented on by
                            merciless operators. Not long since, the writer was earnestly solicited by an outside friend
                            to use her influence in summoning aid in this work from the several Shaker Societies, and
                            have not earnest workers in the various fragmentary reforms of the world, a right to look
                            for co-operation by a people who are called to embody in practical life the truth and
                            goodness in the many phases toward which they are working? As a part of the great life of
                            humanity, is it not vitally essential to our existence as a people to interest ourselves in
                            every movement which tends toward the general progress of the race? In serving our
                            fellow-creatures we find the greatest privilege of life. The broader our fields of labor the
                            richer will the harvest be, and through such support as it is in our power to give to many
                            worthy movements of our time, may we not find favorable opportunities for spreading a
                            knowledge of those truths which have been committed to our keeping. The Secretary of the
                            Antivivisection Society, after thanking for the "proffer of fraternity from the esteemed
                            Shaker Community," exprest a desire for printed matter concerning us, proving how readily a
                            mutual interest is awakened through co-operative effort. <pb n="39" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                            39 The writer has sent to the Secretary the names of a few whom she thought might do some
                            work in the Cause. The signatures of Brethren and Sisters in our Society have been added to
                            the "National Petition" and some financial aid has been given. Could not every family of
                            Believers help in the good work by keeping in our reception rooms some of the literature
                            which will be sent promptly to any who will apply for the same to Mrs. Fairchild Allen,
                            Secretary of the Antivivisection Society, Aurora, 111. Thus many names might be added to the
                            roll of Petitioners and some financial aid be secured. All have some outside acquaintances.
                            By enclosing leaflets on the subject and urging action on the part of those receiving it
                            many others may be stimulated to help. Ministers and school-teachers have wide influence,
                            they should be remembered. Thus, by united effort may we not accomplish much in the cause
                            for God's helpless suffering creatures? Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Brother Albert..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Brother Albert...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Boston, February 2, 1898" TEIform="index"/>Boston, Mass. Feb. 2,
                                1898.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Brother Albert ; It pleases me more than I can tell you to hear that you are
                                becoming more and more a "partaker of the heavenly calling." This is the glorious power
                                of resurrection as experienced by all who enter into the life of Christ. As you advance
                                in spiritual travel you will learn that this resurrection is no far off promise to be
                                experienced after the dissolution of the body. It is a present gift. It is not the offer
                                of a meager hope. It is the joy of Christian posession. It is the power of regeneration.
                                "Except a man be born again he can not enter the kingdom of heaven." Just as soon as a
                                man is born by the power of God's Spirit, he has already entered into the kingdom of
                                heaven which the dear Jesus opened to us by his glorious life and death. So, my dear
                                brother, as you open your heart more and more to the eternal life that is held out
                                before you, you will begin to have eternal life abiding in you. May God make you very
                                rich in both is my fervent prayer. Your countryman, Mr. Varley and myself have become
                                fast friends. I am to spend this evening with him and Mrs. Varley. They are staying here
                                at this hotel. I am delighted and pleased with Mr. Varle}', both as a man and as a
                                preacher. He has become deeply interested in the Shakers. The churches are packt to hear
                                him. I am longing for the day to come when I shall turn my face homeward. 0, how I think
                                of you all! You are always with me. How could it be otherwise ! My heart is in dear
                                Canterbury. Do not let anything trouble you. Do not let your thoughts dwell a single
                                moment on thote things you left behind in old Babylon, but reach out and <pb n="40" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 40 THE MANIFESTO. grasp the better things that await you in happy Canaan.
                                Remember you have not a burden, or a temptation that the dear Christ does not share. I
                                beg you to study his life seriously, as recorded so beautifully in the precious New
                                Testament. Let his life fill your life, let it make you brave, hopeful, and wholly
                                unselfish. Let it make you, what every Shaker should be, a man of God, living in His
                                service, rejoicing in His love, and feeling more and more each day, in your obedient
                                soul the power of His everlasting life. What tongue then will be able to define your
                                peace and happiness ? My heart is filled to-night with gratitude for the grand success
                                of my missionary work. Night after night a large host of eager listeners gather around
                                me. It is so easy to make the world trust one, when one can feel that he is trusted and
                                loved by the dear Brothers and Sisters that form his own household. Adieu, dear Brother
                                until I see you in our dear home. Your true brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Thomas.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Law of love" TEIform="index"/>THE LAW OF LOVE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stewart, Ezra J." TEIform="persName"/>By Ezra J. Stewart,</byline><p TEIform="p">T I ^HERE are probably few who, in the course of their experience, have not JL often queried
                            as to the true nature of love. Many have been prompted to the most heroic self-sacrifice for
                            what seemed to them the fullest embodiment of love and yet have failed to reach that deep
                            satisfaction which only the attainment of their highest ideal could give. This
                            disappointment awaits us all in whatever efforts we put forth just in proportion as we
                            misconceive and misinterpret this most potent and all-pervading force. The desire to
                            understand more clearly and fully the real nature of love, to learn its true analysis
                            through daily experience will bring to us the opening of a new life wherein each successive
                            step brings a clearer perception and more positive knowledge of the great drawing power of
                            love, the law of all lawsattraction. As we are drawn into a perception of this love we see
                            the good as an omnipresent force, the only vital power in the universe. Love is life, and
                            all that is necessary to gain more life and a higher grade of vitality is a fuller
                            recognition of th? love principle and power which is ever around and about us, only awaiting
                            the opening of individual perception when it shall be ours to possess, to appropriate for
                            personal benefit, and for the uplifting to a higher plane than the merely sensuous all who
                            come within the sphere of our influence. With love in the intelligence all desirable things
                            become possible and easily accomplisht; while without it, life seems dreary and hopeless;
                            hardships fill the pathway, and failure like a haunting demon casts the dark shadow of
                            discouragement over every effort till we are led to query why above all things men should
                            desire life. But the answer comesIt is because love, the pos- <pb n="41" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> TKE
                            MANIFESTO. 41 itive, self-existent and eternal in our being calleth for its own. More, more,
                            of life, of liberty, essentially of love, has been the cry of humanity through the ages, and
                            to-day we realize our heaven in reaching for and manifesting more and still more of "the
                            greatest thing in the world" as Drummond has so beautifully exprest it. Paul understood this
                            when he wrote "love suffereth long and is kind." It seems as tho everything of worth wTas
                            contained in those brief words. Under the baptism of this gift how the heart expands in
                            sympathy and kindliness toward all creatures; how willing are we to suffer, to bear and
                            forbear and patiently wait while working for a greater unfoldment of this divine life in
                            those around us, because we have positive faith in it and in its uplifting, all prevailing
                            power. In the early history of the race when the human was lifted but a slight degree above
                            the animal, all conquest was attained through the combative and warring qualities innate in
                            those crude conditions. In the primitive ideal of their personal God was found hate,
                            vengeance and wrath, and every warlike attribute. As the race has gradually evolved to a
                            higher state the conception of God has been divested of personality and correspondingly
                            improved, and is now recognized as the spirit of love and peace. Instead of fighting and
                            struggling so much against evil (so-called) we are learning to turn toward the good, to look
                            for the good in others and to nourish it by kindly thoughts and deeds, to improve every
                            opportunity to so strengthen this good that error shall be displaced, overcome by greater
                            truth. There are those who still struggle and fight like good warriors against what they
                            call the evils of life, not having come to an understanding of the law by wrhich all things
                            work together for good to those who are uplifted from fear and bondage into the liberty of
                            the love realm whence cometh all power. We may be reminded of the old proverb, "The fear of
                            the Lord is the beginning of wisdom," but later we are taught that "Love is the fulfilling
                            of the law," and that "Perfect love casteth out all fear." Love begets self-trust. To have
                            conscious knowledge of the soul's oneness with the All-Good is to be whole or holy. In this
                            oneness we will manifest more and more the divine life latent within, and in that
                            confidence, hope and trust which becomes true men and women, we will find a shield from all
                            harm outwrought through the exercise of the perfect law of love. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Only through spiritualization...." TEIform="index"/>Only through spiritualization....
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Only through spiritualization of thought and feeling do we rise above the base passions and
                            gross inclinations of our lower nature, and feel within our souls the quickening and
                            unfolding of the higher powers of life. This is the true resurrection of which the blessed
                            Master spake.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A,</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Simplicity, is the invariable characteristic of truth." TEIform="index"/>Simplicity, is the invariable characteristic of truth.
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Simplicity, is the invariable characteristic of truth.</p></div2><pb n="42" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. MARCH, 1898. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is publisht by the "United
                            Society of Believees" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all communications
                            to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. One copy one year, postage paid. .50 A
                            cross in the margin will show that your subscription has closed. Remittances for
                            subscription by Money Order should be on the Post Office at Concord, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">January. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Rain. Snow. 1897. 23.68 .75in. 2
                                ft. 1898. 25.45 1.25 " 3&gt; " Highest Temp, during this mo. 48 above 0. Lowest " " " " 12
                                below" Number of rainy days " " 1 " " snowy " " " 8 " clear " " " 7 " " cloudy" " " 15
                                We are having an old-fashioned winter of blizzards, pelting snow, and sleety rains,
                                putting us in mind of Thompson's reflection from a review of winter: " "Tis clone! Dread
                                winter spreads Ms latest gloom, And reigns tremendous o'er the conquered year, How dead
                                the vegetable kingdom lies! How dumb the tuneful!Ye good distrest The storms of wintry
                                time will quickly pass, And one unbounded spring encircle all." When we reflect upon the
                                uncertainty of life for man and beast, by storms and other disasters by land and sea and
                                by human invention, it makes one yearn for that unbounded spring encircling all. The
                                late catastrophe in Boston caused by the late blizzard sweeping from their fastening the
                                electric wires, causing such terrible destruction, is a strong evidence, that the
                                greatest blessings, under certain conditions, may prove the greatest curse.
                                Notwithstanding we have some unpleasant weather, yet the blessing of a pleasant home,
                                interested Brethren and Sisters, and a sufficiency of the comforts of life, and united
                                by the bond of peace, love and union, are still ours to possess. "Thanks to God for
                                every blessing; Thanks to God for what we've gained, Thankfulness we are possessing,
                                Holiness is here obtained." Our Ministry, having given us their farewell blessing, were
                                taken to West Pittsfield, Feb. 2, enroute for Watervliet, where they will tarry for one
                                month, at least, blessing and being blest. At present date the business of our family is
                                getting wood to keep us warm and harvesting ice to keep us cool. An electric road is
                                being built from Pittsfield, west, to Tillitston's factories, if not to West Pittsfield.
                                The prospect is that the State road will be built this year to New York state line, if
                                not further. New York state is waking up to improve its highways. After a time this old
                                Earth will be better fitted for a pleasant dwelling-place for Man, and he may be better
                                fitted to dwell upon it. Calvin G. Reed. North Family. Feb. 1898. We are in the midst of
                                a snow-storm whose force, at present, cannot seemingly be spent. This reminds us of the
                                beautiful poem, "Snow-Bound." "The morning broke without a sun; We lookt upon a world
                                unknown, TERMS. <pb n="43" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 43 On nothing we could call our
                                own. Around the glistening wonder bent The blue walls of the firmament, No cloud above,
                                no earth below A universe of sky and snow." With snow above and all around we are
                                literally walled in by banks of snow. The school was not opened on account of the storm.
                                The large tank for hot water which has been located on the fifth floor of dwelling house
                                for many years, has been lowered to first floor, by the skillful management of Elder
                                Charles Greaves and his core of faithful Brethren. It is now connected with the furnace
                                in the cellar and with less fuel we expect to be abundantly supplied with hot water.
                                Sisters, with the help of Brethren, are weaving rugs. When finisht there will be many
                                nice ones for sale. The subject of Vivisection has been pressed upon our attention by
                                workers in the Antivivisection Society. When confined to Medical Colleges, and for the
                                sole purpose of better understanding the human anatomy, even then it is an outrage upon
                                helpless creatures too great for com' pensation in the benefits professedly derived ;
                                but as any evil unchecked leads to greater evil, we have now to work against that
                                feature in public schools which is nourishing in thousands of pupils those sentiments of
                                cruelty which inevitably tend to criminality. We view the cruelties as practiced by many
                                vivisectors as another form of the Inquisition. Should we not do all in our power to
                                lessen evil and increase good wherever we have opportunity? Sarah J. Burger.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Feb. 1898. Fkom the window of our room where we are domiciled penning these Notes, we can
                                look out upon the garden plat where in a few weeks we shall be engaged preparing the
                                ground for the reception of seed with the hope that it will bring fortl many fold of the
                                good things of life in the shape of fruits and vegetables. At present it is a wilderness
                                of snow and ice, and our picture is in the anticipation of an ideal to which we are
                                looking forward for fulfillment. If it was not for this persistent urging to gain
                                possesion of that which at present we do not have, whether in the spiritual or material
                                phases of life, the main stimulus to exertion would be gone and the energy at present
                                displayed would be fossilized in that of an autonomon which is dependent upon power
                                foreign from itself to move it to action. While perusing the last editorial upon the
                                advancement made in dietetic reform in our Communities we were made assured that the
                                world does move and no intelligent person would wish to go back to the (good?) old times
                                of hard cider on the dining table, or the social smoke. "Physician heal thyself," could
                                with propriety be said to the advocate of abstinence front strong drink who was suffused
                                with the fumes of tobacco smoke or chewing the filthy weed. That such habits have a
                                derogatory influence upon the physical, intellectual and spiritual organization of the
                                user is well known. To what extent is determined by the resisting power inherent in the
                                individual constitution. We rejoice in the advancement that has been made, with an
                                earnest hope that the good work will go on to still greater perfection. Hamilton
                            DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Feb. 1898, February came to us on the winds of a blizzard. The snow fell thickly, the
                                wind tost it about in the air and finally piled it in huge drifts in most inconvenient
                                places,, in front of doors and across paths; like giant battlements they stood,
                                requiring; armed forces to break them down. For a while it seemed as tho peace could
                                never be produced from such chaosr but lo ! in a few hours a change is wrought. The next
                                morning the sun, quietly and without hurry, yet with patient persist- <pb n="44" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 44 THE MANIFESTO. ency sends its beams over the earth, subduing the winds
                                until they become a murmur, and then disappear leaving the earth once more to the reign
                                of peace. Nearly every morning during the last month a procession could be seen starting
                                from our valley and wending its way up the mountain sides, there to lay seige to the
                                fort held by the forest kings. In a short time they descend, bringing their captives
                                taking them to the mill at the base of the mountain, where they received a course of
                                training to fit them for future use. Some are to aid as timbers for a new barn in the
                                place of our west barn. The ice harvest has been gathered. The huge blocks, fourteen
                                inches thick have been stowed away, for days which we can hardly imagine at present.
                                With Brother Ira's hand once more at the helm we move steadily onward. Nearly six weeks
                                of the new year has past and as we daily turn the pages of our calendar should not each
                                day bring us nearer to the fulfillment of our resolves. Our aim is, progression; our
                                motto, "Excelsior," so tho each succeeding day brings like duties to perform we may
                                improve by each repetition, until like the road which, continually winding around the
                                mountain, with each turn brings the summit nearer, we may find our steps leading farther
                                from the self-life, and nearer to the life divine. We would gladly reach our hands to
                                our young friends in each Society for a firmer grasp, while we unite in a resolve that
                                our future lives shall be deeper consecration, more earnest endeavor, and greater
                                loyalty to faith;that from the seeds we now are sowing may grow a harvest to bless the
                                reapers by and by. Fidelia EstabrooJc.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Feb. 1898. Mid-winter is here. Snow lies in huge banks all about us, and it is often
                                remarked,"We are having a real old-fashioned winter." Several fierce storms have visited
                                this vicinity lately making prisoners of us for a day or two and weather severely cold
                                at the same time. Now the days are growing longer and we are rejoicing in the thought
                                that winter will not last forever. The Brethren succeeded in harvesting a quantity of
                                fine ice before the big storm came. At present some are engaged in lumbering. A brother
                                has lately felled an old growth pine, four and a half feet in diameter at the base.
                                Since last Nov. we have been studying the rules of music. An hour each day for the
                                different classes has been spent under the careful training of Sister Ednah Fitts, to
                                which we gladly respond. We most certainly appreciate the kindness of our brothers and
                                sisters of Canterbury who are so lovingly bestowing upon us from their fund of
                                knowledge. Elder Wm. Dumont and Br. Wm. Paul are kindly giving their time caring for our
                                aged Father Samuel Kendrick who is still lingering with us,"Only waiting till the
                                shadows are a little longer grown." Ada S. Cummings.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoossee, Florida" TEIform="index"/>Narcoossee, Fla.</head><p TEIform="p">Feb. 1898. The incoming year has dawned upon Florida with brighter hopes than was at
                                first expected. Not only has Florida overcome the recent disaster of the freeze but at
                                this early date almost everything denoting a visitation from Jack Frost has been removed
                                and the farm and garden have again been planted. The crops are looking well. The orange
                                groves which have been the main dependence of income, was not so badly injured as at
                                first reported. In some sections of the town of Narcoossee the groves received no
                                perceptible damage, while others show it in a small degree. One writer says we can
                                balance our accounts this way,"From five to seventyfive per cent of the foliage is
                                hurt." This shows that the frost came in waves. It struck some locations heavier than
                                others. <pb n="45" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 45 If the farmer and gardener can not pile
                                up money as fast as he can at the north, he is able to make for himself a good
                                comfortable home. The greatest of all gains made by the people of this state is seen in
                                their temper and in thought. Experience has brought to them the full conviction that
                                they can live for themselves. There will be no such time of general depression as we
                                have experienced Our self-confidence has been restored and without arrogance we stand on
                                our own feet. We have had at our home for the past three weeks our Br. Francis
                                Pennebaker of Pleasant Hill, Ky. His general health has not been so good as he would
                                wish and he comes to obtain more health. So you see, Florida has some advantages. We
                                hail the New Year! We need only play our part. Florida will do the rest. Please say that
                                the Mercury in time of the freeze indicated seven degrees below freezing. Andrew
                                Barrett.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Feb. 1898. From the heart of the Christian, swells out the anthems of gratitude; each
                                stanza noted with good deeds to be done for the good of humanity. As a nation we can
                                render tributes of praise to the noble workers in the field of life, for sacrifice given
                                to better human conditions. Thankful that no blotch of cruelty smears our republic life,
                                like that which defiles the Turkish nation, whose fanatical, blood-thirsty spirit, dealt
                                death and misery to thousands of helpless Armenians and Greeks. Thankful that no
                                tyrannical force has been spent upon subjects like unto that which the cruel Spanish
                                executed upon our Cuban neighbors ; also thankful that no spirit of covetousness like
                                the greedy European Powers has moved us to grasp the Hawaiian Islands. Thankful that at
                                the head of the grandest cause of fellow helpfulness to souls struggling in the
                                whirlpool of intemperance, stands a pure, intelligent and active woman, Frances Willard,
                                of whom a nation may well be proud. Thankful that at the head of our government, is one
                                we can look upon with respect, and trust his generalship in matters pertaining to
                                America and her institution's welfare. Thankful that no famine like unto that which has
                                smitten beautiful India, has spread a covering of woe upon our country, and very
                                thankful for the encouraging signs that come from every field of Christian labor, that
                                the past year excels any previous one in work done in the name of Christ and Christian
                                brotherhood. Thankful for love and good wishes brought by our revered Br. John Cumings:
                                from our Enfield, Conn, kindred at whose home he spent a few days. We extend our thanks
                                and grateful feelings for kindness extended to him. An important and lengthy work, of
                                painting the one hundred and eighty-twa windows of our Dwelling House, is being done by
                                Sisters, Ann Cumings, Marinda Keniston and the writer. George II. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Feb. 1898. If a blizzard can add any beauty to the winter season, then we are having a
                                beautiful season. On the last day of January some ten inches of snow fell somewhere.
                                During the storm of snow came the storm of wind and all day and all night the snow fell
                                and the wind howled. The elements brought about a wonderful work, and in some places the
                                snow was piled into huge drifts, and all of one day but few persons attempted to walk
                                out, and for two days the roads were so blockt with snow that no carriages could be used
                                and consequently we had no mail. Directly in front of our dwelling we had a beautiful
                                drift of not less than five feet deep, wholly covering the path where the people wisht
                                to walk. Such are the beauties of winter. The ice is being harvested and is reported to
                                be fifteen inches thick. <pb n="46" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 46 THE MANIFESTO. 1700 cakes 22x22 are
                                expected to be taken from the water. Eighty-five gallons of milk are reported at the
                                dairy per day. With a separator and a churn most of it is soon converted into butter,
                                and all that can be spared is sent to market. A few orders for Sweaters demand active
                                work in that department for several days. We are thankful for all blessings, temporal
                                and spiritual. Henry C. Blinn.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Elder Henry;--I presume it would be interesting..." TEIform="index"/>Beloved Elder Henry;--I presume it would be interesting...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Idaho, Star, Ada County, January 17, 1898" TEIform="index"/>Stab, Ada Co,. Idaho. Jan. 17,
                            1898.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Beloved Eldek Heney;I presume it would be interesting to some of the readers of The Manifesto
                            to hear from the State of Idaho, especially from one of the household of faith. We have six
                            inches of snow but the mercury has only been down to five of zero, and winter did not
                            commence until the 2nd of Jan. The winter months seem to be propitious for revivals, which
                            are well attended. Two ministers of Boise City are conducting a revival in the Christian or
                            Campbellite church at Star and I have attended several of their meetings. These blind guides
                            are clamoring for unity of all churches, yet they claim their church advocates the doctrines
                            of Christ and all others should fall in line with them. But the Baptists and several other
                            churches claim they are the true followers of Jesus, yet we are told that,"By their fruits
                            ye shall know them." The minister stated last evening that none could claim to be followers
                            of Jesus the Christ unless they "walk even as He walkt and purified themselves even as He
                            was pure." I entertain grave doubts as to whether, one of his vast audience comprehended
                            those sayings, for none can "walk as he walkt" and live the pure life of Jesus and Ann and
                            their followers and yet live in the works of the flesh. I preacht three sermons in the
                            Methodist church a short time since and a few days ago I learned they did not want any
                            doctrine preacht in their church which did not grant them license to live in the flesh and
                            that marriage is a divine institution. My text"Be of good cheer, I have overcome the world."
                            In the course of my remarks I called the attention of my audience, to what John meant where
                            he said,"All there is of the world, the lust of the flesh, the lust of the eye and the pride
                            of life," stating that these cor-, rupt conditions must be overcome or we could find no
                            place in his kingdom. The good Apostle said truly,"So then they that are in the flesh can
                            not please God." Rom. viii., 8. Why, because they have their husbands and wives to please.I
                            Cor. vii., 32, 33, 34. For this cause alone I am denied the use of the church. Many
                            nonprofessors said they would come and hear me, because I explained passages of Scripture,
                            that other ministers dare not handle but the good Christians have refused to let me occupy
                            their churches. Now dear Brethren and Sisters I can truly say I am living the virgin life
                            and shall hold out to the end of my faith. Paul said,"He that preaches the Gospel should
                            live of the gospel." May The Manifesto live long to enlighten this darkened and sin-curst
                            world, is my earnest desire. Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bellmire, William W." TEIform="persName"/>William W. Bellmiee.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>OUR EXCHANGES.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian" TEIform="index"/>Christian
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Christian, is publisht by Dr. T. J. Shelton of Little Rock, Ark. Dr. Shelton is a
                                healing medium, but we will copy his own word. "No one can heal. The Word, the I Am, the
                                Yahveh, is the only healer. There is but one Physician." </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soothsayer" TEIform="index"/>The Soothsayer
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> The Soothsayer before us is No.
                                1 of Vol. I. from the Soothsayer Pub. Co. of New York City. It says,Our columns will be
                                open to the Spiritist, the Theosophist, the Christian Scientist and the advocates of
                                every form of investigation of the occult phases of human life.</p></div3><pb n="47" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New Hampshire people" TEIform="index"/>New Hampshire People
                            </head><p TEIform="p">New Hampshire People is the leading Democratic paper of the City of Concord, N. H. It was
                                establisht in 1809 and through this long series of years, it has been the unswerving
                                advocate for Democratic principles. It has recently past under the editorial management
                                of George F. Willey. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Modern philosopher" TEIform="index"/>The Modern Philosopher
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Modern Philosopher a monthly Magazine for progressive people.
                                It is under the Editorial management of Albert Chavannes and is publisht at Knoxville,
                                Tenn. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Temple" TEIform="index"/>The Temple
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Temple is a monthly magazine devoted to the fuller unfoldment of the Divinity
                                of Humanity and issued by The Temple Pub. Co. of Denver, Col.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Freedom" TEIform="index"/>Freedom
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Freedom is a Journal of
                                Realistic Idealism. Edited and publisht by Helen Wilmans at Sea Breeze, Fla. Freedom is
                                publisht in the interest of Mental Science and the Editor makes this statement,'"I can
                                cure those whom the doctors have failed to cure." </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Young people at work" TEIform="index"/>Young People at Work
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Young People at Work is publisht in
                                the interest of the Young People's Societies of the Churches of Hartford and vicinity.
                                The managing Editor is Albert II. Crosby. The paper is well worthy of universal
                                circulation. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harbinger of light" TEIform="index"/>The Harbinger of Light
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> The Harbinger of Light is devoted to Zoistic Science, Free Thought,
                                Spiritualism and Harmonical Philosophy. It is publisht by VVm, H. Terry of Melbourne,
                                Aus. and is an able exponent of Spiritualism and Advanced Thought. Qn Germany, horses
                                are shod with paper shoes and their durability and lightness are found very
                                satisfactory. 2j^=The youngest preacher, known, is L. Lawrence Dennis of Atlanta, Ga. He
                                is four years old and converses readily on subjects in the Old and New Testaments. Some
                                think he is gifted with supernatura powers. sickness of the "Ed." has caused the delay
                                in the publication of The Manifesto this month. We hope it may be better next month,
                                that is the health side of the case.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Make your most simple act complete" TEIform="index"/>Make your most simple act complete
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Make your most simple act complete; do your most common daily duty from its divinest motive,
                            and what a change will come! Still your life will need days of retirement, when it will shut
                            the gates upon the noisy whirl of action and be alone with God. But it will not be upon them
                            that it will mostly depend for spiritual nourishment. They will be like great exceptional
                            banquets and extraordinary feasts of grace. The daily bread of spiritual life, the ordinary
                            feeding of the soul on God, which really makes its sustenance, will be in the perpetual
                            doing of the works of life for Him. The real sitting down to be fed will be mysteriously
                            identical with the most eager and energetic standing on the feet to do His will.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brooks, Phillips" TEIform="persName"/>Phillips Brooks.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hubbard, Melinda" TEIform="index"/>Melinda Hubbard
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Melinda Hubbard, at Enfield, N. H. Jan. 23, 1898. Age 78 years 5 mo. and 14 days. She had
                                been with the Society for sixty years and was widely known and universally loved and
                                respected both by those of her own home and many who had shared her loving ministrations
                                outside the home circle. Such, we know hear the welcome summons, "Well done, good and
                                faithful servant, enter thou into the joy of thy Lord. R. C. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shepard, Hannah P." TEIform="index"/>Hannah P. Shepard
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Hannah P. Shepard, at East
                                Canterbury N. H. Feb. 1, 1898. Age 56 years, 11 mo. and 20 days. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Noyes, Thomas" TEIform="index"/>Thomas Noyes
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Thomas Noyes, at
                                Sabbathday Lake, Me. Feb. 9, 1898. Age 84 years 2 mo. and 6 days. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hastings, Harriet" TEIform="index"/>Harriet Hastings
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Harriet Hastings, at
                                East Canterbury, N. H. Feb. 22, 1898. Age 90 years 9 mo. and 11 days. JL Jn.lL</p></div3></div2><pb n="48" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Popular monthly" TEIform="index"/>Popular Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">What will no doubt prove the most practical and best illustrated magazine article on the
                                Klondike gold regions that has yet been publisht is announced to appear in Frank
                                Leslie's Popular Monthly for February. It is written by Henry Clay Oolver, a wellknown
                                resident of Seattle, and treats the.subject in a simple yet exhaustive manner. After
                                describing the various expeditions that have set out from Seattle for Dawson City, the
                                author gives some valuable and interesting information to those about to embark for the
                                gold regions, including a list of necessary provisions, utensils, etc., to last a man
                                for a year. This article is supplemented by one giving a general description of Alaska,
                                its resources, people and customs, by R. H. Herron. There will be more than thirty fine
                                half-tone illustrations of scenes and people in the gold regions and parts of the
                                Territory and a handsome map of Alaska, 17x23 inches, showing the location of the places
                                of interest along the Yukon and the Klondike. Those who arefpreparing to take advantage
                                of the opportunities presented in Alaska, and those who are only indirectly interested
                                in the new El Dorado, should by all means read these articles. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological Journal and Science of Health" TEIform="index"/>The Phrenological Journal
                                and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal
                                and Science of Health, for February opens with a character sketch of Charles T. Yerkes
                                by J. A. Fowler. Phrenotypes and Side views, No. 20. by H. S. Drayton, M. D. This
                                article has special reference to the nose, and to make it still more interesting, it has
                                several illustra-, tions. Charactei sketch of Rev. Wm. L.Watkin son by D. T. Elliott. A
                                remarkable skull of which three illustrations are given. This skull is said to have been
                                taken from a shell mound in the state of Washington. An Interview with Mrs. E. J. Bacon,
                                by Jessie A. Fowler. Mrs. Bacon has in possession the renowned stone portrait an
                                illustration of which may be seen in the Journal. An interview with the Superintendent
                                of Prison industries, F. H. Mills. The healing Art in the twentieth century, by Susanna
                                W. Dodds, M. D. Child Culture, by Uncle Joseph is interest ing and prettily illustrated,
                                and then comes the Inquisitive Boy. Many other articles of interest will please the
                                careful reader and furnish him with a fund of information. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of Hygeio-Therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                                for January is very interesting. Dr. Gifford has an article on the use of salt and
                                contends that its use is not a necessity. He then extends his article and treats of the
                                cause of Dropsy and then of the treatment. Prof. Bland has an article on A Big
                                Bacteriological Blunder, which has diverted the attention of physiologists from the
                                correct line of investigation. Prof. Allison says, "You rarely find one who believes
                                what he eats has any influence on his character." "Faith," says the Bible, "comes by
                                hearing" and it may come by reading. Read and see. Dr. T. V. Gifford &amp; Co.
                                Kokomo, Ind. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Israel's messiah or why the jews reject christ" TEIform="index"/>
                                Israel's Messiah or Why the Jews Reject Christ
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Israel's Messiah or Why the Jews Reject Christ, By H. L. Hastings. Mr.
                                Hastings sends forth this little book trusting that it will assure the careful reader
                                that the reason Why, will be made perfectly plain. Any one interested in this subject
                                can easily be assured from the many proofs which the little work contains. It costs only
                                five cents and can be obtained at 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Guessing enigmas is an innocent recreation..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Guessing enigmas is an innocent recreation...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Guessing enigmas is an innocent recreation; but guessing enigmas in order to
                                        win a prize and paying a sum of money or purchasing an article, for the
                                        privilege, is a "game of hazard, in which small sums are ventured for the chance
                                        of obtaining a larger value, either in money or in other articles,"and this is
                                        Worcester's definition of a lottery. Its motive is "to gain something for
                                        nothing," which is the motive for gambling. Its effects upon the mind and
                                        character of its victim may be as injurious as the effects of gambling. Its
                                        prizes are given on the same principle by which a gambling house divides the
                                        "bank" among the fortunate gamesters. It allures to repeated trials, not only
                                        novices but also successful as well as unsuccessful guessers, by the chance it
                                        offers of winning coveted aniDunts and by the certainty of receiving a certain
                                        value, as a package of tea or a subscription to a paper, in return for trifling
                                        outlays. The well-baited inducements offered by the papers which have recourse
                                        to the enigma lottery, for the double object of notoriety anil of increasing
                                        their subscription lists, constitute, in fact, lottery, advertisements, and
                                        subscriptions to these papers are sold in place of lottery tickets.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Contributor" TEIform="index"/>The Contributor.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New Hampshire register" TEIform="index"/>New Hampshire Register
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> New Hampshire Register, which has come to be an indispensible hand-book for business and
                                professional men, has appeared for 1898. The book was never so complete as this year,
                                and we note that it has beenincreast by over forty pages not counting advertisments. The
                                greater part of this increase represents added names, so that the Directory is as nearly
                                complete as such a book is ever likely to be. A careful estimate of the added names
                                makes the net increase over 5000 names, Many names of dead men have been dropped so that
                                the Register is up to date this year. The calendar, pages for daily memoranda, lists of
                                United States and State officials, officers of various State associations and societies
                                and all the other information about New Hampshire which has made the Register such a
                                handy book of reference for so many years will be found brought fully up to date. The
                                price remains at 25 cents and the book may be procured of local dealers or will be sent,
                                post paid on receipt of price, by Wm. J. Drew, Concord, N. H.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
Lust summer The < >i ti.ook inside the offer
of three prizesthe largest being i?li)0for the
best siceounts of vac-sit ion experiences, to be
illustrated by photographs tiik en by the authors.    The unique feature of this contest wsis
the awarding of the prizes on the combined
merits of articles and pictures.   The competition was closed on Jan. 15 last.   Very nearly
two hundred articles and not fsir from two
thoussuid photographs were received in response to the offer, sind the editors feel assured that the result will be ext remely gratifying
to the readers of Tiik < M tmmik's Recreation
Number (publisht annually in .June,) which
will contain the three prize art ieles snul   illustrations, together with two or three of the
best of those which did not receive prizes.
($3 a year.   The Outlook Co., 1.'! Astor l'lsiee.
New York.)
Tin.1 readers of Tlic Ladies' Home loitmal are
about as responsive a clientele a* any magazine possesses.   About six months ago the
Philadelphia magazine started to publish a
series of practical architectural plans showing how artistic, houses con hi he built at mod
erate cost.   It employed a special architect,     j
and his work was certainly artistic.    Besides
ths plans it agreed to furnish complete specifications of each house at a minimum cost.
Thousands of people liked the plans given
and the series has been a great, success for
the magazine.   This spring the building of
over five hundred houses, vsirying in cost from
iiMoOOto $7000 each, will be started in different
parts of the country by Journal resulers, in ;iddition to over one hundred other houses
which have already been built.
Newspaper Advertising in tiik Cxited
States.   A book of two hundred pages, containing a catalogue of sibout six thoussmd
newspapers, being all that are credited by the
American Newspaper Directory (December
edition for lS'.iT.) with having regular issues of
maps of each smd every State of the Ainericsin
lTnion, naming those towns only in which
there are issued newspapers having more than
1.000 circulation.   This book (issued December
15, IS(iT) will be sent, postage paid, to smy
address, on receipt of one dollar.    Address
The (ieo. P. Kowell Advertising Co., 10 Spruce
st. New York.
HOW TO MAZE MONEY!
If you are out of employment and want
a position paying you from $.">() to $100
monthly clear above expenses by working
regularly, or, if you want to increase your
present income from 200 to $500 yearly,
by working at odd times write the GLOBE
CO. 728 Chestnut St. Phila., Pa. stating
age, whether married or single, last or
present employment, and you can learn
how to make more money easier and
faster than you ever made before in your
life.
Makes $150 Per Month.
A IT P 11 t 0 cau eas'ly in'l^o s.j.OO to $10,00
A g, u 11 I u per day selling my Latest Improved   Lightning    Fire   Kindler    which
starts fires without the use of other kindling.    Lasts for years and sells for a
small price.    .1. K. Wan-en. Lafayette, Ind.
wriies that he made SIT.00 in one day selling them.    .L  ('.   1!.   Neeland,   Vineland.
Minn., writes that he made at the rate of
2  per hour.    J.   11.   Hudson,    Dickson,
Tenn., writes that he is making sl50 per
month.    Ladies or gentlemen either can
sell them.    One good agent wanted in every town.    Write to-day for particulars.
1). F. WALLACE. ' Smithville, Tenn.
SHARER HAMAMELIS
(W1TCHHAZEL,)
A. remedy for Cuts, Burns, Scald.s,
Headache, Sore Throat and all
cases [of external inflammation
Taken internally for Bowel
Complaint, Bleeding: of the
Lungs or Bowels, and for
all aches and pains.
For use externally, bathe the parts and
lay on a cloth wet with the Extract,     Internally, take one half teaspoonful three
times a day.    Use hot or cold.
Ask your druggist for it or send your
order to Arthur Bruce.
East Canterbury, N. H.
SHAKES   THEOLOGY.
A Book of 320 pages.    It contains not
only the Siiakek's Fajtii but explains
Scripture Metaphor.    By H. L. Eads.
Address H. C. Bli.w, EastCaxteeihuy,
X.   II.
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
A PRIVATE   SCHOOL
For Girls will "be opened, at
]VXt. H.etoaiTLOii. N. Y.
Oct. 1, 1897,
Address        Eldrexs Anna White,
Mt. Lebanon, Columbia Co., 2V". 1".
Instructions in English and the Industiial Branches, board, etc., two hundred
dollars a year, consisting of two terms of
twenty weeks each.    Fifty dollars to be
paid at beginning and fifty dollars at close
of each term.
Competent and experienced instructors
at head of each department.
Location among the beautiful Berkshire
Hills.
Hygienic condition perfect, and all
healthful recreation encouraged.
Careful attention given to moral as well
as mental and physical development.
Here are taught hand and machine sewing, plain and fancy knitting.    With help
of instructors each girl will learn to keep
her wardrobe in repair.     Younger girls
will assist in dining-room, duties about
the house, and light ironing;  larger ones
in general house-work; strength and
adaptability being duly considered.
Those who remain long enough will
have unequalled opportunities to become
proficient in the management of households where order, cleanliness and the
best methods are considered of first importance.
No uniform dress required.    Simplicity
in make and durability in material the
chief requisite.    All articles to be laundered should be particularly plain and
simple.    No jewelry allowed.
AUTHORISED   RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY.
Pric, 10 cts..
Sketched of Shakers and Siiakeiusm. A synopsis of the United Society oe Believers in Christ's Second
Appearing. Illustrated. By Giles
B. Avkry.     Price 1 o cts.
Royal makes the food pure,
wholesome and delicious.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure
ROYAL BAKING POWDER CO., NEW YORK.
50   YEARS'
EXPERIENCE
Trade Marks
Designs
Copyrights &c.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain our opinion free whether an
invention is probably patentable.' Communications strictly confidential. Handbook on Patents
sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice, without charge, in the
Scientific American.
A handsomely illustrated weekly. Largest circulation of any scientific journal. Terms, $','> a
year; four months, $1.   Sold by all newsdealers.
MUNN & Co.36iBroadway New York
Branch Office, 625 F St., Washington, D. C.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>