<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1308" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">13</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><date value="18830801" TEIform="date">August 1883</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">169-192</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="13" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> VOL. XIII. AUGUST. NO. 8. SHAKER MANIFESTO. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT
                        SHAKERS, N. Y. "Blessed are they that hear the word, of God and keep it." SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H.
                        1883. </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p> [Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="169" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><!--                    <div2 type="none">
                        <p> CONTENTS A Trinity, Gods Kingdom, Oue Father's House, Art Thou a Christian ? Act Well tour
                            Part, John Wadleigh, Benefit of Silence, Thy Will be Done, Union, Fishing for Men, Hear
                            much, say Little, Sympathy, Consideration, Morning Thoughts, Letter Box, Page. 169 - 170 173
                            - 174 175 177 - 178 - 179 181 182 183 Page. Notes, - .....184 Aphorisms, -.....- 185 Our
                            Teeth,  " Temperance Speech, ...-" One "with God, -House & Farm, .-...
                            187 The Stinging Tree, - 188 Wanted, Men, ._-.-. Life in the Woods, No. 5, - 189 Discharged
                            for Honesty, - 190 Arab Peculiarities, .'-...Music, Cross of Christ, - - - - 191 Books
                            & Papers- 192 Stick to old Friends, .... Deaths, ......- 193 Vol. XIII.
                            AUGUST, 1883. No. 8. </p>
                    </div2>--><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trinity" TEIform="index"/> A TRINITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>OLIVER C. HAMPTON</byline><p TEIform="p"> What are Religion—Science—Reason? Those mellowing forces all sublime, Which blend their
                            blessings all in season, To light the gloomy crypts of Time; Or, like the calm and gentle
                            showers In April Ides or early May, Unfolding gay, aromal flowers To deck the dreamy, vernal
                            day. Religion! what intense emotion Thy very name and need implies, The wave song of the
                            calm, oid Ocean With thy enchantment faintly vies. All poesy, how dead and soulless, Without
                            thy resurrecting beam, As gleaming sun on Gladiolus, To warm, to chasten and redeem. Thy
                            faith, thy hope, thy glad fruitions, Lift soul and body from the grave Of rudimental, low
                            conditions, From Sin's remorse and sorrow's wave. That hideous spectre of delusion,
                            Agnosticism, drear as Hell, Against thy peace makes no intrusion, Thy gentle force cannot
                            expel. And thy serene, immortal glory Is culminated all in this, That pilgrims of thy
                            halcyon story Exult in never ending bliss. And Science, systematic power, Untangling all the
                            strands of life, Relieving man's intensest hour Of doubt and weary, mental strife,—
                            Relieving all the ways mysterious, All footprints of supernal Love From terrors of a fate
                            imperious, Grim fiat of an angry Jove; Reducing to their proper level All tho't-germs, solid
                            or unsound, A wrathful God or ruthless Devil, With equal ease to powder ground In these
                            remorseless mills of science; Mills of the gods that grind so slow; Yet yield to error no
                            compliance, Or whom or what they overthrow. Pale superstition fears and trembles, And sin
                            and ignorance stand aghast, When science her dread host assembles Their structures all to
                            blight and blast. O, sacred handmaid of Religion, Be mine, thy mysteries to explore, The
                            beauties of thy realm are legion, Thy blessings fresh, forever more. Bright truths m endless
                            evolutions From chaff of wrong and error sifting, Thy bless'd and growing institutions, So
                            purifying and uplifting, Shall never cease to bless the nationsSo long as time and earth
                            endures, Dispensing grandest inspirations <pb n="170" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 170 THE MANIFESTO. In rich
                            and everlasting stores. Then comes in glory human reason, God-given guide to finite man,
                            Both instant, in and out of season, All things of consciousness to scan. Fast faithful Mend,
                            thro' all the ages, Unless by curse of sin defied, Mild lamp of light to saints and sages,
                            "Who thro' all time have lived and died In weal or woe, in fast allegiance To thy rapt
                            oracles of right, To thy suggestions all obedience, Life's dusky paths to cheer and light.
                            Thou sit'st in regal state and royal, And man thy solemn mandate hears, And by thy sacred
                            counsels, loyal, His conscience renovates and clears. Dread, peerless throne of arbitration,
                            Twixt what we are and ought to be In science, art and inspiration, Thou judgest all our
                            destiny. Cold intellect and calm emotion Own equally thy matchless power, And earth, and
                            air, and sky, and ocean, Vast, rolling orb, and tiny flower, And all arcana deep of nature,
                            Here and hereafter, heav'n and hell, Creations all and their Creator, Their mysteries thou
                            unravelest well. This sacred trine—Religion, Science, .Reason, More all the wheels of
                            destiny for man. With these there is no break, revolt or treason, Eternal concord is their
                            peaceful plan. Who would divorce this mystic band supernal' Or break the ties their holy
                            compact rule With atheistic ministry infernal, Must be a gibbering madman or a fool.
                            Agreement, perfect union, reign forever Among all truths wherever felt or found, If any
                            twain, man turning fool might sever, This all the rest might hopelessly confound, If science
                            could with holiest religion Antagonize or make the smallest jar, [region, T'would make all
                            heaven a hell beleaguered And fill the Universe with fiercest war. If pure Religion could
                            conflict with reason And human fate could thus be cut in two, Both halves would be in
                            everlasting treason And God himself a hideous bugaboo. Nay, cease forever this egregious
                            folly, Antagonizing truths with other truths In reason's view, a faith most melancholy,
                            Which only bat-eyed superstition soothes. The truths of sweet religion, reason, science, Are
                            easy, pleasant, all, to reconcile; Unless to common sense we bid defiance, And put our
                            confidence in errors vile. From age to age, like silent dews of Hermon, Distills for every
                            weary, yearning child This pure, this peaceful, elevating sermon, Whereby all truths are
                            blent and reconciled, And still shall sound unto remotest ages This sacred trine of truth
                            and beauty fair [pages Whose light hath gleam'd on all the burning Of past and present
                            hist'ry everywhere. Bright horoscope of future gain and glory, Vast combination of all form
                            and force, Not fickle, fragile, vain or transitory Shall be thy ceaseless upward, onward
                            course. All swift progression and all evolution, From low to high, depend upon ye three,
                            Soul, intellect, and most divine emotion, But in your holy union can be free And normal,
                            timely, and in due proportion, Developed perfectly lor earth or heaven, Dissolve the trine
                            and monsters of distortion Evolve the sins that cannot be forgiven. Religion, may I ever own
                            thy power. Pure science, lead me by thy sacred light, Blest reason, me direct in every hour,
                            As onward, upward still I take my flight To regions pure oi higher inspiration, Of holier
                            tho'ts and actions ever more, Where from sublimest bights of elevation All planes of Love
                            and Truth I may explore. Union Village, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's kingdom,--it's life" TEIform="index"/> GOD'S KINGDOM-ITS LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B" TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p"> Spiritually, as physically, when the pabulum of life is scaut, and hunger is rampant,
                            mankind struggle with determined energy to obtain sustenance ; but, when abundance is
                            dispensed, society becomes dainty ; whimsical and delicate. When the human family,
                            unenlightened, and groping in darkness, stumbled into pitfalls of sin, against the laws of
                            truth and righteousness, and, as the fruit thereof, suffered in sorrow and pain, man was
                            prompted to struggle for light, and emancipation from error; but, when, bathed in the
                            sunshine of truth, by the rays of revelation and science, and a high way of truth is cast up
                            to walk in, and eleared of the stumps and rocks of error, then, there is a tendency to
                            indifference, and listlessness ; to effeminacy and weakness ; a dependence on the
                            institution, and its -provincial strength, instead of personal wrestling for the prize of
                            salvation and redemption ! <pb n="171" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 171 As the belief in the
                            sufferings of Jesus for the sins of professed believers in his mission, induces in an obtuse
                            conscience, a liberty to sin, so the tendency of bylaws, communal
                            organizations,—institutions of safety for souls, in the dispensation of Christ's Second
                            Appearing,— a privilege of fellowship with the pure and good, is, by some, used as a
                            substitute for personal struggle, and wrestling to overcome the powers of sin in the soul of
                            the individual; thus ensues supineness, weakness, stupidity, a lifelessness and want of
                            interest in the attainment of spiritual force ! ! When Institutions survive only by dint of
                            formerly earned respectability, dead weight character, their decease is inevitable. But, if
                            Christianity perishes in the soul of any individual professor, or any community of
                            professors, it is not from outward opposition, but from internal idleness ;—a suicide ! The
                            tendency of religionists, unless constantly supplied with living inspirations, is,
                            graduating to indifferentism ; but, in this condition, man's hope of Heaven dies ; he then
                            sinks into materialism, and lives but for sensual pleasure, which ends in death for both
                            soul and body. A mere ceremonial Christianity, soon becomes not only tasteless, but
                            disgusting. Prayers which do not flow from the soul's vital recesses and consecrated
                            chambers, are like perfumes, wasted on the desert air. A living spirit is shocked at the
                            contradictions between living principles,—Christian, and the practical lives of many
                            Christian professors ; and, yet, custom, fashion, the poise of the multitude, soon fuse the
                            souls of the masses of professors of Christianity into acquiesence. Sorrowful! The
                            bewildering sophism of justification by faith alone, dazes the senses, bedims the spirit's
                            vision, and alone makes possible the organization of a church whose creed is substituted for
                            righteousness of life. Genuine Christianity, which fits the soul for Divine inspirations,
                            will not permit the covering of internal evils, by external professions. But, it is
                            lamentably the fact, that this kind of Christianity, has, at present, very few devotees ;
                            while those professedly Christian churches, falsely so named, that pander most to worldly
                            vices, and selfish greed, which succeeding ages, and non-professing beholders brand as
                            crimes, will be most numerous ! A profession of Christianity which proposes the attainment
                            of Heaven only in the world to come, while countenancing the indulgence of sin in this life,
                            is the curse of the Christian Cause, the bane of true religion. The world is perishing for a
                            religion that makes an end of sinning, and thus introduces heaven upon earth—its advent in
                            the soul of the professor. A claim to a love of God, which does not find expression in love
                            to man, is as frail as a rope of sand. What the world labels Christian, is a vile drug,
                            producing spiritual disease and death, instead of curing the sinner. It would find its
                            analogy in a sick man's contemplating being healed by his prescribing physician using the
                            medicine himself. But, the world desires a Christianity which will save men in their
                            self-hood of sins ; while Christ's Christianity is to save men from this sinful self-hood;
                            and still, the very religion that the world seeks, it despises ! It has lost faith in it,
                            because of its impotency! But, the human soul, like a wind decoyed aeronaut, is peering into
                            universal <pb n="172" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 172 THE MANIFESTO. space to find anchorage,—a place of
                            safety and rest; this is prophetic of a new day ; for "He that seeketh, findeth, and, to him
                            that knocketh, it shall be opened." Humanity is traveling to a new birth ! The tangled skein
                            of the thread of creedal theology,—called popular religion, has strongly tied up the
                            portemonnaie of salvation, and that soul food that satisfies the hungering spirit for Divine
                            Inspirations ; but, the sword of revealed truth will cut its gordian knot, and open a
                            religion whose love to God above is manifest in love to man below. This institutes a kingdom
                            wherein self interest is eliminated ; and inaugurates the platonic philanthropy, and love to
                            humanity, which provides that all gains shall be dedicated to the weal of that kingdom of
                            God, which breathes peace on earth* to man, good will: therefore, no man can come into this
                            kingdom, in its true and spiritual relations, keepingback his possessions. In this kingdom
                            all are servants of God and His Christ; but, in different ranks of service ; hence,
                            obedience to the revealed will of our Heavenly King, is the law of this association. Every
                            true subject stands ever ready for any service unto which the call extends, if able to
                            perform its duties ; giving life, substance and talents, to the kingdom ; and, in these, the
                            King and kingdom are manifested in their glorious dominion ; for every true soldier of
                            Christ, now freed from selfish, worldly cares, is at liberty, like the birds of Heaven, to
                            move where duty in Zion's heavenly interest calls. Souls enveloped in their sin stained
                            garments are repulsive to virgin spirits, clothed in holiness ! Has the Lord instituted any
                            means of soul cleansing? Indeed, He hath not left man without a very efficient soul
                            detergent—an honest confession of every sin&gt; accompanied by sincere
                            repentance,—leaving off*. Then, that universal love, that develops charity and mercy, the
                            ministering evangel which alone can reach their benighted retreat, and lead them out, into
                            the sunshine of God's great salvation, will heal the wounds that sin hath made. But, the
                            Kingdom of God is not formed by coercion ; it is built up by volunteer laborers, who inherit
                            eternal substance ; not as the wages of hirelings, but as heirs,—sons and daughters in the
                            house of our Heavenly Father and Mother. This kingdom permits no extremes of opulence and
                            poverty, but its bounties are the feast of its every subject, and, poverty, unknown.
                            Therefore, when souls are so progressed in godliness that all their interests are merged in
                            the will of the Divine, no selfish desire and purpose can find a residence in their domain ;
                            neither will they contract a larger self interest communistically, solating family from
                            family, and community from community ; but, they will act on the principle that the whole
                            treasure, of souls truly consecrated to the work of building up a "'New, and Heavenly
                            Creation" that centers in God, and all who serve the Lord, will be their welcome guests ;
                            and all who have sinned, and truly confess and repent, will be invited in. This banishes the
                            incentive which propels the selfish man, the man of the world ; banishes the greed of
                            Mammon, and his hireling spoils ; for no man can inherit the riches of the fullness of the
                            Kingdom of God, who selfishly reserves his possessions of private claim ; aye, more, his
                            personal life. But, if souls truly enter God's Kingdom, they will, <pb n="173" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 173 they must lay upon its shrine their only all; for, when their life is merged
                            into this heavenly relation, their whole interest will be like G-od's sunshine, devoted to
                            do good unselfishly, first, to the Household of faith, and thence outward as far as the
                            treasures of their munificence may extend. With true heaven born souls, a selfish portion
                            hoarded, and used only for self, is abhorrent, for their life is swallowed up in the one
                            united inheritance of the saints—the true subjects of Christ's Kingdom. Any other use of
                            gains, starves brotherly and sisterly manhood and womanhood, while the animal body is fed.
                            If the communion table is divided by self interests the Church rends itself into heresies,
                            and ceases to be endued with the Holy Spirit, which i the life of the one united inheritance
                            of Christ's Kingdom. "Let him that readeth understand." And, to rule successfully in
                            Christ's Kingdom one must acquire the virtue to love humanity as God loves ; not sins, but
                            souls ! "All souls are mine, saith the Lord." And, "if ye love those only who love you, what
                            reward have ye ? Do not even the publicans the same ?" Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our Father's house" TEIform="index"/> OUR FATHER'S HOUSE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/> ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p"> Paul, a convened Apostle to the faith of Jesus, and zealous worker and defender of the
                            Church in the first peiitecostal age, when speaking of the earthly tabernacle, and looking
                            towards its dissolution, said : If it were dissolved, we have a house not made with hands
                            eternal in the heavens." He spake of it as a permanent dwelling, also as clothing. As our
                            thoughts turn towards that house we are intuitively led to enquire, What are its component
                            parts ? how made, and of what material is it formed? Certainly it cannot be builded of
                            dissoluable substances like the earthly, and the material bodies which we inhabit. We did
                            not create the elements of which the human structure is formed ; but to a certain extent, by
                            proper food and culture we may shape its features, and add beauty and strength to it and
                            length of days. We reason from the evidence produced to our external senses. If we dwell in
                            the past, and rest upon the experiences of others to the neglect of present duty ; or, if we
                            ignore the past, we cannot employ the present profitably. If we read and rightly understand
                            ancient and modern history, and take lessons from the wise and unwise, and bring forward the
                            Literature, Science and Religion of those of other days, to subserve the present; knowledge
                            thus obtained, is invaluable. The natural is metaphorical of the spiritual; from the former,
                            we generate ideas, and draw conclusions ; and as we advance in knowledge, we see that the
                            purely natural in its proper place, time and season, is as justifiable, as the spiritual in
                            its time and place ; the one is a conduit or stepping stone to the other ; there is no
                            conflict between the two. We find that all material substances, perish with the using, or,
                            are subject to change, by action of the elements. If we, with those materials, build
                            dwellings for the mortal part to inhabit, however deeply the foundations may be laid in the
                            earth, and however strong the superstructure reared upon those foundations may be, yet fire
                            may devour, and floods may devastate. Not so with the <pb n="174" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 174 THE
                            MANIFESTO. spiritual. The "Father's house of many mansions," hath foundations embedded in
                            true principles, strong and enduring as the everlasting hills. Upon those foundations many
                            have builded, and many more will build. If it be so, "that not one good deed is lost, not
                            one petition is unheard, nor forgotten.:" May we not conclude that the glorious house built
                            in the heavens of "lively stones," indissoluble, is formed of imperishable deeds of
                            truehearted, noble, self-sacrificing souls, who give their all to the cause of truth,
                            "consecrate their gains and substance to the God of the whole earth ?" and that the whole
                            building is firmly cemented together with the prayers and intercessions of saints and
                            martyrs? By the Christ Spirit—the Rock of Ages—the basic foundations of God's house were
                            laid; and the same spirit that commenced it will complete the structure, even to the
                            "cap-stone." Every stone in that "house of many mansions,' will be tried and tested. The
                            Angel who holds the plummet and measuring line in his hand, will apply them with exactness,
                            until all is accomplished. God has His instruments and co-workers. In past ages, He has had
                            His agents on the earth plane. Inspired men and women adapted to the time and age in Avhich
                            they lived, have helped to roll onward the car of human progress until the present time ;
                            and He will continue to employ such Agencies. Angels in Spirit Spheres, also work to
                            upbuild, and sustain every part of the fabric, and are more potent in those sphei-es, to
                            give impetus, and hasten the work, than mortals are, or can possibly be. How better can we
                            employ our talents and energies, than to work as bes we may, to help consumate such a
                            glorious design ? Will it not redound to our honor and happiness ? How can we secure
                            treasures in heaven our prospective home in any other way ? It is not by force and power,
                            nor by the wisdom of man, that God's house will be built; but by His Spirit. Let us strive
                            to possess that Spirit. Then we shall not need to wait until the "Head-stone" is brought
                            forth and placed in position; but every stone added to tlie temple, will call forth shouts
                            of triumph; and the Spirit of Zerubbabel which God grant we may all possess, will cry
                            "Grace, grace unto it." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Art tho, indeed, a Christian?" TEIform="index"/> ART THOU, INDEED, A CHRISTIAN? </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Newton, Agnes E." TEIform="persName"/> AGNES E. NEWTON. </byline><p TEIform="p"> To the worthy name of Christian Dost thou hold an honest claim? Art Christ's follower in
                            practice, In thy life, as well as name? Dost thou store and fill thy garners With the best
                            that earth can give,— Can the love of gain control thee And the Christ-life strictly live?
                            "Go sell all!" was Christ's injunction, All forsake, and follow me ! I'm the Way, the
                            Resurrection I'm the Vine, the Living Tree. He claimed those as His relation Who obeyed the
                            will of God; Do ye copy this example, Pattern Him ye claim as Lord? He in tones of living
                            fervor This assertion did declare ; Whoso loveth father, mother,—¦ More, my blessing cannot
                            share. Broad the basis of his friendship, Love, embracing all mankind In a universal
                            kinship, Not to just a few confined. He that seeks his life to cherish, Loses the eternal
                            gain; <pb n="175" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 175 He who freely gives the selfish, May the
                            priceless pearl obtain. Christ proclaimed the resurrection Of the soul from death of sin;
                            And revealed the Virgin order,— "Narrow way," few enter in. To his Father's will and
                            diction, Humbly He resigned his own; Drank the bitter cup, nor murmured— Trod the wine-press
                            all alone. Drink his blood, and share his suffering If ye'd also with Him reign; Live his
                            life of crucifixion Life Eternal to obtain. Ye may follow in the foot-steps Of earth's
                            heroes gone before; But to follow Christ, thy Savior, This, requireth something more. And
                            the cherished name of Christian, Worthily can be applied To him only, who like Jesus, To the
                            world, is crucified. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Act well your part, don't be selfish" TEIform="index"/> ACT WELL YOUR PART, DON'T BE
                            SELFISH</head><p TEIform="p"> WRITTEN FOR TIIE MANIFESTO. ACT WELL YOUR PART, DON'T BE SELFISH. Remember that it is by
                            imparting happiness to others, and making ourselves useful that we receive happiness. Stand
                            by this truth, live it out, and always keep doing something useful for the common good,
                            doing it well, and acting sincerely. Endeavor to keep your heart in the attitude of
                            cherishing good will to all, thinking and speaking evil of no one, and always with a kind
                            word for every body. Selfishness is its own curse, it is a standing vice. The man who does
                            no good gets none. He is like the heath in the desert, neither yielding fruit nor seeing
                            when good cometh, a stunted, dwarfish miserable shrub. Let all your influence be exerted for
                            the purpose of doing all you can for the common good and individual welfare of every one.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Proof Positive" TEIform="index"/> PROOF POSITIVE. </head><p TEIform="p"> Grudges treasured in the heart Show we do not travel, Goodness bids the wrong depart Without
                            stay or cavil; If we wish our brother well Why retain his error,— See it not, and feel it
                            not, But stand forth his Savior.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="John Wadeleigh" TEIform="index"/> JOHN WADELEIGH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/> BY HENRY C. BLINN. </byline><p TEIform="p"> John was the son of Thomas Wadleigh an early proprietor of Perrytown, now Sutton, N. H. He
                            had eight brothers and three sisters, but from this large family he, only, was a Shaker.
                            "Few families in New England have been more respectable, so long lived, so patriotic and so
                            useful as this family of brothers and sisters of Wadleighs." John was born in Hawke, now
                            Danville, N. H. March 1, 1759. Although he was one among the first that entered the Shaker
                            order in N. H. he did not reside in Canterbury till 1792. Ex. Gov. Isaac Hill who visited
                            the Society at Canterbury in 1848 had an interview with John and soon after published the
                            following in the Farmer's Monthly Visitor. "An Unpensioned Revolutionary Veteran." "We had
                            hardly expected at this late period to meet a man in New Hampshire whose recollection should
                            extend back as a participator in the events which occurred on Bunker Hill on the 17th, June
                            1775. In the time of a very pleasant and agreeable visit to our friends of the First Family
                            of Shakers at Canterbury, we took pains to obtain an interview with the oldest man of that
                            Community ; John Wadleigh, aged 92 years. At the age of nineteen he fought side by side in
                            the battle of Bunker Hill with an older brother, the late Thomas Wadleigh, of Sutton. He was
                            then of Col. James Read's regiment who went upon the field with Gen. Stark. "This venerable
                            gentlemen tarried from his work to give us an opportunity <pb n="176" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 176 THE
                            MANIFESTO. for an interview. We found him at the place where he is always busy at work, and
                            in fact would be out of his element if not at work. When the weather is suitable he enjoys
                            being in the open field. In 1789 he was a Shaker in Enfield, N. H. but has lived in
                            Canterbury since 1792. He bought a lot of land after the Revolution, but he says he heard
                            the first sound of the gospel while at Enfield, and was gathered to that place. "During this
                            whole time he has been as enthusiastic as if under a divine impulse in his relig'ous
                            profession, never halting in the zeal and confidence which inspire him to lively activity
                            even at this great age. This man in the last sixty years has probably performed more manual
                            labor than possibly any other man who has ever lived in the State. Within the last twenty
                            years, taking charge of the cultivated fields of the First Family, he has done the work,
                            often, of full two common men ; his diligence has always been unwearied, and he has scarcely
                            ever known one hour of ill health. At this great age, under still severe labor, his sleep is
                            as sound as that of an infant. (This year he is taking care of two acres of beans and has
                            hoed them four times.) "John Wadleigh was a soldier of the Revolution five years. He was at
                            the surrender of FortTiconderoga, May 10, 1775, at the battle of Bunker Hill, June 17, 1775,
                            at the surrender of Burgoyne in Oct. 1777 ; in the Rhode Island Expedition of 1778 and at
                            the surrender of Cornwallis Yorktown, Va. Oct. 19, 1781." Becoming a member of the Shaker
                            Community soon after the close of the war, he never applied for, nor received the pension to
                            which he was entitled by the laws of his country. With the same unswerving courage that he
                            fought against the enemies of his country, he as ably and as willingly manifested while
                            fighting against the enemies of the Lord. Enthusiastic under the Divine impulse, his zeal
                            and confidence in the religious profession which he had espoused was never known to waver.
                            After he had accepted the faith of the Believers, he made a journey to Ashfield, Mass, to
                            have an interview with Mother Ann and the Elders, who were holding meetings in that place.
                            While there, he asked the advice of Mother Ann in reference to the settlement of his
                            temporal affairs, as he was quite anxious to enter the family of Believers. Mother Ann asked
                            ;—Are your parents still living? John replied,—My mother has passed away, but I am living
                            with my father in the town of Sutton, N. H. "Then," said Mother Ann, "I advise you, young
                            man, to return to your home and honestly to confess your sins to your father, and then you
                            will be able to hold your testimony. Own the gospel of Christ wherever you go and that will
                            give you strength and protection. If you are ashamed to own Christ before men, he will not
                            own you before Grodand his angels." For a short season John Wadleigh officiated as an Elder
                            in the first family, at Canterbury, and for twenty years he had the management of the farm,
                            during which time he made many improvements. He passed from this life, Oct. 23, 1852 in the
                            96th year of his age, retaining to the last an active memory and a devoted spirit.
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><pb n="177" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Benefit of Silence" TEIform="index"/> BENEFIT OF SILENCE. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ceeley, Sally" TEIform="persName"/> SALLY CEELEY. </byline><p TEIform="p"> There is great benefit derived from silence and meditation. By these we oft times obtain
                            power, not only to act wisely and truthfully, but by comparing the intended acts of our
                            lives by the example of those who follow Christ in all their walk and deportment. In this we
                            are more able to bring our feelings to harmonize with theirs, and come nearer to that state
                            of perfection than we otherwise could. We have good authority to make this our study by the
                            example of those who have redeemed their souls in our day, and by the testimony oi many in
                            preceding generations. Our first spiritual Parents were silent; bowed before God in deep
                            tribulation of soul, and their spirits breathed prayer. Through all the preceding gifts
                            which have been given of God to his people there has been a sacrifice of the will and
                            natural inclinations by all who obtained them. I have heard the older Sisters with whom I
                            was privileged to live, when a child, speak of threatening dangers which arose in their
                            time, which they passed through unharmed; and that Father Job and Mother Hannah called them
                            to the gift of silence, and prayer to God. At one time they heeded the call so faithfully,
                            they thought one might have heard a pin, if it had fallen upon the floor in the room where
                            they were at work the day succeeding the admonition. Obedience to the voice and spirit of
                            God ever has, and ever will insure a blessing to all souls. When the children of Israel were
                            commanded by Joshua to march around Jericho for six days in succession, he gave an
                            imperative order to them as follows ; "Ye shall not shout, or make any noise with your
                            voice, neither shall any word proceed out of your mouth, until the day I bid you shout."
                            This required silence and watchfulness, but through their obedience they saw and realized a
                            wonderful display of the power of God, as we read in the eighth chapter of Joshua. We also
                            read "Whoso keepeth his mouth and his tongue, keepeth his soul from troubles." And that the
                            prudent shall keep silence in an evil time. The prophet Zechariah commands all flesh to be
                            silent before God. This seems to imply that pleading for our wills to lighten the burden of
                            the cross, or if possible mix flesh and spirit, is not acceptable. There are many truths
                            that prove the benefit of bridling the tongue ; and we know there is no abiding good gained
                            without it. It is the servants of God that possess his love and favor. He has promised to
                            hear while they are speaking, and before they call, to answer. Moses of old saith, "My
                            speech shall distil as the dew, as the small rain upon the tender herb, and as the showers
                            upon the grass." It was this same Moses that argued with the Lord concerning speaking his
                            word to the children of Israel; but through obedience to the call' of God his speech has
                            become as the showers to bring about his purposes. Thus it is with the obedient who
                            persevere with constancy ; the clouds by day, or tempests by night do not change their
                            purpose. Though they are in the midst of deep waters, God is their refuge. Let us be
                            obedient and trust in Him. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><pb n="178" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thy will be done" TEIform="index"/> "THY WILL BE DONE." </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mace, Aurelia" TEIform="persName"/> AURELIA MACE. </byline><p TEIform="p"> Is there any reserve in this ? And can "Thy Kingdom come" unless the will of God is done ?
                            That heavenly Kingdom which we have been so long striving to attain, and so many have fallen
                            in the fearful struggle. Are we able to take it by violence and hold it? We believe that the
                            Holy City, the New Jerusalem hath come down from God out of heaven, and we are privileged
                            spiritually to walk its lovely streets. Here wrangling and confusion are very much out of
                            place, and what would be our appearance in soiled and ragged garments ? Our spiritual robes
                            cannot be clean and white unless we live in purity in thought, word and deed. We have been
                            assured that there are angel bands, who march through the heavens, and surround the Throne
                            of the Highest. How could these be held together unless there was perfect order, and each
                            had his place assigned him and kept himself in it? Do they not resign their spirits, and
                            say, "Thy will be done ?" So also we must resign our spirits, and cheerfully follow that
                            "cloud by day and pillar of fire by night" which goes before the Chosen People, as they
                            travel away from the wilderness of sin. "The tabernacle of God is with man.'' Believing
                            this, we find God in our union and joining to His saints. Separate our spirits from them and
                            we are lost. "He that overcometh will I make a pillar in the Temple of my God, and he shall
                            go no more out; and I will write upon him a new name." This promise is for us if we are
                            worthy ; if not others will take our places. Let us reserve nothing for self, but with full
                            purpose of heart, resolve to carry out, a perfect consecration in our daily lives, "Thy will
                            be done," and realize the blessings that will be sure to follow. West Gloucester, Me. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union" TEIform="index"/> UNION. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Danforth, Nancy G." TEIform="persName"/> NANCY G. DANFORTH. </byline><p TEIform="p"> Believiug that union to the body of Believers is necessary in order to progress in the work
                            of God, we wish to increase our store, that we may travel heavenward, and be able to come
                            into the new earth wherein dwelleth righteousness, that righteousness which admits of no
                            wrong, and where the former things are not remembered, the works of the old creation come
                            not into mind ; but we can labor for all temporal blessings, while our spirits are
                            continually rising over the low degrees of an evil nature ; and by the cross of self-denial
                            constantly ascending higher and still higher in the divine life, until we arrive at the new
                            heavens, where nought but purity reigns, and love to God pervades all. Full well we know
                            that our redemption is not gained by idle wishes or vain aspirations, but it is by
                            self-denial and sacrifice only. When we reflect on those days of deepest sorrow, those
                            nights of bitter agony which our suffering Mother Ann Lee passed through that she might
                            prepare herself a temple for the living God ; How, we ask, are we to become a child that she
                            can own ? Is it by ease, or indulgence in any of the depraved passions or appetites of the
                            human heart ? In no wise, only by continued efforts that we lay hold of eternal life, and
                            have it constantly in possession. "Eternal Vigilence is the price of liberty," and in this
                                <pb n="179" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 179 struggle against self, we grow that strong
                            bond of union which unites us to the whole household of faith, by the tenderest ties of
                            gospel affection,—ties stronger than nature ever knew. When we look abroad over the earth,
                            and behold man made in the image of God, to be a glory to his Creator, what do we behold?
                            what is the present condition of the masses? God is not in all his thoughts, but he is ever
                            following his own passions, seeking pleasure in ungodliness. Where, we ask, is the hand
                            stretched forth to save? Can he ever be reached in mercy? And the answer comes in thrilling
                            tones ; In Zion is salvation for poor suffering humanity—Then how great the responsibility
                            which rests on her inmates, and how few the number to labor for the many millions of earth's
                            inhabitants. We must work, work collectively and individually, work earnestly and
                            consecratedly, till we can fully work for God unreservedly, and feel the blessing of His
                            spirit with us continually. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fishing for men, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>FISHING FOR MEN. NO. 1
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Waugh, John" TEIform="persName"/>BY REV. JOHN WAUGH
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"> [From the <cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Phrenological journal" TEIform="index"/>Phrenological Journal.]</bibl><quote TEIform="quote">The Great Teacher said to his
                                    Apostles after their call: ' 'I will make you to become fishers of men.'* He would
                                    empower them to become the winners of souls. To Peter, the fisherman, he said :
                                    ''From henceforth thou shalt catch men;" the catching being for salvation, not
                                    destruction. Ordinary piscatorial endeavors comprise the death of the prey, but in
                                    this moral labor the caught are transferred from a lower element into a higher, from
                                    one kind of a liie into a better. These fishers of men are not all of one kind*
                                    neither are the fishers of fish. They are of various grades ; being physical,
                                    intellectual, moral, and spiritual. Some address themselves to a part of the
                                    faculties of human nature ; they seem to labor in ignorance whether any department
                                    was made for other realms than the natural, being profoundly agnostic of any light
                                    brighter than the sun, or any worlds beyond the cosmic spheres above. But those who
                                    go down into the waters of life covering these mortal shores are seeking to find man
                                    as he is to know what he should be, and so work out their great ideal to the most
                                    attainable perfection. Let every man be in his own order, ignoring all strife and
                                    selfish rivalries, that each in his own way may contribute to the general success of
                                    all. The anglers in the brooks and rivers, the trollers on the great lakes, the
                                    salmon fishers in Alaska waters, the cod fishers off thn New England coast, the
                                    fishers with nets where the finny tribe go in schools, as well as the hardy toilers
                                    in the Arctic seas, serve as but examples of the variety of endeavors needed in all
                                    parts of the ocean of existence. In our view one of the primest qualifications for
                                    success in this moral-aquatic sphere is love for fishing. Old Isaac Walton went into
                                    ecstasies over its pleasures, saying, "God never did make a more calm, quiet,
                                    innocent recreation than angling." A loved employment, propelled by a strong will,
                                    will never fail to reward the worker. A good piscator can never be made to order
                                    more than a good poet from one utterly destitute of imagination and sublimity. A
                                    sense of duty will never make a Mozart out of a Dr. Johnson ; and there are many
                                    employed as teachers of men who need others to initiate them into the principles of
                                    common sense. Many a fisherman fails because of the absence of the fish; but in
                                    villages and cities the crowds are moving uneaught by the attractions of virtue,
                                    because there are so few to so present her excellencies as to win them into
                                    obedience. The man must be adapted to the calling and the calling to the man. His
                                    meat and drink must be the doing of what his conscience and heart prompt. He must
                                    have self-knowledge in order to know others. A piscator who does not know the nature
                                    and habits of the fish he is in search of will return with but few of them as his
                                    reward. Human nature is a great study for the win~ <pb n="180" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 180 THE
                                    MANIFESTO. Aers of men, and wanting it many whose profession is the benefit of their
                                    fellows become repellants rather than attractives. They never find the road to human
                                    hearts in order to enthrone reformatory good. It is largely owing to the want of
                                    skill in the fishers of men that the fullness of the seas, with all its tide of
                                    life, remains unreached. Good fishermen go to the fish. They rarely wait for the
                                    finny tribes to come to them. They go to their grounds, seek them in their haunts,
                                    and wait for them in their passage. The corrupters of youth, the destroyers of men,
                                    throw out their baits where men most congregate. They spread their nets and allure
                                    with their decoys Like the illegal salmon fishers of Scotland, so graphically
                                    described by Sir Walter Scott in his "Guy Mannering," they attract them by their
                                    torches within range of their slaughtering leisters, or three-barbed prongs, and
                                    carry off their unsuspecting victims. It won't do to stand on formalities when men
                                    are perishing through an ignorance that may be enlightened, or swept away by a
                                    destruction that may be stayed. We need a host of amateurs preparing the way for the
                                    professionals, proving their fitness for the catching of men in order to their
                                    installation for it as their life-calling. He should be regarded as the best
                                    fisherman who gets the most fish, but one who had tried his skill upon all waters
                                    and yet caught nothing should not be slow in concluding that he had mistaken his
                                    calling; to say that he had here and there taken in one should not be regarded as a
                                    corrective. In angling, a great deal depends upon the bait. It should be adapted to
                                    the wants of the fish. The bait should not be too large, neither the line too long.
                                    We may well be amazed at what was thrown to the young in former years. The little
                                    ones were whipped because they could not take in the baits of knowledge given in
                                    incomprehensible rules and the driest of all definitions. Catechisms were too often
                                    given as soul-food made up of dry bones having not a particle of nutriment. Teachers
                                    talked in dead languages. The school was made a house of correction. Biting and
                                    digestion were out of the question. Few would expect fish to bite at the naked hook;
                                    but the little learners were too often given no better : and how often have children
                                    been addressed in a language which pretty well educated adults could not take into
                                    their understandings without a lexicon. Gospel fishermen have let down their baits
                                    from the pulpit with nothing worth biting at. A nibble or two might be given
                                    followed by a general turning away. The baits were too large for ordinary
                                    swallowing. What a vast amount of preaching is worse than lost because too high and
                                    dry—too far removed from human want and comprehension' The fishing should always be
                                    according to the fish. Some swim in deep waters and need a long line to reach them.
                                    Some keep well to the surface; others go in compact bodies, hence we speak of
                                    schools of fish. Some keep by themselves watching for prey near the rocks or under
                                    the shelving banks. Some are bold and fearless, others shy and suspicious. Some can
                                    be driven into the net by shouting and splashing the waters. The larger number can
                                    be caught after a gentle rain in the early morning, or after the sun has passed
                                    under a cloud, all of which is strikingly suggestive of appropriate times and
                                    seasons for the winning c f souls. Bearing in mind the varieties of human nature as
                                    calling for diversity of treatment, Paul tells us that he became all things to all
                                    men—to the Jews as a Jew, to the Greeks as a Greek,—that he might catch some, though
                                    liable to the charge of catching them by guile. Some moral fishermen proceed upon
                                    the supposition that the fish ought to bite because it is their profes" sion to
                                    angle for them; but to the subjects of this labor the matter does not appear in this
                                    light, and he who would benefit the character of his fellows must make it as clear
                                    as he can that the catching will be their gain; that he seeks not theirs, but them,
                                    for better things in the present and the future. All those who make it their
                                    business to win men over from a lower to a higher plane of life must study their
                                    make-up, their physical, intellectual, and moral qualities. A man cannot angle for
                                    smelts as he would for flounders, for trout as he would for perch, or for rock bass
                                    or cod as he would for pickerel or muscalonge; the hooks, lines, baits, and
                                    treatment must be as diverse as the fish sought. Adaptation is a prime requisite for
                                        <pb n="181" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> TPIE MANIFESTO. 181 success in the leadership of mankind,
                                    and -a great many pretentious and fancy anglers, with all the latest improvements
                                    for piscatorial enterprises, return as empty as they went, while some rustic, with
                                    an extemporized pole and simple line, will leave the waters with a string heavy and
                                    shining with their spoils. Often the failure results from a want of observation of
                                    the signs of the skies, seeking for that which is unattainable because absent,
                                    letting the lines down too low when the subjects are near the surface, stopping just
                                    where there should be a beginning, or beginning where there should be an ending. (To
                                    be continued.)</quote></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hear much, but say little" TEIform="index"/>HEAR MUCH, BUT SAY LITTLE
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Francis S." TEIform="persName"/>FRANCIS S. SMITH
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"Hear much, but say little," my
                                    masters — You'll find it an axiom strong— 'Twill save you from many disasters, As
                                    you journey life's pathway along. [bor, Get what knowledge you can from your
                                    neighBut if he speaks ill of a foe, Be silent—let not your tongue labor, 'Tis none
                                    of your business, you know. "Hear much, but say little,"—you'll find it A wise thing
                                    to bridle your speech— There's freedom from trouble behind it— 'Tis better to
                                    practice than preach. If you meet with a wise man or scholar, And out in his company
                                    walk, Let your mind his grand ideas follow, For you nothing will learn if you talk.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York weekly" TEIform="index"/>N. Y. Weekly.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sympathy" TEIform="index"/> SYMPATHY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/> MARY WHITCHER. </byline><p TEIform="p"> Human sympathy, what is it? Just a passing thought or word? Or an inbred true compassion
                            Welling up mankind toward? If the stream hath not a fountain, Thoughts and feelings ebb and
                            flow While the constant love and action, Very few are blest to know, Then true sympathy is
                            god-like, Shining forth as doth the sun, Stationed in the heart or center, Giving warmth to
                            every one. Who inherits hath a blessing, Who hath earned it, greater gain But without it
                            we're possessing Little worth the Christian name. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Consideration" TEIform="index"/> CONSIDERATION. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Williams, Flora" TEIform="persName"/> FLORA WILLIAMS. </byline><p TEIform="p"> What went ye out into the wilderness to see? Matt. xi. 7. These were the words of Jesus to
                            the multitude who had gathered to hear John preach. May we not learn from this that we
                            should always have a worthy object in view in attending places dedicated to religious
                            worship, no matter what the profession of the worshipers may he, a respectful attention is
                            demanded of us as rational beings. It does not become us to act like creatures led by
                            instinct, without reflection or motive. They as the Scripture says, have no understanding
                            and must be guided by those above them. But, God has bestowed upon man a higher form of
                            intelligence capable of comprehending divine truths. And wherein is this pre-eminence to
                            appear but in our acting wisely and with design ? Design is essential to moral conduct, and
                            though a good motive cannot sanctify a bad action, a bad motive will always vitiate a good
                            action. The Pharisees fasted and prayed and gave alms ; but it was to be seen of men ; and
                            thus the deed was corrupted in its principle. An individual that acts without a motive never
                            acts in earnest. It is the result to be obtained, that stimulates the zeal; that sweetens
                            labor ; that repays <pb n="182" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 182 THE MANIFESTO. every expense. What could
                            induce a patient to submit to the amputation of a limb, but the thought of restoration and
                            preservation of life and health? In common and trivial matters, we may sometimes act without
                            motive, but in every duty pertaining to our moral growth and development in. religious life,
                            Ave should be actively in earnest and never in any degree trifle with divine things; it
                            impairs the conscience and deadens the moral sensibility. The object in attending religious
                            worship should be to gain useful instruction to have truths re-applied and re-impressed. If
                            we do not seek new light, it is desirable to have the mind quickened by remembrance of
                            forgotten truth, and to have our knowledge reduced to livingworks. It is written, that if we
                            "draw nigh unto God, that he will draw nigh unto us."Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Morning thoughts" TEIform="index"/> MORNING THOUGHTS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/> MARTHA J ANDERSON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Even as the sun in the beauty and glory of its rising, shineth out from the east, and sheds
                            its glowing effulgence over hill and valley ; so, in the fullness of Thy blessing,
                            beneficent Father and Mother, I feel my soul immersed. Out of the chill and darkness of
                            superstition's night, out of the blinding mists of error, Thy gracious spirit hath led me,
                            until in Thy light I behold the life of immortal joy and hope. My soul, made plastic by the
                            influences of the molding power of truth, shall be fashioned according to Thy will, a vessel
                            fit for service in the temple of Infinite Love, where all nations, kindreds, tongues aud
                            people shall mingle thsir offerings of praise to Thee, the First Great Cause, the Central
                            Sun of all existence. I feel the expanding life of the soul of Universal Good which
                            permeates material things ; it bursts the casements of earth-bound thought, and the germs of
                            all that is true and pure, spring upward to the light. O God ! Wisdom and Love, benignant,
                            merciful and just! As I behold Thee, visible in all the length and breadth of this grand
                            universe ; as I contemplate the vastness of Thy creations of thought; the perfectness of Thy
                            laws, and the harmonious relation existing between the mighty forces that carry on the
                            ceaseless motions of vast systems of worlds ; I am bewildered, over-awed, and wrapt in
                            reverential admiration. How narrow the mind that cramps Thy revelations in a creed ; that
                            closes the volume of Thy truth, and stifles the inspiration of Thy life, ever welling up in
                            the unfolding soul. Expand, O mind of man ! Leap the prison walls of dogmatism ; drink in
                            the light of heaven that beameth even from the east to the west. The painted windows of
                            man-made sanctuaries have too long intercepted its glorious rays ; while thy religious
                            natuie, has been clouded by the darkening shadows of false theologyLTp! for the morning
                            dawns; put forth all thy energies ; scale the eternal hills of truth ; find rest only where
                            living streams are flowing in pleasant vallies ; where the jarring strife of passion is not
                            known; where man with man in holy brotherhood, do justice, love mersj, and walk uprightly
                            according to the law of God written in their hearts. Then earth shall blossom and teem <pb n="183" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 183 with the fruitage of universal love, and no dark
                            veil shall hide the brightness of that sun that ushers in the day of everlasting peace. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Letters" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Youth :—If you make earthly pleasure your object..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Youth :—If you make earthly pleasure your object...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Enfield" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, Conn.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Youth :—If you make earthly pleasure your object of life, you will fail of
                                obtaining real happiness. You cannot afford to live without a noble aim or purpose. It
                                is sad to see youth with God-given talents and abilities, yield to the "Adversary" when
                                he says, "All these things will I give you, if you will fall down and worship me." It is
                                sad to see valuable youth wasting golden opportunities, regardless of the dictates of
                                conscience. "Death is the wages of sin." Be not deceived, but "watch and pray that ye
                                enter not into temptation." Cry unto God, "deliver us from evil." He is able to keep you
                                from falling. Be pure in heart. Let nothing else satisfy you. "Seek first the kingdom of
                                God." Cultivate the immortal part. Exemplify in daily life that which is true and
                                virtuous. Expand and beautify every noble attribute. Now are your golden days. Have a
                                noble object in view, and with all your might, press forward until it is yours. Let your
                                aspirations be high, your intentions honest, your lives pure, and all will be well. Life
                                is a race and you are on the course. Don't "look back," or you will suffer defeat.
                                .;.,,Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/> Daniel Orcutt. </byline></div3></div2><div2 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rules for new-beginners" TEIform="index"/> RULES FOR NEW-BEGINNERS. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/> DANIEL OFFORD. </byline><p TEIform="p"> 1. When hitching on to a wagon, always put up the pole, or shafts, before hitching the
                            traces. 2. When unhitching from a wagon, or sleigh, always unhitch all the traces, before
                            doing up the lines or letting down the pole. 3. When taking the team out, especially in the
                            morning, be extra patient and gentle, for they are then the most full of life, which life
                            should be directed and guided by the teamster, not provoked by impatience into ugliness. If
                            the team is inclined to back out with a rush, take them by the head and do not use the whip,
                            but speak kindly and deal gently. 4. After getting hitched on to the wagon or sleigh, never
                            start off the instant you get in, but teach the team to stand still till you are sure
                            everything is all right. Glance over the harness and whiffle-trees before starting— make
                            this a habit. 5. After you have driven or been at work and have occasion to stand awhile,
                            put the blankets on, if the weather be at all cold. 6. Never leave tlie team a minute
                            -without; hitching! 7. Always hitch with ties, not with the lines, or bridle, unless from
                            absolute necessity. 8. Always take your ties with you. 9. When a horse is sweaty, never let
                            him drink more than a small pail of water—never let him go to the water tub and drink all he
                            inclines to, when he is warm, whether on the road, or going to the stable. 10. Upon putting
                            the team into the stable, never leave the door open so that the cool, or cold air will blow
                            upon them. 11. On no account, take the lamp when it is lighted, out of the lantern, in the
                            stable or barn—have a place to hang it. 12. Always know that your team is all right, before
                            you retire. 13. Remember that it is with harness as with your own clothes—a stitch in time
                            will often save much loss. 14. Govern your own spirit, if you would have perfect control of
                            your horse. Never strike a horse when you are out of temper. Reprove your own self, then you
                            will succeed much better in training your team. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> He who saves in little things can be liberal in great ones. </p></div2><pb n="184" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes" TEIform="index"/>NOTES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><index level1="[Editor]" TEIform="index"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> In the Church of Christ there is to be one faith, which in its ultimate development must
                            lead on to one baptism,— that of the Holy Spirit. This cannot be otherwise than a living and
                            actively growing faith which sees and feels and comprehends what may be wanted to maintain
                            this very desirable condition, of the soul. The ceremonial form which John the Baptist was
                            commissioned to use was only the preliminary step to a greater work and to a higher calling.
                            Jesus accepted il as a fulfillment of righteousness, tut his baptism into a oneness with
                            God, made him a Teacher of God's will to man, and a Savior of the world. In this he becomes
                            our example in humility, in his practical self-denial and in his zeal for the establishment
                            of the Kingdom of God upon the earth. As disciples we must become one with the divine
                            Teacher, when the heavens will be open to our view, and the Angels of God can be no less
                            faithful in their manifestations of care and guidance into the truth. Our lives must
                            correspond with his life, our righteousness with his righteousness and our zeal for the
                            maintainance of the principles of truth, must be moulded by his form of zeal and grow in his
                            likeness for the prosperity of God's work. To accept the profession of a Christian without
                            making continuous and strenuous efforts to learn the righteousness of this new life, and
                            then to secure and put on the whole armor of God, is a sad waste of time and the squandering
                            of a precious privilege. We profess to follow Christ. He left the Adamic plane of generation
                            and gave his life, a holy consecration, to the establishing of the work of re-generation.
                            His kindred were to be known as those who were seeking to do the will of God. We certainly
                            cannot be justified to do less. "No man can serve two masters." To follow Christ we must
                            forsake the life of the children of this world. Our relation must be of the same order as
                            was his relation, it must be among those who have come out from the old, selfish,
                            inheritance of the flesh, and be placed among those who have established their hope on a
                            spiritual foundation. These are the fruits which follow a baptism of the Holy Spirit, and
                            which affords life and peace to the soul. As an evidence that he had renounced the world
                            with all its treasures and pleasures, that he might obtain a treasure in heaven, Jesus gives
                            this graphic illustration,—"The foxes have holes, in which to dwell, the birds have their
                            nests, but the Son of man hath not where to lay his head." His time, his ability, all that
                            he was privileged to possess in this world was consecrated to God, and given in support of
                            the mission to which he was called. Tempted in all points, as we are, and yet without sin,
                            he became so successful that he was able to say, "Be of good cheer, for I have overcome the
                            world." We have a corresponding privilege to manifest our love for God, and to follow our
                            Teacher in righteousness, by forsaking the earthly and securing the heavenly treasures. Like
                            him we may pass through trials, and be subjected to temptations, in their multiplied forms,
                            but if we have forsaken ALL we may <pb n="185" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 185 have the
                            pleasant experience of being able to testify with him.—"Be of good cheer, for I have
                            overcome the world." As Jesus secured his inheritance by a daily cross and by a strong
                            self-denial, his followers must walk carefully, in his footsteps in order to obtain the same
                            divine blessing. This journey of faith toward the baptism of the Holy Spirit of Christ,
                            leads us into the elements of eternal life, and makes our lives one with Christ, in virgin
                            purity, in consecration to God, and in our separation from the world.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>SANITARY</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Aphorisms from Dr. Hall's works" TEIform="index"/> APHORISMS FROM DR. HALL'S WORKS. </head><p TEIform="p"> To live long, and well, and usefully, be temperate in all things, remembering that the
                                only certain and effectual way of being temperate in reference to liquor is, never taste
                                a drop. What a grand thing for the doctors that so few people have any sense, not even
                                sense enough to keep well, by living justly, Jiving temperately, etc. True wisdom lies
                                in the moderate use of all the good things of this life. Alcohol has an affinity for the
                                brain. Within an hour after a glass of brandy is swallowed, more of it is found in a
                                given quanthy of brain than in any equal quantity of blood. Man is the only animal that
                                drinks without being thirsty. If you are eating and find you have had enough and don't
                                want a mouthful more, why in the world don't you stop? There is not a pig or puppy or
                                poodle in existence that has not sense enough to stop eating when he's got enough. Your
                                brother, the donkey, does it. Don't you see you are more than a mule ? Aren't you
                                ashamed of yourself for doing such stupid things and putting yourself beneath the brutes
                                which perish? Let no other man's appetite be a guide for your stomach. Let every man
                                watch over his habits ; cultivate those which are good, and break off those which in the
                                end destroy both body and soul. If alcohol is food, why not give it to your horses? If
                                liquor fattens, why not give it to your beef cattle, your turkeys, your pigs—a good dram
                                of it night and morning? All radical reformers aim at preventives, rather than
                                rectifications. Brandy kills multitudes every year who enjoyed perfect health before
                                they began to use it: hence it would seem fair to infer that it will kill the sick more
                                speedily. It is well to give bad animals as well as bad men a wide berth. If "bitters"
                                aid digestion, why is it that those who take them all the time are never well?
                                Temperance, cleanliness and industry! This is the hygiene of the Bible,—a "pathy" as old
                                as the race. The three best medicines in the world are warmth, abstinence and repose. As
                                men have lived in perfect health without liquor, the use of liquor can not add to that
                                health, because a man cannot be better than well. As to use of wines, beers, brandies,
                                cider, opium and tobacco, the only infallible guarantee from a wasted life, an early
                                death, the gutter, or the mad-house, is in obeying the counsel of the inspired volume,
                                "Touch not, taste not, handle not." Nature is never cheated. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our teeth" TEIform="index"/> OUR TEETH.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">They decay. Hence unseemly mouths, bad breath, imperfect mastication.
                                        Everybody regrets it. What is the cause? I reply, want of cleanliness. A clean
                                        tooth never decays. The mouth is a warm place, 98 degrees. Particles of meat
                                        between the teeth soon decompose. Gums and teeth must suffer. Perfect
                                        cleanliness will preserve the teeth to old age. How shall it be secured? Use a
                                        quill pick, and rinse the mouth after eating; brush and castile soap every
                                        morning; the brush with simple water on going to bed. Bestow this trifling care
                                        upon your precious <pb n="186" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 186 THE MANIFESTO. teeth, and you will
                                        keep them and ruin the dentists. Neglect it, and you will be sorry all your
                                        lives. Children forget. Watch them. The first teeth determine the character of
                                        the second set. Give them equal care. Sugar, acid, saleratus and hot things are
                                        nothing when compared with food decomposing between the teeth. Mercurialization
                                        may loosen the teeth, long use wear them out, but keep them clean and they will
                                        never decay. This advice is worth thousands of dollars to every boy and girl.
                                        Books have been written on the subject. This brief article contains all that is
                                        essential. Never have a tooth taken out if it be possible to hare it filled. The
                                        loss of a single jaw-tooth will not only give the cheek a sunken appearance, but
                                        it will prevent the proper mastication of the food, and this is a long step
                                        toward dyspepsia, with its train of evils.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Domestic journal" TEIform="index"/>Domestic Journal</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Temperance speech" TEIform="index"/>TEMPERANCE SPEECH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mitchell, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Mitchell</byline><p TEIform="p"> [Contributed by G. B. Ayery.] TEMPERANCE SPEECH. BY JOHN MITCHELL. "My father," said
                                John, "used both Rum and Tobacco, and I took to his example as a duck to the water. I
                                smoked young, and it created a fiery appetite for alcholic drinks, which resulted in
                                making me a drunkard. When twenty years old, my case was alarming, and my friends took
                                unbounded pains to pluck me from destruction. "About this time, I was induced by a young
                                friend to attend a Temperance lecture, by Dr. Jewett. The doctor's wit fascinated me,
                                and his logic impelled me to sign the Pledge that night. The Pledge, however, was but a
                                partial thing. It prohibited Strong Drink in all forms, but not Tobacco. I soon found
                                that in renouncing one stimulant, I used a double quantity of another or, in the words
                                of Theodore D. Weld, I had 'Swapped Brandy for Tobacco !' In fact, I ate Tobacco as an
                                ox eats green clover; and this terrible appetite created a thirst for Rum more fierce
                                than I had ever experienced. My Throat was parched—my chest was a furnace; and I said,
                                'drink I must, and drink I will!' and like a dog to his vomit, I went back to my cups.
                                "In two years from this time, by a happy Providence, I heard a lecture on Tobacco, which
                                showed me my mistake, and snatched me from perdition. The lecturer maintained that nine
                                drunkards to ten, probably ninetynine to a hundred, were Tobacco users ; that the
                                Tobacco habit was a boyish one, early formed, and laid the foundations of the gloomy
                                structure of a drunkard; the Washingtonians, who apostatized, were Tobacco sots, almost
                                to a man; that the Pledge, to be safe, must go against Drug and Drink; and that
                                thousands of drunkards; by giving up Tobacco first, had soon given up Rum with
                                comparative ease. Tobacco feeds a fire which no Temperance efforts can quench. I
                                followed the lecturer's advice, and that night threw away my Tobacco forever. "Now came
                                the tug of war, not with my bottle, but with my PIPE. I was unnerved, my nerves were
                                like the sails of a ship dismantled by the storm. I felt nothing, thought nothing, did
                                nothing, and, like the poor college student, I cried, 'I need* Tobacco to give me
                                Resolution to give up Tobacco !' But God was on my side. I avoided old scenes and
                                associates; I avoided gluttony, and sparingly used nutritious food. I used cold water
                                freely, inside and outside. To raise my prostrate nerves and banish my 'awful goneness,'
                                I used the Fitchburg Antidote a few days; and with gratitude to God I can say, I then
                                conquered both Tobacco and Rum and for seven years have trampled both demons under foot.
                                "Hence, I would say to every Temperance Lodge and Temperance Society and Temperance Man,
                                the world over, You Can't Curb a Drunkard whilst a slave to his Pipe." From Anti-
                                Tobacco Tract. The Day Star.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One with God" TEIform="index"/> ONE WITH GOD. </head><p TEIform="p"> Who feels there is a God And gives their all to Him, Can never falter on the road, Or faint
                            through sacrifice or pain; The earth is likewise theirs, His creatures all their own : For
                            every insect well he cares, And such with God are one.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/> M. W. </byline></div2><pb n="187" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>House and Farm</head><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watermelon preserve" TEIform="index"/> Watermelon Preserve</head><p TEIform="p">—To 30 lbs. of melon add 34 lbs. sugar. Cut the melon in pieces an inch thick, or larger
                                if preferred, and boil in 9 quarts of cider, or acid water, until it is soft, then skim
                                out into a cullender to drain. Pour out the cider and put in the sugar, with water
                                enough to dissolve it readily, and skim it well. Then put in the melon, and let it boil
                                until it looks clear.—</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tomato catsup" TEIform="index"/> Tomato Catsup</head><p TEIform="p"> —To a peck of tomatos, boiled soft, and strained in a sieve that will allow the pulp to
                                run through. Add four table spoonfuls of salt, four of ground pepper, four of ground
                                mustard seed, two of ground allspice two of ground cloves, one of cayenne pepper, one
                                gallon of strong vinegar, boil gently three hours, cool and bottle.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. C.</byline></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Care of irons" TEIform="index"/> Care of Irons.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">When irons become rough or smoky, lay a little fine salt on a flat surface
                                        and rub them well; it will prevent them from sticking to anything starched, and
                                        make them smooth; or scour with bath-brick before heating, and when hot rub well
                                        with salt, and then with a small piece of bees-wax tied up in a rag, after which
                                        wipe clean on a dry cloth. A piece of fine sand paper is also a good thing to
                                        have near the stove, or a hard, smooth board covered with brick-dust, to rub
                                        each iron on when it is put back on the stove, so that no starch may remain to
                                        be burnt on. Put bees-wax between pieces of paper or cloth and keep on the table
                                        close by the flatiron stand. If the irons get coated with scorched starch, rub
                                        them over the paper that holds the starch and it will come off. Rubbing the iron
                                        over the waxed paper, even if no starch adheres, adds to the glossiness of the
                                        linen that is ironed. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Religious telescope" TEIform="index"/>Religious Telescope</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cooking does not render diseased..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Cooking does not render diseased...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Cooking does not render diseased or putrefying meat wholesome.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To remove a scorch" TEIform="index"/> To remove a scorch.</head><p TEIform="p">—If a shirt-bosom or any other article has been scorched in ironing, lay it where the
                                bright sun will fall directly upon it. It will take it entirely out. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Worms" TEIform="index"/>Worms
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">—"The Formation of Vegetable Mold through the Action of Worms" is the
                                        title of Mr. Darwin's latest book. He says that every English earth-worm—a
                                        creature which is little else than a digestive apparatus—probably passes, on an
                                        average, about twenty ounces of matter through its body in a year. It brings
                                        this matter to the surface of the earth, and there deposits it, and brings it up
                                        in a very different form from that in which the matter existed before it passed
                                        through the worm. The earth is digested or triturated in the gizzard of the
                                        worm, and combined with the fibrous parts of the leaves on which it feeds and
                                        with which it lines its burrows. The moid that results is what is known as
                                        "vegetable mold." He says: "When we behold a wide turf-covered expanse, we
                                        should remember that its smoothness, on which so much of its beauty depends, is
                                        mainly due to all the inequalities having been slowly leveled by worms. It is a
                                        marvelous reflection that the whole of the superficial mold over any such
                                        expanse has passed, and will again pass every few years, through the bodies of
                                        the worm. The plough is one of the most ancient and most valuable of man's
                                        inventions : but, long before he existed, the land was in fact regularly
                                        ploughed and still continues to be thus ploughed, by earth-worms." In many parts
                                        of England, Mr. Darwin estimates that more than ten tons of dry earth annually
                                        passes through their bodies, and are brought to the surface on each acre of
                                        land. Supposing that in Great Britain there are thirty-two millions of such
                                        acres, three hundred and twenty millions of tons of earth are brought to the
                                        surface by them, in Great Britain alone, in a single year.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One thousand laths will cover..." TEIform="index"/>One thousand laths will cover...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">One thousand laths will cover seventy yards of surface, and eleven pounds of nails put
                                them on; eight bushels of good lime, fifteen bushels of sand, one bushel of hair will
                                make about enough mortar to plaster one hundred yards. A cord of stone, three bushels of
                                lime and a cubic yard of sand will lay one hundred cubic feet of wall. One thousand
                                shingles laid four inches to the weather, will cover one hundred square feet of surface,
                                and <pb n="188" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 188' THE MANIFESTO. eight pounds of nails fasten them on.
                                Onefifth more siding and flooring is needed than the number of square feet of surface,
                                because of the lap in the siding and the matching of the floor. Five courses of brick
                                will lay one foot in height on a chimney; six bricks in a course will make a flue four
                                inches wide and twelve long, and eight bricks in a course will make a flue eight inches
                                wide and sixteen long. Selected.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Woodchuck" TEIform="index"/> THE WOODCHUCK. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Albertis" TEIform="persName"/>Albertis</byline><p TEIform="p"> Woodchucks are very pretty creatures, although they are mischievous and we are sometimes
                                obliged to kill them. Once we had some beans planted on the farm, and there was a
                                company of woodchucks, that began to harvest the beans beforethey were ripe. The man who
                                took charge of the farm put an end to their trespassing, and saved his beans, by setting
                                traps and catching the animals. I guess after we catch all of them we shall have better
                                crops. Albertis.—Age, 10 yrs</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>SELECT</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stinging Tree" TEIform="index"/> THE STINGING TREE. </head><p TEIform="p"> The stinging tree of Queensland, Australia, is a luxurious shrub, pleasing to the eye
                                but dangerous to the touch. It grows from two or three inches to ten or fifteen feet in
                                height, and emits a disagreeable odor. Says a traveler, "Sometimes while shootirg
                                turkeys in the shrubs, I have entirely forgotten the stinging tree till I was warned of
                                its close proximity by its smell, and have often found myself in a little forest of
                                them. I was only once stung, and that very lightly. Its effects are curious ; it leaves
                                no mark, but the pain is maddening, and for months afterwards the part when touched is
                                tender in rainy weather, or when it gets wet in washing, etc. I have seen a man who
                                treats ordinary pain, lightly, roll on the ground in agony after being stuns, and I have
                                known a horse so completely mad after getting iato a grove of the trees that he rushed
                                open mouthed at every one who approached him, and had to be shot Dogs, when stung, will
                                rush about whining piteously biting pieces from the affected part. —</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leslie, Frank, III" TEIform="persName"/> Frank Leslie's III. </byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wanted, Men" TEIform="index"/> WANTED, MEN.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">We take up the paper daily, and casting our glances down the long column we
                                        see many persons asked for after the word "Wanted." Cooks and chamber-maids,
                                        coachmen and butlers, clerks and porters are needed here and there and
                                        everywhere. And yet the greatest need of the nineteenth century we do not see
                                        adA^ertised, and if we diJ all that could conscientiously apply would find room
                                        for employment, and still there would be acres at least of unoccupied space. Men
                                        wanted. Men who are honest and pure. Men who are wholesome and truthful. Men who
                                        will not be bribed. Men who are like fair, refreshing fruit, sound at the
                                        heart's core. Men wanted. Men who are unwilling to eat the bread of idleness.
                                        Men who will scorn to wear what they have not honestly paid for. Men who know
                                        what ought to be done and will do it. Men who are not egotistic, but rather have
                                        the courage given by the spirit to do and to dare. Men who will give good
                                        counsel, who will set a good example for emulation, who will sympathize with the
                                        grieving and succor the distressed. Men who will scorn to do a base thing even
                                        in their zeal for a friend; for as Jeremy Taylor says, he that does, "burns the
                                        golden thread that ties them together." Men who know how to obey before they
                                        take the command. Men who do more than they talk. Men who do good to their
                                        friends to keep them, and to their enemies to gain them. Men whose hearts
                                        compare favorably with full pocketbooks—who believe in systematic giving and
                                        advocate it. Men whose hearts are touched by the sadness of others, who are
                                        moved by a little hungry face and cold bare feet. Men wanted. Men who are brave
                                        and tender, who are not ashamed to wipe tears away. Men whose acts will bring
                                        smiles to wan faces. Men who hush lamentations, and are rewarded with sweet
                                        songs of thanksgiving.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Sherman democrat" TEIform="index"/>Sherman Democrat.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Extinquish vanity in the mind..." TEIform="index"/>Extinquish vanity in the mind...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Extinguish vanity in the mind, and you naturally retrench the little superfluities of
                                garniture and equipage. The blossoms will fall of themselves when the root that
                                nourishes them is destroyed.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Steele" TEIform="persName"/>Steele</byline></div3><pb n="189" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life in the woods, no. 5" TEIform="index"/> LIFE IN THE WOODS, NO. 5. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sproat, Granville T." TEIform="persName"/> GRANVILLE T. SPROAT. </byline><p TEIform="p">It was in the month of September, 1837, that, having closed up my school in camp I
                                started on a second vaccinating tour across the great plains that lay across the sources
                                of the Mississippi. It was, I said, the month of September, the month in which the
                                Indians say, "The Fire Spirits are awake," that, with Ma-gwah-gah-bo for a guide, I
                                started on my journey. The weather had been very fine for many days ; there had been no
                                rain for nearly a month, and we had noticed, at a distance, as we lay down at night, the
                                distant horizon glowing, as if it caught its hue from burning prairies. Still we did not
                                feel any particular cause for alarm, as the fire, if there was any, must be at an
                                immense cistance, and therefore not likely to visit us, without giving us sufficient
                                opportunity to escape. It was about two o'clock, in the morning, that I was aroused by
                                the voice of Ma-gwahgah-bo, sounding at the door of my wigwam. "Ish-Jco-da! ish-Teo-dal
                                wain-je-tah! ivaweep!" (Fire! fire! get up! haste! the Fire Spirits are upon us.) I
                                sprang up, and rushed to the door of my wigwam, to witness a sight such as I had never
                                seen before. The whole western horizon, far and near, was one vast sheet of liquid,
                                rolling flame. It streamed up far past our meridian, blazing, and dazzling over-head
                                above even the place where we stood. " Wa-weep! wa-weep!'' (quick! quick! for life .')
                                cried Ma-gwah-gahbo ; and away he rushed through the tall grass, myself following close
                                at his heels. Away he sprang over the prairie, I with difficulty keeping up. Such speed
                                he made, although he had to break his way through the tall prairie grass before us. At
                                last he reached a rising swell of land, and as we gained the summit, and began to
                                descend on the opposite slope. I perceived before us a broad marsh filled with reeds
                                standing in the midst of water. But the fire, was by this time, upon us ; we could feel
                                the heat as we descended towards the marsh; the air became close like an oven. I was
                                covered with perspiration, and felt my strength rapidly going. As we reached the shores
                                of the marsh I threw myself down, perfectly exhausted. "Get up! get up!" cries
                                Ma-gwah-gah-bo. "Haste you will burn to death here!" "Life, or death," I exclaimed, "I
                                cannot go one step farther." "Get on to my back, then," cries the old man, "get on to my
                                back." I did get on to his back, and he carried me on, running with me a great distance
                                toward the centre of the marsh. He then threw me over his head into the water, laying
                                himself close beside me, and saying, "Keep under! keep under! and watch for the burning
                                clouds!" By "burning clouds," he meant heavy masses of burning prairie grass brought
                                here by the wind, and lighting all around us, which, if they fell on us, would burn, or
                                smother us. Here we lay amid the rushes and water, looking out on the terrible scene
                                before us. Yonder, over the swell that we had just passed, came the flames, rolling and
                                rolling onwards, a vast deluge of fire. Down the descent they came, we could hear them
                                hiss as they reached the waters of the marsh, and see them careering, like race horses,
                                along its shores, which seemed to say to them, "Thus far shall ye come, and no farther."
                                Presently I looked, and saw crouching among the reeds just beside me, something black—I
                                knew not what. I said to Ma-gwahgah-bo, "What is that?" "Ma-gwah !" he exclaimed, (A
                                bear !) "Do you see that thing, which looks like a bush, yonder among the reeds? That is
                                a moose, a moose's horns. Oh, we are not here alone. Company enough! company enough 1"
                                It was so indeed. All the animals in the vicinity had fled to this marsh for protection
                                from the fire. "Will you kill them?" I asked, referring to the moose and the bear, for I
                                had never before made a bear my bed-fellow. "Kill them! No ! The same Great Spirit that
                                sent us here sent them here! I will not hurt a hair of their heads." After a few hours
                                the fire passed off, leaving behind it, a vast plain, covered with smouldering grass,
                                whose damp roots the fire had not consumed. The Indians make war not only against the
                                lives of their enemies, but, also, against their language and inventions. They will not
                                suffer their enemies names to be mentioned in their wigwams, and will have no spoils of
                                    <pb n="190" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> 190 THE MANIFESTO. theirs, excepting their scalps. Perhaps I
                                cannot better illustrate this fact, than by relating an incident which took place in the
                                autumn of 1837. I had been instructed to go across the Mississippi and vaccinate old
                                Hole in the Day's band. Hole in the Day was a Sioux, and a mortal enemy to the
                                O-jib-ways, with whom I made my home. I said to Ma-gwah-gah-bo. "Tomorrow I cross the
                                Mississippi, to visit the Sioux camp, on the other shore, avid will depend on you to go
                                with me, to paddle my canoe safely over," for the stream was rapid. The old man's
                                countenance fell. "There never was an O-jib-wah" said he, "who ever went into the Sioux
                                country and come back again alive.". "You go, I replied, "under my own protection, and
                                are as safe as I myself." "Well," he replied, "I put my life into your hands. I will go
                                with you." (To BE CONTINUED.) </p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Discharged for honesty" TEIform="index"/> Discharged for Honesty.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">—A country gentleman, says a Boston paper, placed a son with a merchant
                                        in-----street, and for a season all went on well. But at length, the young man
                                        sold a dress to a lady, and as he was folding it up, he observed a flaw in the
                                        silk, and remarked, "Madame, I deem it my duty to tell you there is a fracture
                                        in the silk." This spoiled the bargain. But the merchant overheard the remark;
                                        and had he reflected a moment, he might have reasoned thus with himself: "Now I
                                        am safe, while my affairs are committed to an honest clerk." But he was not
                                        pleased; so he wrote immediately to the father to come and take him home; for,
                                        said he, "he will never make a merchant!" The father, who had brought up his son
                                        with the strictest care, was not a little surprised and grieved, and hastened to
                                        the city to ascertain wherein his son had been deficient. Said the anxious
                                        father, "And why will he not make a merchant?" "Because he has no tact. Only a
                                        day or two since, he voluntarily told a lady who was buying silk, that the goods
                                        were damaged, and so I lost the bargain. Purchasers must look out for
                                        themselves. If they cannot discover flaws, it will be foolishness in me to tell
                                        them of their existence." "And is this all the fault?" "Yes : he is very well in
                                        other respects." "Then I love my son better than ever; and I thank you for
                                        telling me of the matter; I would not have him in your store another day for the
                                        world."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Arab pecularities" TEIform="index"/> ARAB PECULIARITIES.</head><p TEIform="p"> An arab is a queer fellow. On entering a house he removes his shoes, but not his hat. He
                                mounts his horse on the right side, while his wife milks the cow on the left side. In
                                writing a letter he puts nearly all the compliments on the outside. With him the point
                                of a pin is its head, whilst its head is made its heel. His head must be wrapped up warm
                                even in Summer, while his feet may well enough go naked in Winter. Every article of
                                merchandise which is liquid, he weighs, but he measures wheat, barley and a few other
                                articles. He reads and writes from right to left. He eats scarcely anything for
                                breakfast, about as much for dinner ; but after the work of the day is done, he sits
                                down to a hot meal swimming in oil, or better yet, boiled butter. His sons eat with him,
                                but the females of the house wait till his lordship is done. He rides a donkey when
                                traveling, his wife walking behind. He laughs at the idea of walking in the street with
                                his wife, or of ever vacating his seat for a woman. He knows no use for chairs, tables,
                                knives, forks or even spoons, unless they are wooden ones. Bedsteads, bureaus and
                                fireplaces may be placed in the same catagory. If he be an artisan he does work sitting,
                                perhaps using his feet to hold what his hands are engaged upon. He drinks cold water
                                with a sponge, but never bathes in it unless his home be on the seashore. He is rarely
                                seen drunk, and is deficient in affection for his kindred. He has little curiosity and
                                no imitation; no wish to improve his mind, and no desire to surround himself with the
                                comforts of Life. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leslie, Frank, III" TEIform="persName"/>Frank Leslie's III.</byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scarcely have I ever heard or read..." TEIform="index"/>Scarcely have I ever heard or read...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Scarcely have I ever heard or read the introductory phrase, "I may say without vanity,"
                                but some striking and characteristic instance of vanity has immediately followed. </p><byline TEIform="byline">&gt;<persName reg="Franklin" TEIform="persName"/>Franklin</byline></div3><pb n="191" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cross of Christ" TEIform="index"/> THE CROSS OF CHRIST.</head><p TEIform="p"> Canaan, N. Y. 1. Oh the glory of the cross of Christ! The beauty of the heavenly 2. With
                                holy trust and living faith, Press on toward the shining 3. Oh come ye heavy laden
                                souls, Cast off your robes of guilt and way! Uplifting souls from goal; Where pearly
                                portals sin; Come to the stream that sin and dross, Unto the perfect day. angels ope
                                Unto the weary soul, maketh whole, Its moving waves step in. i No more shall death have
                                power to harm, While steadfast in the narrow O happy thought! there's rest and peace
                                Beyond the care and burden There's healing in the flowing tide, Then plunge beneath the
                                swelling way, For conq'ring faith shall bear the palm And God will be their stay. here;
                                The wicked from all troubling cease, In the eternal sphere, flood And wash in faith,
                                till purifled And born anew in God.</p></div3></div2><pb n="192" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>The Herald of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Herald of Health. July; Contents : Substitutes for Brandy; Words from India;
                                Physical Exercises and their Regulation; Be wise in Work, and in Recreation; Perfect
                                Health; Antipathy to Fish Diet; Against Tobacco; Studies in Hygiene for Women. M. L.
                                Holbrook, M. D. Publisher, 13*15 Laight St.N. Y.. $1,00 per. year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>Phrenological
                                Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Phrenological
                                Jouiinal and Science of Health, May; Contents; Modern Drama; The true Basis for the
                                Science of Mind. Krao, the missing Link, Illustrated; God, Immortality and Deity;
                                Bermuda Easter Lily; Fredrika Bremer, with Portrait; Aunt Ellery's Ideal; Contagious
                                Diseases; Offensive Breath; Treatment of the Hair; Editorial Items; Answers to
                                Correspondents; etc., etc. Fowler and Wells, 753 Broadway, N. Y. $2,00 per. year, </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Hall's Jouknal of Health, May; Contents: Methods of Building up Health; Pure Air and Pure
                                Blood; Piles; The Family Table; The Scarlet Fever ; How to be young at Eighty; Cheerful
                                People ; Efficacy of Vaccination; Food Adulteration; Sleep; etc. E. II. Gibbs, M. D. 21
                                Clinton Place, Eighth Street,N. Y., Terms $1,00 a year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Homiletic monthly" TEIform="index"/>The Homiletic Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Homiletic Monthly for July
                                is a most brilliant number of that periodical. It contains the usual Sermonic matter
                                from the most popular preach ers. Among them J. W.Rylance, D. D.; C. H, Fowler, D.D.;
                                Canon Farrar R. S. Storrs, D. D.; David Swing; Rev. J E. Converse; Adolph Sophir, D. D.;
                                Decoration Services, by N. D. Williamson and Rev. T. Johnson Lamont; Prayer-meeting
                                Services; Comments on Hebrews; Dr. Schaff's second article on the "Homiletic Value of
                                the Revised Version'' is exceedingly interesting, as is also Dr. Ormiston's Commentary
                                on James; The Methodist divines come forward in this number and express their views as
                                to the best methods of preaching; Dr. Chamber on Misquoted Texts; D. II. Wheeler, LL,
                                D., brings to us "Truth From an Enemy," and John Hall, D. D., stands up for the
                                Independence of the Ministry. Surely the above is abundant for one month. There still
                                remiffli editorials, brief discussions, quaint and useful "IIomiletic Materials in the
                                Rough"—all written in masterly style. $2.50 a year; Funk &amp; Wagnalls, 10
                                &amp; 12DeySt. New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Crayon papers" TEIform="index"/>Crayon Papers
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Irving, Washington" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Washing-ton Irving's "Crayon Papers." This very Prince in
                                the realm of letters is at last able to enter the homes of ordinary mortals. Until
                                lately his inimitable productions have been practically inaccessible on account of their
                                high cost. The recent expiration of copyright has freed them from the short-sighted
                                monopoly which has preferred to harvest the dollars of the thousands rather than the
                                dimes of the millions of his countrymen who take delight in his memory. The very
                                beautiful Elzevir edition of his "Crayon Papers," with a brilliant sketch ©f the Life of
                                Irving by the poet, R. H. Stoddard, making a volume of over 350 pages, is just issued
                                and the publisher with a view to securing promptly the immense sale that is necessary to
                                make the low price possible, offers to send, if ordered at once, a specimen copy, in
                                neat cloth binding to any address, for the nominal price of 35 cents, or in half Russia
                                binding for 45 cents. Irving's complete Works are offered for prices ranging from less
                                than $6.00, upwards. The cheapest edition until recently cost over $30.00. The publisher
                                will send specimen pages free to any one upon request. JOHN B. ALDEN, Publisher, 18
                                Vesey Street, New York.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stick to old friends" TEIform="index"/>STICK TO OLD FRIENDS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S. S." TEIform="persName"/>S. S.</byline><p TEIform="p"> [Contributed by S. S. Woods.] STICK TO OLD FRIENDS. Never give up old friends for new ones.
                            Make new ones, if you like, and when you have found that you can trust them, love them if
                            you will, but remember the old ones still. Do not forget they have been tried and found true
                            ; that they have been merry with you in time of pleasure, and when sorrow came to you they
                            sorrowed also. No matter if they have gone down in the social scale and you up ; no matter
                            if poverty and misfortune have come to them while prosperity and plenty have fallen to
                            you—are they any the less true for that? Are not their hearts as warm and tender if they do
                            beat beneath homespun instead of velvet? Yes, kind friends, they are as true, and tender,
                            and loving, and don't forget old friends. Selected. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The finer the nature, the more flaws..." TEIform="index"/>
                            The finer the nature, the more flaws...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> The finer the nature, the more flaws will it show through the clearness of it. The best
                            things are seldomest seen in their best form. The wild grass grows well and strongly one
                            year with another; but the wheat is, by reason of its greater nobleness, liable to a
                            bitterer blight.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ruskin" TEIform="persName"/>Ruskin</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bathrick, Eunice" TEIform="index"/>Eunice Bathrick
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Harvard, Mass. July, 1883. Our Beloved and venerable sister, Eunice Bathrick, migrated to
                                the next phase of human existence, June 24th, in the 90th, year of ler age. She was the
                                oldest proprietor in he Society, and was widely known b"y her etters of correspondence
                                with the different Societies, and many other friends who will miss the inspiiation of
                                her encouraging epistles. Her's is a Crown of life. Elijah Myrick.</p></div3></div2><!--
                        <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]<pb id="p30"/>
                            <pb id="p31"/>
                            <pb id="p32"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>