<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0104" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><date value="18710401" TEIform="date">April 1871</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">25-32</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="25" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">" I WILL SHAKE ALL NATIONS, AND THE DESIRE OF ALL NATIONS SHALL COME ; AND I WILL FILL THIS HOUSE WITH GLOET, SAITH
                        THE LOKD.5&gt; Published Monthly, by, and under the direction of the Mi Lebanon Bishopric, Vol. I. SHAKERS,
                        ALBANY, N. Y., APRIL, 1871. No. 4.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Communities" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Communities</head><p TEIform="p">Are they Charitable Institutions for the Body, or for the Soul ? So long as Shakers were known to the religious
                            world as a band of superstitious fanatics, who condemned marriage per se, and danced on the Sabbath, it treated
                            them with ridicule as law-breakers, or with silent contempt. When influential and highly educated men and women
                            belonging to the popular de- nominations of Christian sects,—Baptists, Presbyterians, Episcopalians, Methodists,
                            etc.,—and not a small company of the priests, " were obedient unto the faith," and put it into practical
                            operation by (where it involved no dereliction of duty, or violation of contracts previously formed), sundering
                            all the ties that bound them to " this vain, this wicked, world "— those of consanguinity, property, and
                            marriage ; and these founded societies in different States, they ascended above contempt, and "a great
                            persecution arose." At first, this took the form of personal abuse, and often destruction of property combined
                            with it. Their motives were impugned, and impossible crimes laid to the charge of Ann Lee, and the leaders
                            generally. All manner of evil was said, and often sworn to as truth, until the powers of the Judiciary were
                            evoked to prove these imaginary crimes, and punish the authors and perpetrators thereof. Lawsuits were
                            instituted to prevent the hold- ing of property " in common," and thus break up these society-deranging
                            establishments. In process of time " these Shakers having become reputedly rich, are considered also to have
                            become respectable, and are voted a place among the Christian sects; a prominent position being assigned to them
                            in the theological world, no less than that of having ' modified the religious thought of America.'"—Dixon. A
                            new danger besets them; that of popularity, and the "friendship of the world." Living necessarily in large
                            houses, to accommodate large numbers, the wondering public, not considering how many "families of five" reside
                            and have their homes in one of these great unitary dwellings, which to them look so grand and so much like some
                            individual rich man's mansion, speak one to another: " Are not these Shakers always neat and clean in personal
                            appearance ? Is there not ever the glow of content upon their countenances, indicative of well-supplied physical
                            wants-, and comfortable, social conditions? Do they ever run in debt ? or do any of their members ever end their
                            days in a poor-house ? Certainly they must be rich; for what constitutes riches, if it be not a permanent and
                            ample supply of food, raiment, and lodging? " " And now that we, the discriminating public, have ridiculed,
                            contemned, calumniated, lawsuited—persecuted—these Shakers into an American institution, that will neither run
                            out at our bidding, nor be anything but respectable on its own basis; and now, that they have become an object
                            of general curiosity to the political economist, the socialist, the co-operative people; to the moralist, with
                            his " social evil " problems; to the advocates of Woman's Rights, who desire a mixed government of male and
                            female elements, and that taxation and representation should be united; to physiologists, who seek to save
                            bodies first, and souls afterwards, if they need it; to Spiritualists and theologians generally, and to
                            religionists in particular, who behold with awe and reverence the re-incarnation of the Christ Spirit—a
                            veritable Primitive Church—furnishing to the P^uropean tourists much of the staple of their books of travel in
                            the United States of America ;—the momentous question arises, what are these Shakers for? and to what use can we
                            put their successful industrial establishments ? " And the answer comes back spontaneously from all people who "
                            have the poor always with them,"—turn them into eleemosynary institutions !! they will, as such, exactly meet
                            the wants of the age in which we live. The aged and infirm, who belong to wealthy families; the merchant who has
                            failed in business, and lost hope in the struggle for pre-eminence ; the lone widow, the orphan children, and
                            poor relatives, generally, who are a burden to their friends; how convenient it will be to have them taken into
                            these charitable, public institutions, where they will receive more than parental and filial care from the
                            religious, the good, the Christian people "called Shakers." Here follows a specimen letter of the many we
                            receive, omitting the name and place of the writer : "Feb. 8, 1871. "F.W.Evans—Can you extend the hospitalities
                            of your society to a married woman and her two girls, aged seven and three years ? The mother is educated,
                            intelligent, and virtuous ; but is sick with consumption, and cannot do much work. Her husband is so lazy, that
                            he has compelled his sick wife to chop wood, and make the garden; and consequently, as they have no means, she
                            is about to be consigned to the charities of the town. " If you are able to offer a home to this unfortunate
                            woman, without separating her from her children, please address, with particulars—Mrs. --------; and likewise
                            notify me. ---------." To this appealing letter we returned the following answer, characteristic of our usual
                            replies to such applications: " Mount Lebanon, Feb. 12,1871. "Respected Friend—The case which you present is not
                            one that we could do anything with, for several reasons : First: This is not, as many suppose, primarily, an
                            eleemosynary institution for the relief of physical, human suffering. There are institutions especially devoted
                            to that object, and they are above all praise. Second: The woman is not legally divorced, and we do not part man
                            and wife [nor 'forbid to marry'] : the law of the land must do that. Third: This is strictly a religious order;
                            a home for the souls of seekers after righteousness,—those who are not, and cannot be, satisfied with the
                            righteousness of worldly Christians, who ' marry and give in marriage,' hold private property, and ' fight'
                            about it and their husbands and wives. " We seek the best (physiologically) the world can produce—those who are
                            ' compelled,' by the wants of their souls—to come, with the intent and hope of making them better. We can take a
                            limited num- ber of children of good parentage, who have had a moral and religious training, when old enough to
                            understand somewhat <pb n="26" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 26 THE SHAKER of our faith and principles—twelve years and
                            upwards,—preferring them at eighteen or twenty-one, when they are free men and women. Respectfully, "F. W.
                            Evans." This answer did not give entire satisfaction to the parties applying, as witness the following extract
                            from a subsequent letter: "Imagine Jesus at table, and refusing food to a woman because she had a husband, and
                            not suffering her little children to come unto him because their mother had not a divorce. I am aware that there
                            are charitable institutions 'beyond praise,' but not beyond censure. They do not furnish country air, fruits,
                            cleanliness, employment and home, such as are to a considerable degree found in your societies ; and, thinking
                            of the future of the little ones, I thought they would be safest among you. Let me give you this advice, as a
                            lady: Be charitable outside of yourselves ; build a workshop, a hospital, a school-house for non-Shakers, and
                            thus show the world that you can spend money for the good of others. "I am, very sincerely, the well-wisher of
                            you and your associates." Now we know what the Shakers are for. Each society is to build workshops, and manage
                            them so that the poor can earn a living, and the public be relieved of the English question, "What shall we do
                            with the pauper baby?" and with the pauper question generally; "for, even in famine and captivity, they (the
                            public) will still get children," without any rational forethought or insight into their future. Each society is
                            to build a hospital, and nurse the victims of small waists, thin shoes, idiotic, ball-room head-gear, anc
                            fashionable air, food and medicines, thai the public conscience may be at ease, knowing how the simple Shakers
                            are living upon, and suffering for, their sins. And next, they may erect and officer school-houses for
                            non-Shakers the more readily, as now we are likely to have " A Law for the Protection of Minors," termed by the
                            Tribune, " Norton's Inquisitoria Bill." And this will amply protect sucl children from any mistaken ministratioi
                            on the part of the Shakers, of their hereti cal, unorthodox, and unpopular theology or even of their religion,
                            "which is con trary to all nature; " but of whose tempo ral " fruits " the public are desirou enough to possess
                            themselves. This is what the Shakers are for: t provide a home for the body, if they d not prove to be so
                            ignorant, and sue' " obstinate heretics," that they canno comprehet-d their mission in and to " th world " who
                            "marry and give in marriage.' It appears, upon record, that Jesus did ebukc those who followed him, not b*eause
                            of his miracles—his soul ministraions—but for the incidental li loaves and ishes " with which he had fed their
                            bodies. And the " little children " who constitute j leaven, are (in their characteristics of inocence and
                            dependent love of truth) such s have become little children. " Except e receive the kingdom (which in the later
                            day was to be established upon earth) s little children " just born into the atural world receive external
                            things from natural mother, and then successively rom a father, and brothers, and sisters, hey should in nowise
                            enter therein ; and not that little children (who are simply used as a figure) literally are subjects of a
                            heavenly order, until as men, and wonen, they, by their own free agency, ravel into it. If " the kingdom " were
                            j composed of " little children " physically, ;hey would outgrow the " kingdom " when hey come to be men and
                            women. The suggestion of the above letter writer to the Shakers is not a bad one, at all. [t is questionable
                            whether we ourselves lave not become somewhat mixed in our deas of charity, confounding the body and soul
                            together; the Lord's poor, and " the world's" poor. There is no law against love and good works—against charity
                            to the poor and afflicted of this world. But, what Believr ers are able and willing to do for nonShakers," let
                            it not be done by "taking them into the number " who, from Christian faith, "have all things common," and
                            thereby attempt to make Shakers of them. But rather, build work-shops, wash-houses, hospitals, and
                            school-houses, or help to support those that are already built. " Hanging a man " is not a worse use to put him
                            to, than converting a Shaker Society into a world's charitable institution for the relief of the poor. It would
                            be a desecration, and a double wrong; first, to the real Shakers, by compelling them to associate with paupers,
                            and then to the poor, by " compelling " them to become Shakers (if that were possible) in order to have a home
                            for their bodies. Let there be a separation. 7</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lost! somewhere between sunrise and sunset, two golden hours; no reward is offered, as the loser knows they are                                 gone forever !" TEIform="index"/>Lost! somewhere between sunrise and sunset...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Lost! somewhere between sunrise and sunset, two golden hours; no reward is offered, as the loser knows they are
                            gone forever ! </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. MYRICK</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If all should be Shakers, the world would run out!..." TEIform="index"/>If all should be Shakers, the world would run out!...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">1. " If all should be Shakers, the world would run out! " We want none to be Shakers, who copulate only, to
                            prevent that terrible catastrophe—"running the world out." 2. Ye consumptive patients ¦' abandon your diseased
                            animal food—live on natural food. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilcox, George" TEIform="persName"/>Geo. Wilcox</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="While the young in Zion are anxious to spread true testimony, let them not forget..." TEIform="index"/>While the young in Zion are anxious to spread true testimony, let them not forget...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">While the young in Zion are anxious to spread true testimony, let them not forget that a practical working-out of
                            the beautiful theory is just now, more than ever, needful. Jesus' teachings were plainly mani fested in common
                            life ; and the conviction of mankind in our day must be, by our efforts, in the sami homely manner. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Briggs, N. A." TEIform="persName"/>N. A. Briggs</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Poetry" TEIform="index"/>POETICAL</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Morning" TEIform="index"/>Morning</head><p TEIform="p">A brighter day is dawning, Blest Zion, upon Thee ! I see the rays of morning-, Now gilding spire and tree— I
                                see the cloud-capped mountain Take on a golden line. As up the eastern horizon The snn appears in view.
                                Arise ' and shake thy garments ; Thy night of rest is gone .' Arrayed in thine adornments, Come forth to
                                meet the morn I Hail, with a joyful greetingThe Messenger of Light' Before whose face retreating, Are seen
                                the shades of night. Come, ix;vr, and view the landscapes So splendid to behold ; ¦While Light, as with a
                                mantle, drapes The Earth in limpid gold. See. Iittle; pearly drops of dew All sparkling with delight; Soon
                                these will vanish from onr view, As have the shades of night. Tor, as the Sun ascendeth higher, The glided
                                Glory fades ; While radiant Light, like heat from fire, The shadiest nook invades. All who within the forest
                                stand, Are shielded from bright rays ; While those who cultivate the land, Work in the Sun's !&gt;road
                                blaze. So, well improve these golden hours E'er they have passed away ; On wings, the Morning upward soars
                                To full Meridian day. "Arise and work,7' is duty's call; Come forth, the vineyard prune ; And renovate the
                                broken wall Upon the^rovmd now strewn. Tor, all the beasts that roarn the fields, Can enter when they please
                                ; And whatsoever fruit it yields, Appropriate with ease. Let more security ensure The product of this soil,
                                Although the laborers are fewer Who in the vineyard toil.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., A. E." TEIform="persName"/>A. E. P., Har.</byline></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soliloquy" TEIform="index"/>Soliloquy</head><p TEIform="p">Oh, my sweet gospel treasure ! Oh, my soul-cheering treasure ! All the cross, a?id burdens vanish At the
                                sight of my reward ! See ! my Fathers and my Mothers! All my Sisters and my Brothers! Can the world, with
                                all its glory, Produce one like unto these ?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dorothy" TEIform="persName"/>Dorothy</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Items" TEIform="index"/>Items</head><p TEIform="p">" I want to be an Angel," is sung by the multitudes with much sincerity ; bnt the reality of the ideal is not
                            desirable, with the majority, while carnal gratifications are possible. People too commonly live as though they
                            despised the life of an Angel, nor would they be "children of the Resurrection" if they could. " Do you enjo}'
                            yourself? " asked a scoffing inquirer ofBr. Daniel Moseley. "Xay,"said Daniel, "lcruci/y myself, and enjoy
                            Christ! " The inauguration of Christianity called upon all to forsake the carnal lives of father, mother, wife,
                            husband ; and property, such as houses and lands. Has the gospel of Christ changed hands ? The Shakers do not
                            worship Ann Lee ; never did. They do not worship Jesus ; never did. Jesus was a man—a Jew ; Ann was a woman—a
                            Gentile ; they were both baptized with the Christ Spirit—this Spirit we worship. *</p></div2><pb n="27" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is infidelity and who are infidels" TEIform="index"/>What is Infidelity and Who Are Infidels.</head><p TEIform="p">Growth is a law of soul, as really as of the corporeal frame, AU truth is, in its nature, adapted to progress. AU
                            genuine revelations from God to man are conformable to this law. It follows that all religious creeds, that do
                            not admit of continuous and eternal revelations of the purposes and will of God to man, are of human, instead of
                            divine origin. It only re- quires researches into the plan of human progress in divine grace, set forth in the
                            Christian Bible, to perceive the truth that God's requisitions and laws to man in one dispensation of His grace
                            and truth to humanity, are superseded, or transcended, by succeeding dispensations of the revelation of His will
                            to man. A primary necessity with correspondents, in order to be rightly understood, is a mutual acceptance of
                            the meaning of words and phrases ; a want of this precaution has been the cause of fierce verbal contentions
                            among those whose real faith and convictions—whose actual life conditions—were not dissimilar, except in a
                            limited degree. Since the prefix in. negatives words to which it is applied, we are first to look for the
                            signification of "fidelity" and to its application to God, Christ, and Religion. As used in theology, fidelity
                            means faithfulness to the testimonies of a Creed of religious faith. Hence, infidelity is unfaithfulness to such
                            testimonies. Thus, since we have opposition of religious Creeds in what is called Christendom, in this sense, we
                            might have Christian Infidels, as well as heathen Infidels. And, to illustrate: The Creed of Universalism is
                            Infidel to the Creed of Episcopalianism, since the former teaches the eventual salvation of all mankind, while
                            the latter teaches that only an elected few are to be saved, and the remainder are subjects of damnation!
                            Equally Infidel to these two is the Christian faith "par excellence," taught by Jesus and his disciples : " Come
                            unto me, all ye that labor and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest." " Whoso will, let him partake of the
                            waters of life freely." " He that covereth his sins shall not prosper ; but he that confesseth and forsaketh
                            them, shall find mercy." That is, all who come to Christ, confess and forsake sin, will be saved ! But, as the
                            creeds of all religions claim God as the " Kock of Ages" on which to build their faith, so Infidelity, in a
                            wider and more extended sense, refers to a disbelief in God. Yet, as there are " Gods many, and Lords many," and
                            the character and attributes con stituting the Being which religious people call God, vary so widely in the
                            Creedal faith of different denominations called Christian, that, the first subject to be decided in order to
                            determine the question what constitutes an Infidel to the Christian's God, is to determine what are the true
                            attributes and true character of the Christian's God. As God, the Creator of Heaven and Earth, and the
                            illimitable Universe of Universes, is infinite in power and wisdom, so is God unknown to, and incomprehensible
                            by man, except by revelation ; and the God, or the character of God, revealed to the human family of one era of
                            the world's history, is widely different from that revealed in a subsequent age. And, further, the God revealed
                            to one nation, or class of human beings, differs widely from the God revealed to another class of human beings
                            in the same era of the world's history. Thus, one class of believers in God are infidel to another class of
                            believers in God! But, this infidelity is easily seen to be simply relative infidelity ; that is, the creed of
                            one class of believers in God is Infidel to the creed of another class, leaving the question still open, " What
                            is positive Infidelity to God ?" The lowest, most primitive idea of God known to man, is that of Fetichism, so
                            called: God, as known to the Africans ; consisting of some vast object of wonder or power — as vast rocks, huge
                            mountains, immense forests, boundless waters, etc. Their symbolical representations of gods, their idols, are in
                            human form, because this form exists intuitively in the human mind as the highest manifestation of God's
                            creative power. The first act of reason in man is to personify incomprehensibilities, so as to obtain a clear
                            idea of such existing facts. The second idea of God, manifest to humanity in the ascending scale, was God as a
                            vast, abstract, incomprehensible power, possessing all the prominent passions of man, and the cause of the same;
                            or God, in the character of a vast Producer, Provider, Originator of all things, ministering to man's
                            necessities, or pandering to his desires, good or evil. In this character man attempts to present God to the
                            imagination of his fellow man, in any ¦ form embodying what he most needs or desires—as a rare plant, a strong
                            element; as winds, waters, fire, etc. This era of the knowledge of God embraces the Grecian Mythologies. For the
                            most part, God is now represented as a Positive or Generative power, or Being; and the idolatrous symbol was a
                            Bull; an Orb — as the Sun, the Moon — Egypt's Osiris, which, with other Egyptian Idols, was meant to represent
                            whatever acts upon passive matter, for the good of man; or, the active energy of life ! This character of God
                            was also represented by the Grecians' Jupiter, the most powerful of the heathen gods, and the Origin of
                            everything, good or evil — the Active Power. It was also represented by the Musselman's Allah, the Platonist's
                            All Good, the Theist's Deity, and the Norman's Odin. The third idea, or first revelation of God, is religious —
                            God as a liuler of mankind! yet, incomprehensible to man. This is the first character of God, designated by
                            Moses to the Jews; that is, I. AM. A jealous, revengeful, passionate, repenting, changeful and fitful Sovereign,
                            visiting the iniquities of the fathers upon the children to the fourth generation : giving the Jewish law to
                            Moses. This idea of God might have been spontaneously suggested by the want of government in the human family
                            upon earth. The fourth idea of God, or the second revelation of God, was made to Moses, and revealed God as a
                            Parentage, under the Hebrew name of " Jehovah," literal!}'meaning "He, She." This name was so sacred to the
                            Jews, that they only pronounced it in a whisper, evidently because the time had not yet arrived for the
                            comprehension and declaration of the character of God as a dual Being, Male and Female. The fifth idea, or third
                            revelation of God, is a Heavenly Father; a Being, but a spiritual Being; the Creator of all things, and
                            dispenser of blessings to man ; the establisher of law, and obedience thereto was life; disobedience, death; a
                            kind, loving, merciful Parent ; careful for the good of His creatures; in character the opposite of the Mosaic I
                            Am. The law of the I Am God, as revealed to Moses, was that of revenge; " An eye for an eye, and a tooth for a
                            tooth ;" " Whoso sheddeth man's blood, by man shall his blood be shed." This God was in possession of the
                            passions of humanity ! Joshua said: " Our God is a jealous God." The law of the Heavenly Father God, as revealed
                            by Jesus Christ was : "Do good to all, and good only .'" " Ye have heard that it hath been said by them of old
                            time," said Jesus, " thou shalt love thy neighbor and hate thine enemy; but I say unto you, love your enemies;
                            bless them that curse you; do good to them that despitefully use you and persecute you." The sixth idea, or
                            fourth revelation of God, is God as a Dual, Spiritual Parentage, Father and Mother God; kind, merciful, loving
                            and forgiving; not only creating, but nursing, developing and happifying their creatures. Thus, it is clearly
                            seen, that a human intelligence, who, in any of the former eras of these manifestations of God, had a revelation
                            of God more full and true, in advance of the day in which he lived, would be considered Infidel to the God, or
                            God Character, previously known. Also, the believer in the former character of God, would be infidel to him. It
                            has been said, and we believe truly, that " The God of the Jews was not the God of the Universe;" and, we might
                            truly add, not the God of the Christians! This, to some understandings, may appear infidel; but, viewed in its
                            true light, the kind of infidelity which is the fruit of a new, a true, and increasing revelation of the
                            knowledge of God, is a virtue, and not an evil! It is not difficult to see that the character of God revealed to
                            Moses, in the name of / AM, was different from that revealed in the name of Jehovah; neither is it difficult to
                            perceive that the character of God revealed in the name of a Heavenly Father only, is different from that of God
                            as a Heavenly Father and Mother. Hence, the actual truth, when fully revealed, is, that there is but one true
                            God, consisting of Male and and Female constituents or principles, forming one complete Being, as God, A
                            Heavenly Father and Mother, the primary source and Creator of all existences ; yet, this God, in this Character,
                            has not been generally revealed to man; but God has been gradually revealed to man, and understood by man in
                            different characters; and, in this light, " The God of Moses was not the God of the Universe." The God of the
                            Universe, the Heavenly Father and Mother, God, was not fully revealed until <pb n="28" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. the
                            second coming of Christ, in the female. This is the dispensation of the revelation of God to man, wherein " the
                            mystery of God should be finished."—Rev. x. Tth. Then, and not till then, was to be revealed the Mother in God,
                            or, the Motherhood of God! She was hinted at by Moses, and alluded to by Jesus, but the time for the revelation
                            was when Christ should make the second appearance, through " One like unto the Son of Man." Nothing is more like
                            unto a Soil of Alan than a daughter of man ! And thus, as the Son Jesus, revealed the Father, God, so the
                            daughter, Ann, "the Word," revealed the Mother, God ! Here it should be observed, lest the understanding be
                            falsely impressed, that, aside from the clothing of the spiritual baptism, the Mediator of this revelation, the
                            embodiment of this Sonship, is not an Oracle of God ; is not authority. Had Jesus, as a man, been infidel to the
                            duties of his high calling, as the first-born Son of God, the Father would have rejected him, and called in
                            another Medium in his stead, to reveal the Fatherhood of God. In like manner there is no absolute impor- tance,
                            in the abstract, attachable to the person of Ann Lee, that she should become the firstborn daughter of God—the
                            Oracle to reveal the Mother in God, and the Bridal help-meet of the " Second Adam," " The Lord from Heaven," " a
                            quickening Spirit." Had She been infidel to her high calling into Christ's death and resurrection, another
                            female would have been called who would be filial, and by her sufferings and obedience, reveal the Motherhood,
                            the Duality of God, and of his Christ! Many Creeds of religion teach that Jesus is God; that the Holy Ghost is
                            God, and that the Father alone is God ; but, wThence is this idea of God derived ? When we search for the
                            divinely inspired Mediator between God and man, to find who was the chosen Oracle to reveal this character of
                            God to man, we fail to find such an agency. It had no existence until near the close of the fifth century of the
                            Christian Era ; hence, it was no revelation of God through Jesus Christ; but its birth seems to have originated
                            in a Popish Council. Now, if Jesus Christ is the Oracular lawgiver, and divinely-anointed teacher of the Church
                            of Christ on earth, and he never taught that Jesus is God, but did, habitually call himself " the Son of Man,"
                            as if to wisely forestall all legendary and mythological assumptions of his Divinity, is it not Infidelity to
                            the Christian religion to declare that Jesus Christ is God ? His immediate disciples, the twelve Apostles, dared
                            not do it; they declared him to be the Christ of God, after he had been clothed upon by the baptism of the Holy
                            Ghost! In answer to the question which Jesus put to them, saying, " Whom say ye that I am ?" Simon Peter
                            answered, " Thou art the Christ, the Son of the Living God .'" Jesus blessed him, and told him flesh and blood
                            had not revealed it to him, but " My Father which is in Heaven." Again, where is the Oracle who was Divinely
                            authorized to declare that the Holy Ghost is God ? We have no record of such an Oracle! The idea was not taught
                            bj* Jesus, neither by his apostles, nor by the Primitive Christian Church. From all of the teachings and
                            references of Jesus and his Apostles concerning the Holy Ghost, the only idea taught is, that the Holy Ghost was
                            a godly spirit, which the fol- lowers of Christ should receive and be filled with, and be covered, by a baptism,
                            once spoken of as a "Witness for Christ;" " The Comforter;" an Anointing resting on Jesus (see Acts x. 38), and
                            on his disciples, as is manifest by multitudinous passages of Scripture. The Apostles spoke of the " Holy Ghost"
                            also, as a Servant or Messenger of God ! Paul speaks of the " love of God shed in your hearts by the Holy
                            Ghost." Peter speaks of the "Holy Ghost sent down from Heaven ;" but, no where, in Scripture, is the Holy Ghost
                            called God ! No history, then, gives us any account of a revelation of God proclaiming to us the Holy Ghost as
                            God ! but simply a ministering spirit ! The Holy Ghost, God, like unto the Jesus, God, had its birth in the
                            Anti-Christian Church, after the falling away of the Primitive Christian Church ! It was a god-child of the
                            Catholic Priesthood ; and, may it not be truly said, born of folly ? And, when the true God (Heavenly Father and
                            Mother} is revealed to all humanity, will not a Triune God be considered by all humanity as Infidelity ? The
                            Christian revelation of the true God will bear stating; bear canvassing; bear inves- tigation; and, God of Mercy
                            be praised, that, however infidelic it may appear to some pro- fessors of the Christian faith, there are, at the
                            present day, even in Rome, " Prelates wiio do not believe that the Pope is the authoritative and infallible
                            interpreter of God." But freedom of belief, liberty of conscience, is infidel to Popery! And, in these days,
                            Modern Italy, the Governor of the Catholic World, has become somewhat Infidel to Popery in the proportion of 40,
                            835, to 46. But, we are not to consider this question as Catholics, nor as Protestants, but as men and
                            Christians! Descending from Infidelity to God, we are more particularly to inquire after Infidelity to
                            Christianity; that is, the doctrines of Christ, and those opposed thereto; Infidelity to the Christian Church !
                            In reference to Christ's doctrines, as the standard for Christianity, we have the Gospel Testimony in a
                            nutshell, the fulfilling of the law ! Jesus said, " I came not to destroy the law (of Moses), but to fulfill
                            it." The great precept of the fulfillment of the law, is " love to God and Man." We then have the fruits of
                            love: First, Purity; second, Peace; third, Mercy; fourth, God-like, or good fruits. Goodness embraces Charity
                            and forgiveness; these all sum up in newness of life, in everything ! " He that sat on the throne said, 'Behold,
                            I make all things neAV.'" This was Jesus Christ. New Heavens, New Earth, a new man, a new woman, a new relation
                            and association of the soxes, for a new, a heavenly purpose — to people the new Creation of God by regeneration
                            (which is synonomous with the resurrection of the soul), not b}r genera- tion! For, said Jesus, "My Kingdom is
                            not of this world;" " They that are counted worthy to obtain that world, the heavenly resurrection from the
                            dead, neither marry, nor are given in marriage, but are (in this present time and world) as the Angels of God in
                            Heaven." Generation is the basic law of this world, and the Oracle for its perpetuity. Of genera- tion we have
                            the selfishness of man; mine and thine. Of this is derived the impurities and lusts of humanity, both of the
                            flesh and of the mind ! Of these lusts come ambition, fraud, strife, war and woe. " Whence come wars and
                            fightings ? come they not hence, even of your lusts that war in your members?"—James. Thus, then, an Angel life,
                            a Celibate life of virgin purity, in thought, word and deed, is the Christ life ! The Christian chai acter is
                            set forth by the Apostle as follows: First pure, then peaceable, full of mercy and good fruits; a life Christ
                            lived out—not merely 6cUeved in; this is Christianity. Jesus said, "Not e\'ery one that saith unto me Lord,
                            Lord, shall enter into the Kingdom of Heaven, but he that doeth the will of my Father which is in Heaven ! This
                            is fidelity to Christianity ! Hence, Infidelity to Christianity consists in merely believing in Christian
                            precepts, and trusting in the merits of Jesus for Salvation; for, said Christ, "Behold I come quickly, and my
                            reward is with me to give to every one according as his works shall be." Not to crown him iviih Salvation
                            according to the righteousness of Jesus ; this is Infidelity to Christianity ! Judged then, by Jesus Christ, all
                            are infidels to Christianity who trust in the merits of Jesus for Salvation, instead of living as Jesus lived!!
                            Descending in our inquiries from the Christian's God and the Christian Testimony, to to the Christian Church, to
                            inquire what is Infidelity and who are Infidels, we are first to consider, that a Heavenly Father and Mother,
                            God, presumes a family; who are their children ? for no Being, not even God, can be a Father or Mother without
                            children ! Hence, we have Sons and Daughters of God, constituting the Christian Church, the Kingdom of God. The
                            Governmental Order of this Christ Church is theoretically Patriarchal, the Supreme Authority being the Heavenly
                            Father and Mother, God ! The secondary, derivative, or mediatorial authority, Eider Brethren and Elder Sisters !
                            Jesus was the Elder Brother of Christ's Church — " The first-born among many Brethren," as set forth by Paul.
                            Ann (the Shakers believe) was the first-born among many Sisters; if not, then a first-born Daughter is yet to
                            come! But if the Son revealed the Father, should not the Daughter be the legitimate revelator of the Mother ?
                            The Church of Christ, then, being constituted of a heavenly family of Brethren and Sisters, living in the
                            innocent and dependent capacity of the Children of God (not of husbands and wives), in a pure, celibate, angelic
                            state, as live the Angels of Heaven, and governed, in an immediate capacity, by the Heavenly Father and Mother,
                            God, but in a Mediate Capacity, by the Older (Elder) Brethren and Sisters of the family, and practicing the <pb n="29" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE life-teachings and examples of Jesus Christ, is the Christian Church! And, thus
                            to live, is fidelity to the Church, "par excellence .'" Then, may not Infidelity to the Church consist : First,
                            in ignoring the Father and lUother, God, as the leading authority of the Christian Church, and substituting a
                            Triune God, of three males, Father, Son, and Holy Ghost, all equal in age—that is, the Son as old as his Father,
                            and older than his Mother (Mary), yet, having two Mothers, the Holy Ghost Mother being the same age as her Son ?
                            And secondly, as Mediatorial authority to lead this Church, substituting Popes and Cardinals, all of the male
                            sex, as infallible vicegerents of this Trinitarian, Masculine God. And, thirdty, for the Church laity, instead
                            of simple Brethren and Sisters, of grace, and of the regeneration, whose souls are resurrected from the death of
                            sin and made immortal, substituting husbands and wives — men and women living in natural generation — who
                            propose to be carnally resurrected, to continue to propagate an earthly, sensual race, to be forever mortal,
                            only simply clothed by a frock of immortality. In a financial capacity, Fidelity to the Church of Christ on
                            earth, is, for its Church members to have all things in common, as Brethren and Sisters of the Parents'
                            household ! May not Infidelity be claiming personal and selfish property for their generated offspring, mine and
                            thine—practicing wars and bloodshed by which to settle controversies, instead of loving and forgiving ? The
                            language of Fidelity to the Christian Church is, " Come unto me all ye that weary and are heavy laden, and I
                            will give you rest." The language of Infidelity is: Believe or be damned, and be damned if you do believe,
                            unless elected by God to be saved, let you be Sinner or Saint. Fidelity teaches election to Heaven ; Salvation
                            to all souls, indiscriminately, who will confess and repent of all sin, whether in this world or in the next.
                            Prospectively considered, Fidelity to Christ's Church consists in forsaking the world, for the purpose of living
                            a holy life—that is, a life set apart for a godly use; coming unto Zion, Christ's Church, with a motive to build
                            up the Cause of God in the earth; consecrating temporal substance, time, talents, and spirit to work for God,
                            and work, too, with a will. Infidelity to Christ's Church prospectively, is to gather to the Church because of
                            poverty, "for the loaves and fishes," because of inability through sickness, idleness or negligence to make a
                            home in the world ; hence, ready to unite with any movement that promises ease plenty and individual freedom
                            from earthly cares! Nay, these may not build the temple of the living God on earth! these may not reform society
                            and "make all things new." These are Infidels to the Church! ! The problem of a new life for humanity and a new
                            order of society, of heavenly type must be solved by those in possession of living faith, unflinching devotion,
                            indomitable perseverance, and undying energy, and who consecrate their lives and treasures to God forever. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. Avery Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Biographical: teachings of Ann Lee" TEIform="index"/>BIOGRAPHICAL. Teachings of Ann Lee</head><p TEIform="p">Multitudes visited Mother Ann at her home, md made many inquiries. She was ever ready ind willing to give
                            information when inquiries came fiom the honest seeker after truth. From the following remarks may be learned
                            the answers she made to some of the questions \sked her; the questions are generally omitted as unnecessary. 1.
                            Joseph Meacham, on meetng with her, asked : " How is it, you being a woman, teach in the Church, and even claim
                            ;o be the head of it ? " "The order of God in the natural creation, s a figure of the same in the Spiritual: As
                            in nature, it requires a man and woman to produce children, the man being first, and the woman second in the
                            government of the family; and the children must be subject to their parents, and the woman subject to her
                            husband, who is first; and when the man is gone, the right of government belongs, not to the children, but to
                            the woman; such is the case in the family of Christ." 2. " The Gospel is the greatest of treasures; be faithful
                            unto it. Put your hands to work, and give your hearts to God. Beware of covetousness, which is the sin of
                            witchcraft. If you have anything to spare, give it to the poor." 3. "Be faithful unto gospel duty; be neat and
                            industrious; keep your family's clothes clean and decently repaired. See that your house is kept clean, and your
                            food prepared in good order; that when the brethren come from their hard work, they may bless you, and eat their
                            food with thankfulness, and be able to praise God in the beauty of holiness. Watch and be careful; don't speak
                            harshly, nor cast reflections upon them; let your words be few and seasoned with grace." 4. " You must put away
                            your covetousness, your lust and your filthiness, and be prepared for the increase of the Gospel. Remember the
                            poor and need}'-; the widow and the fatherless; deal your bread to the hungry, and your clothes to the naked.
                            Your natures will say, ' let them work for them;' but Christ sayeth not so. Remember the cries of those in need
                            and in trouble, that when you are in trouble, God will hear your cries." 5. " Little children are innocent; and
                            they should be kept so. If brought up in innocence and simplicity they will receive good as easily as evil. Do
                            not blame them for every little fault; teach them obedience, let your word be law. Never speak to them in a
                            passion; it will put devils into them. When I was a child, vaj mind was taken up with the things of God, so that
                            I saw heavenly visions, instead of trifling with toys. Do all your work as though you had a thousand years to
                            live; and as though you were going to die to-morrow." 6. " Once my feet walked in forbidden paths; my hands
                            handled unclean things, and my eyes saw nothing of God aright. Now, my feet are in the narrow Avay; my eyes see,
                            my ears hear, and my hands handle the word of God. You can never enter the kingdom of God with hard feeling
                            towards any. God is love; and if you love God, you will love one another.'' 7. " The work of God in this day is
                            an inward, spiritual work. It is not so great in outward appearance as it was in past Dispensations ; therefore,
                            souls must be very careful how they treat this Gospel. Such as finally reject the testimony thereof in this
                            world, will not have another day equal to this; nor any, until an offer of the Gospel shall have been made to
                            the entire race of Adam. The Gospel will increase; small at first, but will yet be embraced by hundreds and
                            thousands. It will increase, until the covering is taken off, that now covers the rottenness of anti-christ's
                            foundation; then, souls that are bound in sin will call to the rocks and the mountains to cover them." 8. "
                            Those who obeyed the Gospel on Earth, taking up their cross as Jesus did, stand with him on Mount Zion; these
                            are in the first resurrection; while those who wait to receive and obey the truth in their disembodied states,
                            will not be so glorious, but constitute the second fruits." 9. " All souls will have an offer of this Gospel,
                            either in this world or the world of spirits. You have your day now, prize it. By obedience you can progress out
                            of your loss, and become over-comers as Jesus was; but souls in the world of spirits make their progress through
                            sufferings, passing from prison to prison, until they find the mercj^ of God ! " We purpose a continuation of
                            Ann Lee's sayings; they may sound ancient; they may seem superstitious; but obedience to them has ever wrought
                            greater purity of character, and created an appetite for works of righteousness—a progress from a little faith
                            unto greater faithfulness. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion of the revolutionary fathers" TEIform="index"/>The Religion of the Revolutionary Fathers</head><p TEIform="p">In early childhood — almost in infancy — when the mind is plastic and confiding, I wrent to meeting. The meeting
                            was in a barn, still standing, near the 45th parallel, on the High- gate side of the line, between what was then
                            Elder Thomas Best's and Colonel Lake's. The preacher, in demonstrating the necessity for deferring the final
                            judgment to some remote period, used the following argument: " It cannot be ascertained, at death, the amount of
                            good or evil that a man has done. For instance, there is Father Wesley: it may take thousands of years to
                            determine the amount of good he. has done. On the other hand, there is Tom Paine : it may take as many thousand
                            years to calculate the vast amount of evil he has done." Of course, I took it for granted, that Father Wesley,
                            if not the best, was next to the best, man that ever was; and that Tom Paine must rank next to a certain
                            unmentionable character, of which or whom the preacher made frequent mention. First impressions, especially in
                            theology, remain, till driven out by sternest logic. While still a child, of some ten or twelve summers, my
                            father, from one of his frequent visits to his brother, Captain John Prentiss, of Rutland, Vermont, brought home
                            a book, entitled " The Jeffersonade; or Democracy Unveiled: by Dr. Caustic." This I read. 29 <pb n="30" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 3O THE SHA.KER. Jefferson, in his " Notes on Virginia,'" written while Governor of Virginia, said : " It
                            matters not to me, whether my neighbor believes in one God, or twenty. It neither picks my pocket, nor breaks my
                            leg." Jefferson wrote the Declaration of Independ- ence, and it was unanimously adopted by the Continental
                            Congress, with slight variations. When something over twenty years of age, a gentleman from Albany gave me a
                            pamphlet purporting to have been written by Thomas Paine. How dared I to read it ? I did read it, and then threw
                            it into the fire. The pamphlet, written in America, was addressed to the masses of Europe, with the intent of
                            lifting them from the thraldom of superstition, that they might begin to be men. He dealt in great plainness of
                            speech, with what he seemed to regard as the unwarranted assumptions of the clergy; told, at considerable
                            length, what he did not believe. Then he said, ''Perhaps some of my readers would like to know what I do
                            believe. That there was such a man as Jesus of Nazareth I verily believe; and that he was the most perfect
                            example of righteousness this world ever saw, I also believe. And, if they who profess to be his followers would
                            pay more attention to following his example, and make less noise about it, I believe it would be infinitely
                            better for the world of mankind." Some years later, I met with my father, who was deeply religious and an
                            admirer of Father Wesley. I ventured to question him on what seemed to me an incongruity in my early-imbibed
                            notions of Tom Paine, as compared with the sentiments expressed in the pamphlet. I said to him, "Do you know
                            anything of Thomas Paine ?" He said, " Yes; I was well acquainted with him. He was Washington's private
                            secretary; and, while I was in the Life Guards, I used to see him every day." " Well," said I, " what can you
                            say of him ?" This was the first time I had ever moved the question. I regarded it as a delicate subject; and my
                            father seemed so to regard it. After some deliberation, he said : "Well, to do him justice, if I say anything, I
                            must say he Was the best man in America. He did more to achieve our independence than any other man, except
                            Washington. And I don't know that I do right to make that exception. For when, after repeated disasters, we were
                            retreating south, pursued hj a wellfed, well-clad, superior force (it was the darkest time of the war),
                            Washington said to his Secretary : ' Paine, what shall we do ? This army is the only hope of the country. Here
                            we are, in dead of winter, unclothed, unfed unshod; the men leave the prints of their bare and bleeding feet on
                            the frozen ground; their term of enlistment is about to expire; and I have not the heart, under such
                            circumstances, to ask them to re-enlist. What can we do ?' " After solemnly reviewing the situation, Paine
                            replied, 'If you will form the men into ¦ a hollow square, around that stump, we'll see what can be done.' The
                            men were formed; Paine mounted the stump All eyes were upon him. The men had often seen him, but had seldom
                            heard him; for he was a man of few words. Paine, carefully and solemnly surveyed his audience. There was silence
                            audible. He spoke. His words were highly charged with electric fire. Thus he began : " ' This is the time to try
                            men's souls! The summer soldier and rotten-hearted villain that noiv deserts his country's cause deserves the
                            curses of his fellow-citizens.' " When his oration was ended, the soldiers, almost to a man, re-enlisted. They
                            had received Paine's inspiration. A new soul was in them. They assaulted and carried the Hessian camp. The tide
                            of war was turned, and success followed success. Cornwallis surrendered ; the war ended; the men, unpaid, went
                            home to provide for their little ones as best they could; and Paine's reputation, like that of public
                            benefactors in general, was committed to the tender mercies of—not the wicked, of course not — the clergy." "
                            Independence is my happiness; I view things as they are, without regard to place or person. My country is the
                            world; my religion, to do good."—Paine.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., O." TEIform="persName"/>O. P.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plain Talks, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>Plain Talks—No, 1</head><p TEIform="p">There is a deep, religious agitation at work in the hearts of the people. It is not mani- fested by bubbling,
                            church revivals, that too commonly burst, and leave the individual the worse for its spirit-intoxication; but it
                            is deeply, silently working; silently anxious for, and demanding more of soul-satisfaction. Church theologies
                            are becoming stale, and the Divine life is looked for, yearned for, demanded. " What shall I do to be saved ?"
                            stirs the bosoms of thousands who cannot find satisfactory answers in their temples of worship. Popular
                            preachers are learning that popular preaching may pamper the intellect, but does not feed the hungry soul; and
                            that it is impossible to impart the love and life of Christ to their flocks, when they neither have that love,
                            nor live that life. The crisis is coming. The Life-of-Christ testimony has taken issue with the death, and
                            Calvary-blood theory! Life versus Death ! There is much soul-distress in the land ; this is the result of
                            disobedience to heavenly light—" this is the condemnation." God hears the earnest seeker after truth, and
                            answers; but God's answer speaks of self-denial, of the physical cross ; of the higher life and the Angel
                            character, and sweetly says, " Come up hither ! " and the representative soul responds, "Lord! (for the present)
                            excuse me." God does excuse; the soul's trouble increases; it feels that it is excused from God's help, by
                            refusing to obey God's will. "Help, help!" cries the soul; "Livk, Live ! " cries the Spirit. And yet, how hard
                            is the lesson, " live unto God and die unto ever}r sinful practice ! " Scores of individuals are writing us,
                            predicting the coming of the Spirit of Christ the second time. Scores of periodicals are just issuing, declaring
                            the same fact; to all of which we say, Amen. The Spirit of Christ has appeared once, through Jesus, and already
                            to some the second time; and we learn from its testimony, to live apart from sexual and sensual lusts; we learn
                            from it that the virgin character is alone countenanced in the heavens; we learn from it, that private property
                            belongs to the earthly life—to the generative sphere, and has no part with Christ nor with Christians. It
                            teaches us that war is devilish, and those who practice it, the servants of the devil! Plain, but true. The soul
                            wants truth; it will be satisfied with nothing else. We have taken issue with the whole world of sin ; we have
                            stripped off the mask that covers, with fine words and splendid appearances, with false philosophy and
                            unchristian teaching, the distresses of the soul, that rob it of eternal life; and we accept the consequences.
                            Theorise, twist with dexterous legerdemain the Scriptures; transform the real life of Jesus into what his
                            teachings may have meant; we accept his life and love of goodness as our pattern and hope of Salvation, knowing
                            full well, that as fast as the second Appearing manifests itself to souls, and its teachings are accepted,
                            others will do likewise. We have large respect for the sincere; but we have no respect for those who sing the
                            praise of Jesus, but hate him in their lives, knowing what they do. We cannot daub, with hopes of salvation, the
                            carnal mind nor body, whose loves and practices are at enmity with Christ's life. Let us, before accepting any
                            religious sympathy from our professedly Christian leaders, demand that they strictly follow the true
                            leader—Christ; and were this rule generally adopted, we would see the sheep's-clothing thrown off extensively,
                            and the hood-winks dropping from the eyes of the multitudes. Let us have Christ's life as a pattern—can we do
                            better ? and what in our lives, does not harmonize with it, let us confess the same to be unchristian, and we,
                            so far from being Christians. " Open confession is good for the soul;" and to this point of decision is the
                            present religious agitation bringing souls—to a self-examination. Many there are who have arrived at the
                            conviction (in foro cons cienticz) that their lives have not been Christian; and rather than do the work, and
                            live the life of a Christian, they have renounced the name—F. E. Abbott-like—and declare we are not, and will
                            not be Christians. This is the more honorable course, rather than live and die in sin; exulting in all the
                            practices, or even in some of them that are opposites to Christ's life, and yet hope to be saved from the
                            penalties of sins we will not relinquish while it is in our power to engage in them. *</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The following is Prof. Bush's rendering..." TEIform="index"/>The following is Prof. Bush's rendering...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The following is Prof. Bush's rendering of Zach. ¦4:7:— "MI ATTAUH HAUR GAUDOL LIPNA ZERTJBBABEL LEMISHOB HOTSIA
                            EBEN KOSH TESHUA ANN ANN LEE." Let us look into the next world : Bodily habits contracted here, will have no
                            medium there ; and hence we will be necessitated to unlearn there, wrongs we have indulged in here. Is it not a
                            wise choice, to engage in nothing here, but what we can hereafter ? The most useless of tasks is to save another
                            from conditions we are lost in ourselves. Jesus first overcame the whole world of evil, before he encouraged his
                            disciples to follow him. We are called to be Saviours; let us first seek salvation, not from penalties' but from
                            practices of sin ; then can we help our fellows out of the pit. Parents should think, while teaching their
                            children to confess to them their wrongs, that the gospel of Christ demands of Parents, confession unto
                            apostles. *</p></div2><pb n="31" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Church of Christ" TEIform="index"/>The Church of Christ</head><p TEIform="p">What is the church of Christ ? The apostolic term, which is rendered church in our English version of the New
                            Testament, is ecclesia, which signifies, sometimes, a collection of believers in Christ in any one place, and
                            sometimes, all the believers, wherever located. In ancient Athens, the term was applied, commonly, to the
                            assembly of citizens for the transaction of public business. The ecclesia included only the freemen of Athens;
                            hence, by a very appropriate transfer, it was applied to the Assembly of Christians, who were all regarded as
                            one, and entitled to equal privileges in the church. In respect to all essential rights, no association of
                            persons has ever existed in which was greater equality than in the church of the apostles' day. In this respect,
                            there was neither Greek nor Barbarian, bond nor free. The Greek word, ecclesia with slight changes, has been
                            retained by the Latin nations of Europe. In the Italian language, it is chiesa; in the Spanish, ighsia, and in
                            the French, eglise. But the Teutonic or Germanic nations have taken their term for the church from another Greek
                            word, kuriakon, an adjective, which, taken with the agreeing noun, soma, signifies the Lord's body, and, with
                            doma, the Lord's house. Hence, we find in the German language, kirche, in the Danish and Scotch, kirke and kirk,
                            and in the English, church. The Apostle Paul, who, in common with most Asiatic writers, had a fondness for the
                            use of metaphors, sometimes represented Christians in their collective capacity as an edifice. " That thou
                            mayest know how to conduct thyself in the house of God," he wrote to Timothy; then, in immediate juxtaposition,
                            he used three other similar yet appropriate figures, " which is the ecclesia or assembly of the living God, the
                            pillar and foundation of the truth." Again, in addressing Christians, he said, " Ye are the temple of the living
                            God." But his favorite figure was that of the human body, which probably as aptly illustrates the real, living
                            church of Christ as any figure that can be empk^ed. "God has appointed him (Christ), pre-eminently, the head of
                            the ecclesia, which is his body, the fullness of him who fills all things among all." " For as the body is one,
                            yet has many members, and all the members of this one body, though many, are but one body, so also is
                            Christ"—that is, Jesus Christ and his church,—"for by one Spirit we have all been baptized into one body." The
                            figure has been so amply enlarged by the apostle that one can hardly fail to comprehend its full force. He has
                            presented to the imagination a living, active being, composed of various parts, yet all actuated by an impulse;
                            the head devising what is deemed needful for the entire body, and each part acting in harmony with the whole, so
                            that whatever is done by each, contributes equally to the welfare of every other. That which characterizes this
                            being, is the spirit with which it is animated. Its fulness or completeness is from the Infinite Beintr who
                            fills all things. That Beine; is unchangeably the same—Eternal Love. The body that is actuated and governed by
                            Love, evinces it by harmonious action within itself— there can be no division among its various par Is. The
                            figure means this, or it means nothing. Hence, the propriety of these words of the apostle,—" If any man has not
                            the Spirit of Christ, he is none of his." By no effort of the imagination can we include in such a body opposing
                            elements which array the members against each other. We may use other figures, if we choose, to express the
                            various opposing elements that exist among mankind; but how they can be admitted as appropriate to a hoAy moving
                            under the impulse of divine love, and governed by it in all its actions, it would be difficult to tell. Not only
                            must the apostle's rhetoric be changed, but human reason must be reconstructed. Let it be granted that human
                            nature has been such in all ages, that wars and contentions have been unavoidable, yet, why not assign to these
                            their true origin ? If human passions are stronger than God's grace in Christ, yet it was never admitted by the
                            apostle. The Christian's course has been represented by Paul as a warfare, it is true, yet such a warfare as is
                            not inconsistent with the figure of a united body, a well-constructed and beautiful mansion, or a temple which
                            is the glory of the whole earth. So he has represented it as a race, but only such a race, as that in which the
                            prize—the crown of immortal glory—may be gained hj every one who enters upon the race-course. Not so with those
                            who ran in the Grecian stadium. It maybe asked, "Are you aiming to prove, from a mere figure of speech, that the
                            mighty hosts which have come down to our times through the ages, with the standard of the cross conspicuously
                            elevated above every battallion, every division, and every army, do not really constitute the body of Christ ?"
                            The figure certainly proves this, if these hosts have all along been contending with each other with "carnal
                            weapons of warfare" as wrell as with "the sharp sword that goeth out of their mouth," instead of using those
                            weapons that are "mighty through God" to destroy sin in themselves. That the history of the past as well as the
                            present condition of the nations show this, every one may see who casts but a cursory glance over both. The "
                            God of all peace " as well as of love, rules the body of Christ. It requires no great force of logic to show
                            what must be the result of such rule. But if the figure of speech is not clear enough, then let us take simpler
                            language equally apostolic writh the figure. " Whosoever doeth not righteousness is not of God, neither he that
                            lovethnot his brother." " Let us not love in word, nor in tongue, but in deed and in truth." " He laid down his
                            life for us, we ought also to lay down our lives for the brethren." These words are explicit enough to show that
                            those who make war upon each other, instead of loving and laying down their lives for each other, do not
                            constitute the body of Christ, whatever else they may be. These words of Jesus Christ to his disciples, though
                            expressed in a figure, are sufficiently clear to show of what characters only his church is composed :—" I am
                            the vine, ye are the branches. He that abideth in me and I in him, the same bringeth forth much fruit. If a man
                            abideth not in me, he is cast forth as a branch that is withered." The life of the vine and its branches, as
                            well as that of every plant in the vegetable kingdom, is maintained only so long as they adhere to that which
                            supplies the vivifying sap. Christ abides in God, His life is the life of God—eternal love—and those who are
                            united to him also partake of the same life. There is no other alternative,—either make the tree good and its
                            fruit good, or the tree corrupt and its fruit corrupt. The church of Christ, then, consists of those persons,
                            wherever they may be, who are so united to him that his life, which is the highest element of life in the
                            universe—divine love— pervades their being and has a controlling influence upon their entire conduct. In this
                            sense the oft-repeated expression, " there is no salvation out of the Church," is true. There is nothing else
                            that will save one, in the broadest and highest signification of salvation, but that which unites him to the
                            divine life, and when he possesses this within himself, he is an integral part of that body in which is the
                            divine completeness. Christ's church has also been represented as a kingdom. This was the prevailing form of
                            government in his day, and that under which the Messiah's government was prefigured by the Jewish prophets, so
                            that it was almost a matter of course that he used such an illustration. But in our democratic age, the figure
                            is less agreeable to the taste than some others. It conveys an idea of too much pomp and splendor. There is too
                            great a distance between ruler and subject. We can scarcely get a glimpse of the meek and lowly Jesus amid the
                            glitter and show of palaces, thrones, and countless attendants, and through the smoke of the adulatory incense.
                            However attractive and venerable it has become by reason of its existence of ages, yet, "Come from the four
                            winds, 0 breath," breathe upon and dissolve forever this scene of oriental enchantment! We like better the
                            gentle shepherd leading his flock through verdant pastures and by the side of still waters. If we wished to
                            indulge the feeling of reverence, then we would enter the magnificent temple, -where God dwells and walks among
                            his people. But the figure of the family admits, if not as great a variety and splendor as that of the kingdom,
                            yet more naturalness, more attractiveness to the soul in its gentler and kindlier moods, and is really more in
                            accordance with the spirit of divine love and tenderness that dwelt in Christ. Male and female are each
                            representative of distinctive features or principles in Deity, and as these are one in essence and co-equal in
                            office in the Divine Being, so are they to be, and should be regarded in Christ or in the church. In the family
                            of Christ are Father and Mother. They have their offspring, those who have been born into the higher life of
                            divine love. These are brothers and sisters, possessing equal rights and privileges. There are. in this family,
                            no rights of primogeniture. There is <pb n="32" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> no oldest son to claim all the dignities and in- herit
                            the estate, while the rest are dismissed to the plebeian ranks. There is reciprocal love between parents and
                            children and between brothers and sisters, for love is the clement of their existence. They have unlimited
                            wealth— "durable riches of righteousness; " "all things are theirs, whether things present or things to come,"
                            and they are to remain theirs throughout "the aoe of ages."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>Wm. H. Bussell</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To my youth, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>To My Youth—Mo. 1</head><p TEIform="p">By the good providences of God you have a privilege to see and hear of, and practice Chris- tian principles.
                            There are many persons educated in schools and colleges, and called Christians, who preach and pray, and yet
                            have not begun to practice the first Christian principles; indeed, have not j^et begun to practice the first
                            just, natural principles—that is, to get an honest living with their own hands. Your opportunities to become
                            truly learned, greatly exceed theirs; and if you receive the principles and truths of the gospel—the glad
                            tidings that Christ and Mother brought—and put them into practice in your every day life, in all your goings
                            forth, you Avill become truly learned, and finally, you will be assured that in Christ Jesus is hid all the
                            treasures of wisdom and knowledge. My object in writing to you is not to open up any branch of knowledge, but to
                            point where some of the treasures of wisdom and knowledge may be found. The Old Testament is a wonderful book—it
                            contains a system of law adapted to the natural man, which exceeds all other systems of human law; and
                            portraiture of human character, so truthful, and applicable to human conditions, that even after the lapse of
                            three thousand years, they are still fresh, new and instructive. In the above respects, the Bible is without a
                            parallel among books—it is above and beyond them all. And of the New Testament, the parables alone are caskets
                            of knowledge, to say nothing of the great leading principles which underlie Christianity—lived out by the
                            Saviour and opened in his teachings. What can be more comprehensive, or fuller of sim- plicity than Christ's
                            interview with the young man who came to him, and kneeling, asked, what shall I do to inherit eternal life ? In
                            a few words he conveyed to the young man a knowledge of the work necessary to be done as a preparation to
                            entering his kingdom—to keep the Moral Law—that is, do nothing to injure others, and give his all and himself to
                            God; then he would be in a condition to learn of Jesus. The reading of the parables as presented in the
                            Scriptures, is very much like unto a rich man having a casket of precious things, who comes along and shows you
                            a nice box; he opens it, and every little compartment is stored with jewels; he shuts it up and takes it away
                            with him, and you are none the richer for what you have seen. So of the sayings of Jesus ; you may read them,
                            and get an outside understanding of them, but if you do not practice, nor square your life by them, you will not
                            be any richer in heavenly things. Jesus spake from the life he lived; hence, he was able to say, "the words that
                            I speak unto you they are spirit and they are life." Now, if you will make his life your life, so in your
                            degree, you will be able also to speak from your life. But if you fail to do so—have not the life of Christ in
                            you, you will be able to speak of natural things only, for out of the contents of the heart the mouth speakcth.
                            It may be observed here, that all human beings have in them a two-fold life—an inward or spiritual life, and an
                            outward animal life. Before I close, I will say a few words on this subject. In the meantime, I will open one of
                            the caskets. On the outside is written the following words: "I will open my mouth in parables, I will utter
                            things which have been kept hid from the foundation of the world"— the natural man. Parable first: A sower went
                            forth to sow his seed, and as he sowed, some fell by the way side and was trodden down, and the fowls of the air
                            devoured them. And some fell on stony places, and forthwith the seed sprung up because there was but little
                            earth, and when the sun shone, the plants withered. And some fell among thorns, and the plants were choked. And
                            some fell on good ground, and brought forth, some one degree of fruit, and others, a greater measure. When Jesus
                            had opened this casket, he said, "he that hath ears to hear let him hear." He then shut the casket up and took
                            it away with him, and left the multitude to think about what might be the meaning of the parable. No doubt, you
                            would like to know the reason why Jesus did not explain it to them. He would have been well pleased to have done
                            so, but he considered their state of preparation to hear his word and wisdom, forbade committing further
                            knowledge to their keeping. And with pleasure he turned to his disciples and said, "blessed are your eyes, for
                            they see, and your ears, for they hear." "Hear ye therefore the parable of the sower." And he began to open to
                            them its interior meaning', which }tou may read by turning to Luke 8:5. But before he began, he said, " Many
                            prophets and righteous men have desired to see what you see, and hear what you hear, and have not." To the
                            language used by Jesus in explaining the first part of the parable, I would draw }rour attention. " Those by the
                            wayside are they who hear; then cometh the devil and taketh away the word out of their hearts." Now, how did the
                            devil manage to take the good word out of their hearts ? They gave way to lightness—"the fowls of the air
                            devoured it." Here we see, that giving way to lightness in sacred things, is an act of the Devil. Young persons
                            are greatly exposed to receive from others, this spirit of lightness; to many, it is just as natural to be light
                            as it is to breathe, or in other Avords, they willingly work the work of the Devil, and minister the same spirit
                            of lightness to others, and think nothing about it; and that is the way the Devil wishes his work to be done; do
                            it, and never think about it afterwards. Christ, knowing how exposed souls are, said, " Watch and pray that ye
                            enter not into temptation," that is, into the spirit of the Evil One. The Devil has the easiest access to young
                            people through the avenue of lightness ; they think there is no great harm in it, and will actually sing the
                            songs of Zion in a vain, careless sense. When a soldier is placed on guard, it is his duty to watch and see that
                            no enemy goes over the line or gets a foothold in the camp. So of all the thoughts that enter your heads; except
                            you gather and keep the gift of self-examination, you will find that the Devil will enter your premises every
                            day, and instead of you being a guard to keep out evil, you will be an avenue to receive and admit it.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="F., D." TEIform="persName"/>D. F.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If the people called Shakers, do not exhibit..." TEIform="index"/>If the people called Shakers, do not exhibit...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">If the people called Shakers, do not exhibit, ivith an increase, before all men. the faith, spirit, doctrines and
                            principles of the primitive, Christian Church, together with power over evil in their own souls, let that decide
                            the whole question. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leonard, William" TEIform="persName"/>Wm. Leonard</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editor's notes" TEIform="index"/>Editor's Notes</head><byline TEIform="byline"><index level1="The Editor" TEIform="index"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Attention is called to the address of Wm. Leonard, " Ayer, Muss.." changed from "Groton;" also, a change in "Mt.
                            Morris" agency. Individuals sending articles for publication will regard the spirit, of the "Circular" issned to
                            Believers. The Editor's drawer, though nearly full of good matter, will hold some more. We want a wider sphere
                            of contributions ; some think we are acting on too contracted a scale—the reason is, we have not yet heard from
                            the East nor West, but in small degree. Remember, The Shaker is the organ of the United Societies. We want short
                            articles ; full of pith, testimony, and true to life. We repeat: we will send one copy extra tor five
                            subscribers. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker, monthly journal, devoted to the exposition of religion, acording to Shaker theology" TEIform="index"/>THE
                            SHAKER. MONTHLY JOURNAL, DEVOTED TO THE EXPOSITION OF RELIGION, ACCORDING TO SHAKER THEOLOGY.</head><p TEIform="p">Fifty Cents, Per Annum, in Advance. G. A. Lomas. Resident Editor, Shakers, Albany, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Members of society" TEIform="index"/>MEMBERS OF SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p"> Appointed to answer Corresporidents, among whom are the Board of Editors. Elder F. W. Evans, art. Lebanon,
                            Columbia Co., N. Y. " Issaehar Bates. Shakers, Albany, N. Y. " Peter H. Long, Mt. Morris, Livingston Co., N. Y.
                            " Simon Mabec, West Pittsfield, Mass. " Stonghton Kellogg, Thompson ville, Conn., Shakers. " Albert Battles,
                            Tyringham, Berkshire Co., Mass. " Wm. Leonard, Aver, Mass., Shakers. " John Whiteley, Shirley Village, Middlesex
                            Co., Mass. " Nehemiah Trull, Shaker Tillage, Merrimack Co., N. H. 11 Henry Cummings, Enfield, Grafton Co., N.
                            II. " John B. Vance, Alfred, Shakers. York Co., Me. " Alonzo Oilman, West Gloucester, Cumberland Co., Me.,
                            Shakers. " O. C. Hampton, Union Village, Warren Co., O., Shakers. " Ezra Sherman, Preston, Hamilton Co., Ohio,
                            Shakers. " Stephen Ball, Dayton, Shakers, Ohio. " George linnyou, Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co., Ky. " J. It. Eades,
                            South Union, Logan Co., Ky. " J. S. Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio, Shakers. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publications" TEIform="index"/>PUBLICATIONS.</head><p TEIform="p">Christ's First and Second Appearing Dnnlavy's Manifesto Millennial Church Compendium of Shakerism Three
                            Discourses on United Interests Tracts free, where postage is paid. $1 25 1 26 1 00 0 50 0 50 32 THE SHAKEE.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>